Hi, welcome to the Dynamic Duel podcast where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in crossover battle
simulations. I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin
brother Marvelous Joe. And this episode, our main
event is Azrael vs. Blade. Yeah, we know that we
wanted to review Blade in our next episode with the
countdown to the Black Panther movie coming out.
We thought it would be a good idea to give homage to
the character that kind of not only started the
whole modern wave of superhero films, but also was
one of the first leading Black superhero
characters to start in a film. Yeah. And you know,
putting him against Azrael, I don't think most
people would have thought of this match. It was so
hard. Like, I spent the longest time trying to
convince you that Constantine was the best
matchup for Blade. The worst match ever. There's
no way Blade would stand. Blade would not even
touch Constantine. If you say so, I disagree with
that. But I think I ended up googling like DC
superheroes that carry swords or something like
that. I saw a cool image of Azrael Yeah. hearing the
sword. So I was like, oh, that might work. I hadn't
even thought of Azrael. And well, Azrael kind of
has he has like a pseudo supernatural, more
religious background. Yeah. So it's kind of
comparable. And because Blade is a supernatural
hero. So I think it works. Yeah. I mean, you know,
Azrael, he's strong and faster than the usual.
He's super human is what I'm saying, along with the
blade. Yeah. So you know, Blade was always like
this really, really like unique character. And so
when you when you suggested Azrael, I was like, why
didn't I think of that? So that's what we're doing.
I think we're also thinking like Zeriel for a
while. But it was really hard to get information on
him. Zeriel, the angel who Zario Zario. How do you
say it? I see Zario. He was an angel character that
was featured in the Justice League of America
during Grant Morrison's run. I thought that might
be a good matchup too. But I like this one better.
Dude, Zeriel would have stopped Blade, not even a
good match. All right. If you say so, man, I
disagree. But before we get into the match, we like
to do the news breakdown. There's no DC news. Good.
This episode sucks the way I like it. All Marvel all
the time. So Logan gets an Oscar nomination for
best adapted screenplay. Wonder Woman gets a
snub. We'll be talking about that. Hans Zimmer
comes out of retirement to score X-Men Dark
Phoenix. That's cool. There's a new set photo and
video that gives us our first look at Captain
Marvel. Brie Larson is Captain Marvel. Yeah,
there's a ton of like internet outrage. There's a
reading talk about that. We're going to get into
that. And that's that's pretty much all the news
there is. It's kind of a slow news week. A little
bit. It's not too bad for Marvel. But up next, let's
talk about the no prize. Yeah. So last week, our
question of the week was, which Marvel or DC
television series do you think had the strongest
pilot episode? No one chose my favorite. No one.
Well, actually, a few people chose my favorite.
But I think the most interesting answer and the
winner of the no prize for this week is John Spees,
who gave the answer. He said, I think the X-Men
animated series had the best pilot. Yeah, I didn't
even consider like any animated series. No, yeah,
when I was thinking about this question. But I
recently watched the X-Men animated series
again, because we actually, we did a guest spot on
John's podcast, which is the blast from our past
podcast, which is an amazing show that they put on.
If you haven't listened to it yet, super nostalgia
feels. Yeah, check out the blast from our past
podcast. They talk about all the cool stuff that we
enjoyed as kids in the early nineties and late
eighties. So but I will rewatch the X-Men animated
cartoon and that pilot episode did such a good job
of setting up the themes of the show. Like it wasn't
afraid to get deep, but it had tremendous action.
And I think it did a great job introducing these
iconic characters in a way that made it so
palatable to the mainstream audience. Like that
show was heavily inspired by the early nineties,
Jim Lee and Claremont Run. Yeah. Yeah, I think that
was a great answer. It's definitely one of the
strongest pilots that has ever been produced.
Yeah. So John will be getting the no prize. But what
was your favorite pilot? I think my answer to this
question, I think everybody who has listened to
this podcast for a while knows that I'm a huge fan of
the Legion TV show that came out early last year.
And I think that pilot episode drew me in in a way
that nothing else did. I was I was so concerned that
the Legion show was going to be such a radical
departure from the comics. And it was, but it made
it so interesting that I was compelled to keep
watching. And I just loved every episode as much as
the first almost. So yeah, that has to be my answer.
I've seen the pilot. It was good. But I didn't like
it as much as I liked Smallville's pilot.
Smallville had a great pilot back in the day. That
was the one that ended with like the tornado in the
cornfield. And they like strung him up like a
scarecrow with the kryptonite necklace and they
had the the S painted on the chest. But just like
seeing Clark Kent and Lex Luthorin, like I grew up
with I was a freshman when Smallville came out. So
like when Clark became a sophomore and I was
growing along with him. So I was like, I was the
perfect age for that show. It was a good one. I mean,
I think I stopped watching after the second or
third season because it kind of became apparent
that they were never going to show him become
Superman. And the way that show ended. They never
really did. Yeah, it's so stupid. I think I stopped
after like season five. I stuck with it for a while.
I just like every episode I just want to like after
the third season, I was like, just shut up Lana. I
just like to the concept of it. Like it was like, you
know, the meteorites coming with Superman to
Earth, the kryptonite meteorites and the
radiation from those creating weekly villain of
the week villain of the weeks. It was, you know, it
may not work now, but it totally worked on me then.
Yeah. Yeah, definitely. Yeah, I had had good
action to get special effects. Yeah, great kind of
portrayal of the powers that he did have like with
X-ray vision and the heat vision and all that
stuff. Yeah, it was a good show for a while. Yeah.
And then I sucked. I don't know. I know. But yeah, I
stopped watching. I agree. Great pilot episode
for sure. Yeah, I know I was hooked on that one too.
And I'm not even a DC guy. So that that's a testament
to how good it was. Yeah. All right, so we'll be
asking another question later on in the show
during our news segment. So keep an eye out for that
if you want to win that note prize for our next
episode. Yep. So on to the news segment. Logan. No,
the real news here is that Wonder Woman was
snubbed. No, I think the real news is that Logan is
the first comic book movie to be nominated for the
Best Adapted Screenplay Award. Which? So it's
going to go to, I think James Mangold wrote the
script. Really? Yeah. He also co-wrote it with
writers named Scott Frank and Michael Green. So if
they win, it would mean so much to the comic book
genre, I think as a whole. Yeah. Because it's not
like a technical award or like a makeup award like
Suicide Squad 1. Right. It's a testament to how
strong the story was. Right. Honestly, this is the
one category of Oscars that I'm sorry. I've always
wanted a comic book film to be nominated. And to
win. Besides the best picture. Well, besides the
best picture, I think the biggest award a comic
book film has really won was, you know, Best
Supporting Actor for Heath Ledger. That's
definitely like, I think, like the most
prestigious. But again, that's not really
commenting on someone's performance rather than
like the source material and giving legitimacy to
the source material. Or the adapted material.
Right. Yeah, I agree. I agree. I think this, if it
wins, it can mean so much because I feel like
there's a slight sense of superhero fatigue out
there, especially I felt it a lot like around when
Justice League was just released. And I like when
people come down on superhero movies, one of their
criticisms is that maybe there's too many of these
being made or something like that. So good
superhero movies can only, you know, benefit the
genre as a whole. And especially when they win
awards, that they can only mean positive things.
And I think that if it wins an award, we'll see maybe
more movies being made like Logan in the future.
Yeah, I'm not sure. Well, what is it going up
against? Oh, that's a good question. It's going up
against adapted screenplay. Let's see. Call me by
your name. Donut. The Disaster Artist. Oh, no,
that Molly's game. He sort of know that. I've heard
that one was written by Aaron Sorkin. Sure. I heard
that was really good. And the last one was
Mudbound. So like I would have to, I'd probably
give Logan like the number two seed in this list. It
might go to Molly's game, which would suck because
I mean, well, Aaron Sorkin is really good, but he's
won Academy Awards before. So it would be cool to
see these guys win. You know what the sucky thing is
though, even if it wins this award, what can they do
with that? Because, you know, Disney is about to
own those characters now. Plus, like Logan is
dead. Like you can't really like take that and run
with it into like a sequel. Like I'm sure like
someone really would want to, especially with,
you know, like because it's in a franchise. What I
mean, unless Marvel wants to hire main gold to do an
X-Men film, which I think would be fantastic. I do,
I think about how the X-Men are going to go into the
Marvel Cinematic Universe all the time. Like I
dream about that. And I was actually, this is a kind
of a tangent off the main topic, but I was thinking
in the shower the other day, how are they going to
introduce mutants into the MCU? Yeah, how they'd
never been mentioned before. Right. And I kind of
came up with a theory that I don't know if has been
already come up somewhere else. It probably has.
But I was thinking, what if mutants have been
around in the MCU this entire time? Like they were
there for the Battle of New York with the Avengers
and everything like that. But the reason that
nobody remembers them is because Professor X is
like neuralizing them like with Cerebro kind of
like in Men of Black how like, Oh, what? Like how Men
of Black you can like make people forget with the
neuralizer. Like what if Professor X is doing
something like that? He's just mindwiping
everybody? Just yeah, using Cerebro. He's like,
and that's how he keeps the mutants anonymity is by
keeping them safe. So the whole world doesn't know
that mutants exist? Right. Yeah. I think it would
be cool if mutants did already exist in the MCU, but
no one knew about them. People would just keep
getting their mind wiped regarding the mutation
and everything like that. And then they would
almost make Professor X a villain. Yeah, but he's
done shady things like that in the past before, you
know? So I think it's not outside of his character.
And then maybe when they're introduced into the
MCU, Professor X is no longer able to hide the
existence of mutants because Magneto like
launches like an offensive against mankind or
something. Destroy Cerebro or something like
that or something like that. Yeah. That's not a bad
theory. I'm trying to think of any other way it
could be done. Nope. That's the only acceptable
way it could be done. I think it's a great way to kind
of establish them in the history of the MCU, but
also introduce them as new characters. Huh. So
we'll see if they end up going that route. But yeah,
I just thought about that in the shower and I was
like, oh, I got to talk about that in But regarding
Logan, I was a little bit disappointed that the
film wasn't nominated for Best Picture because to
me it was like among my favorite films of last year,
not just because it was a Marvel film or because it
was a superhero film, but because it was such a good
story. I know that after the the Dark Knight was
nominated or wasn't nominated for Best Picture,
like the Academy increased the number of
nominees. And I can't remember. I think they went
backwards. I could totally be making that up. But I
remember like it was like checking her some tweets
about this and they were like, oh, you couldn't
extend the list again to include Logan? Yeah. You
know. Well, it just feels like the industry has
somewhat of a not of a data, but the fact that Logan
didn't get nominated for Best Picture and the fact
that Wonder Woman didn't receive any nominations
when it was recognized by the PGA, the American
Film Institute and everything as well. Yeah. It's
just a little bit weird. It seems like the you know,
the AFI and the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and
Sciences and they like they didn't agree this
year. No, not really. I think it's almost like
Hollywood is trying to send a message to everybody
that they don't want more superhero films being
made. Yeah. Yeah. It doesn't matter how good you
make them because we're not going to recognize
them anyway. It sucks because I don't foresee any
movies this year coming out that are like more
impactful than Logan. Maybe Aqua Man. Maybe. No.
Definitely not. You don't know. I was gonna say
maybe Infinity War. I don't know. I did it. We'll
see. So you're feeling bad about Wonder Woman
though? I can't do. Okay. That's all that matters
to me. Moving on to the next news item. It should
have been nominated for Best Director. What? It
should have been nominated for Best Actress.
Should have been nominated for Best Picture.
Should have been nominated for Best Supporting
Actor. Should have been nominated for Best
Screenplay. Should have been nominated for...
This is not the Jonathan Fantasy Awards. This is
the Academy Awards. Dude. It should have been
nominated in each one of those categories. I don't
think so man. Alright. Moving on to the next bit of
news. Hans Zimmer who has apparently stated
before that he was not going to score any more
superhero films. Yeah. He's going to score X-Men
Dark Phoenix. Which is... Yeah. So apparently
he's only done with DC films. Thanks a lot Hans
Zimmer. What the fuck? He... I think he's done
great work on Man of Steel and of course the Dark
Knight trilogy. So this is great news for X-Men
because I don't think that they've had a
particularly strong score in any of their films.
Maybe X-Men 2. I think John Ottoman's score in
X-Men 2 was pretty well done. It was like... Oh
yeah. Yeah. But I mean they kind of reused those
themes in both Days of Future Past and X-Men
Apocalypse and the other films just weren't that
memorable. Yeah. I didn't like the score at all for
X-Men Apocalypse. No. Yeah. So the fact that it's
going to at least have more memorable music
registers more on my radar a little bit more. I mean
I could listen to the Man of Steel soundtrack all
day. Just all day. Just had headphones on and just
listened to that all day. It's so good. It's really
good. I thought the Dark Knight score was better.
What he did with Batman was good too. I don't know.
Hans Zimmer to me right now is like the best
composer and I know like a lot of people would argue
John Williams because he's definitely had like
the most iconic and most memorable scores. Yeah.
But to me like technical wise I think I have to give
it to Hans Zimmer. He's done more interesting
things I think than John Williams. John Williams
scores are definitely memorable and classic but
it seems like Hans Zimmer is slightly more
experimental and yeah I don't know. It's just it
appeals to me in a more unique way. Yeah. This is I
mean this is great news for the for the X-Men
franchise but I mean again it's like are you going
to be able to reuse those themes? I think I would not
want them to because I think if you're watching the
new MCU X-Men you're going to associate those
themes especially if they're memorable Hans
Zimmer themes to the old shitty X-Men universe.
Yeah. So yeah. All right moving on to the next set of
news. This is probably the biggest news item of the
week. We got our first glimpse through a series of
set photos of Brie Larson suited up in her Captain
Marvel superhero costume. It immediately caught
me off guard when I saw these. Yeah. I texted it to
you. But it only took me like at least 10 seconds to
like readjust like oh that's the that's the Cree
uniform. Yeah. I remember I texted you the photo
and your response was what? What's that? I mean
we've all seen the concept art that was released
during Comic Con last year that shows that she will
have the costume in her traditional colors of red
and blue and with the gold holostar in the center.
So this like if you're familiar with the comics
when Marvel first came to earth and he's the
character that mentored and became the romantic
interest of Carol Danvers. It's going to be Jude
Law in the movie. Jude Law. Yes. His costume was a
green Cree army uniform. So I'm pretty sure that
she's wearing his suit or not his suit
specifically but wearing the same that same
thing. Yeah. So this this may be before she like
customizes it to not resemble a Cree outfit
anymore and more of her own thing. Yeah. I'm
assuming. Yeah. So the design itself is a little
interesting. It does have a few more
embellishments than I would have thought it would
have. It looks one way in concept art but in the
photo it doesn't quite fit nearly as well as it
should which at first made me think that she was
wearing his suit. Oh there's like an abundance of
embellishments like if you rivets some piping
kind of. I thought yeah I'm glad to hear I'm not the
only one who thought it didn't fit her that well. I
mean not that it needs to be skin tight but like
there's a sizable amount of fabric in the crotch
area that is just like what is that just dangling it
so she could she could do her high kicks I guess I
guess but like the design of like where the knee
pads are well they're not actually knee pads to the
top of the shin pads but they look like knee pads so
it makes it look like her legs are like super tiny
and everything. It's not the most flattering
design. I have to say I like the top half more than I
like the bottom half like if you just kind of cover
up the bottom half. Yeah that looks pretty good and
then you cover up the top half and you just look at
the bottom and it's like what is happening but I
think with the the corrected colors I think
that'll be fine. Because we know that she's
appearing in Infinity War and I wouldn't be
surprised if you know she has her normal suit
colors in that movie but for this movie maybe she
has green all the way up until almost the end. I
wouldn't be surprised. Yeah well because her
movie will be her origin story. Right. There was a
brief little set video as well that was released
along with these photos and it didn't really
reveal much so it's not it didn't go into spoiler
territory but we did see a man approach her
somewhat threateningly and then he she like grabs
his hand and like crushes it and he like winks and
falls to his knees in pain. Not sure what's going on
there but I thought that was pretty interesting.
It seems like I think she's like has a big smile
afterward. I don't know if that's just Rilarzans
reaction to like the performance or it's actually
part of the script. Part of the character. Yeah
yeah like kind of discovering her powers or
something like that. Yeah I have to say the first
thing I thought of when I saw this suit was for a
studio that's trying to distance itself like
origin wise from Green Lantern this really
reminded me of like a Green Lantern suit. It's like
if you wanted to do that this wasn't the best way to
do that at all. It's almost like a Green Lantern
uniform. One of the actually one of the early
thoughts that I had as well was that this suit was
green because they were going to animate part of it
like a green screen kind of effect but then I was
like no that's too Green Lantern they wouldn't do
that but you never know they might but yeah that's
actually an apt criticism is that if they're not
animating over it it somewhat resembles a Green
Lantern suit and if they are animating over it then
it somewhat resembles the Green Lantern suit from
the 2011 Green Lantern movie. You know what it
really reminded me of? You know the character
Jade, Ellen Scott's daughter. Yes. Ellen Scott is
the first Green Lantern. She still she has like
that same like Hollister kind of symbol on hers.
That's what it reminded me of. Oh okay
interesting. I think that's all I have to say about
that. I'm just looking forward to seeing more set
photos as you know they're taking. I'm interested
in seeing more different looks at the costume
essentially and seeing the costume in its proper
color. Right. That'll be cool. This kind of brings
us to our question of the week. The question for
this episode is speaking of costumes who in your
opinion has had the best adapted live action
costume design out of all the Marvel and DC films.
So go ahead and write your answer into us by
searching for us on Instagram, Twitter or
Facebook. Just do a search for Dynamic Dual
Podcast and you'll find us. Or you can email us your
answer at dynamicdualpodcastatgmail.com and
we'll go ahead and pick our favorite answer and
draw them a Dynamic Dual No Prize with their name on
it that we post to our social media accounts. Yeah
if anyone says Green Lantern they will
immediately be blocked. They will not only be
disqualified from winning the No Prize they will
be banished from our social media accounts.
Actually you know what I didn't hate the Green
Lantern costume so it made sense to me the way they
approached it because if you're going to create
like this this costume that's made of like you know
a green construct a green mental construct yeah
maybe it is made of like a CG energy I don't know I
don't know. All right yeah let us know who you guys
think had the best superhero costume and with all
that news out of the way let's go all right asriel
versus blade um the fight of the century maybe
maybe probably not no probably not I mean it's a
good fight I do think I'm interested in seeing how
this one will pan out I like both of these
characters I know very little about asriel so I'm
interested in learning about him and seeing what
makes him so cool because despite only sticking
around as the replacement for batman for I don't
know like a year maybe less than that he still kind
of shows up every now and then in like the the nerd
consciousness yeah so he's an interesting
character for sure. I mean I didn't know too much
about him either so this was a lot of fun research I
think I think he would have been a great match up for
moon night. Really? Yeah once I get down into his
his profile description you know they both have
you know they're both you know kind of superhuman
they both have like multiple personalities in a
way um they both you know they're both hooded
figures yeah who sometimes were white I guess.
Well you never know eventually maybe way down the
line a few years from now we may get to the asriel
versus moon night match that's that's actually a
good idea so. Yeah write it down write it down.
We're gonna forget. So if you haven't listened to
to one of our dual episodes before the way this
works is we run a thousand spreadsheet battle
simulations the figures from which are
extrapolated from stat sheets that that we record
we we do the the simulations a thousand times which
I think is is sort of a big thing for us. It's an
accurate way to do it to get a good answer because I
feel like a lot of other people who do something
similar in in a way that you know they only do one
match and the thing is is that there's so many
different ways for characters when they're
fighting to win or lose you have to do it so many
times to get you know like an inaccurate result I
think. Yeah in our simulations in our simulations
no character wins like 100% of the time. No no. So I
always thought that was pretty neat so it feels
very accurate we simulate a thousand times we get
the numbers from the stats that we compile from the
official Marvel power rankings as well as a few
other stats that we uh determine ourselves. Yeah
we extrapolate the the DC stats from from those
power rankings. Yes it's math there's it's no bias
there's no fan votes you know like the the comic
from the 90s where the winners were decided by
votes. Oh yeah that was bullshit. Lobo would have
never lost to Wolverine that's what I'm saying so
it's it's nothing like that it's it's science yeah
it's science. Yeah and before we do the 1000
simulations uh before we run those numbers in the
spreadsheet we like to go over the profiles and the
powers of each of the contestants involved in the
match as well as speculate on how we think at least
one of those matchups would kind of play out. Yeah
it's always fun yeah we don't talk about
environment though uh I think that's one of the
things that's also unique is is you can't really
record environmental stats because it's so
variable one character can win one environment
and not in another so it's just we don't we don't do
it. Mm-hmm but before the speculation we do the
profile breakdowns so let's I think you it's I
think it's your turn to start. Yeah yep I'll go
ahead and uh talk about blade. All right so in 1929
London a pregnant prostitute named Tara Brooks
summoned a doctor named Deacon Frost to her
brothel to assist with severe labor
complications uh Frost was actually a vampire who
feasted on her blood as she gave birth and in doing
so the vampire accidentally passed on certain
enzymes from his saliva through Tara's
bloodstream into the child that made him immune to
the effects of a vampire bite and gave him an
attunement for sensing the supernatural and a
lengthened lifespan. It is all of the strengths of
an out of his weaknesses. No it just gave him those
three powers. Oh so it essentially turned the
child into what's called a dampier. Dampier I
think I'm pronouncing that right which is someone
who has been touched but not converted by a
vampire. The other women of the brothel were able
to dry frost away before he could kill the child as
well and they named the baby Eric. Eric Brooks and
he grew up to be the vampire hunter known as Blade.
Wait that's Blade's real name? Eric Brooks yes.
Blade has a real name? Yeah I did not expect Eric
Brooks. It wasn't it's not Wesley Snipes. I was
thinking Wesley Snipes or something cool like
that. Yeah so as a teenager Eric was an orphan
living on the streets when he first happened upon a
group of vampires attacking an older man named
Jamal Afari. He helped fight them off and saved the
man's life. Afari was actually a lifelong vampire
hunter who realized that Eric's special immunity
made him ideal for hunting vampires so he took him
under his wing and taught him everything he knew.
Eric's main motivation in learning how to kill
vampires was to avenge his mother's death by
killing the vampire responsible. He called
himself Blade after his preferred vampire
killing tools. He used these like teak wooden
knives throwing knives to kill vampires. So that
was his goal he was unable to find Deacon Frost
however but he ended up teaming up with a small
group of vampire hunters to hunt the ruler and most
powerful of all vampires Dracula. The group
succeeded in staking Dracula's heart but his
servants were able to resurrect him and he got
revenge by killing the group except for Blade. So
he persisted in his fight against Dracula with a
new team of hunters that included Quincy Harker
and Rachel Van Helsing who were the descendants of
the characters from Bram Stoker's Dracula novel.
Over the years they killed Dracula multiple times
but he kept getting resurrected by his servants
and his brides. After a while Blade was probably
just like fuck this shit and decided to return to
his original mission of avenging his mother. So to
track Deacon Frost he teamed up with Hannibal King
who was a detective that was turned into a vampire
and he was played by Ryan Reynolds in the Blade
Trinity movie. That's right. Together they
uncovered a plot by Frost to usurp the title of Lord
of the Vampires from Dracula. They battled An army
of frost vampires, but ended up killing him. A few
years later, Blade teamed up with Doctor Strange,
Hannibal King, and Frank Drake. Frank Drake is
like an inventor dude with a Ghostbuster proton
pack. It was an energy gun that could affect
supernatural entities. I thought he was the
lamest thing ever. But they teamed up with Ghost
Rider to fight and defeat Lilith, who is the mother
of all demons and her offspring called the Lilin.
So Blade continued his mission to rid the world of
vampires, which brought him to New York to stop his
former ally Morbius, who was being controlled by
another vampire at the time. He teamed up with
Spider-Man for the fight, but managed to get
bitten by Morbius. Blade had been bitten by
vampires before, but he's immune to any effects,
that's one of his natural abilities. Morbius
however, was a different sort of vampire, not one
turned by supernatural means. Morbius is like a
pseudo-vampire created by scientific means when
he tried to cure himself of a blood disorder using
the genetic material of vampire bats. That's more
like genetic manipulation than... Yeah, so he's
like part vampire bat basically. But when he bit
Blade, it turned him to a daywalker. Meaning he got
all of the powers of a traditional vampire, and
none of their weaknesses except for the thirst for
blood. He got the thirst. Right. But Spider-Man
was able to fashion a serum for both Blade and
Morbius to satiate their thirst and they would
both take it regularly. Spider-Man did that?
Yeah. Interesting. Blade eventually met his
father, Lucas Cross, who was still alive and
coincidentally turned into a vampire a long time
ago. He captured Blade and told him about a
prophecy he was to fulfill that results in all
vampires getting their souls restored. So Cross
tried to get Blade to drink the blood of a young girl
as one of the conditions of the prophecy was that he
had to drink the blood of a virgin. Blade ended up
escaping, but he ended up fulfilling that part of
the prophecy when he drank the blood of his enemy
Draconus, who turns out was a virgin. But he drank
as blood as a means to drain his powers. So he ends up
fulfilling that part of the prophecy and then he's
abducted again by his father and taken to Draconus
Castle to complete the final part of the prophecy.
So it turns out that Cross had been tricked by
Dracula into thinking that the prophecy ritual
would restore all vampire souls, but what it did
instead was resurrect every vampire that had ever
died, effectively resetting Blade's mission
back to zero. That's pretty much it for his
backstory highlights. Recently he helped the
X-Men fight off an invasion of their island Haven,
though not before Jubilee was bitten and turned
into a vampire. Oh, so dumb. And Blade was also a
member of Luke Cage's Avengers team called the
Mighty Avengers for a while. As far as powers go,
his vampire bite immunity, his long lifespan, and
his ability to send supernatural creatures,
those were all acquired at birth during Deacon
Frost's attack on his mother. His later vampire
abilities came from Morbius's unique bite that
gave him the more traditional powers of a vampire,
although I've never seen him turn into a bat and
I've never seen him hypnotize people. So it's more
like the physical stuff. So Blade has enhanced
strength. He can lift about one ton. He has
superhuman speed, especially in fast bursts over
short distances, which he can cover in almost an
instant. He has enhanced agility, reflexes,
stamina, and durability. He has an accelerated
healing ability that we saw in the movie as well.
Not quite as good as Wolverine's, but still pretty
good. I remember seeing this image of him fighting
Wolverine and like Wolverine, like put his claws
right through his head and Blade was just smiling.
So it has to be pretty good. Yeah, like Wolverine, I
told him, it's like, you know, it's not as fast as
mine, but it's it's almost there. He also has
heightened senses, including eyesight, that
make him an expert marksman and able to see in
complete darkness. He's a master martial artist
with expertise in multiple fighting styles and a
specialist with bladed weapons, including
swords and throwing knives. He also carries
automatic machine pistols loaded with hollow
point garlic filled silver bullets. He does have
one weakness. I mentioned it before. It's his
thirst for blood. If he doesn't consume blood or
his serum for over the course of a couple of weeks,
he dies. And that's everything about him. Did you
learn anything? Does he have an English accent?
Yes, he does. Weird. Weird. Yep. Instead of
there's worse things out tonight than vampires.
He says it more like, there's worse things out than
vampires. Gov'n'at. I can't do an English accent.
So I was real skill wise and ability wise. He's not
too far off from Blade. You'll see. OK, so as real.
Jean Paul Valley was a mild mannered programming
student at Gotham University when one night a
masked figure crawled bleeding into his
apartment. The figure turned out to be his father
to Jean's surprise. And he had been mortally
wounded fighting demon worshipers as the
assassin slash enforcer for a 500 year old
religious secret society known as the Sacred
Order of Saint Dumas. Saint Dumas. And you're
sorry. Saint Dumas. With his father's last dying
breaths, he explained to Jean Paul that with his
death, Jean Paul was the next in line to become the
order's personal angel of death, as real. Using
resources, his father bequeathed him. Jean Paul
traveled to Switzerland and met with the Order of
Saint Dumas. There he learned that he was a
genetically modified test tube baby. Whose DNA
had been spliced with animals to make him stronger
and faster, among other things. He had also been
subtly conditioned and brainwashed unknowingly
his whole life. What kind of animals? It's not
specific. OK, so he's like part grizzly bear.
Possibly. OK. So he'd been brainwashed
unknowingly his whole life in a process known as
the system. Now, under the system's
conditioning, Jean was psychologically
manipulated, not only to serve the will of the
Order, but also subconsciously trained to become
a violent fighting machine and perfect assassin.
And again, this has been going on his whole life
through the Secret Society. I had no idea. Thanks
to the system, it wasn't long before Jean Paul was
ready to don the suit of Azrael. Soon after which,
he came into odds with Bruce Wayne, who had
traveled to Switzerland while investigating the
death of Jean Paul's father, Beck and Gotham.
Bruce's investigation led him to a man named
Carlton LaHaw, a former acolyte of the Order of St.
Dumas and believed servant of the demon Bisse.
Bisse? B-I-I-S. Bish. The same man. This was the
same man who killed Jean Paul's father. The new
Azrael was tasked with killing LaHaw, but instead
ended up rescuing Batman while LaHaw seemingly
died. Aware of Bruce Wayne's secret identity and
inspired by his humanitarian and heroic nature,
Jean Paul rejected the Order and returned home to
Gotham with Batman to break the system's
conditioning and to help end the crusade against
Gotham's criminal element. Breaking free from
the system proved extremely difficult. It
just...it's impossible. While fighting crime,
Azrael would often unknowingly and unwillingly
become over-aggressive and violent. This would
cause him a great amount of stress and
frustration, which would turn him into a more
aggressive and vicious cycle. He was a
subconscious assassin. Yeah, kinda. Yeah,
interesting. I almost think of him like Jason
Bourne, in a way. Like he didn't know he had all
these abilities until he was triggered. Yeah.
Batman had strong hope for Jean Paul, who had
proved his usefulness time and time again, thanks
to his physical abilities. When Bane broke
Batman's spine, Azrael was chosen to fill in for
him to stop Bane's rise to power. After getting his
ass handed to him by Bane initially, Azrael
developed a new armored bat suit that made him even
stronger and faster, with flame-throwing
gauntlets also capable of firing high-velocity
razor-sharp batterings. I think most people,
when they... They may not know Jean Paul, but when
they see this suit, they're like, Oh, that's who
Azrael is, that's who Jean Paul Valley is. Yeah,
he's like the robotic Batman. Yeah, yeah. The suit
was designed by Joe Cassata, actually. Oh,
really? Yeah, interesting. He defeated Bane in
their second match, and this confidence boost
only led to him becoming even more violent and
unhinged. He sealed off all entrances to the
Batcave, locking Robin out, wanting nothing to do
with him due to Robin's deus approval of Jean
Paul's violent tendencies. After nearly killing
the Joker, Jean Paul lost the trust of many of the
Gotham Police Department. Drunk on power,
delusions and hallucinations had developed and
intensified, eventually to a point where he let a
serial killer fall to his death, even though he
could have saved him because he was having visions
of Saint Dumas. By this time, Bruce had recovered
and confronted Jean Paul to strip him of the Batman
mantle. Using nonviolent maneuvers, Bruce
stripped Jean Paul of his bat armor in a both
physical and psychological match. That also
stripped Jean Paul of his delusions. Mentally
broken, Jean Paul began a rehabilitative quest to
take down the Order of Saint Dumas, which he was
mostly successful in doing as Azrael. Was the
order not good though? They were like taking down
like demons and stuff. Like why would why would he
take the order down? They're not, I wouldn't say
they're good or bad. They were just, they were a
secret society. They go back to the Templars. They
were a splinter group of the Templar Knights
during the Crusades. And I think it was Dumas. I
forget his first name. What are those Templar
Knights? He found like the treasure of the
Templars and used that to fund a secret society.
It's just, it's just one that has been like
carrying out assassinations for centuries. So
we're supposed to assume that they're also doing
shady things. Yeah. Okay. I'll believe that. So
Azrael died fighting Garry's surface to La Ha, but
he came back as part of the new 52 relaunch in which
he was an agent of the Order of Saint Dumas once
again. He now wore armor known as the suit of
sorrows, an ancient armor forged from the swords
of fallen Templar Knights that has something like
a mystical artificial intelligence. It's not
technical. It's like mystical. It interfaces
with the wearer's nervous system, feeding them
extra sensory information like enemy weaknesses
and such. In addition to reinforcing the system's
conditioning, it's been described like having
two brains in one body, which is enough to drive any
man insane. This includes Jean-Paul. Batman
tried to help him by putting him in a new suit,
designed as a throwback to the Batman armor
Jean-Paul wore in the previous continuity.
Developed by Lucius Fox's son, Lucas, the new bat
armor had an AI of its own based on Batman's mind
that countered the system's more violent
mindset. Having deemed the Azrael line a failure,
the Order of Saint Dumas unleashed a robotic
replacement assassin known as Ascalon, an
android with artificial intelligence based on
the entire recorded experiences of the suit of
sorrows. As Azrael and Batman tried to stop
Ascalon, it was revealed to Jean-Paul that the
leader of the now mostly extinct Order of Saint
Dumas was his father, a revelation that sent him
into a rage that temporarily overthrew his own
programming and caused him to punch right through
Ascalon's body, which infected its system with
Batman's AI. Due to his genetic modification as a
fetus, Azrael has enhanced strength able to lift
several tons, two tons. What? Yes. As well as
increased speed, reflexes, stamina,
durability, and the ability to heal several times
faster than ordinary. His mental programming
coupled with his innate enhanced senses,
enhanced senses, and the intelligence system of
the suit of sorrows, makes him an extremely
skilled and tactical fighter, albeit he is prone
to visions and hallucinations. Weapons wise, he
wields a sword that he can ignite on flame, two
gauntlet mounted blades, which could also set a
flame, and a dagger that he keeps strapped to his
front scabbard. Is the dagger special in any way?
Has like a fleur de lis on it? Pretty fancy. Oh,
that's cool. Okay. I don't think there's anything
sweet about it. No. Okay. It's just a dagger. Yeah.
Okay. So that's Azrael. Well, I didn't know
anything about him. So that's pretty
interesting. I've always, I never really liked
the Joe Cassata design. It was weird. It was when he
replaced white sleeves and it was just weird. It
was bizarre, but I always liked his modern look. He
kind of looks like the Assassin's Creed guy kind of
a little bit. Oh, but yeah, if you're gonna take
like the Assassin's Creed and Moon Knight and mix
them together, you get. I think that's real in a
way. All right. We're going to go ahead and
speculate before we, before we actually do the
stats and simulations. We're going to speculate
on how we think this matchup would go. When
considering this matchup, we always start the
characters 50 yards apart from each other in a
non-environment zone, where they know that each
other are threats, but they don't know anything
else about each other. Right. They're actually
more comparable than I thought they were going to
be. Yeah, yeah, I'm trying. I thought I had this one
in the bag and then all of a sudden you're like, oh,
two tons. Well, actually, it may even be stronger
than that in some instances, but. So can blade.
Those are essentially just feats of strength
again. When I'm breaking down the characters, I
tend to think of them more as like, you know, what's
what's typical. There's no way as real is going out
there being able to lift eight tons, which
apparently like he's done something like that
before. I just think of that as sloppy writing.
Yeah. You know, oh good. Good. I agree. Slappy
writing. What weapons does he have? Let's go over a
weapons list. Well, I went through them. He has his
sword that he's able to ignite. He has his blade
gauntlets, which kind of makes him like Wolverine
and he has his dagger. But like in previous
incarnations, like he's had he's had multiple
suits. He's had like eight different suits, maybe
not that many, but like he wants to have like a
pretty close to a bad man. So he did have things like
batterings and stuff like that. You could assume
that he could throw his dagger if you need a
projectile. Sure. If you want one blade, he'll
have his throwing stakes. He'll have his two
automatic pistols. His guns. Yeah, he has guns. He
has his his main sword and I'll give him his glaive
that he throws. It's like a boomerang knife thing.
It's so badass. It was in the movie. Yeah. But he's
also had it in the comics as well. It's really
badass. And what else? I think I think that's
that's about it. Metal stakes, glaive, sword,
guns. Gauntlet blades, sword, dagger. Is Azrael
suit bulletproof? It's armor. That doesn't
answer my question. It's made from swords. Yeah.
Swords of the suit of sorrows is made from. Is that
why he's wearing in this? Yes. Yeah, he's wearing a
suit of sorrows. The one that makes him insane. OK,
well, it also makes him more lethal. So does it?
Yeah. OK. More lethal than blade. And it helps him
track things, right? So it makes him it helps with
his his agility and it helps with his
marksmanship. OK, I think not just marksmanship
with like with weaponry, but also with like his
fists and stuff. It's it's not going to find any
weaknesses on blade because blade doesn't really
have any weaknesses. So that sort of aspect of is
useless in this match. I think it's going to start
off with blade pulling out his guns. I think that's
inevitable. I think in every match, I think as
real's primary objective is going to have to be to
disarm blades, guns, somehow or evade the bullets
long enough until he runs out of ammo. Question is,
how do you see him doing that? That's because
that's how the match is going to start off. He's
fucking running. He is running his ass off. Like,
shit. He's running, but he looked at his sword and
he ignites his sword and he's dragging his sword on
the ground and he's creating like a wall of fire.
And that's going to sort of act like a screen. Oh,
that's that's not a bad move. Like, yeah, smoke. Is
it hot enough to set the ground on fire? I've seen
like stuff basically explode like when he slices
them just like fire erupting. OK. OK. So he creates
a screen using his speed, agility and his flaming
sword. Yeah, it's a pretty good one. All right. So
Bway's going to, you know, Wesley Snipes his gun
back into his jacket holster. And then but he, you
know, he has good vision. He has good hearing and
stuff. So he could probably peer through the fire
and see where Ezreal is. And he's just like a
badass. He's going to leap over the fire like a
strike a cool pose like in midair. And as he lands,
he's going to hurl his glaive right at right at
Ezreal. OK, so Ezreal catches the glaive out of
what? What? What? You can't catch blades. Maybe.
Yeah, he absolutely. So OK, so he's not. Can blade
catches on glaive? Yes. OK, then Ezreal can. So
what you're saying is Ezreal no longer has a hand.
No, he goes to catch it and then it goes right
through his hand and he's like, damn it. I remember
how does blade catch it? He's just a badass. Well,
he has enhanced senses so you could time it well as
it's coming back to him with his eyesight. Not only
does Ezreal have enhanced senses, he also has the
suit of sorrows. What the fuck ever, man? OK, so he
catches it fine. He catches it and he's texted away
for later. OK, he pulls out his sword. OK, right.
And then blade pulls out his sword. And raise blade
lands and then blades like ready to die.
Motherfucker. OK, John Paul, I have no comeback.
John Paul, just he's just silent and cool. So he. So
they go at each other with the swords. Yeah. And the
sword fight. But as real as you know, sword is
better because it's flaming. OK, so yeah, they're
the sort of thing. I'm pretty sure Azrael is a
better sword fighter. No, I'm pretty sure he's not
because blade is like the best sword fighter, one
of the best sword fighters in the Marvel Universe.
Azrael is one of the best sword fighters in DC. OK,
so that means they're even. OK, who the fucking
sword fighting? It probably looks bad ass. Yeah,
yeah, yeah, like doing flips and like cool shit
spinning around. Yeah, like the capoeira kind of
stuff. The cool thing, though, is that, you know,
well, Azrael has his sword in one hand and he's, you
know, sword fighting there. He ejects and ignites
the risk mounted blade on his other arm and just
goes at blade with two blades. He's fighting blade
with blades. So blade is fighting off two two
blades all of a sudden. And he and he's surprised.
He is surprised. He didn't see those those
gauntlets blades come out. So he he reaches into
his little hip holster and he flings like three
silver stakes right at Azrael. Now they bounce
right off his armor. No, right at his face. They
bounce right off his armored face. He doesn't have
an army. Yeah, he does have an armor. It's like it's
like a cloth. No, it's not. Look closer. It's it's
metallic. OK, so there's no. Are you saying that
there's no where that blade can strike Azrael with
his stakes? Well, there is. I don't know if you
could see them, though. Oh, he sees. He's Azrael.
He doesn't wear a helmet. He wears a mask with the
hood. Oh, so the back of his head. So blades sees the
hood. So he does a flip over and as he's up, you know,
upside down mid flip, he jumps a stake into
Azrael's head. Right. Except that no, because as
he's doing that, Azrael is also moving at the same
time as well as constantly moving. He's super
agile. OK. That's when he takes his dagger and
throws it at blade. And that's when blade. Oh, his
dagger. Yeah. Oh, blade would knock that out of the
air with his sword. But it's super fast. I don't
know if you know this. He's like super fast in short
distances. And so now that he knocked the blade out
of the way, that's when he pulls his gun back out and
then goes. So that's when Azrael pulls out the
blade that he had been saving. And knocks the gun
out of blades hand with it. OK. Oh, yeah. Good call
there. I'm all out of projectiles. What else do I
got? I use the guns. I use the glaive. I use the
stakes. I have the sword. So he knocks the the
glaive or the gun out of blades hand with the glaive
that he stole from him. Yes. OK. You have to
remember like there's fire everywhere. Fire
everywhere. Blade doesn't give a shit about fire.
Yeah, he does. Well, kind of mean like he can still
burn. Yeah, he's in pain. He's in pain. Yeah, but he
you know, he heals pretty quick. So it's just it's
just it's just a flesh wound. Just a minor burn.
Well, his body is is too busy healing itself to be
paying as closely attention to Azrael and his
attacks as it should be. I'm trying to figure out
how blade can get through armor. Azrael's armor.
Like it's not that durable. Right. I mean, like
eventually, yeah, I mean, yeah, it's really
durable. He's gonna have to he's gonna have to
target the back of his head then or something. I
mean, it's not because it's unfortunate that he
has bladed weapon. Like I don't the bladed weapons
won't necessarily get through a metallic armor.
Like if it was like slashing weapons, right? Yeah,
like slash and stab weapons. That's what armor is
made for, you know. Right. So that's a little
rough. Yeah. You want to take this to the stats?
Because you give up. Do you have? Because you give
up. I don't give up. No, I just already know that
blade already killed Azrael with the stake to the
back of the head. He was like, some other fuck as a
wish on an ice skate uphill and then stabs him in the
back of the head. What does that even mean? It just
sounds cool saying it so you could say it. Yeah,
yeah, yeah. Yeah, let's go to the stats. All right,
we'll go to the stats. We'll be right back.
Gregorian chants always remind me of Monty
Python. It's true when they hit themselves on the
head with the board. Yes, you're Dominic. Don't
he's right. I think that's just off the top of my
head. That was pretty good. We've ever seen that
movie in decades. Yes, seriously. Decade.
Decades. One decade at that one. Yeah, we're not
that old. All right, so we ran a thousand
simulations, putting their stats together. The
stats were interesting because a lot of them came
out closer than what I thought they would be. It was
mainly being like, oh, yeah, blades way better at
this. And then Jonathan going, no, no, no, he's
just as good. And then me going, no, shut up, you're
stupid. And then him going, no, look. Yeah, we
determined that blade is faster in short bursts
because he could essentially almost almost
teleport. Yeah, almost. Yeah, as well as is
stronger. Yeah, he's stronger. That surprised
me. Barely though. His insanity was a bigger
detriment than I thought it was going to be. Right,
which makes me kind of sad because he's he's
definitely not as intelligent as Batman, but he
is, you know, he does have that conditioning that
essentially just makes him a perfect weapon.
Unfortunately, you know, he is again, once again,
prone to to hallucinations and stuff like that. So
it's unfortunate and it hindered him in these
stats, I think. How confident are you feeling
right now? Not as confident as it was earlier
because I was like, fucking, as we could do
anything blade can do and he wears armor. But there
was one thing that he couldn't do, which is shoot
guns. Yeah, yeah. Yeah, that ended up being a
factor in this as well. I'm not going to pretend
like, you know, Azrael doesn't get tagged
occasionally because, you know, I've seen him
bleed for sure. But I'm curious to see what the
results are for sure. All right. Okay, so the
winner of the Azrael Blade Dynamic Duel is...
Azrael. What? No, I'm just kidding. No. Aw, you
asshole. I do that to you all the time the other way
around. I hate you. It's Blade, whatever. Blade
won... Not by much. Blade won 596% or 596 battles
out of 1000, which is 59.6%. And yeah, the guns
played a huge factor in this. It's fucked up. I
mean, I don't think they would have played that big
of a role in this match. I mean, Azrael has taken on
guys like Deathstroke and Batman and Bane and
beating them. You say that there's nothing that
Blade can do to Azrael, but what can Azrael do to
Blade, considering his healing factor, his
speed, and all that stuff? It's a close match. I
mean, 59.6 is not that high. It's not as high as the
last match. I mean, this is not too bad for you,
right? I mean... Dude, I'm still sad. I'm
heartbroken. It broke my heart. It's what I do.
It's what Marvel does. They stomp on DC
characters. It's what they're good at. They stomp
on DC characters and they know things. They have
the t-shirt that says that. That's what they do.
Anyway, I've never seen this shirt. I have no idea
what you're talking about. Do you know what that's
a reference to? No. Okay, never mind then. All
right. That does it for this episode. Don't forget
to answer our question of the week, which was
basically who do you think has the best live action
costume in the Marvel and DC films? Follow us on
social media and Instagram, Twitter, Facebook,
search for our dynamic dual podcast. Buy our cool
ass t-shirt designs by going to t-public. We have a
link on our website, which is dynamicduld.com. So
if you want to check out those sweet ass t-shirts,
go to dynamicduld.com. Honestly, if you go to our
website, we have links to our podcast, to our
merchandise, to everything. Our social. It's all
there. Social media. Yeah. Yeah. Not social
security number. What? I don't know. No, it's not.
I don't really know anything. Next episode, we
will be kicking off Black History Month by doing a
review of the first Blade movie. Super excited for
that, especially since Blade is a winner in my
book. It's been a long time since I saw the movie.
It's good. Forget the director's name. Steven
Norrington. Steven Norrington. He's just a
fantastic director. Yeah, he is. He is really
good. So stylized. Don't count the League of
Extraordinary Gentlemen against him. Yeah,
totally. Totally. But yeah, so looking forward to
that. And we will talk to you guys in a week. Yep. Up,
up and away. True believers.