This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi, welcome to
the Dynamic Duel podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin
brother, Marvelous Joe. And in this episode,
we're going back to doing one of our review
episodes, this time a review of the Marvel
television series, Ironheart, on Disney+. Yeah,
it's been a while since we've done a review. I don't
think we've done one since the Thunderbolts movie
came out. We've been getting through a lot of the
duel episodes, but this whole month of July is
going to be jam-packed with reviews. Yeah, not
only are we reviewing Ironheart, but also
Superman next week and two weeks after that,
Fantastic Four. And then the week after that,
Sandman season two. So we hope you get out there and
watch this stuff, listen to our reviews, and then
we'll get back to the duels. Yeah, but before we get
to our review, we're going to break down the comic
book movie news to come out this past week, which is
a lie because there was none. Yeah, I do want to say
R.I .P. Julien McMahon, who played Dr. Doom in the
2005 Fantastic Four franchise. He died of cancer
at age 56, which is way too young, way too fucking
young. So thoughts and condolences to his family
and friends. As always, we list our segment times
in our episode description, so feel free to check
out the show notes if you want to skip ahead to a
particular topic. Our artificially intelligent
duel simulator, AJ9K, has a quick message for our
listeners. So listen up. Why hello there. Do you
want even more from this podcast? Then become a
part of the dynamic dual community on Patreon,
where you can choose from three tiers. The Dynamic
2.0 tier gives you access to our Discord chat
server. The Fantastic Four tier gives you two
bonus episodes each month, and the X-Force tier
makes you an executive producer of this show.
Lastly, the Dynamite podcast network tier lets
you create your own podcast using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and
consultation, and get you simulation results.
Pitch the twins your ideas via email at
dynamicdualpodcast.com. Check it out at
Patreon.com slash DynamicDuel. Pip pip cheerio.
Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast. Guys, be sure to tune in to the other
shows on the DynaMic podcast network this week,
including the console combat podcast, where
hosts John and Dean simulate battles between
popular video game characters. In yesterday's
episode, they determined who would win between
Crash Bandicoot and Bubsy. I remember Bubsy. Over
on the Max Destruction podcast, hosts Scotty and
Gilly put your favorite action heroes from film
and television against each other. This week, the
show will be reviewing the Minecraft movie. And on
the Senjoh  World podcast, hosts Zachary Hepburn
speculates on fights between fan favorite anime
and manga characters. In his next episode, Zach's
going to reveal who would win between Aoi Toto of
Jujutsu Kaisen and Ryo Shimizaki of MopPsycho
100. Visit dynamicpodcast.com or click the link
in our show notes to listen to all of the shows in the
DynaMic podcast network. But with that out of the
way, quick to the no prize. A no prize is an award
that Marvel used to give out to fans. Our version,
the dynamic duel no prize, is a digital award we
post on Instagram for the person that we feel gave
the best answer to our question of the week. Last
week, we asked you guys, what movie do you think
we'll be making more at the Worldwide Box Office?
Superman or Fantastic Four First Steps and why?
And this question pertains to the entire
theatrical run at the Worldwide Box Office. We got
a lot of answers. Let's go ahead and run down our
honorable mentions as well as the no prize winner.
Our first honorable mention goes to Daniel
Alonzo. Who said? Oh, Fantastic Four is going to
destroy Superman. I mean, people that aren't even
superhero fans want to see Pedro Pascal. So that
alone is going to bring people Marvel fans have
been waiting for a great Fantastic Four movie,
which this looks amazing. I mean, I like the thing,
but I've never been a fan of Fantastic Four and
neither have my brothers and we're all hyped to see
this movie. But Superman, dude, Superman sucks.
Like, and not even DC fans want to watch this one.
What hope do they have? Really? I don't know,
Daniel. I'm a DC fan. I want to watch it. Maybe you
suck. No, I think he's right. I think you guys have
no hope. I mean, like he said, the Fantastic Four
First Steps movie has Pedro Pascal. What star our
audience is going to see in the Superman movie?
Rachel Brosnahan, bro. Really? Freakin' Miss
Maisel. Yeah. Okay, okay. Great answer, Daniel.
Our next honorable mention goes to Matt from
Texas. Who said? Hey guys, Matt from Texas here.
I'm going to preface this by saying I am going to see
both of these movies. But for the film, my feel is
going to make the most worldwide. It's probably
going to be Fantastic Four. Both have been getting
a lot of hate online. Superman more than Fantastic
Four. And I feel like more people enjoy the MCU and
want to see how this movie is going to connect to all
the future films coming out. And not many people
care about another Superman film. You know what
really? Like I'm only seeing hype for this movie. I
think in general, there's a lot of hate for the
superhero genre online, which saddens me because
you know, this is peak cinema just a few years ago.
And all of a sudden, you know, the genre isn't as in
vogue as it once was pre-COVID. I just see a lot of
uninformed opinions when I scroll around out
there and it just, you know, it pisses me off to no
end. So I've been kind of staying off social media
more than I already usually do. Because every time
like a Fantastic Four TV spot or Superman image
comes across my feed, it's just nothing but
negativity. Great answer, Matt. Our next
honorable mention goes to Travis Herndon, who
said, What's up, dynamic dudes? Travis here,
shout out to me in between. So my answer would be
Fantastic Four. Why? Because Superman movie is a
dime a dozen. We have multiple Superman movies
throughout the years. Now you can make the same
argument about Fantastic Four. But here's the
thing, Fantastic Four is back at Marvel. It's back
home with people that know what the hell they're
doing with it. Plus, it's part of a bigger
overarching story that's going on. Meanwhile,
Superman is just a simple Superman movie. You know
what else is back home, Travis? Me at your mom's
house. Since when are you so good with your
insults? Like, I put you down all the time when you
never have good comebacks. I don't know, man. It
just gets to me when people talk about it at
Superman. I think he makes a good point, though, in
that this Fantastic Four movie is to the Fantastic
Four franchise as Spider-Man Homecoming was to
the Spider-Man franchise. You know, there have
been multiple iterations of this throughout the
years, but I think people are aware that now that
the franchise is back with Marvel Studios is going
to be more true to the spirit of the characters than
ever before. I just have a really hard time
believing that people are really excited for a
Fantastic Four movie. Being that, like Travis
said, we have had multiple Fantastic Four movies.
They haven't done as well as the best Superman
movie, both box office wise and critically. Like,
we have yet to get a good Fantastic Four movie.
Which is why people are craving one. No one's
craving a Superman movie when they could just go
back and watch, you know, the Christopher Reeve
movies, right? Or Man of Steel, depending on, you
know, what decade they grow up in. But a great
answer, Travis. We want to give a quick shout out to
Kai-O-G, Lorenzo Valdes, and Peter Troll for
taking the time to visit our website and leave an
answer. Thank you guys so much. But the winner of
this week's still prize is Alex Albro. Who said?
Hey guys, I think it'll ultimately be Superman
making more money largely because it comes out
first. I think the Fantastic Four is more cast
appeal, but I really do think the success of the
Fantastic Four is somewhat based on Superman.
Even good Marvel movies recently have been
tracking with low numbers, and even though both
are team-up movies and all that, I think just the
rebirth of the universe and just the great
American hero, Superman is more attractive to
just the general casual fan, as well as, you know,
the hardcore fans are going to show up either way.
You know what else is more attractive to the casual
and hardcore fans, Alex? Your answer. Very well
said, my friend. I also like his point that people
seem to be kind of soured on the MCU as of late, as
evidenced by the recent box offices of Marvel
films of late. Like Deadpool and Wolverine, which
made over a billion dollars? No. I'm talking about
Captain America, Brave New World, and
Thunderbolts. Oh, yeah. Well, I mean, if
anybody's gonna save the MCU or the superhero
genre at the box office, I can guarantee you it's
not gonna be DC. It's gonna be Superman, of course
it is. Who else would it be? It's gonna be Marvel
itself that pulls itself out of its own fire. And
it'll, if you're lucky, bring DC up with it. I feel
like you're gonna learn a very hard lesson this
year and I'm here for it. I'm here for that growth
experience you're about to have. When have I ever
learned a hard lesson in the course of this
podcast? And how many hard lessons have you
learned, Jonathan? I mean, enough to know how
wrong you are. Okay. All right. So as per usual, I
think we mentioned this on the podcast already.
Jonathan and I have a bet going as to which of these
films actually will grow more at the Worldwide Box
Office in their theatrical runs. Jonathan has yet
to win one of these like annual bets that we make. So
stay tuned to see if that changes later on this
year. Spoiler alert, it won't. And once again,
this motherfucker's gonna owe me money. Remember
this, folks. Jokes on you, I've never paid once.
That's true. I do want to point out that we went with
Alex for the no prize win, but everyone else who
answered besides those who got the honorable
mention answered with Superman. So actually
Superman did get a majority of the answers from our
listeners. You can't prove that. You can't prove
anything. But great answer, Alex Albro. You win
this week's no prize. If you, the listener, want to
shout out winning your own no prize, stay tuned to
later on this episode when we'll be asking another
question of the week. And now that that's done,
onto the question of the week. For those of you who
have seen Superman in its opening weekend, what
did you think? Yeah, give us your best 30 second
review. We'd love to play in our next episode in
which we're reviewing the Superman movie. Record
your answer at dynamicduld.com by clicking on the
red microphone button in the bottom right hand
corner of the screen, which will prompt you to
leave us a voicemail. Your message could be up to 30
seconds long. And don't forget to leave your name
in case we include you on the podcast. We'll pick
our favorite answer and award that person a
dynamic dual no prize that we'll post to
Instagram. Be sure to answer before July 13th.
Right, because on July 13th, we'll be recording
the next episode. But now let's go ahead and move on
to the main event of this episode where we review
the Marvel television original series on Disney
plus Iron Heart season one. Okay, Iron Heart six
episode first season was produced by a Marvel
television created by Chinaka Hodge and stars
Dominique Thorne, Anthony Ramos, Alden
Ehrenreich and Sasha Baren Cohen. It was
executive produced by Ryan Coogler, the director
of Black Panther Wakanda Forever, where the Iron
Heart character made her first live action
appearance. In it, Riri Williams was an MIT
student who engineered a vibranium detecting
machine, which is a rare metal which had been
heavily sought after by the world's governments.
She was brought in by the Wakandans for protection
from Namor and the telekinesis, building a
vibranium suit of armor for the battle between the
nations. At the end of that story, Shuri, the new
Black Panther, made Riri leave the armor behind
and return to MIT. We knew by the time of Wakanda
Forever's release that an Iron Heart series was
being produced and I remember at the time being
less than excited because I wasn't a huge fan of
Riri as a character in that film. If you listen to
our review of Wakanda Forever, I think I remember
saying that Iron Heart felt inconsequential
despite being the catalyst for the events in the
film and that I thought Dominique Thorne was less
than capable of leading Korone series as an actor.
I think if I would have known then what I know now, I
would have been a little more excited for this Iron
Heart season because not only were most of my
earlier concerns dispelled, but there were a lot
of interesting themes and characters at play here
in this season. Ultimately, I think that the Iron
Heart series is worth watching for fans. I'm not
sure general audiences will get much out of it
because it doesn't seem like essential watching,
but if you're interested in smaller and more
personal stories and getting some world building
from the magic side of the MCU, be sure to watch Iron
Heart season one prior to listening to the rest of
this review because we will be delving into
spoilers here. Yeah, I think I would recommend it
as well, which is something that's kind of
surprising for me because I went into the show with
the lowest of expectations. I was not really
looking forward to watching this at all, but not
only did it surpass my expectations, maybe
because they were so low, maybe not, but also a lot
of the preconceived notions I had about the series
in general turned out to be way wrong. Yeah, the
marketing was a little off for the series and I'm
not entirely sure why. It almost seems like Marvel
or Disney thought that the show would be less well
received than it probably is. I mean, it's doing
well among critics, maybe not by fans. It's hard to
gauge this early out, but yeah, I would say I
recommend it largely because of the deep themes
that I think the show successfully addresses. You
know, we're talking repressed trauma, sins of the
fathers, selfishness versus heroism, the
validity of artificial sentience, and the
central question at hand, which is how far will you
go to get what you want? What lines would you or
wouldn't you cross and why? It's a great question
and the idea of superhero selfishness is largely
ignored in Marvel and DC films and shows because
for the most part, comics deal with uncommonly
upstanding selfless individuals. Right,
heroism is selfless. And realistically, a lot of
people who would receive these superpowers would
have to decide to what degree they would use them to
serve themselves and or others on the fact that
Riri makes so many of her choices in her own
interest. And even at the expense of others, it
definitely doesn't make her heroic. But she's
also not really a villain, even if she and others
question that in the course of the season. And
especially when you consider the reasons behind
her reason behind her armor. Right, that's a
question that's posited to her multiple times
like why are you doing this? And often her answer is
because I can. Yeah, right. They asked her why the
suit? Why is the money to complete it so important?
Why was that worth getting expelled? Why was that
worth stealing for? As you said, she responds with
because I can and for a lesser series, maybe that
would be enough in terms of motivation and maybe
that reasoning would speak to the self assurance
and hubris of the hyper intelligent. But the show
goes deeper because because is not really an
answer. So as we learn for Riri, it was all a trauma
response. And she was obsessed with building her
suit out of the unprocessed grief of witnessing
her best friend and dad bleed out in front of her.
From out of that, you know, she was smart. She knew
there existed a president of an armored hero who
could protect people in Iron Man. So she became
hyper focused on making an armor because she
didn't know how else to process her emotions. I
thought that was fantastic. I thought that was a
really well done exploration. But even beyond
that, because we all know building a suit alone
doesn't make you heroic, you know, you have to help
people and Riri mostly just helps herself in the
show. What's fascinating is that the series
actually addresses that in the final episode, the
hood calls her out saying, you thought you were one
of the good guys. What are you doing with that
armor? You're not rescuing people from burning
buildings or saving car crash victims. And I
thought that was a particularly complex moment
because, you know, she kind of was helping others
and preemptively fighting the hood to protect her
family and friends. But she was also fighting for
the artificial life that she created. And while
the show never explicitly discusses the value of
digital sentience and whether that's really
worth fighting for, I like how at least the topic
was addressed. Yeah, it was very timely,
especially with the advent in recent years of AI
and its common use. Well, yeah, I don't know if
something like chat GPT could really be
considered an artificial intelligence or if it's
just, you know, a conversation, but I don't know
enough about the technology to really comment on
that. But I will say that I'm not really willing to
steal or cross other ethical boundaries for the
sake of my chat GPT conversations at this moment.
Well, I mean, you say that, but it's not like you
have an AI programmed to respond and look like a
loved one who has passed away. That's valid. I'd
have to think about that. Just the fact that I think
that may be possible now is kind of terrifying.
It's interesting, for sure, for sure. And it does
make me wonder how AI chat technology will be used
in the future in that regard, missing loved ones
and stuff like that. This is all to say, Iron Heart
season one touched on some heavy shit. And that's
just like a part of the thematic bits. We'll talk
more about the themes when doubling into
characters like the hood. But I think the best
thing about the show is that beyond the special
effects and the plot turns and the acting, there
was this subtext of something deeper. Right,
definitely a subtext. I don't know if it's delved
deep enough in any kind of meaningful way to be
satisfying. It definitely didn't. But I did
appreciate that it broached certain subjects, I
guess. Yeah, I agree. The themes were great, but
they don't always make a good show alone, right?
You need the other elements there for a quality
superhero show, including, oh, you know,
sticking the landing at the end. The worst thing
about the show probably was the ending. I thought
it was way too ambiguous as to whether or not we were
looking at a vision of the future where Riri sold
her soul to Mephisto, or maybe she didn't sell her
soul. I probably think that she did, but that would
also take the series down a route that I wouldn't
want it to go, because then she's probably got to
get her soul back. And then the show is going to dive
deeper into the magic stuff, and Riri really
belongs in the world of science fiction, you know,
the tech side of Marvel. Yeah, no, I agree. I
despised this ending. I couldn't believe that
they ended this season this way, especially
because even Ryan Coogler has admitted that he
doesn't know where Riri is going to appear next,
whether they're going to have a second season of
the show, or what. Right, the Marvel mid-credit
and end credit scenes were great back in the
beginning when we knew that for sure these
upcoming projects were greenlit and confirmed.
When the fate of a franchise is kind of up in the air
and we don't know what's coming next, it can be
highly frustrating when things are ambiguous,
because we don't know if they'll ever get
resolved. We've had a number of post-credit and
mid-credit scenes from Marvel now that are left
dangling. There's so many loose plot threads that
I think I've lost track. Also, one thing I didn't
like about the show were some of the acting. Aside
from, you know, the main cast, I thought the
supporting cast was a little bit cheesy,
especially with the hoodscrew, clown slug, and
the blood siblings. I thought we're not great
actors if they even were actors, and I don't think
they were good adaptations of their comic book
counterparts, which I guess is forgivable
because they're obscure, but what's less
forgivable is that they were cheesy. Well, they
were borderline caricatures by the end. Right, in
the comics, the blood siblings are aliens.
They're called the blood brothers, but here they
made them either female or non-binary. One or the
other slug was, I think, trans, and then clown. I
wasn't quite sure which clown she was an
adaptation of in the comic books, but they kind of
brought down the show, I think, and it's not
because of the gender fluidity of the group. I'm
all for representation. I mean, Iron Heart
herself is an example of representation within
Marvel comic books, where they decided to bring
this kind of like hidden figures type element with
a strong black smart woman taking on the Iron Man
legacy. But if you're going to have
representation in your show, you got to make sure
it's done well, otherwise it's just going to put
people off. Well, you have to make sure it's
believable. You know, when it's not believable,
it's just pandering, and I feel like the same way
about the blood siblings. Like, I didn't think
they could kick anyone's ass. Yeah, I don't know if
they were actual aliens on the show, but maybe they
were, and maybe that's why they were so
formidable. It wasn't addressed regardless.
Now, I would agree with you when I came to the
supporting cast of the Hood's crew, but I actually
liked the acting of Riri's supporting cast from
Natalie to Xavier, and even her mom, Ronnie, I
thought did a fantastic job. Oh, for sure. Yeah,
they were all great. The third thing that I didn't
appreciate about the season were the number of
plot holes. There were a lot of fucking plot holes,
maybe not quite as much as Secret Invasion, but I
definitely want to address them in the course of
this review to see if maybe we could get answers.
But first, let's get into our character
breakdown. Starting with Ironheart, aka Riri
Williams, played by Dominique Thorne. Man, I was
so much more impressed with Dominique Thorne's
acting in this series. She legitimately blew me
away with the reality of her performance as Riri.
So much so, that I was shocked that I ever even
doubted her. I felt like a piece of shit. Well, she
was given so much more to work with in this show than
she was in What Kind of Forever. I agree. I that she
gave a fantastic performance in this series.
Absolutely. Like when she was feeling defensive
and like no one else could help her with her
problems, I was like, just leave her alone. And
when she had panic attacks, I was like, breathe,
girl, you're gonna pass out if you don't breathe.
Like I was into her performance. It was just so
believable. I'm still not sure she entirely has
the presence yet, but I will say that at the end of
the show, that giant afro really helped. I wish she
had that all the time because when I finally saw her
with the classic Riri look, I was like, holy shit,
that's her. That's Riri Williams. And I feel like I
saw the character for the first time. I thought the
same thing, actually. I much preferred the afro.
That was a cool look. Yeah, it's a staple of the
character in the comic books. And I got to say
Dominique Thorne rocked it. Now Riri's arc was
complex as we discussed a little bit earlier. When
you look at Natalie's origin, how that
intelligence emerged from Riri's brain while she
was mapping it for her AI system. That's actually
straight from the comic books. Riri mapped her
brain for her suit system and was surprised to see
her late friend from childhood show up. In the
comic books, that's treated as more of kind of like
a novel oddity than like a psychological reveal. I
like to think that the showrunner saw that moment
from the books and decided to explore that more and
explore the grief behind that and maybe make it the
reason behind everything. And emotional trauma
can be an acceptable means of letting your
character be a little morally loose. Because like
look at the Punisher. The only reason we as comic
book readers accept his immoral behavior is
because we can see the psychological reasoning
behind it. So in hindsight, we can say, okay, Riri,
you stole and you played Robin Hood. And now we know
why it's fascinating. But I do think that it brings
up two big issues. One is that it doesn't make Riri
particularly endearing because she's a thief.
It's not a huge issue because you still root for her
despite wanting to flick her upside the head a few
times. But the second and more important thing is
that I feel like there's a plot hole in that someone
as intelligent as Riri would find a better way to
earn money. Riri says at one point that she's doing
this stealing because she has to. But I don't
understand why she sees it that way. Why would her
options be so limited if she's one of the most
brilliant engineers on the planet? Right. She was
creating all kinds of gadgets at the beginning.
That's how we're introduced the character at the
beginning of this series at least. So why not sell
those? Exactly. Like she can make a fortune
selling her advanced AI or the force field watches
or something like that. I really don't believe for
a second that she felt that she had to resort to
crime. Maybe it was her impatience that led her to
do that. But that goes back to point one where she's
not very endearing. I don't know if she wasn't
endearing. I think sometimes she wasn't
likeable. But I think the struggle she had, the
moral one, made her slightly endearing because
she was doing bad things. But she had a moral code.
She knew what she was doing was wrong. It never
really identified as a thief because of that moral
code, you could say. And it made for a really
compelling thematic arc. It was kind of like
watching to see how far she would kind of spiral
down and how she would get herself out of that.
Yeah, kind of developed into an arc of redemption
to see how she would overcome these failings of
guilt that she had. Which made the ending that much
more tragic, I would say. Yes. And that much more
heartbreaking, not only because it wasn't
satisfying, but also because it kind of broke her
arc, I would say. Yeah, she didn't really redeem
herself, it seems like. And so it left her arc
incomplete and the audience without closure.
Such a bizarre choice. So really. Yeah. Regarding
the iron heart suit, I was really hoping for a final
suit design at the end that looked more like the
main one that she wears from the comic books, or at
least the pink, black and gold one. And readers of
the comics should know what I'm talking about. I
don't think it would have to be pink in live action.
I think you can still go red because the pink is
probably a little bit too dainty for Dominique
Thorn's version of iron heart, who's a little bit
rougher than the comic book reary. But in the comic
books, that design is really sleek and awesome and
not bulky like in the show. Well, I liked the final
suit. It probably didn't have enough color,
you're right. But I did like that they used pieces
from the barracuda that her dad built her to create
it. I thought that was pretty cool. Yo, she and her
dad built it. And yeah, that was a really nice
touch, for sure. Let's go ahead and move on to the
hood, aka Parker Robbins, played by Anthony
Ramos. Dude, Anthony Ramos almost carried this
entire season. I thought his performance was
fantastic. I first saw him in Hamilton. I really
haven't seen him in much else, but he's an
incredible actor. He's really good. I've seen him
in Hamilton and Twisters and in the Heights. The
dude can kind of do it all. And while I thought that
initially he was going to be pretty shallow and
this was just like a petty revenge kind of arc, when
we learned that this was all because his dad
abandoned him, that blew me away. The character
was really cool once I learned that. Yeah, his
whole arc is that he was trying to get back what he
felt was kept from him when he was kicked out of his
house at the age of 12 by his rich father. That
reveal was fantastic. And when you can understand
the motivations of a villain like the hood, it
makes things so much more interesting because
suddenly you're kind of rooting for the villain.
Right, the villain becomes sympathetic. The
character was so good that I'm convinced that's
why they had the mid-credit scene that they did,
where instead of being defeated, it looks like
they were wanting to continue the hood story arc.
Does he become a whole sympathy angle? Otherwise,
you're going to have an Ezekiel stain type
situation, which we'll get into a little bit
later. But first, I want to address the plot hole of
why didn't the hood just go straight to his father?
Like, why did he decide to go this all-round about
way and hire a crew and introduce a ton of
liabilities and variables to the situation? He
could have just literally gone to his father and
threatened him to get his estate. Well, he wanted
more than the estate. He wanted... It was
interesting because the hood only went after
organizations that were affecting poor Chicago
communities. So he had somewhat of an ethical
grounding. But then, you know, he's out there
having his cousin kill the Rampage guy and tie up
loose ends. So I don't know if the hood was maybe a
corrupting influence on him because it also
seemed in the flashback scenes that he wasn't a
100% evil guy. Well, I kind of took his whole
ethical approach to the companies they targeted,
not as genuine I took that as a way to manipulate his
crew to get them on board. Yeah, I think that's
totally valid for sure. Great character, great
character in that regard. Yeah. What did you think
of the actual hood? I thought it looked cool. You
know, it looked like straight out of the comic
books. It looked old, but kind of stylish. I
thought it was going to look cooler. Not going to
lie. Really? Like what? I don't know. I think I
expected something that maybe fit a little bit
better. It was a little bit more flowy and
supernatural looking. It was a little heavy. Like
it was made out of leather or something. Maybe if it
was made out of like a lighter fabric, it would have
flowed more, but I didn't mind it at all. I did like
the scarring that was going on with him and like how
they were trying to cover it up with tattoos and how
the tattoos got more elaborate as each episode
progressed. I thought that was really cool. And I
also liked the nod to characters like Cassilius,
how they were tainted and physically affected
when they kind of made deals with these dark
entities. Yeah, that is interesting. I guess I
didn't think about the tie into Cassilius, but
yeah, his body was getting all fucked up too in his
dealings with Dormammu. What's interesting is
that in the comic books, Parker Robbins got the
hood by killing a demon that was wearing it who had
ties to Dormammu. So his hood did get his power from
the dark dimension and they kind of had an Easter
egg reference to that in the show because Zelma
thought that the hood came from Dormammu. Though
later it was revealed to be Mephisto behind
everything. Let's go ahead and move on to Ezekiel
Stain, played by Alden Ehrenreich. Now I like
Alden as an actor. I think I've only seen him in
solo. I wasn't sure what to think of the character
from the marketing because Joe McGillicuddy was
an alias. But once he was revealed as Ezekiel
Stain, I was like, yes, like this guy definitely
deserves to be a villain within the Iron Man
franchise. And I was kind of disappointed that
they transformed the character into a more
sympathetic henchman type role. It was really
hard to get a beat on the character because on one
hand, you know, he was a tech ethicist and he didn't
have like malicious intentions, really. But also
he was a black market dealer and seemed to have this
kind of dark streak to him. The show kind of seemed
to want it both ways with this character. And that
was kind of unsatisfying. I did think it was cool
that they made him the son of Obadiah Stain. Is that
a real character from the comics? Yes. Yeah, Zeke
Stain is Obadiah Stain's son. He was a second Iron
Monger and he is interesting because he takes a
more biotech route with his superpowers just like
in the show. OK. And he developed a way for the body
to use like 90 percent less energy and the energy
gets transmitted into these energy enhancements
that he has on his body. Very similar to how he was in
the show. Does he have a different look in the
comic? Because I kind of feel like they missed an
opportunity to make him more monsterish, almost
like Frankenstein's monster. Well, he's more of
like a cyborg and he can like manifest it to look
more like a suit of armor, but he's always part
machine, part human. And that's kind of his whole
shtick as an Iron Man villain. It's less about
creating a suit of armor and more about merging man
and machine to become a true Iron Man. Yeah, I think
they missed an opportunity to make the character
more tragic. He ended up being kind of lame in the
way that he was just kind of a puppet. I didn't like
that. Well, he lost the fight by getting kicked in
the balls, right? Yeah, I was weird. I love that.
Didn't love that for him, especially since he's a
lot more formidable in the books. And I guess
during that first fight, he was quite the force of
nature, but the second fight was just
disappointing and embarrassing. I'll say,
though, that it is nice that Marvel is revisiting
some of its earlier plots in projects like this one
and like Captain America Brave New World. Oh,
yeah, totally. I definitely got excited when they
found a way to squeeze an element of the Iron Man
movies into the show for sure. Let's go to move into
our final character. We're going to discuss and
that is Mephisto played by Sasha Baron Cohen. Now,
he only had a small part in the show. He was only in
the final episode, but you know, Sasha Baron Cohen
is a pretty big actor who's led some of his own
films. And I thought his approach to the role of
Mephisto was pretty interesting. I don't know if
you noticed, but in Mephisto's conversation with
Riri in the reflection of his spoon, you can see the
actual demonic looking character. Oh, I did not
catch that. Really? Oh, dude, you got to go back and
look at that because it's scary as hell. Like, I
don't know if you've seen the film in Sidious or if
you know of that classic shot where the demon guy is
poking out behind Patrick Wilson's head. But it
felt kind of like that. Like he has these glowing
eyes and he's all red. It's really fucking creepy.
And I was really pleased with that look. Oh, I just
googled it. Yeah, no, I didn't need to see that. I
was hoping that they would give a full on reveal of
the Mephisto character. But in hindsight, I kind
of like this a little bit more where he's almost
like too evil to actually look at outside of the
demonic appearance. You know, the overall
approach that they seem to take with the character
was this very Faustian type angle where, you know,
he is a smooth talking deceiver. Right. He'll
grant any wish you have in exchange for your soul,
essentially. Yeah, very charismatic. I could see
why they went with Sushabar and Cohen for this
particular role because he has the range in that he
can be conniving but also charming and
convincing. And he did this weird thing with
accents that really made you feel like he was a
being of the world and had been doing this for a
while. I'm just glad he didn't break into his
Kazakhstan accent. And my name is Mephisto. I like
sex. It's nice. I was trying to figure out why they
even incorporated someone like Mephisto into an
Iron Heart series. But it does make sense in terms
of the theme of how far will you go for the things you
want? What bigger price is there than, you know,
your own soul dealing with a character like the
devil himself? So then it kind of clicked for me why
he was here. Well, I also think it's appropriate
that he's in a show that deals with the morality of
good and evil. When Riri is trying to choose the
path between good and bad to have the ultimate
adversary be the embodiment of bad, of evil, I
thought that was an interesting approach. And
what's also interesting is that it seemed like she
did sell her soul. I don't like. Titan's Smash
every Tuesday, Max destruction, where TV and
action heroes battle every Wednesday and Sendra
world, where anime champions clash every
Thursday. Join us as we speculate on the matches
and armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge
victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com where we
settle the debate and settle the score. Let's go
ahead and move on into the episode highlights. The
first episode was called Take Me Home. In it, Riri
Williams requests for MIT to extend her grant to
rebuild the Iron Heart armor is denied and she's
expelled from the school after getting caught
completing assignments for other students in
exchange for money for her work. Riri takes off in
her new suit of armor to her hometown of Chicago,
but she is locked out of the suit en route. After
crashing and gathering the pieces, she returns
home, where it's revealed that she, her mother,
Ronnie and her friend, Xavier, are still grieving
the deaths of Riri's late friend, Natalie and
stepfather, Gary, who were both killed in a drive
by shooting. She's approached by John, the cousin
of Parker Robbins, aka the Hood, to join their
crew. After passing a booby trapped audition,
Riri is hesitant to join, but the hood convinces
her with financial compensation and the promise
that their theft will serve the community. Back
home, Ronnie suspects something is wrong and
probes Riri, suspecting she has unprocessed
grief. After falling asleep while mapping her
brain to create a new AI for her armor, Riri awakens
to see that the intelligence is a recreation of
Natalie. Now, one of the signs of a good character
is that they have what's known in literary terms as
a ghost, because it's something that haunts them
from the past, whether it's shame or guilt or loss.
I find it really fascinating that they gave Riri a
literal ghost in Natalie. I thought that was
really smart because she absolutely is haunted by
Natalie. So for her to pop up accidentally was a
great source of conflict throughout the whole
season. They did it really well. Absolutely. And
they could have based the entire season off of that
conflict alone. And maybe they should have spent
more time on it. But yeah, it was so well done,
especially progressing through the episodes
where it culminated with Natalie believing she's
real and trying to meet her brother, Xavier, him
rejecting her and then ultimately her dying,
essentially, and Riri coming to terms with how
much that AI meant to her, despite being
standoffish with it at the beginning.
Fascinating stuff. It was hands down the best part
of this series by far, I think. I was really
surprised to see Eric Andre show up in the Marvel
Cinematic Universe. He played a character called
Stuart Clark, also known as Rampage in the comic
books. I thought it was funny how he kept trying to
get people to call him Rampage in the show. But
Rampage was the successor, basically, to Micro
and he assisted the Punisher in the comics. And I
think it would be fucking awesome if it turns out
that Stuart didn't actually die. And then he ends
up teaming up with John Berndthal's Punisher
character. All right, he would be a great foil for
that character. Yeah, he's such a great comedian.
Now, is John a character in the comics? Yeah, the
cousin John. His name is John King. He's the hood's
cousin as he is in this show. And he's part of his
gang. He helps him out. At one point, he gets
recruited into another gang called the Zodiac.
And I think that was the only time he had
superpowers. But yeah, otherwise, he basically
serves the same function that he did in the show in
the comic books. Cool, let's get to know. Episode
two was called, Will the real Natalie please stand
up? While trying to come to terms with the Natalie
she created, Riri meets with the hood's crew to
discuss extorting the CEO of a new underground
private highway system called Tunnel. Needing
more parts to complete her armor before the job,
Natalie helps Riri track down a black market arms
dealer named Joe McGillicuddy in the Chicago
suburbs. He takes her to his arms bunker and Riri
finishes her armor before the heist. The crew's
hacker, Slug, gives Riri a computer virus on a
flash drive, though she's startled by Natalie and
loses it. Improvising, Riri helps the crew still
pull off the job with hood teleporting into the
CEO's car and extorting her. Escaping the
underground tunnels, Ironheart is confronted by
a guard at gunpoint and Natalie freezes. The hood
saves her with magic bullets, covering Riri's
escape back home. At the hideout, John tattoos
over the hood's magic scars, which grow worse the
more he uses his cloak. Now could the hood
teleport? I didn't think he could. I thought he
could just turn invisible. Is it like Frodo? Yeah,
he could teleport, he could turn invisible, he can
imbue weapons with Hellfire. He's a pretty cool
character and we're definitely going to use him in
a duel in the near future. But his power set does
speak to another plot hole that I have in that, you
know, forget the fact that he probably could have
gone straight to his father. Why couldn't he just
go straight to the CEOs? Why did he need all these
elaborate plans when he can literally sneak by
anything and just show up like in their home or
something? Yeah, just make him sign the contracts
at gunpoint. So much easier. Exactly. That is a
plot hole, right? Yes. Yep, I would say. Now in your
character breakdown, you didn't mention the
actress who played Natalie. I thought she did a
fantastic job though. I thought from the trailers
and everything that she was going to be super
cringe, but she wasn't. She was fantastic.
Absolutely. Yeah, she's played by Lyric Ross, who
I haven't seen in anything else before. But I
thought she brought a lot of heart to the character
of Natalie, even as an AI for sure. It was kind of
weird to see Natalie on a computer screen trying to
figure out how to escape into the rest of the house
because she's kind of talking to herself on a
screen. But beyond that, yeah, there was a lot of
humanity in her performance. Episode three was
called We Endanger Girl. After celebrating their
success, tensions rise in the crew when
demolition expert Clown touches Parker's cloak
and John Reprimands them. The hood announces
their next target, a biotech company named Air
Loom. Jo visits RiRi at her home, blackmailing her
for engineering help with his biotech designs.
Learning from the police that former crew member
Rampage was killed, RiRi suspects the hood and
John of tying up loose ends. She decides to get a
sample of the hood to study it and learn more about
what kind of threat he poses. RiRi visits Jo and
learns that he is Ezekiel Stain, the son of Obadiah
Stain, the Iron Monger, but that he abhors his
father. She borrows a sample of his biomass skin
design in order to get her laser cutter through Air
Loom's metal detectors, which she can use to get a
piece of the hood's cloak. However, during the
heist, RiRi's laser is detected by security
sensors and triggers a CO2 defense system. RiRi
tries to help rescue the crew, but is discovered by
John out of her armor and with a piece of the hood's
cloak. He tries to kill her, but RiRi escapes with
her armor's help, losing the biomass skin sample
in the process and leaving John to suffocate. The
crew flees and the hood is distraught over the loss
of his cousin. He sees in a vision that RiRi was
responsible for his death and RiRi has a panic
attack over the disastrous turn of events. This
was a good episode. I think this was my favorite
episode. Just because of all the tension of RiRi
working for the guy who she thinks maybe trying to
kill her and figuring out how she was going to get to
him first. I thought it was a cool episode. It was
pretty good. There is another plot hole here
though, in that a laser can cut off a piece of the
hood. You would think it would be heat resistant.
You would think, but also by the end of the show,
RiRi ends up incorporating magic into her suit of
armor and that ends up deleting Natalie, which
leads to the deal with Mephisto. You know what
would circumvent all of that? A shit ton of lasers?
A fucking shit ton of lasers. Like the ones that
Iron Man used in Iron Man 2, where he was fighting
alongside War Machine and he told him to duck and
then he spun around and killed all of those hammer
droids. Just fucking put some of those on the Iron
Heart armor. You'll be able to cut through
anything, including that fucking cloak and just
destroy it. Okay, take it back. This is not a good
episode. This whole show sucks now. I understand
why scientifically she wanted a piece of the
cloak, but I really think they kind of shot
themselves in the foot with the reveal that it
could be cut with a laser beam. Especially when
you're dealing with a character like Iron Heart
who can shoot fucking lasers. Major plot hole.
What the heck? Yeah, yeah. But yeah, other than
that, great episode. Episode 4 was called Bad
Magic. In a flashback, we see Parker and John
attempt to rob a mansion, but are discovered by
security. In the present, RiRi meets with the crew
and suspects that the hood knows she was involved
with John's death. She returns home and analyzes
the hood piece she recovered, which she learns is
magic. She goes to visit Ezekiel and discovers
that he's been arrested for the discovery of his
biomech tech found at the heirloom crime scene.
She visits the prison to apologize, and Parker
deduces the connection between RiRi and Ezekiel
via news of the arrest. Afraid for the safety of her
family and friends, RiRi fashions them force
field-emitting watches. Her mother, Ronnie,
offers to help whatever situation she's in and
accompanies RiRi to Stanton's, a book and candy
shop, to learn what might destroy the hood's
cloak. Madeline Stanton, a former comertase
trainee and her daughter, Zelma, learned that the
hood is working with an ancient evil until RiRi
that it cannot be destroyed. The hood sneaks into
Ezekiel's cell to form an alliance against RiRi
and helps him escape prison. Natalie tries to help
RiRi by bringing her friend Xavier to her, but he's
upset that the AI isn't as late sister's likeness.
The crew uses Ezekiel's biotech designs to outfit
him with cybernetic enhancements, secretly
putting the hood in charge of the programming.
Parker informs the crew that their next job is to
kill RiRi for being responsible for John's death.
A lot of plot holes in this episode. Let me break
them down and see if we can get answers. First of
all, why didn't the hood just go after RiRi's
family right away if he suspected her of being
responsible for John's death? He said earlier
that he had plans for her, but you also can bend
bullets, bro. Yeah, just shoot her at that point,
right? Why not? Why all the complicated schemes?
The hood is not a very efficient villain, I'll say,
in this season. Next plot hole is if RiRi suspected
the hood and John of being responsible for
Stewart's death, which she later brought up with
Clown during their fight in the next episode, why
didn't she bring that up with the crew earlier?
That Stewart was dead, because the crew would have
questioned it at that point. I know, there's
something to be said for a dramatic timing though,
and maybe she really didn't fully trust the crew.
That's fair, that's fair. Maybe that one's not a
plot hole. But how did authorities track the
biomass skin to Ezekiel Stain, considering that a
lot of his stuff was black market and off the books?
That's exactly what I was wondering. Now, to be
fair, he did mention to her that this black market
stuff could be traced back to him, but it was not
clear how. And if it could, I was like, bro, what is
the whole point of the black market then? I thought
this stuff was supposed to be untraceable. Right.
Those are all the plot holes I have for that
episode. Other than them, I did enjoy episode 4. I
really liked the scene where RiRi tried a bunch of
different scientific means to destroy the cloak.
I don't know, I thought some of them were kind of
basic. Like she tried a small bomb, she tried acid.
I guess she could have tried more lasers. Right, so
it's like a laser can cut it, but the heat couldn't,
the bomb couldn't? You just ruined the whole show
for me. Sorry. Episode 5 is called Karma's A
Glitch. In it, Natalie and the Iron Heart suit are
captured by the crew while RiRi meets with Zelma at
a White Castle. Zelma explains her belief that the
hood belongs to Dormammu before the crew ambush
and attack RiRi. She traps the blood siblings with
a force field watch, knocks Clown out with her own
explosive, and manages to get her armor back
before being run down by Slug. However, Zeke shows
up and uses his biotech energy and physiology to
shut down and destroy RiRi's armor. However,
instead of killing her, he spares her life and
tells her to leave the city. She runs home and tells
Ronnie to pack her bags to leave, confessing
everything. RiRi admits her obsession with
building the suit was based on her trauma from
Natalie and Gary's death, and her mom takes her to
the garage where the drive-by occurred and
reminds her of the good memories also had there.
Inspired to build a new suit and fight back, RiRi
recruits her friends to transform the Plymouth
Barracuda her and her dad restored into an
upgraded armor. Convinced magic is the only means
of stopping the hood. She has Zelma perform a
ritual to imbue it with magic energy. Meanwhile,
Parker, believing RiRi is dead, controls Zeke's
body and uses him to invade the mansion from the
flashback, reveals to be his estranged father's
house. Revealing that he was kicked out at age 12
and now has controlling stakes in his dad's
businesses, he forces him to sign over his estate.
Zelma's Iron Heart Armor. Now this was a great
episode, but there is one small plot hole, and that
is why didn't the hood accompany the crew at White
Castle? Like the hood was there for all the other
jobs that the crew was doing, and I don't know what
he was doing at the time they were trying to kill
RiRi, but if he had joined them, he would have been
there to either finish the job or at least see that
Ezekiel Stain was lying to him. Yeah, you kind of
put too much faith in Zeke, I guess, which made no
sense because he was new to the crew and he hadn't
earned that trust yet. Well, I was still trying to
figure out how Zeke was able to defeat RiRi so
easily. Was his electricity draining her
battery? Is that what it was? It seemed like it kind
of short circuited her systems or something like
that. Okay, that makes a little bit more sense, but
you're right about the hood not being there. He
definitely should have been to contribute. And
confirm the kill. I did think it was a little weak
that Zeke just told her to run away. It felt kind of
like a convenient cop out. Despite the fact that
the show went out of the way to establish him as more
of a morally gray person, but that in itself is also
a cop out considering he is a villain in the comic
books. It was all just too convenient.
Absolutely. I hear that all the time where it's
like, oh, superhero movies are done. Why doesn't
the villain just kill the hero when he has the
chance? This is the perfect example of that. Yeah,
for sure. I will say I did love the White Castle
fight showing how resourceful RiRi is outside of
the armor. It kind of reminded me of Iron Man 3,
where we saw Tony Stark take out all the henchmen at
what he thought was the Mandarin's mansion. And
you know, he went to Home Depot and got all
creative. Here, RiRi had to get creative inside a
burger joint and really prove her metal. I don't
know why Zelma didn't help her. Yeah, I guess she
could have used her magic to help fight back,
right? She seems like a pretty powerful
sorceress. I mean, she's not that powerful. She's
still learning in the books she is Dr. Strange's
librarian. Oh, interesting. But I mean, she could
transform candy into other candy. Right,
exactly. So she could like transform one of
Clown's bombs into candy. Into candy. Yeah. The
sixth and final episode is called The Past is the
Past. In a flashback, Parker and John split up
after being discovered by security. Cornered,
Parker is approached by Mephisto who helps him
magically escape. He assures Parker that he can
help him achieve his desire for power, respect and
wealth by giving him the cloak in exchange for his
soul. And Parker accepts the deal. In the present,
the hood argues with Zeke about the emptiness of
his ambitions. RiRi tries to recreate Natalie but
can't and vows to defeat the hood and use its magic
to bring her back. Parker accuses Mephisto of not
fulfilling his end of the bargain, but Mephisto
threatens to replace him with someone more
capable. Ironheart and Zeke fight in a rematch,
and he allows her to knock him out to reset Parker's
programming override. She confronts the hood and
the two fight with the hood transforming into a
demonic figure. RiRi detonates a magic energy
blast that seemingly destroys her armor, but it's
revealed to be a holographic illusion and she
removes the hood's cloak and he's left in pain
without it. Leaving the hideout RiRi is
confronted by Mephisto who also assures her he can
help her achieve her desires. In a vision of the
future, or perhaps, reality, RiRi hacks the
suit's magic to recreate Natalie, or as it turns
out, resurrect the real Natalie. Dark magic scars
form on her skin. In a mid-credits scene, Parker
asks Selma for help. Now the ending aside, I really
liked the final battle between Ironheart and the
hood. I thought it had a great tit for tat momentum
in that she was able to negate his invisibility and
teleporting magic, but he transformed into a
demon who was ripping her armor apart. But then she
set off a magic blast that hurt him but also left her
vulnerable. There was a lot of back and forth that
felt very satisfying in terms of who's going to
win. The hood was definitely a good villain. I did
find it odd that Mephisto or Mephisto,
apparently, is pronounced Mephisto. He was
agreed to every single aspect of our bargain. I'm
like, no you didn't. You promised he would be a
king. What are you talking about? Well, he did
achieve that. He was sitting at his father's
table. I don't know. When Mephisto said that, I was
just like, whatever bro, no you didn't. The devil
is a liar. Yeah, he definitely didn't tell him
about the whole magic scarring thing. I think if he
would have admitted that, maybe he wouldn't have
gone through with the deal. Although Riri knew
about the magic scarring and she still went
through with the deal too. So weird. Such a weird
choice. Do you want there to be a season two of this?
You know, I really like the character of Riri
Williams, especially what they did with her in
this season. I would like there to be a season two,
but I don't want it to continue the story of where
they left it off here. I think Riri belongs
squarely again in the tech side of Marvel, not the
magic side. And I would like to see the hood return,
but maybe as a villain against someone like Moon
Knight or Blade or Ghost Rider or something like
that. That'd be cool. I keep hearing rumors that
Mephisto is going to kind of take over for Kang as
the primary antagonist for this upcoming
multiverse saga. How would you feel about that? I
could totally see that working, for sure. That'd
be awesome. Mephisto is a big enough character to
hold his own against an entire Avengers lineup. If
they do that, I kind of wish they would have
introduced him in a different project than this
show. Well, if they do do that, maybe it'll get more
people to watch this season in the future.
Overall, there was a lot to like about the show, a
little bit to dislike, a lot to question. It's kind
of a mixed bag. I think the strong elements within
it really do a lot to make up for its shortcomings.
The season definitely carries a subtext of deeper
emotional meaning and thematic importance
despite the weak supporting cast, the plot holes,
and the ambiguous ending. All things considered,
I'm rating Iron Heart season 1 3.5 stars out of 5. A
fresh rating on Rotten Tomatoes. I would agree
with you that it's a mixed bag. The lead
performances were great. The special effects
were great. The themes were great. That said, I do
think the writers dropped the ball in several
instances, including the ending, including the
plot holes. I do think ultimately the good
outweighs the bad, which is why I would still
recommend it. So I would agree with your 3.5 star
rating, especially if Mofisto is going to be a
major player in the MCU going forward. And
especially if they're able to clear up the ending
with a subsequent season or some other project. I
think that would actually make this season better
if they cleaned everything up in a satisfying
manner. Still probably not to elevate the show
beyond a 3.5 star rating though. But that does it
for this review. H.J .9K, help close us out. Next
episode is not as good as this episode, because
it's going to be a review of the Superman movie,
which is almost certainly going to be 3 stars or
under. H.J .9K, 5 stars. It's going to be a 5 star
start to the new DCU. Just you wait. But that does it
for this episode. We want to give a big thanks to our
executive producers, John Staroski, Zachary
Hepburn, Dustin Belcom, Mickey Mathen-Geehan,
Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yatn, Austin Wisalowski,
AJ Dunkerly, Nick Obanto, Scott Camacho, Gil
Camacho, Adam Spees, Dean Molesky, Devin Davis,
Joseph Kirsting, Josh Leiner, Mike Williams,
Oscar Galvez, and Paul Graves for helping make
this podcast possible. And we'll talk to you guys
next week. Up up and away, true believers. For the
Gen Z fam, Iron Heart was low-key mid but didn't
take crazy L's in its flop era and is giving
scabiddy toilet-riss vibes on God. Period.