This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi and welcome
to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe and I'm his twin
brother Johnny DC. And in this episode we're going
to find out who would win in a fight between the two
lords of the underworld, Neron from DC and Hela
from Marvel. Now listeners are probably familiar
with both of these characters. Hela was the main
antagonist in Dora Gnarok and Neron was a freaking
horrifying character in the Arrowverse. Oh I
didn't even know that he was in that show. Yeah
don't Google it, he looks freaking gross. I'm
googling it right now, Neron Arrowverse. What the
fuck is that? Exactly. I regret googling that, you
should have warned me. I literally did. He doesn't
look anything like the comic book character. No.
It's one of those weird Arrowverse adaptations.
Okay. Yeah basically it's a demon from hell versus
the Norse god of death. My money's on the Norse god
of death. Everybody knows that hell with two L's is
superior to hell with one. Before we get into that
matchup guys we're going to break down the latest
comic book movie news to come out from this past
week, uh which there was none. Likely because
we're just coming off of New York Comic when the
studios gave their latest updates on all the
existing projects. So we'll have to wait a few more
weeks for more news. As always though we list our
segment times in our episode description so feel
free to check out the show notes if you want to skip
ahead to a particular topic. Our artificially
intelligent dual simulator AJ9K has a quick
message for our listeners so listen up. Why hello
there. Do you want even more from this podcast?
Then become a part of the dynamic dual community on
Patreon where you can choose from three tiers. The
dynamic 2.0 tier gives you access to our discord
chat server. The fantastic 4.0 tier gives you two
bonus episodes each month and the X-Force tier
makes you an executive producer of this show.
Lastly the Diner Mike podcast network tier lets
you create your own podcast using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and
consultation, and get you simulation results.
Pitch the twins your ideas via email at
dynamicdualpodcast.com. Check it out at
patreon.com .pippip.chirio. Thanks AJ9K and
thanks to everyone who supports the podcast. Guys
be sure to tune into the other shows in the Diner
Mike podcast network this week including the
console combat podcast where hosts John and Dean
simulate battles between popular video game
characters. In yesterday's episode they
reviewed the film Silent Hill. Over on the Max
Destruction podcast hosts Scotty and Gilly paint
your favorite action heroes from film and
television against each other. On Wednesday
they're going to find out who would win between
Wesley Snipes blade and Vlad from Dracula Untold.
And on the Central World podcast hosts Zachary
Hepburn speculates on fights between fan
favorite anime and manga characters. In his
latest episode Zach revealed who would win
between Whitebeard and Kanpachi both from one
piece. Visit dynamicpodcast.com or click the
link in our show notes to listen to all of the shows
in the Diner Mike podcast network. But with that
out of the way quick to the no prize. A no prize is an
award that Marvel used to give out to fans. Our
version the dynamic dual no prize is a digital
award that we post on Instagram for the person that
we feel gave the best answer to the question of the
week. Last week we asked you guys regarding the
Wonder Man and Bat Fam trailers both of which were
released during New York Comic Con. What the fuck
did I just watch wrong answers only. And we got no
answers for the first time in the history of this
podcast. I think no one called in with their
answer. I blame Jonathan entirely for that. I
thought it was a good question. I did think it would
be hard for people because it kind of requires some
creative thinking. Basically the prompt was to
rename the shows based off of your impressions of
each series trailer. And since no one called in
with an answer this week's no prize is being
awarded to us. We're giving ourselves the prize.
I've always wanted to win a no prize. I've never
been eligible. I got to say it feels pretty damn
good. My answers for last week's question of the
week would have been for Wonder Man I would have
retitled it the Studio Season 2. And for Bat Fam I
would have retitled it Gotham Knights Season 2
because it stars a cast of characters that no one
gives a shit about. Given that we all thought it was
going to be a show about the Bat Family as we know it
you know with Nightwing and Red Hood and Batgirl
and things like that. And instead we're getting a
Bat Fam show with like the ghost of Ross Hallgool,
Man Bat and a bunch of characters whose names I
can't remember. Yeah just like that CW show that
lasted one season Gotham Knights featuring
characters that no one knew and no one cared about.
That was a good pick. I also liked the Studio Season
2 because that was just a fun show and I definitely
understand like that same behind-the-scenes
approach to Hollywood vibe that you're going for.
What would your answers have been? Well for Wonder
Man I would have I think that show is essentially
Bat Bluey because it looks like it's for
preschoolers and also I think if it was called Bat
Bluey people would actually watch it. That seems
pretty harsh considering do you liked the Merry
Little Batman film? Well I did like it. I also
acknowledged that that was for a younger
demographic so I mean that's not really an insult.
I do want to make it clear to listeners that for as
much as we are questioning the initial trailers
for both of these series and maybe even that's not
to say that they're not going to be good. We may end
up enjoying them once we watch them. In fact I'm
pretty sure that's going to be the case especially
for Wonder Man. Bat Fam I'm not so sure. I was going
to say the reverse. I'll probably enjoy Bat Fam
with my children but Blunderman and Blah Blah Land
I don't even know if I'm going to tune in for that.
Well that's your loss but congrats to us for
winning this week's No Prize. If you the listener
want a shot at winning your own No Prize go to our
website and click that record button next time and
that brings us to our question of the week. Where
the fuck were you guys last week? Wrong answers
only. Yeah what were you guys doing last week? Not
calling in that's all I know. We want to hear about
it. Give us your best excuse. Again wrong answers
only. Record your answer at dynamicdool.com by
clicking on the red microphone button in the
bottom right hand corner of the screen which will
prompt you to leave us a voicemail. Your message
could be up to 30 seconds long and don't forget to
leave your name in case we include you on the
podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer and award
that person a dynamic dual no prize that we'll post
to Instagram. Be sure to answer before October
25th. But let's go ahead and get into the main event
of this episode where we find out who would win in a
fight between the Lord of Hell, Neron and the Queen
of Hell, Hela. Alright Neron versus Hela. Now this
episode is actually an executive producer
special request from Brandon Estregard. He
wanted to find out who'd win in a fight between
these two characters and it was a great request for
the Halloween season considering that Neron is a
demon or devil from hell. I don't actually know too
much about the character. He's a demon. A demon?
Okay so he's not like a mafisto? Um. Or I guess
mafisto is a demon. Technically he's a hell lord.
Neron's a hell lord. Okay Hela is also a hell lord.
She's considered one despite the fact that her
domain of the underworld only pertains to
escardians and even then it only pertains to
escardians who have not died in battle because
escardians who do die in battle go to Valhalla. So
it's not a place of torment. It's just no
underworld. No it's not like a realm of fire and
torture and suffering. It's just where
escardians go when they die. Okay that's lame. Not
nearly as metal as Neron. I am interested in
learning how powerful Neron is and how that
compares to Hela so let's go ahead and get into the
backstories. First to explain the methodology
behind our duels let's go to our sentient dual
simulator Alfred Jarvis 9000. AJ9K tell our
listeners how you go about determining a winner in
our dual matchups. Yes of course sir. The way I
determine a winner between the contestants is by
running 1000 Monte Carlo simulations using the
character's statistics. A Monte Carlo
simulation is a probabilistic model used to
determine outcomes through random sampling. In
this case I randomize the statistics along a
normal distribution as a way to simulate the many
variables that can occur during battle. The stat
parameters are based on the official marvel power
grid from which the DC characters statistics are
extrapolated. Additional stat categories are
included such as range, damage potential,
versatility and perception in order to create a
more detailed and accurate simulation. The
results of the 1000 simulations provide a
percentage of wins for each character. The
contestant with the higher percentage is
declared the victor as they have a higher
probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing neither character should win
100% of the matches. The comic book stories have
shown that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman so the confidence rate of my method falls
in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks AJ9K. Before
we run the simulations though we like to break down
each character's histories and abilities before
improvising a scenario on how we imagine one of the
1000 simulations would play out B for beat. And
it's my turn to go first with the DC characters
backstory so let me tell you all about Nier on. In
the infernal depths of hell Nier on was once a
lesser demon whose cunning and ambition set him
apart from his kin. Through deception and mastery
of infernal law he rose within the demonic
hierarchy, binding both fiends and mortals to his
will through perfectly worded bargains. Over
countless centuries he became renowned for
crafting covenants that damned their signers
while strengthening his own dominion. To extend
his reach to the mortal realm he crafted black
candles that when lit would summon him to the
bearer or draw the bearer to his court. Through
these devices Nier on bartered for souls in
exchange for granting mortals their hearts
desires each packed designed to twist to his
advantage. His mastery of such dealings earned
him titles among the damned. The wish weaver, the
lord of lies and the king of hate. From his throne in
hell he turned his gaze toward earth preparing a
grand design to expand his infernal power beyond
the boundaries of his realm. Nier on initiated a
plan to unleash the underworld by appearing to
five of the flashes rogues. Captain cold, mirror
master, heatwave, weather wizard and captain
boomerang convincing them to carry out
synchronized acts of destruction across the
united states. The five explosions arranged in
points of a pentagram killed the rogues in green
fire and opened a passage from hell to earth. You
can learn more about the rogues in their teen dual
episode against the brotherhood of mutants.
Emerging through the flames Nier on offered
countless villains and even some heroes black
candles promising power or fulfillment in
exchange for their souls. Dozens accepted
villains were transformed abilities magnified
and desires granted. Nier on's true ambition
however was the corruption of a single pure soul
whose fall would magnify his dominion. Many
believed he sought superman but Nier on's true
prize was shazam. When the hero offered his soul to
save earth and his fellow heroes his selflessness
rendered the contract uncollectable. Bound by
the infernal law that required him to honor his
deals exactly as written Nier on was forced to
release his claims. The trickster exploited the
loophole and unraveling Nier on's network in
bargains and banishing him back to hell empty
handed. Two years later Nier on resurfaced and
resurrected the same five rogues sending them to
terrorize Keystone city. His true target was the
flash Wally West whom he drew into hell. Refusing
Wally soul Nier on instead demanded something
pure. His love for Linda Park. When Linda offered
her own soul to spare him Nier on intended to use
their combined essence to ascend heaven's gates
by channeling the speed force. But the purity of
their love corroded him and affecting his being
with pity and compassion. Desperate to be rid of
the contamination he struck a new bargain. He
restored their love and lives in exchange for
bringing the rogues fully back from death. Nier on
honored the deal found vengeance against the
flash for the humiliation. You can learn more
about Wally West in our flash versus speedball
episode. Soon after Nier on observed chaos in the
celestial order as the angel Asmodel rebelled
against heaven. Seeing opportunity he allied
with Asmodel's army to seize heaven itself but at
the moment of the assault he withdrew support
without explanation and returned to hell. Not
long after Trickster again crossed his path
binding Nier on in a new bargain that compelled him
to forget the rogues entirely. Nier on agreed and
the Trickster walked away as the one mortal who had
bested him twice. You can learn more about
Trickster in his duel against Toad. When Etchigan
manipulated Asmodel's punishment by fusing him
with the unhosted specter force hell erupted into
turmoil. The merging froze hell's fires and
unleashed the damned upon the earth. Nier on used
Superman's body as a vessel to reach the mortal
plane attempting to claim the specter force for
himself. The spirit chose hell Jordan instead and
hell's princes punished Nier on for abusing
hell's power for personal gain. They stripped him
of his royal title and cursed him to speak in rhyme
demoting him to a lower demonic caste. Determined
to reclaim his crown Nier on trialed through time
to seize the souls of Barry Allen, Jason Todd and
Superman at the moments of their deaths. He
captured the first two but Superman's purity
defied him. When Nier on erased dead man's memory
to prevent interference the specter restored it
exposing the scheme. Nier on failed but
maneuvered through infernal politics to regain
his powers and status. From hell's throne he
turned again toward earth. Nier on empowered
Felix Faust to masquerade as Dr. Fate luring Ralph
Dibney into a ritual that promised the
resurrection of his wife Sue. When Nier on
appeared to claim Ralph's soul Ralph activated a
binding circle that trapped them both inside the
tower of fate. Nier on killed him only to find the
binding unbreakable by any but its creator.
Eventually Nier on escaped and resumed his
bargains transforming Eddie Bloomberg into a
demonic metihuman known as Kid Devil. Nier on's
pact was conditional if Eddie lost faith in blue
devil his soul would be forfeit at age 18. Years
later Eddie discovered blue devils and winning
role in his aunt's death and lost faith fulfilling
Nier on's expectation. War soon erupted in the
underworld when Blaze and Satanus the twin rulers
of purgatory invaded hell promising hope and
redemption to the damned. Nier on rallied his
armies summoning Lilith's monstrous offspring
to his side as victory neared Satanus unleashed a
modified demon plague activated by the word
Shazam. The spell transformed demons into
soulless humans perjuring centuries of devoured
entities from Nier on's body. Script of power he
was beheaded and Blaze usurped her brother to
claim hell's throne. Though dethroned Nier on's
influence persisted through artifacts he had
forged on earth including Ocean Master's Trident
and a get out of hell free card that circulated
among mortals desperate to cheat damnation. In
post flashpoint continuity Nier on claimed
hell's throne after Lucifer abdicated and set his
sights on earth once more. He overthrew Papa
Midnight's operations and repurposed
Midnight's New York City club as a conduit for his
growing influence intent on seizing control of
New York as the first step in conquering the world.
When he trapped both Midnight and John
Constantine in hell Constantine escaped and
dismantled Nier on's plan by exploiting a
loophole in Nier on's own hex forcing the demon
back to his realm. You can learn more about
Constantine in our John Constantine vs brother
voodoo episode. Later Nier on captured the solar
powered hero Apollo and imprisoned him within his
palace baiting his partner Midnighter into hell
for a direct confrontation. Midnighter fought
through demonic hordes and engines of torment to
free Apollo ultimately defeating Nier on in
personal combat and costing Nier on his captive
prize. When the great darkness rose to consume the
multiverse Nier on was among the infernal lords
enslaved to its will forming parts of the dark army
that clashed with the Justice League. After the
heroes severed the darkness's link to reality and
later purged its new host Nier on and the others
were freed from its control. In time Nier on was
dethroned by Raven who restored order to hell
displaced again Nier on resumed his dealings in
the shadows crafting new packs leaving infernal
contracts and searching for the next soul whose
fall might restore his supremacy and that's Nier
on's backstory powers wise Nier on is one of the
most powerful demon lords of hell possessing vast
strength and durability he can manipulate
reality through sorcery unleash hellfire and
eldritch force and assume either a regal humanoid
guise or his true form a green tentacled mass he can
fly teleport and conjure artifacts of immense
power including weapons his defining ability is
contract magic he grants power transformation or
resurrection to mortals in exchange for their
souls within his own realm this power grows
exponentially and he will reform there if slain
making him immortal so is he shumagorath in his
true form not with like the giant eyeball or
anything like that it's more just like a chunky
green mass gross you know hella has a true form as
well if her headdress is ever removed she was
actually born like half dead and half alive so like
half of her is beautiful but the other half is
basically like a zombie that's her true form
interesting she's severely weakened when in that
state so her headdress is her weakness i will take
note yeah nieran's not gonna know that but let me
tell you more about hella in her backstory hella
was mystically born in joenheim the land of the
giants as the daughter of the giantess engerbota
and the trickster god Loki whom you can learn more
about in his duel with aries some myths claim hella
was the offspring of an earlier incarnation of
odin but all accounts agree that she was born half
dead her body split between life and decay as she
came of age odin appointed her the goddess of death
granting her dominion over two of the nine realms
hell the land of the dead and niflheim the land of
eternal mist and shadow cloaked in garments that
concealed her half-rotted massage she appeared
as a darkly beautiful woman when veiled but
beneath the cloak was the withered form of death
itself the garment held Hela held her power and
vitality, without it, she became weak and frail.
Though Hela's role was to guide souls of
Asgardians and their followers to the afterlife,
her ambition soon exceeded her station. She
sought to extend her dominion to Valhalla, the
realm of honored warriors slain in battle, and
longed to claim the souls of Odin and his son Thor.
During one of their earliest encounters, she
appeared before Thor when he offered his own life
to spare Lady Sif, and impressed by his nobility,
Hela allowed them both to live. Yet her
fascination with Thor persisted, often walking
the line between adversary and reluctant
admirer. You can learn more about Thor in his duel
against Wonder Woman. In time, Hela's hunger for
power grew. She stole a fragment of Odin's soul
during his slumber upon the Sea of Eternal Night,
using it to create a cosmic entity called
Infinity. The being nearly unmade existence
before Hela was defeated by Thor's sacrifice and
Odin's intervention. Though Odin slew her to end
her threat, he was persuaded by Thor to resurrect
her, restoring the balance between life and
death. Hela continued to test the gods resolve,
once slaying Thor only to restore him when Sif
offered her own life in his place. When the
monstrous mangog killed Odin, Hela clashed with
Pluto, the Olympian god of death, over the right to
claim Odin's soul. To deny Pluto the victory, she
revived Odin herself. Later, alongside Loki, she
attempted to trigger Ragnarok, the apocalyptic
rebirth of Asgard, by slaying Thor's friend Baldr
and unleashing an army of monsters upon the realm.
Odin thwarted her scheme, but her obsession with
the prophesied end of the gods endured. Hela's
authority was challenged by O'Larris, the
unmerciful and Asgardian military commander who
sought to usurp her throne in Hell. The conflict
drew the attention of the superhero team, the
defenders, who aided her in repelling O'Larris
and restoring order to Valhalla. She later
conspired with Loki and the war god Tyr against
Odin and joined the Hell Lords, Mephisto, Pluto,
and Satanish in merging their netherworlds to
consolidate power. Their union awakened the
god-eater Demogorge, who devoured Hela and the
others before being destroyed by Thor, restoring
her once again. Throughout these eras, Hela's
realm served as both prison and battlefield for
divine souls. She commissioned the construction
of Naglfar, a massive ship built from the
fingernails of the dead intended to carry her army
across the Nine Realms during Ragnarok. Yet
before it could sail, it was destroyed by Scourge,
the executioner who defied her tyranny to save
mortal souls. Hela's repeated attempts to claim
Thor's life culminated when she cursed him so that
his wounds would never heal and his body could
never die. After a brutal battle with the Midgard
serpent left him mangled, Thor entered Hell
within the armor of the destroyer and forced Hela
to lift the curse, restoring his body and trapping
the destroyer in her realm as a warning. Even so,
she continued to meddle with mortal and divine
affairs, at times battling Mephisto for the right
to claim Thor's soul. You can learn more about
Mephisto in his duel against Sandman. When Odin
entered the Odin's sleep, Hela seized the
opportunity to expand her influence, corrupting
the Valkyria and turning them into fire demons.
Among them was Mirage of the new mutants who
rebelled against her queen. With help from the
dwarven King Ytri and the young mutants, Hela's
Uruforge sword called the Night Sword was
destroyed, and Odin was spared. You can learn more
about Mirage and Valkyria in their respective
duels against Aeroet and Powergirl. When
Ragnarok brought about the fall of the Nine
Realms, including Hel in Niflheim, Loki awakened
her in Immortal Guies in Las Vegas. There, she
resumed feeding on human souls and aided Loki in
his schemes. During this period, she attended
councils with Mephisto, Dormammu, and other Hell
Lords, often shifting alliances based on
convenience and survival. Her presence drew the
attention of mutant allies when Mirage sought her
aid in battle, gaining from Hela a sword and steed
that allowed her to defeat Ares. Around the same
time, Hela accepted the soul of Primhari, the Wolf
Prince of Asgard, who bargained his own life to
save his mortal lover and unborn child. After
Asgard was destroyed during an invasion led by
Norman Osborn, whom you can learn more about in our
Joker vs Green Goblin duel, many Asgardian souls
were left without a resting place. With no realm to
claim them, the cursed Valkyries, known as the
Dessir, began feasting on their spirits. Loki
approached Hela with an offer to restore her
dominion. By bargaining with Mephisto, he
granted her a portion of Hell to rule for 1,001
years, forming a new Hell, single L, and saving
countless Asgardian souls from oblivion. In
exchange, Hela erased Loki's name from the books
of Hell, freeing him from his predestined death.
Soon after, the Dessir turned on Hela and attacked
her new domain. In the ensuing battle, her hand was
severed and she was forced to absorb the dead into
her body to shield them. With the aid of Thor and
Tyr, Hela repelled the Dessir, though the
conflict left her weakened. She later made a pact
with Loki and Mephisto during the rise of Odin's
brother, Kul Borson, aka the Serpent, ensuring
her realm's protection and pledging her servants
to Loki's cause. When peace returned, she
regained the true Hell and reclaimed her place as
its ruler. After Loki restored Hela's severed
hand with the power of the Holy Grail, Hela faced
Angela, the lost daughter of Odin and Freya, in
combat. Angela had descended into Hell to free her
lover, Sera, and overcame the Death Goddess. She
seized Hela's crown and took her place as Queen of
Hell, before abdicating the throne to Balder.
Stripped of power and seeking vengeance, Hela
allied herself with Thanos, the Mad Titan,
offering him the one thing he desired most, death
itself, in exchange for his aid in reclaiming her
realm. You can learn more about Thanos and his duel
against Darkseid. Together with the Black Order,
Hela stole into the collector's vault to retrieve
a version of Thor's hammer, Mjolnir, from a dead
universe, only to fail. Returning empty-handed,
Hela slew Proxima midnight before Thanos as proof
of her worth and sealed their alliance with a kiss.
You can learn more about the Black Order in their
duel against Darkseid's elite. However, Hela's
pact with Thanos eventually brought ruin. When
she sought to resurrect him after his death, Hela
succeeded in restoring Thanos' body, but his
consciousness was fractured, his mind left
broken by the failed resurrection. During the
battle against the Guardians of the Galaxy that
followed on nowhere, Hela commandeered a weapon
capable of creating a black hole. Upon firing it,
she was caught in the black hole's collapse,
vanishing alongside Thanos into oblivion. You
can learn more about the Guardians of the Galaxy in
their duel against Doom Patrol. Hela survived the
void and clawed her way back into existence,
reclaiming her throne in Hell. She later joined
forces with Camilla, Queen of the Norns, to defend
the realm from Cinder, Queen of Cinders, during a
war among the realms. For strategic reasons, she
and Balder agreed to a ceremonial marriage,
though Carnilla ultimately bound herself to Hela
in Balder's place, joining the two as reluctant
co-rulers. Together they ruled Hell in an uneasy
alliance. You can learn more about Malekith in his
duel against Eclipso. When the Cult of Null on
Earth attempted to resurrect the Symbiote God,
she seized his weakened form and siphoned his
power, seeking to command the living darkness
itself and seize control of the Symbiotes. You can
learn more about Null in his duel against White
Lantern. And that's her backstory thus far.
Powers-wise, Hela has as Guardian Physiology and
Dark Magic as the Goddess of Death. She has
God-level strength, able to lift over 100 tons.
She can teleport, run over 100 miles per hour, has
vast durability, and is immortal. She can fly,
astral project, cast illusions, manipulate
magical energies into blasts or weapon
constructs that can kill even an Asgardian God.
Her power over life and death can kill others with a
simple touch. She is formidable in hand-to-hand
and weapons combat, particularly with her Night
Sword, which is forged of the same Uru metal that
Thor's Hammer Mjolnir is made of. And that's Hela.
Is there anything special about the Night Sword
besides it being forged from Uru? I mean, she can
kill people with it. That's lame. So it's just a
plain-ass sword? It's a fucking durable-ass
sword, and she has all these other magical
abilities in conjunction with this badass sword.
I mean, kinda. She's basically Nier on. Don't say
that. That's rude. What a rip-off. In a world where
fantasies collide and heroes clash, one podcast
network rises above the rest. Prepare yourself
for the ultimate showdowns in comic books, video
games, movies, and anime. The Dynamite Podcast
Network presents Console Combat, where video
game legends brawl every Monday. Dynamic Duel,
where comic book titans smash every Tuesday. Max
Destruction, where TV and action heroes battle
every Wednesday. And Cendro World, where anime
champions clash every Thursday. Join us as we
speculate on the matches and armed with the power
of mathematical simulations discover who will
emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
Now that we've got their histories and abilities
out of the way, let's speculate on how one of the
1000 simulated matches will go. The winner is
determined by simulations, not the speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how this fight could play
out. AJ9K, what are the rules of our speculation?
Well I should say there are no rules, other than the
characters have no prior knowledge of the other
going into the fight. All they are aware of
starting out is that the other character is a
threat that needs to be eliminated. For the
speculation, the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a non-descript
environment that will have no bearing on the match
itself, as no environmental statistics are
considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. Alright then
let's get into it. Neron and Hela meet on the
battlefield. Who goes first? I think before even
fighting that Neron is probably going to offer
Hela what she's always wanted, a way to obtain
Thor's soul. And to help her with that, he's going
to present her with a black candle that transforms
into a glowing green hammer called, let's say, B.
Olner. And that's like 10 times more powerful than
Mjolnir and it shoots green lightning because
that's cooler. A hammer that's 10 times more
powerful than Mjolnir? Yeah. Well, what happens
if she takes it? What does she give up? That's for
Neron to know and for Hela to not find out until it's
too late. So he's just going to present this as a
present to her? Yeah. I don't deny that she would
probably be tempted by the offer just for that much
power. She'd probably take him up on it actually.
So she grabs the green hammer, Bjolnir, whatever.
She grabs Bjolnir and just wallops the shit out of
Neron with it once she gets it. What an idiot. Okay.
She tries to, but Neron, he's going to go
intangible. So he's just laughing as the hammer
swings through him just time after time. And each
time she swings, that actually is going to drain
Hela's soul, weakening her while Neron gains her
strength. And that was the twist on his offer. The
hammer drains her rather than empowering her. And
with her weakened, that's when he is going to
straight up uppercut her and she's going to go
flying towards the horizon, dropping Bjolnir.
Okay. Well, first of all, Hela knew that some shady
shit was going to go down. Okay. Obviously she's
dealing with the demon, wildswood, your enemy
grant you power. So this was all just a test. Like
she split her soul, a fraction of it off before
taking the hammer. So Neron may have drained like
1% of her soul's power, but she has power to spare.
So instead of getting knocked to the horizon, when
Neron hits her, her body just explodes into a huge
flock of crows. That just fly back together again
and they're going to reform back into Hela with 99%
of her soul intact. Wait, wait, she can split her
soul? Yeah. She's done it quite a few times in the
comics. Oh, it's like a Horcrux thing. Uh, no, not
really. Okay. Well, Neron's probably pissed that
his bargain backfired. We'll say that with the
contract avoided, Bjolnir is just going to melt
like candle wax. That's fine. Hela didn't need the
hammer. She has her own night sword. So she's going
to manifest it in her hand and she just flies
forward lunging at Neron and just running the
sword right through his torso. Oh dang. Okay. So
Neron is impaled by the night sword, but these
green flames are going to be flicking out of the
sword's entry and exit points because Neron's
hate is so hot that it's going to cause the night
sword to burn Hela's hand. That's going to force
her to let go of it. And that's when Neron's going to
pull out the sword from his torso and he's going to
imbue her weapon with sentience, transforming it
into this Uru armored hell knight that starts
attacking Hela with its sword arms. Okay. A
sentient sword hell knight. Hela's going to block
the hell knight's attacks with a magic eldritch
shield, but then she summons her own warrior, this
giant spider from her realm of hell. Think like
Shalob from Return of the King. That spider
actually serves as a warden in her realm and the
spider's going to web up this hell knight so that it
can't even use its swords. Okay. Well, I mean, if
Hela's going to start conjuring beings from her
realm, Neron, he's going to summon the four
horsemen of the apocalypse and they're going to
circle this giant spider on their horses and just
stab it to death before charging Hela and doing the
same. No, except Hela has her own steed and she
rises up on it. It's this 15 foot tall wolf, Fenris
wolf, who's just going to pounce on these tiny ass
horsemen and rip them apart just like how a wolf
would do to a herd of baby deer. Oh, you think Fenris
is big? Yeah. Neron's going to mount a fucking
giant 50 foot dragon that's going to blast Fenris
and Hela with a blast of green hellfire just
disintegrating them. Fenris will be fine. Hela
leaps off of him so the wolf gets the brunt of the
blast. He has a healing factor, but Hela summons a
group of giant rock trolls from hell and their skin
are like immune to fire, right? And they just beat
the dragon to death and Neron with their rock clubs
and axes. Okay. Well, like Hela, Neron's going to
leap off the dragon before he's also attacked and
he's going to cause these iron chains like burning
with green flame to shoot up from the ground and
wrap around the rock trolls and Hela, pulling them
down into hell where they'll be trapped and
tormented for eternity. That's ending this
match. So Hela's in hell, Neron's hell. So what she
does then is she's going to summon the souls from
her hell into Neron's hell. And because the
Asgardians are all badasses with more strength
and fighting skill than Neron's weak ass souls,
Hela and her undead army kill all the souls in
Neron's hell and so he gets weakened and then
killed. I mean, I've got to have strength in
numbers, you'd think. Doesn't matter, even if
that's the case, as guardians are badass Vikings.
I mean, all the real badasses went to Valhalla
though. So Hela's squad is the JV team. It'll be
enough. It'll be enough. A great disagree. We'll
leave it there. Either the souls in Neron's hell
overpower the souls in Hela's hell or vice versa.
Let's go ahead and input the stats on these two
characters, run the simulations and come back
with a winner. AJ9K, hit it. Inputting data,
running calculations, processing results,
simulations complete. All right, I thought last
week was a good matchup. This matchup between
Neron and Hela, I think, is even better. These guys
are so close. Like, they're the same when it comes
to speed and invasiveness, damage level, range
and versatility, but they had enough differences
to make things interesting. Yeah, we said that
Neron is slightly more perceptive because he can
see a person's desires and that's what he exploits
in his bargains with them. Yeah, we also said that
makes him smarter because he's a little bit more
crafty and cunning in that regard. But we said that
Hela was not only a better fighter, but she was also
better physically in terms of durability and
strength because while Neron does have demon
physiology, the dude lost to Midnighter and when
he goes up against foes like Superman, his
strength is often bolstered through magic. Yeah,
so between the differences in their brains and
brawn, they were able to cancel each other out for a
truly even match. So taking all of these stats into
consideration, Joseph, who do you think is coming
out on top? Hela. You would. Well, Instagram
wouldn't. I'm guessing largely because you got
the poll up Hela late because Neron is beating Hela
65% to 35% in that poll, meaning more people think
that Neron's going to win. It's okay to be wrong
though. That's surprising. I did not see that
coming. I was pretty confident Hela was going to
get the popularity vote. Yeah, me too. Well, let's
find out who's correct. AG9K, the results please.
Here you are, sir. The winner of the matchup
between Neron and Hela is Hela. Oh yeah, baby. Me by
51.4% or 514 of the 1000 matches compared to
Neron's 48.6%. Wow, that's almost a coin toss.
That is a coin toss. Considering the way they
differed in stats, I'm surprised it came out to be
this close. Well, like I said, they kind of evened
each other out when it came to brains and brawn.
Usually a win rate lower than 52.5% of the matches I
consider a coin toss where if you ran another 1000
simulations, you might get a different result
because it's just that close. But let's not do
that. I mean, we could. But let's not. Fine.
Congrats to Hela. Congrats to the Marvel fans.
We're on a streak now, guys. It's been a while. A
streak of two. That's not a streak. It's a streak,
baby. We're just going to keep it rolling. Keep it
rolling all the way into January. That does it for
this dual episode. H.A .9K, help close this up.
Thanks for listening to Dynamic Dual. Visit the
show's website at dynamicdual.com and follow us
on Instagram at Dynamic Dual podcast. You can
support the show on Patreon at patreon.com slash
dynamicdual and joining a tier that works for you
or by rating and reviewing Dynamic Dual on Apple
podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser or on our website.
Don't forget to listen to the other shows in the
Dynamite podcast network, including Max
Destruction, Senjo World and Console Combat. In
our next episode, which is dropping days before
Halloween, we are going to bring you a special
spooky episode where we pit the House of Mystery
against the Crypt of Shadows. Yeah, this is a
special dual request. It's going to be a team duel
between seven supernatural and mystic users from
DC and Marvel. But we're going to tie in some like
tales of the crypt goodness in there. It'll be a lot
of fun. But that does it for this episode. We want to
give a big thanks to our executive producers, John
Starosky, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Belcom,
Mickey Methegien, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yatyn,
Austin Wieselowski, AJ Dunkerley, Nick Ibonto,
Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Spees, Dean
Maleski, Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, Mike
Williams and Paul Graves for helping make this
podcast possible. We'll talk to you guys next
week. Up, up and away. True believers.