This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi and welcome
to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe and I'm his twin
brother Johnny DC. And in this episode we are going
to review the very first DC Universe film,
Superman. Hell yeah we are, heck yeah we are. Calm
down, calm down. Right off the bat Jonathan,
you're gonna fucking annoy me this whole episode I
already know I just want to let you know that you
need to just be normal. I mean if we were reviewing
Iron Man for the first time would you be calm? I
would not but how dare you compare this movie to
Iron Man. Oh I'll compare it to Endgame. What did I
just say about annoying me? What did I just say?
We're gonna review the movie and talk all about
spoilers so hopefully you've seen the movie.
Before we do that we're gonna break down the latest
comic book movie news that came up this past week
which there was none. So really we're just gonna do
the upfront stuff and then get right into the
review. As always we list our segment times in our
episode description so feel free to check out the
show notes if you want to skip ahead to a particular
topic. Guys our artificially intelligent dual
simulator AJ9K has a quick message for our
listeners so listen up. Thanks AJ9K and thanks to
everyone who supports the podcast. Be sure to tune
into the other shows in the DynaMic Podcast
Network this week including the console combat
podcast where hosts John and Dean simulate
battles between popular video game characters.
In yesterday's episode they determined who would
win between Banjo Kazooie and Yuka Laylee. Over on
the Max Destruction podcast hosts Scotty and
Gilly pit your favorite action heroes from film
and television against each other. This week
they'll be finding out who would win between Alice
from Resident Evil and Selene from Underworld.
And on the Senjo World podcast hosts Zachary
Hepburn speculates on fights between fan
favorite anime and manga characters. In his next
episode Zach's going to reveal who would win
between Sasuke Ichihara from Naruto and Uryuu
Ishida from Bleach. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com
or click the link in our show notes to listen to all
of the shows in the DynaMic Podcast Network. But
with that out of the way, quick to the no prize. A no
prize is an award that Marvel used to give out to
fans. Our version, the Dynamic Dual No Prize is a
digital award that we've put on Instagram for the
person that we feel gave the best answer to our
question of the week. Last week we asked, for those
of you who have seen Superman in its opening
weekend, what did you think? Hey we got a few
answers so let's go ahead and run down our
honorable mentions as well as the no prize winner.
Our first honorable mention goes to Brandon
Estregard who said. Hey guys just wanted to say
congratulations to Team Marvel. You guys really
nailed it as the Reddit posting monkeys in the
movie. Roll Oscar worthy stuff. Great job guys. Oh
man you would not believe the casting process I had
to undergo for the role of the Reddit posting
monkeys. Man, I went full method with it and was
just hoping that that's what they would want from a
performance and luckily everything came through
and I got the role. I was the one that was posting
super shit in the movie. Let me guess you flung your
poo at the casting director. That's how I got the
role actually. Yeah, for those who are missing
context on what we're talking about in the
Superman movie this isn't too much of a spoiler.
Lex Luthor trained a bunch of monkeys to talk shit
about Superman on the internet. Which is
basically my full time job on our Discord server.
There were a lot of funny scenes in the Superman
movie and that has to be in the top five. I was
cracking up at the monkey scene. Thanks for the
answer Brandon. Our next honorable mention goes
to Alex Albro. Who said? Hey guys, I thought it was
great. Rated at 9.5. My wife rated at 8. Just really
good Superman show. I'm excited to see where they
go with the Hall of Justice and the Justice Gang or
Justice League or whatever they end up being. We
really liked them. Mr. Terrific was great. I think
Nicholas Holt really stole the show. It was Lex
Luthor for me and I'm just excited to see where it
goes. It was a nice surprise to see Millie Alcock as
Supergirl at the end and Crypto was great and
overall just a good way to end the weekend. Thanks
guys. Okay, that is actually a spoiler but if
you're on social media it's already been spoiled
for you. There's been news articles about
Supergirl showing up and yeah, her cameo did not
disappoint. I totally agree with Alex, Lex
Luthor, Mr. Terrific, the Justice Gang. All of it
was great as I will expand upon in our review. Let's
see, Alex gave it a 9.5 out of 10 which on a five star
scale equates to four and three quarter stars.
Let's see what Matt from Texas rated it. Hey guys,
Matt from Texas here. Superman 4 out of 5 was a great
film. It had a little bit of issues, camera angles,
some pacing, stuff like that, mostly minor but all
the actors did really well. David Cornswet as
Superman was fantastic. This is what Superman is.
Colorful, helps everybody, you know, does the
right thing. He is a Boy Scout and that's exactly
what he portrayed in this film. Yeah, Superman
needs to be redefined for a new generation every
once in a while. I'm not quite sure that Henry
Cavill find the character of Superman back in the
20's in the same way that Cornswet has now defined
the character for modern times. Yeah, he did a
fantastic job. Although as Matt says the movie's
not perfect, there are issues but they are minor, I
would agree. So great answer Matt. We want to give a
quick shout out to CJ Kraft for taking the time to
visit our website and record an answer but the
winner of this week's No Price is Scott Camacho and
his daughter Rena. Who said? Hi, I'm Scotty Macho.
Hi, I'm Rena Macho. And we are? The Machos. We just
watched the Superman movie. That's how you do a
Superman movie. That was awesome. I don't care
about his outfit though, I still don't like his
outfit but that is how you do a Superman movie.
Rena, what did Supergirl say? I'm thankful for
watching my dog bitch. Oh my gosh. Yeah, again that
Supergirl scene was great. I've seen a lot of flak
for it online because I think a lot of people
haven't read Supergirl Woman of Tomorrow but it
was straight from that comic. Yeah, it's
definitely a unique take on the character who's
typically portrayed as similar to her cousin in
terms of demeanor and stuff like that. So yeah,
Millie Elcock's Supergirl is probably at a left
field for a lot of people. Honestly, the whole
reason we gave this no prize win to Scott and Rena is
because it was hilarious. Jonathan, how old were
your daughters when you heard them say their first
curse word? I think my younger daughter Faith once
said piss not realizing it was a bad word. I can't
remember how old she was though. Is piss a bad word?
I think so. I told her not to say it again. I'm
horrified that my two-year-old any day now is
going to start saying fuck out of the blue because I
say it way too much in front of her. Yeah, you have
this podcast running in the background and all of a
sudden fuck DC. I'd be so proud. I'd be so proud. For
a great answer, Scotty and Rena, you guys win this
week's no prize. If you, the listener, want to
shout out winning your own no prize, stay tuned to
later on this episode when we'll be asking another
question of the week. And now that that's done,
onto the question of the week. What the high
praises that most audience members seem to be
giving Superman, the odds of it getting a sequel
are really high. So with that in mind, what do you
want the sequel to the Superman movie to be about?
Yeah, what do you want the story to be about? What
characters do you want to see in it? Who do you want
the villain to be? Let us know. Record your answer
at dynamicdool.com by clicking on the red
microphone button in the bottom right hand corner
of the screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long and don't forget to leave your name in case we
include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a dynamic
dual no prize that will pose to Instagram. Be sure
to answer before July 18th. But let's go ahead and
get into the main event of this episode where we
reviewed DC Studios first feature length film,
Superman. OK, Superman, written and directed by
DC Studios head James Gunn, is the first
theatrical film to be released under the DC
Studios banner, as well as the first film to be set
in DC's new cinematic universe known as the DCU. A
gun was hired by Warner Brothers to launch a new DC
cinematic universe after the prior one
established in 2013's Man of Steel failed to match
the box office success of the rival Marvel
Studios. Despite Gunn's prior success writing
and directing Marvel's Guardians of the Galaxy
franchise, as well as DC's The Suicide Squad and
Peacemaker Projects, I was initially conflicted
when I learned that he was writing and directing
the first film in DC's new cinematic universe
because I wasn't sure his raunchy yet heartfelt
comedic style of filmmaking would work for a
character like Superman. A notoriously raunchy
character. What? No. Now, with each new trailer
that was released for this film, my expectations
grew to the point where I was actually a little
depressed that Superman wasn't going to be able to
live up to my expectations. But to my surprise, the
film hit my expectations dead center. And I'm
actually proud of this new start to DC's cinematic
universe. I'm still thinking about the film days
after seeing it. And for anyone interested in
seeing the movie that hasn't already, be aware
that this is a spoiler review. So you should stop
listening now so you could go into the movie fresh.
Yeah, I feel like there's too many people out there
who are willing to spoil themselves, just
claiming that it doesn't affect them. But you are
doing yourself a disservice, whether you admit to
it or not. Seeing something unfold on the big
screen for the first time without prior knowledge
is absolutely the best way to experience these
stories. Yes, totally an experience, especially
this film on the IMAX screen. It was incredible. I
saw it on a really big screen on a RPX theater. And I
wasn't aware at the time that I had actually
purchased RPX tickets. So I walk into the
auditorium and I'm sitting way too fucking close
to the screen. That's all I thought. I was like, God
damn, this screen is too big. I'm going to have to
like lean back in my chair to really enjoy this. But
did you enjoy it? The movie overall? Yeah, I did.
Yeah, I think I have a few gripes with it, but they
are largely nitpicky bullshit that had more to do
with my own subjective feelings about world
building and traditional story structures and
anything really substantial. OK, I could see that
and we'll get into that later. But I actually think
that this is James Gunn's best superhero film yet,
or at least his most mature, because here he was
focused on reimagining characters through his
usual quirky lens. He instead set out to show how
radical true righteousness and unconditional
kindness can be in a world of moral relativism. The
film's whole thesis is that in a cynical,
distrustful society, simply choosing to trust
and see the good in others becomes the ultimate act
of rebellion. And with that simple, yet profound
idea, Gunn somehow made Superman cooler than he's
been in maybe a century. And it just transformed
him for this film into a countercultural icon
while staying true to his spirit. It turns out that
you don't need to reinvent a classic character to
fit the current zeitgeist. You just need society
to shift enough that the forgotten philosophies
of the past feel bold and new again, no neck
snapping required. I agree with you partly in
that, yeah, being kind is cool, but I'm not going to
say that Superman is countercultural. I wouldn't
go that far. I would say more so in this film than he
has maybe ever been. Because you think society at
the current moment is so cynical that this type of
thinking is radical. I think radical is a strong
word. I'm sorry, are you not on social media? Do not
look at comments. I think it's radical. I think
it's more appreciated now, more than ever. I think
this was a better way to adapt the character for
modern times than the whole dark and serious
approach that Zack Snyder took. That's totally
valid. Yeah. Now, I loved Man of Steel and I've been
a staunch defender of its sci-fi approach to the
Superman lore. But if I'm being honest, after
seeing Superman and its more faithful
interpretation of the character, it makes Man of
Steel feel somewhat like an Elseworld tale, like
still interesting. But definitely a departure
from who the character actually is. And that's not
to say that this depiction of Superman was
perfect. He's much more pouty and easily agitated
in this film than he is in, say, the comics. But the
fact that he would go out of his way to save babies
and dogs and even squirrels is in sharp contrast to
the criticisms of apathy leveled at the Zack
Snyder's take on the character. Right. Apathy,
because we saw Metropolis essentially destroyed
at the nuclear level in the Man of Steel movie
without seeing Superman handle a lot of the
civilian saving duties of his role. Right. The Man
of Steel version of Superman is very much an
objectivist take, which focuses on the self and
selfishness, which is why you had, you know, pot
can't say, OK, maybe you don't save those kids. And
while you had my can't saying, you don't owe anyone
anything. This take on Superman is very much at
odds with that. And it was pretty refreshing. Now,
where I work, we have a saying that we shouldn't
make perfect the enemy of good. And I largely feel
that way about James Gunn's approach to Superman,
which was a really good interpretation. What was
perfect, however, in my opinion, were his takes on
Superman's supporting cast, particularly Lex
Luthor. Now, Lex has never been done right on film.
He was always supposed to be a mad scientist type
character that could invent challenges for
Superman that were essentially unfathomable for
anyone else. Portrayals from Gene Hackman or
Kevin Spacey lacked the scientist aspect of the
character, while Jesse Eisenbergs was a little
too mad, even getting comparisons to the Joker.
But Gunn's version not only involved a real estate
scheme, but also incorporated nanites, cloning,
international politics and even a freaking
pocket universe. There is so much Silver Age ask
shenanigans going on here. And it was really cool
to see how unapologetically Gunn showcased his
love for that era of comics. Yeah, the film's plot
at times got a little bit bonkers. And a lot of that
has to do with Lex's pocket dimension
shenanigans. They took the story places that I
didn't think they were going to go literally. Oh,
yeah. Like, for example, the trash talking
monkeys that we talked about earlier. Yeah, once
you go to trash talking monkeys online, you could
go literally anywhere. There were just these
really idiosyncratic ideas that are a trademark
of James Gunn's that I wasn't quite sure fit in the
realm of Superman as much as, like, say, Guardians
of the Galaxy or something like that. But it was
nice that Gunn was able to put his stamp on the
project in that way, because it did feel very
Silver Age and therefore did communicate a love
for the very comic booky version of Superman,
which is something that we haven't really seen
from the character on the big screen. And it's
pretty fun. There's a lot of fun to be had with
Superman that we haven't gotten in a long time. I
was actually surprised by how much fun I had
actually, because typically I like a serious
approach to my superhero films. I don't like it
when it gets goofball. And while this went
interesting places like you mentioned bonkers,
it never felt goofy to me. You know, between it felt
at times a little bit goofy. What? When? With
crypto? Oh, I'm sorry. What do you have against
crypto? I'm going to state right off the bat. I
don't like crypto. I thought he was annoying in
this movie. Every time he was not on the screen, I
was relieved. Crypto was a total scene stealer
that everyone loved. You are on the wrong side of
history. Die your head in shame. I think crypto is a
scene stealer, but in the wrong way. No, dude, I
loved crypto. Like, I actually have no notes on
crypto in my review. I just loved him. He was too
chaotic. And every time he was brought into the
story yet, it kind of detracted, I think, from the
pot. No, there were times where he felt a little bit
deus ex machina e. And overall, the concept was
just goofy. I think actually the film would have
been better if he wasn't included. I don't think he
was entirely necessary. I think he was included
just for merchandising or something. I don't know
to add a cute element to the movie. I could actually
see that, especially with the mid credit scene how
it left off with like this super, super cute moment
between Superman and crypto, just having
probably a majority of audiences leave with that
final moment, I think was perhaps a little
manipulative. And maybe his appearance in the
film overall is a little manipulative. But I was
totally sold on it. Crypto was one of my favorite
aspects of this movie. And I totally couldn't see
it being as successful without him. I definitely
could. Well, you don't know what the hell you're
talking about, you dog hater. I love dogs. I have a
dog. I love my dog. I love this dog. Fuck this guy.
But I don't love crypto. He's kind of a dickhead and
I'm not ashamed to say it. Hey, bad dogs deserve
love, too, bro. Not bad dogs who are also just made
out of pixels. I don't care about them. No, crypto
felt real to me. I didn't feel like he was made of
pixels. I thought they did a really good job with
this CG. And actually, the CG throughout the whole
film, I thought, was a lot better than I've seen in a
lot of films as of late. Every time those crypto
pixels appeared on the screen, I just wanted to
kick them right out of the movie. The hell is wrong
with you? Now, between Lex Luthor's hijinks and
the powers of Mr. Terrific Guy Gardner and
Metamorpho and I guess crypto, there are some deep
cuts in this film that we've never seen on the big
screen before. And the fact that Gunn wasted no
time explaining any of it, literally starting
this universe three years into Superman's
career, but still having audiences beyond board
with the film, I think is a testament not only to how
strong of a filmmaker James Gunn is and to his level
of respect for the audience, but also to how much of
a cultural icon Superman is still to this day.
Absolutely, yeah. I mean, Superman needs no
introduction. Everybody already knows him,
which is probably why James Gunn was able to put
audiences in the deep end in this new DC universe
that he created. It's one of the more unsatisfying
aspects of the film, though, in my mind. Superman
is like if the Avengers movie was the very first MCU
film in that it would still be good and enjoyable,
but it lacks the foundation that prior world
building films would have set up. The most world
building we got for this new DC universe were like
six lines of text at the very beginning of the film
that is basically saying many humans have been
around for a while. Superman introduced himself
to the world like three years ago. Let's get the
story started. I actually thought that was a
brilliant piece of world building. It was almost
like Star Wars ask the way you were kind of thrown
into that universe with just the opening crawl.
Yeah, I mean, I can't knock this approach too much
because I understand why James Gunn did it. No one
wants to see Superman's origin again because
we've seen it a lot. Whether it was in the Donner
film or the Man of Steel film, everybody knows that
Superman was a baby who was sent from Krypton. And
we even got references to that in this movie. So his
backstory is essentially established. I guess
what felt hollow to me were like the other
supporting metahumans that just kind of exist in
this world without a whole lot of setup. In a
perfect world, each of these characters would
have had the chance to live and breathe on their
own. But again, I understand, you know, how many
different superhero films have come out in the
past couple of decades? We're at the point now
where you can drop people in the deep end and they
won't feel like they're drowning because they
understand what these movies are about and
largely who these characters already are. I agree
and I could see where you're coming from, although
I would argue wouldn't that mean that characters
like Obi-Wan Kenobi and Han Solo and Darth Vader
would have also needed some project that you would
have seen them in prior to Star Wars? Yes and no. And
I'm trying to articulate what felt slightly
unsatisfying about the film. I think the reason
characters like Obi-Wan Kenobi and Han Solo
worked in a movie like A New Hope where you're
dropped into this world and introduced to these
characters largely without context is because a
movie like A New Hope followed a very traditional
storytelling structure wherein being
introduced to the characters at the point they
enter the script felt organic and you didn't feel
like you were missing context because you were
still being introduced to the world. Here in the
Superman movie, the storytelling structure is
not traditional. There is no three act structure
here. It feels very episodic. It feels very much
like a comic book series. That's to its credit and
to its detriment, I think. When I say to its credit,
I mean because the plot of the film is very much
unlike what audiences are used to seeing from
these stories on the screen. And therefore it
feels new and unique. When I say the structures to
its detriment is because it makes the story feel a
little off in general. I could see that, you know,
with the amount of stuff thrown at Superman in this
movie. The film felt longer to me than it actually
was, though not at all in a bad way. Like, I was
surprised that this movie was only about two hours
long when so much happened in the film. The film's
pacing definitely moves forward at a steady clip,
particularly in its second half, where it
seemingly feels like there's climax after climax
after climax. It's like, what? Superman's about
to fall into a black hole. What? Bravian and Jarhan
Perr are going to war. What? Metropolis is being
torn in half. What? There's Kryptonite. What?
He's joining in that night. What? There's a clone
in much the same way that Batman was very
reactionary to the Joker in The Dark Knight or the
Riddler in The Batman. The ultimate stakes set up
by the film's antagonist aren't revealed to the
hero until after their plans have already been set
in motion. So there's no telling just how far the
villain is willing to take things for the hero or
the audience. Typically in a three act structure,
audiences are made aware of the ultimate stakes of
the film between the end of the first act in the
middle of the film. You know, that's when we see
Alderaan blow up. That's when we learn what the
matrix is. That's when Frodo is straight up
stabbed and nearly killed. But the primary
conflict of this film seems to be will Superman
embrace his Kryptonian destiny or remain true to
his humanity rather than will Metropolis be
destroyed and actually thought that was a
fascinating approach. But speaking of
characterizations, let's move into our
character breakdown. Starting with Superman
slash Clark Kent, who was played by David Corrent
sweat. Now, his performance is extremely sincere
and extremely likeable. I mentioned in our review
of The Batman that Robert Pattinson brought more
interest to the character of Bruce Wayne than any
actor before him. And I'd say the same for Corrent
sweat. Again, I'd say the characterization isn't
necessarily perfect. My ideal Superman
personally is actually pretty stoic. But I do see
the appeal in Corrent sweat's performance, who
definitely puts the man in Superman more than
anyone before him on the big screen. He's
definitely a more humanized character than like
Henry Cavill, right? You talk a lot about the
appeal of DC comic books over Marvel in that DC
comics are a lot more iconic and more legend like
than Marvel comic books, whose characters are a
lot more relatable. Given that I feel like this
version of Superman in this movie is more Marvel
like than any previous adaptation of the
character. How do you feel about that? You know, it
is what it is. I wouldn't disagree with you. It's
again, not necessarily my favorite version of how
the character is portrayed because, you know, I
don't necessarily need my mythical characters
like Hercules, for example, to have so much of a
personality. But it doesn't hurt as long as they
stay true to the essence of the character, which I
100 percent believe they did in this film. I'll let
it slide. You closet Marvel fan. What? No, I knew
it. No way. Now, Superman begins the film as this
embodiment of unwavering optimism. A figure so
committed to seeing the good in others and
protecting life that it strains his relationship
with the American public and even his
relationship with Lois Lane, when Lois
essentially accuses him of being naive, pointing
out that while she questions everyone and
everything, he's eager to trust and see beauty in
everyone he meets. His reply that may be trust and
kindness are the real punk rock reveals the moral
steadfastness at the heart of his character.
Clark's unwavering faith in humanity isn't just
his greatest strength. It's what makes him
potentially more human than anyone else. I think
the scene that this clicked the most for me was when
he was in Lois's apartment and the Justice Gang
were fighting. I think that was Mixed Spitalik in
the background. Yeah, weird, huh? Superman
called him a dimensional imp. But that was a great
scene as far as characterization goes. And when he
says that he's going to turn himself in knowingly
going into a trap for the sake of this dog, who he
doesn't even particularly like just because it's
the right thing to do, says a lot about his
character. And Lois realized that. And that's
when she planted a big old smooch on him just for
being a good guy. Yeah, that was a fantastic scene.
I loved that scene. Although I thought it was in
Clark's apartment, not Lois's. Was it? I don't
know. Now, Superman's moral foundation was
shaken to its core when he learned what the full
message from his Kryptonian parents was,
essentially that they intended him to dominate
and repopulate Earth rather than uplift it.
Reeling from this seeming betrayal, Clark
confronts a painful question of identity. Is he
the benevolent protector he always believed he
was? Or is he a harbinger of conquest? In a tender
moment with Jonathan Kent, his adoptive father,
he's reminded that his actions, not his origins,
define him and its Clark's choices, his failures
and the courage to keep stepping forward, despite
those failures, that shape who he truly is. By the
end of the film, as he faces Lex Luthor and is called
an alien, Clark delivers the gist, essentially of
his arc, that his humanity, along with Lex's and
everyone else's, is everyone's greatest
strength when they're able to recognize that
humanity in each other. Yeah, it's so fantastic.
Such a fantastic message. I freaking loved it. I
freaking loved this movie. What do you think,
though, about the alleged message from Jor-El and
Lara about Superman's purpose being the
domination of planet Earth? That was a twist. I did
not see that coming. That was actually really
interesting. And I don't mind it, honestly. Like,
it's definitely a deviation from what we know
about the characters in the comics, and it's
almost kind of sacrilegious in that way. Yeah, my
head cannon is that Lex is lying. And no matter how
many times they keep saying in the movie that it's
the true translation, I don't really buy it
because it's so perfectly fit Lex's agenda. That
could be the case. And I love that the movie kind of
leaves it up to interpretation. For anyone upset
by the implication, you have to remember that this
is coming from Lex Luthor, who's not a trustworthy
source, especially when he could easily create
new video footage with the engineer. Now, through
his journey, Superman doesn't just save the
world. He reclaims his place within it, embodying
a radical kind of hope. His arc is a reminder that
being human isn't about where you come from, but
about choosing kindness and having courage.
Again, fantastic arc, fantastic angle for the
character. And I'm really glad that James Gunn was
smart enough to kick off this cinematic universe
with this approach for Superman. Now, what did you
think about the suit? Well, as listeners know from
this podcast, when the suit was first revealed, I
didn't really like it. I've been largely
ambivalent since I don't like the texture of the
suit. I don't love the design. That being said, it
hardly registered with me in the course of the
film. I don't hate it. It definitely grew on me as
well, I would say. I was thrilled about it at the
beginning, but this has kind of become, I would
say, my favorite Superman outfit, even though I
would have preferred something with a more
traditional logo just to put a more iconic stamp on
the suit. I think it really worked for this movie.
The best Superman suit is the one from Superman and
Lois, the TV show. Maybe. Again, I don't need like
the abs. Why do I need to see your abs, you know? To
make me feel bad, is that what you're trying to do?
So he can communicate that he could kick your ass
without having to say it out loud. I mean, I feel
like the symbol on the chest should do that. But you
see Superman's abs in the comic books. I don't
necessarily think you need to. All right. Moving
on to Lois Lane, she was played by Rachel
Brosnahan. Now I called it from the very
beginning. She was going to be the most perfect
Lois Lane to date on screen. And I was right. She
freaking nailed it. I loved her
characterization. I loved her performance.
Mwah, Chef's kiss. Yeah, she was fantastic. She
was definitely more like the comic book character
of Lois Lane than any other iteration I think we've
seen on the big screen thus far. Yeah, 100 percent.
She was true to character as the ultimate skeptic
that she is. She's this sharp, relentless,
investigative journalist who questions
everything and everyone, including the man she
loves. After Superman's controversial
intervention in Baravia, she openly questions
not just the ethics of his actions, but the very
foundation of their relationship. For Lois,
trust is earned, never given blindly. Her
instinct is to push back against power, even when
that power belongs to Superman. And that makes her
a really strong and independent character, which
she's always been in the comics. Yet, despite her
doubts in this film, she alone refuses to believe
Superman has any hidden agenda to repopulate
Earth with Kryptonians because she knows and
trusts Clark in a way that no one else does.
Throughout the film, Lois' arc is about
confronting her own fear of vulnerability and
learning to see the humanity beneath Superman's
invincibility. By the end, she realizes that
beneath the cape is the same man who had a mighty
crab joist poster in a smallville bedroom, a man
whose open heart and unwavering faith in others
aren't weaknesses, but proof of his shared
humanity. And choosing to stand by him and profess
her love, she overcomes her fears, embracing the
idea that love, despite all the differences and
uncertainties, is worth it. The character of Lois
Lane is usually portrayed as a damsel in distress
in her history in comic books and film, which never
quite sat well with me because she has such agency
as a character and is really smart or supposed to
be, you know. And I really like how this film chose
to use that agency and that intelligence to have
her go and seek out resources and help save
Superman. Right, exactly. They definitely do not
go with the traditional version of Lois Lane that
needs to be saved. She's the one that does the
saving in this film, which is fantastic and maybe
different from what we're used to seeing with the
character. But I never once for a second thought
that this version was not true to character
because of that. What did you think of the romance
between the characters of Lois and Superman here?
They definitely went a different route in that
Lois is in the dark on Superman's alter ego. So I
like the fact that right off the bat, they know who
each other are. And really, there shouldn't be a
long period of time between Lois's discovery of
Clark Kent being Superman because of how smart she
is and how inquisitive she is. But that doesn't
mean that they're automatically like head over
heels and love with each other. I actually thought
it was really interesting that Lois Lane would not
be sure And yeah, she probably believed Superman
to be naive, but she also found the good guy
qualities about him to be endearing because they
had the strength of character and the strength in
general to boot. And she understood that kindness
is not weakness. Yeah, especially when you're as
strong as Superman. Moving on to Lex Luthor, he was
played by Nicholas Holt. Like Brosnahan, I
thought Holt's performance as Lex is the best to
date. His pettiness and overall emotionality
makes more sense to me than it does for someone like
Superman because Lex, as the film explicitly
says, is essentially the embodiment of envy. And I
have suspect that Holt's performance was so good
because he actually auditioned for the role of
Superman in this film, but lost the role to
Corenswet. Oh, for sure. He can easily identify
with Lex's envy in that way. That's a great point.
And I really like how this movie brought about the
theme of envy for Lex and the idea that he admitted
to it and leaned into that was kind of profound for
the character I felt. Yeah, absolutely. Like he's
intelligent enough to recognize his own faults in
a way, but also justify them. It's interesting.
Now, this film, Lex orchestrates this complex
array of schemes that includes cloning Superman
into Ultraman, manipulating global politics by
arming Baravia, inciting war for profit,
creating a pocket universe prison, engineering
villains, and even fostering public distrust
against Superman. His schemes are part
selfishness, part pettiness, and they reflect
his dual nature of his unparalleled genius yet
deep rooted in security. Lex's motivation in the
film explicitly is pure undiluted envy. He admits
that envy consumes him and that he cannot stomach
humanity's idolization of Superman because it
highlights humanity's collective weakness and
his own perceived undeserved inadequacy. His
rage isn't just about hating Superman. It's about
proving that humanity doesn't need gods or
saviors, that human intellect and willpower such
as his alone should define the future. Through his
obsession, Lex becomes something of a tragic
figure, a genius so terrified of his own
insignificance that he would rather destroy the
world than see it uplifted by an alien and foreign
ideal. He's a profound character that nothing
nailed him in this movie. Absolutely. And
admitting his whole weakness of envy thing,
because of that self-interestpection, he was
able to dive deeper into the why of his being and the
whole philosophy behind that, which I think is
incredibly profound when a character can speak to
their own truth like that. Oh, totally. I feel like
it came away from this film understanding Lex in a
way that I never really have before. A lot of the
characters even, including Superman. Yeah,
there's a lot of characters in this film. I just
wanted to touch on those three specifically, but
the roster is huge, including Jimmy Olsen, who was
played by Skyler Gizondo, who I thought nailed the
character, even though his depiction as a pussy
magnet. That exactly was, I think, unique to the
character, but I thought it worked really well for
this story. It was funny. He was one of many Daily
Planet cast members. Not all of them worked, I
felt. I felt they were largely background noise.
Yeah, really the only one that stood out to me was
Beck Bennett as Steve Lombard, but even with him,
I'm not sure why he was included in Mr. Terrific's
hovercraft towards the end, or really any of the
other Daily Planet staff other than Perry White,
Jimmy Olsen, and Lois Lane. I don't want to say the
cast was overstuffed, but there were definitely
some superfluous characters. For sure. Of
course, there was also the roster of the Justice
Gang, which I don't love the name of Justice Gang,
I'll be honest. I think it eventually will be
Justice League, just based on trailers from
Peacemaker Season 2. But if it were up to me, I would
actually prefer Maxwell Lord's team to sort of
segue into a Justice Society. I don't understand
why they wouldn't just call them the Justice
League to begin with. Like, why circumvent the
formation of the Justice League in this way? I
don't know if that has to do with the fact that
Superman, Batman, and Wonder Woman are not
involved in it, or maybe the fact that they're
being somewhat indecisive this early on in the
universe, as to whether they want it to be the
Justice League or Justice Society. Who knows, I
did not care for it though. I'm on Team Hawk Girl in
that instance. Except Hawk Girl kind of sucked in
this movie, played by Isabella Merced. Yeah, I did
not like her characterization at all. Way too much
screaming for no reason. She didn't do nearly
enough damage to the kaiju with her mace. She
basically just tapped the fucking thing. And I was
like, okay. You think hitting it in the eyeball
with that mace would hurt it? But yeah, she didn't
do anything. Hawk Girl doesn't scream in the comic
books, so like she's not Black Canary, right? She
does, and I've actually seen some instances where
she does have a canary cry, but I feel like that's
just bad writing. Because yeah, she
traditionally does not have that. And it's not
like it did anything anyway in this movie. Her
enthematal mace should have knocked out the
kaiju's eye. I'm just gonna say it, but it didn't.
Yeah, I had real problems with Hawk Girl.
Hopefully she redeems herself in Peacemaker.
We'll see. I did love the other members of the
Justice Gang though, namely Guy Gardner, the
Green Lantern, played by Nathan Fillion. He
friggin killed it. Guy Gardner is not my favorite
Green Lantern, as I've mentioned in prior
episodes, but I thought he was perfect for this
movie because he was just a great foil in a way for a
Superman. Like he represented the cynicism of the
world. Yes, exactly. But I also liked the fact that
each character, including Guy Gardner, was able
to showcase their power in this really impressive
way. Like Hawk Girl was really the only one who
didn't get the opportunity to do that. But the most
impressive was actually Mr. Terrific, in my
opinion, played by Eddie Gathage. His moment
where he's taking on the soldiers at Fort Cramer
with his T-Spheres was so cool. One of the best
action scenes in the movie, I would say. I do like
how they showcased his multitasking ability in
the course of that fight, in that it felt like he was
kind of everywhere at once fighting everybody
through his T-Spheres. I like the T-Spheres in
general. I want the T-Spheres. I guess it was maybe
a little bit vague exactly what they did, at least
to newcomers, but I think people would be
impressed nonetheless. I mean, in the comics,
they kind of do everything. So it was appropriate.
I also just really liked Eddie Gathage's
performance. I kind of hope that he leads his own
spin-off, maybe, Justice Society show later on. I
don't know. That'd be cool. I need to see more Mr.
Terrific. That's all I know. Metamorpho joined
the Justice Gang at the very end of the film. He was
played by Anthony Kerrigan, who played him a
little bit more meekly than I think he's depicted
in the comics. But I did like the fact that they made
him a family man, because that's really important
to the character in DC Comics. Is his son like that
in the comic books? Green? Yeah. Interesting. I
really loved the special effects behind his
powers. It was weird, especially when he was like a
flying head, it would just have like tentacles.
Yeah. After he turned his body into acid and
sprayed those guys. Yeah. Yeah, really
interesting. But of course, there's also Lex
Luthor's own superhuman crew, which included the
engineer who was played by Maria Gabriela de
Ferreira, who was better in the movie than I
thought she would be. Like, I didn't think she
really belonged in this movie based on the
trailers, just what I know of the character. But I
thought James Gunn made good use of her, being that
she was a creation of Lex Luthor to tackle
Superman. But is that true to the authority comic
books? Does she have any association with Lex
Luthor? No, not initially. She was a wild storm
character, a member of the authority that was
brought into DC Comics later on. I guess in that
regard, she just still feels random to me. Well,
that's what I was afraid of, but I didn't get that
sense, because she was a part of a team called
Overwatch, created by Lex Luthor to bring down
Superman specifically. So I kind of liked the idea
that he was working on these experiments to create
superpowered individuals capable of taking on
Superman. And I thought her power set was really
cool. I was horrified when she was like flooding
Superman's mouth with nanites trying to drown
him. That was wild. I wonder why Lex didn't give
himself superpowers. I don't necessarily think
he wants them. I think he wants to prove that he's
better than meta-humans. He's always kind of been
anti-meta-human. Just being in control of them as
opposed to joining them. Right, yeah, he uses
them. Like the clone of Superman in this film,
Ultraman, which I don't love that they named him
Ultraman. I don't understand why they didn't just
go the bizarro route with this character. Yeah,
they were trying to keep it this secret or
something like that, as if fans didn't already
know or highly suspect that this was going to be a
Superman clone underneath the mask. Well, I
wasn't 100% going in. Like it was a genuine mystery
who the character of Ultraman was to me. I was kind
of actually disappointed when they revealed that
it was a normal looking, for the most part,
Superman clone. Would you have preferred a
disfigured looking one? Yeah, I would have much
preferred like if Lex Luthor was still working on
perfecting his clone technology. And maybe that
would lead to Superboy in a later film. I don't
know. I didn't love what they did here. For all I
know, that version of Superman being sucked into
the black hole maybe ends up in some bizarro
universe and comes back later on disfigured. But
we'll see, I guess. I think it would have been more
expedient if you replaced Metamorpho in the movie
with Metalo. And Metalo could also serve in the
engineer's role as well. Oh, just made of like
nanites? Yeah. Yeah, Metalo and bizarro? That
would have been awesome. And I think more
reflective of Superman's traditional rogues
gallery. Not gonna lie, I would have loved to have
seen that. I can't even deny that. But let's move on
to the story highlights. Visit
dynamicpodcast.com where we settle the debate
and settle the score. Superman crash lands in
Antarctica three minutes after being pummeled in
Metropolis by the hammer of Baravia, who is
seemingly the mid human champion of the nation of
Baravia, an ally of the United States, whom
Superman stopped from invading its neighboring
country of Jarhenpur three weeks ago. Superman is
taken to the Fortress of Solitude by the unruly
crypto, the super dog, where he is healed with the
help of his robot assistants and a concentrated
dose of solar radiation. All while an
inspirational yet incomplete recorded message
of hope from Superman's Kryptonian parents,
Jerell and Laura, plays in the background. Once
adequately healed, Superman flies back to the
city of Metropolis, though he and his Antarctic
fortress are noticed by the engineer who works for
and was created by Alex Luther. Again, brilliant
use of the opening crawl as it were for this film. I
guess many humans emerged three centuries ago and
in this movie, Superman is 33 years old. I'm not
sure why they went with the number three, but I
thought it totally worked timeline wise. Yeah, I
don't think there was real significance to the
number three. It was just kind of a coincidence
that all these occurrences lined up with the
number three. It made me interested in which
metahumans emerged three centuries ago. Like
what century would that have been? The 18th
century, I guess? The 1700s? You can't wait to
learn more about that, but I also liked that they
build it as ushering in age of gods and monsters,
which is the name of the first chapter,
essentially, for James Gunn's DC universe, like
his phase one. Were you surprised that Bradley
Cooper was Jerell? No, that was actually spoiled
for me beforehand and not even on social media,
like it was a news article. I was pissed. In
Metropolis, Lex and his team are alerted to
Superman's return and issue instructions to the
hammer, resulting in Superman's defeat once
again. The injured Superman is helped to his feet
by a friendly food vendor named Malik, while he's
also criticized by the public for his
intervention in the foreign conflict. The hammer
departs, flying to Fort Kramer, a nearby military
base, where a series of interdimensional
gateways through a pocket universe takes him to
Lex Luther's command center, and it's revealed
that the hammer is Ultraman, another creation of
Lexes. The hammer of Baravia is an original
character to the story, yes? Yes, yeah, he's not in
the comics. I do gotta say I really like Lex
Luther's fight system that he has set up against
Superman, where he calls out like specific moves
to Ultraman to defeat him. That was really cool.
Yeah, he essentially plotted like thousands of
moves to go against Superman, which is wild. I
thought that was really cool. It's like Lex Luther
playing a video game against Superman with like a
thousand buttons. I was surprised that the war
suit that the hammer of Baravia or Ultraman war was
not Lex Luther in a battle suit, because I totally
thought that was going to be the case from the
trailers. I thought that was a really cool suit,
and I kind wish Lex Luther would use it later on.
Yeah, that would have been cool. Or at least you
think he'd put on like a raptor suit or something
like that. Oh yeah, yeah, I guess that's green and
purple. More traditionally, Lex's colors. That
would have been cool. Nicolaar Kant arrives at the
Daily Planet after getting his first front page
news story published about Superman's fight with
the hammer. While Lois Lane and Jimmy Olsen
questioned the hammer's motive and Superman's
actions, the president of Baravia, Vassil
Gurkos, criticizes Superman during a televised
press briefing and insists Baravia's invasion of
Jarhanpur was to liberate its people from its
oppressive government. Lex Luther meets with US
military executives at the Pentagon, presenting
Ultraman, the engineer, and an army of flying
armored soldiers known as Raptors as a military
unit known as Planet Watch, pitched as the best and
only method of neutralizing the alien threat that
Superman presents as all Kryptonite has now been
removed from the planet. Though the executives,
including Rick Fleck Sr., are hesitant to allow
Lex to kill Superman, they give Lex the authority
to hold Superman for questioning. You mentioned
that the story did a good job of showing the
multiple sides of Lex Luther as a villain as he's
been portrayed in the comic books as like, you
know, an evil scientist, a businessman. When I saw
Lex in the Pentagon speaking with generals and
stuff like that, I could easily see a route to him
becoming president in maybe like a sequel or a
third film in a trilogy down the line. Yeah, that
would be interesting. I've always loved that
storyline with Lex. It was really cool in the
comics. Now, I have to imagine that Planet Watch is
a precursor to Stormwatch in the comics, which is
related to the authority and maybe one of the
reasons they went with the engineer for this
movie, because the authority is a film that James
Gunn has been planning to be a part of this Gods and
Monsters chapter in the DC cinematic universe.
Now, Lois arrives at her apartment only to find
Clark there cooking dinner. It's revealed that
the two are having a secret romantic relationship
and that Lois knows Clark is Superman. After
agreeing to allow Lois to interview him as
Superman, Clark nevertheless becomes agitated
by her questions and leaves. Meanwhile, Lex
arrives in Antarctica with Ultraman, the
engineer, and his current girlfriend Eve
Tessmucker, who all infiltrates Superman's
fortress, destroys his robots, kidnaps crypto,
and steals the recording of Superman's
Kryptonian parents. To prevent Superman from
interrupting their infiltration of the
fortress, Lex has his team unleash a distraction
in Metropolis, a small alien creature that grows
into a skyscraper sized kaiju overnight. Now,
there's a lot of things in this film that they don't
really explain, and it makes me wonder if there was
a longer cut of this film earlier on. Things like
the kaiju. When did it grow? Why did it grow? Where
does it come from? Things like that. Yeah, I
definitely had those questions about it as well.
Like I was maybe missing something, or maybe it was
some kind of easter egg to the comic books. Like he
was a well-known character for DC fans, but I never
got those answers. No, the kaiju. I mean, there are
kaiju's in Superman comics, but I think this one
was original to the movie. As Superman protects
Metropolis from the kaiju, the Justice Gang
arrives, with its members Guy Gardner, a Green
Lantern, Mr. Terrific, and Hawk Girl ultimately
killing the kaiju to Superman's dismay. While the
public celebrates the hero's victory, Lex Luthor
reveals on a new show a repaired and full recording
of Superman's parents, their inspirational
message of hope, followed by their wish that their
son Cal-El rule over Earth's citizens and spread
his seed to rebuild the Kryptonian lineage.
Devastated by the revelation, and with a public
sentiment turned against him even further,
Superman realizes Luthor must have stolen the
message from his fortress. Upon flying there,
Superman finds his robots destroyed and Krypton
missing. While President Gerkos meets with Lex
Luthor in his pocket universe, the two revealed to
be in cahoots. The kaiju scene was a great action
scene for not only Superman and showcasing how
heroic he is with the saving of like dogs and
squirrels and stuff, but also just a great
introduction, I think, to the Justice Gang. I was
looking forward to this scene from the trailers,
and I thought they pulled it off really well. Yeah,
it was interesting how Superman was largely
serving in a support role, like preventing
collateral damage while the rest of the heroes
took on the kaiju directly. Yeah, set Superman
apart from other heroes. They just wanted to kill
this thing. He didn't. He wanted to take it to like
an intergalactic zoo or something. I thought that
was cool. Despite confronting Lex Luthor about
Krypto's whereabouts and getting no
information, Superman returns to his metropolis
apartment after spending the day looking for the
dog. There, he and Lois discuss their strained
relationship before Superman reveals that he's
going to turn himself into the government for
questioning, figuring that may help lead him to
Krypto. While Superman is arrested by Ultraman,
Rick Flagg Sr. reveals that Superman is to be held
in Lex's custody for the time being. Superman is
escorted through the interdimensional portal at
Fort Kramer to Lex's pocket universe, where he is
placed in a prison cell with metamorpho, whom Lex
has neutralized and tortured Superman by
creating Kryptonite. Superman spots Krypto
being experimented upon and realizes Lex has no
intention of ever releasing either of them.
Meanwhile, Lois and Jimmy try to find the
connection between Lex and Baravia, resulting in
Jimmy reaching out to Eve, who turns out to be
Jimmy's obsessive ex-girlfriend and the two
agree to meet. I like the Kryptonite effect in this
movie, where it really made Superman feel more
alien and really feel much more affected by the
Kryptonite element than in other screen
adaptations where it just looks like he's sick to
his stomach or something like that. Yeah, it
definitely looks like the Kryptonite was
poisoning his blood here, and it actually did.
Kryptonite is so inconsistent, I'm glad that it
had lasting ramifications in this movie. After
Jimmy meets with Eve to ask her to find
information, Lois visits with the Justice Gang to
ask for their help, and though their leader Guy
Gardner refuses, Mr. Terrific tracks Superman to
Fort Kramer. After Lex kills Malik in a game of
Russian roulette in front of Superman to force
information out of him, Lois and Mr. Terrific
arrive at Fort Kramer, where Terrific defeats the
soldiers there to uncover the portal to Lex's
pocket universe. While Mr. Terrific searches for
Superman using his T-Sphere, Minimorpho agrees
to help Superman escape their prison cell in
exchange for the rescue of his also imprisoned
infant son, Joseph. Though Superman manages to
rescue Joseph and Krypto, he struggles against
the Raptors and is knocked into an anti-proton
river before nearly getting sucked into a black
hole at the center of the pocket universe.
Eventually, Superman manages to escape the
pocket universe with help from Minimorpho. Along
with Mr. Terrific and Lois, the Superman
continues to suffer from Kryptonite poisoning,
and Lois takes him to the Kent Farm in Kansas while
Mr. Terrific stays behind to try to close the
portal. I feel like using Super Breath to escape a
black hole makes no sense in any sort of reality.
Okay, well how would you have done it? You could. I
don't know, squeezed my flying muscles a little
bit harder or something like that? I have no idea.
But Super Breath had me scratching my head during
the movie. Well, I think it was Super Breath
combined with Minimorpho's tugging that really
got him out of there. I did think the anti-proton
river was really cool. Did not expect to see
anything like that in the Superman movie. Yeah, it
was a cool special effect. For sure. Why do you
think Jimmy Olsen didn't like Eve? Because the
implication was that he was kind of shallow and
thought she had weird looking toes and that's why
he didn't like her? I mean besides the obvious
personality reasons, if she was so clingy I wonder
why they even inserted the toe thing. Yeah, it does
kind of make Jimmy look kind of bad. It had to be a
personality thing. I don't know. Furious as
Superman's escape, Lex abuses Eve, who texts
information to Jimmy out of spite, though she's
caught immediately upon doing so and imprisoned
in the pocket universe. Though Jimmy is
disappointed to see the information Eve sent was a
series of selfies, Lois recognizes that the
background of each selfie contains critical
evidence that reveals Lex's plans. Despite
warnings from his team, Lex overloads the portal
generator at Fort Cramer causing a destructive
rift to grow between realities that begins
tearing Metropolis apart and Lex's desperate bid
to attract Superman. While Clark has a heartfelt
talk with his adoptive father Jonathan Kent about
Jor-El and Lara's full message, Metropolis's
citizens evacuate the city and Baravia's army
gathers at the border ready to invade Jarhenpur,
whose citizens call out to Superman for help as
their people do not have an advanced military to
defend them. There's a few scenes in this movie
that not gonna lie got me choked up, one of them
being the discussion between Jonathan Kent and
Superman. Oh for sure, yeah really heartfelt
stuff. But also the Jarhenpur scene with the kids
lifting up the flag, that was real touching. For
sure and not just for us as audience members but
also like the characters from the Justice Gang who
decided ultimately to go help despite their
criticism of Superman doing the same thing
earlier in the film. As a parent hearing the wisdom
of Jonathan saying that parents aren't for
telling their children who they're supposed to
be, we're just here to give them the tools
essentially to make fools of themselves. I really
liked that message. Oh yeah so good. Letting your
kids make their own choices to become who they are
going to be on their own is a challenge I think as a
parent because you want the best for them and you
kind of end up wanting to control their lives in
some way but the wisdom of not doing that just
struck Yeah telling someone who they are in
general is just going to build resentment on their
part. Totally yeah. Now despite seeing the
Jarhenpurian people call out for him on
television, Superman is notified by Mr. Terrific
about what's going on in Metropolis. As
Metropolis is being destroyed, Lois and Jimmy
reveal to Daily Planet editor and chief Perry
White that Lex had given military arms to Baravia
at a discount in exchange for half of Jarhenpur's
conquered land which would serve as the site for a
tech haven as well as provide him with billions of
dollars in oil reserves. The three of them along
with several other Daily Planet journalists
write a story exposing Lex in Mr. Terrific's
hovercraft while Mr. Terrific and Superman
themselves are attacked by Ultraman and the
engineer after working to protect Metropolis's
citizens. After the engineer nearly drowns
Superman in nanites, Superman flies into space
and crash lands back in Metropolis knocking out
the engineer along with her nanites and also
damaging Ultraman's mask which reveals that he's
a clone of Superman. What did you think of the way
Superman defeated the engineer? I liked it. I
liked how he took issues into his own accord. You
know he didn't have outside help to come in and
rescue him at the last minute like you would expect
maybe from a situation like this. He had to use his
own wits being a character who isn't necessarily
known for his high intelligence. It was a
desperate move on his part but it made sense and it
worked. Yeah I agree. I totally thought with Mr.
Terrific being there that he was going to disable
the nanites in some way but I loved that they came up
with a unique way for Superman to overcome his own
challenge. A way that even Lex didn't foresee
coming. Yeah it was also hardcore. Even the
engineer was like I'm not going to survive this and
Lex was like the only one they're protecting is
Superman. That was genius. That was good. As Guy
Gardner, Hawkeye Girl and Metamorpho defend
Jarhan Perr from the Baravian army going so far as
to even kill President Girkus, Ultraman
meanwhile pummel Superman under the fight
direction of Lex Luthor. With help from Crypto
however, Superman is able to disable Lex's
observational drones and knock Ultraman into the
pocket universe's black hole. After defeating
the Raptors as well, Superman, Crypto and Mr.
Terrific crash into Lex's flying command center
and after a brief debate between Superman and Lex,
Crypto attacks Lex, injuring him while Mr.
Terrific hacks Lex's systems to reverse the rift
destroying the city. Once the Daily Planet's
expose outs Lex as manipulating the war between
Baravia and Jarhan Perr, Lex is arrested and his
pocket universe prisoners are set free including
Eve who embraces a reluctant Jimmy. Superman and
Lois also share a kiss. This whole third act was so
action packed and so fun to watch. I do have to call
BS on a code fixing that rift between dimensions
though. I don't know how that's possible. Kind of
the whole Silver Age zockiness at work there.
Yeah. But the rest of it I loved. Do you think the
Justice Gang will come under the same kind of
scrutiny that Superman did for interfering in an
international conflict going so far as to
assassinate a world leader? I was actually
wondering that. I think with revelation that Lex
was manipulating them and that President Gerchos
was corrupt, probably gives them a bit of
leniency. Maybe. I really didn't appreciate how
the whole Crypto attacking Lex comedic beat in the
film was a direct ripoff of the puny god scene where
the Hulk beats the shit out of Loki in the Avengers
film. It was like this same exact joke. That's a
beyond the reasoning of the antagonists just
being more of a force of nature and beating the shit
out of the villain because they can. For me it was
almost the same exact moment. Okay so that's only a
lot to happen once in storytelling for all of
history? At least for superhero films? Yes. No.
I'm sorry. It was way cooler when Crypto did it. Now
back at the fortress of solitude as Superman
undergoes healing treatment from his now
repaired robot servants, a drunk super girl
arrives and is reunited with her dog Crypto. After
she leaves, Superman watches videos of himself
growing up with his adoptive parents, the Kents in
Kansas. In a mid-credits scene, he and Crypto
overlook the planet from the moon and in an
end-credits scene, Superman chastises himself
for being a jerk after pointing out to an irate Mr.
Terrific that the city was not seamlessly
rejoined after closing the rift. I gotta say both
the mid-credits scene and end-credits scene were
entirely worthless. Like I did not need to see
them, I regret wasting my time. Well it's been said
that DC Studios is not going to make the mistake of
recent Marvel Studios films in setting up
promises that they can't deliver. It wasn't
really necessary, it was cute, it was comedic. I'm
glad I stayed for them. I think to that end they
should just not have mid or end-credits Why even
include them if it's just going to be pointless?
You know what? Just let DC do what it's going to do.
You don't need to worry about it. I did really like
the ending how Superman started watching the
videos of Ma and Pa Kante as opposed to his
Kryptonian parents. That whole switch-up was I
thought a great culmination to his arc because it
spoke to how he started defining himself. I
actually kind of loved how they played up more on Ma
and Pa Kante in this movie than Krypton. Even with
Pa and Ma Kante being portrayed as the simpletons
that they were, to Clark they were still more
important because they were the ones who raised
him than his Kryptonian parents. You know in Man of
Steel we got a really brilliant take on Krypton and
I wasn't really sure that this film could improve
on something like that and I'm kind of glad it
didn't even really try to. Like Krypton is
interesting but beyond it being the planet he came
from his real origin story is his upbringing in
Smallville by Jonathan and Martha Kent and I'm
glad that this film acknowledged that. Yeah
Krypton is irrelevant to his actual character.
This film really puts the causation of Superman's
morals and ethics on the Kants which kudos to the
film. Yeah there's a lot that this film gets right.
It surprised me in a lot of ways. I thought it was
profound in more ways than I would have thought it
would have been. It was a soaring reminder that
true heroism lies not in mites but in the radical
choice to see goodness in others. I thought it was a
bold heartfelt and fun start to the new DC
universe. I loved this movie. It's not perfect but
it's really close so I'm giving it four and a half
out of five stars. A fresh rating on Rotten
Tomatoes. Yeah I think viewing it on a surface
level doesn't quite seem as profound as it
actually is if you look deeper. You know that whole
message is the essence of Superman. At least how he
should be and beyond that I think the film was just a
lot of fun and a lot more true to the tone of the comic
books and true to the characterization. You can't
really ask for much more than that from a superhero
film. So yeah I think four and a half stars is a solid
rating. I cannot wait for the Supergirl movie
after this. I cannot wait to see Batman. I really
hope they incorporate Robert Pattinson's The
Batman into this universe because I think it would
work perfectly. I'm so stoked to be a DC fan right
now and see what they have coming up. What a time to
be alive. And I gotta say Marvel's Fantastic Four
has a lot to live up to after this movie. Oh it's up
for the challenge and then some. You'll see. It is
going to get trounced by Superman. No way
Fantastic Four has a chance. R.A .P. Marvel
Studios. Calling it now. You know what I like. I
give this movie zero stars. Well thank goodness it
doesn't matter what you think. And also I'll
remember that in my review of Fantastic Four.
Never mind. Never mind. But that does it for this
review. AJ9K help close this out. Thanks for
listening to Dynamic Jewel. Visit the show's
website at dynamicjewel.com and follow us on
Instagram at dynamicjewel podcast. You can
support the show on Patreon at patreon.com slash
dynamicjewel and joining a tier that works for you
or by rating and reviewing Dynamic Jewel on Apple
Podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser or on our website.
Don't forget to listen to the other shows in the
Dynamite podcast network including Max
Destruction, Senjo World and Console Combat. In
our next episode we will be doing a quick break from
the reviews to do a team duel this time pitting the
Justice League International versus the West
Coast Avengers. It's the Justice League versus
the Avengers again. Yes like a rematch or like a
grudge match where this time the Avengers are
going to be kicking all kinds of ass. Not as much as
the Justice League. You'll learn. But that does it
for this episode. We want to give a big thanks to our
executive producers John Straussky, Zachary
Hepburn, Dustin Belcombe, Miggy Mathen-Geehan,
Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yatn, Austin Wazalowski,
AJ Dunkerly, Nick Obanto, Scott Camacho, Gil
Camacho, Adam Spees, Dean Molesky, Devin Davis,
Joseph Kirsting, Josh Leiner, Mike Williams,
Oscar Galvez and Paul Graves for helping make this
podcast possible. We'll talk to you guys next
week. Up, up and away, true believers. I'm so punk
rock that I despise punk rock.