This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi, welcome to
the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin
brother Marvelous Joe. And in this episode we are
doing a duel between the Superman villain, Mister
Mxyzptlk, and the Fantastic Four villain,
Impossible Man. Yeah, they're both impish
characters who are insanely powerful. They
actually had a crossover in the Superman Silver
Surfer pop one-shot issue, but we're here to fully
settle the debate who would win between these two
characters no holds barred. Right, because that
ended in a stalemate. And we don't play like that.
There's not gonna be any Superman or Silver Surfer
to save Mister Mxyzptlk's ass this time. Or
Impossible Man. But before that we're gonna break
down the comic book and movie news from the past
week, which you know we're not because once again
there is no comic book movie news worth talking
about. Yeah, what's up with this drought that
we're in right now? You think as we're gearing up to
the Superman and Fantastic Four films and the Iron
Heart show that there'd be more news going around?
Well I figured that Superman and Fantastic Four
would be having final trailers soon to kind of say
hey tickets are now on sale but Fantastic Four
jumped the gun and put their tickets on sale before
even having a final trailer. And I'm like what?
That reminds me I gotta buy my tickets. Wait, you
don't have your tickets yet? Fake fan. I'm getting
them. I'm gonna get them right now actually. So
just keep talking while I do that. So I don't know if
you guys know this but Marvel sucks big time. Let me
tell you why. Not only do they put their tickets out
without releasing a final trailer like who does
that but also what are you doing? You told me to keep
talking. I may continue on with the episode. Oh,
okay. Now go on to an editorial. Got you. Alright.
Well as always we list our segment times in our
episode description so feel free to check out our
show notes if you want to skip ahead to a particular
topic. Our artificially intelligent dual
simulator AJ9K has a quick message for our
listeners so listen up. Why hello there. Do you
want even more from this podcast? Then become a
part of the dynamic dual community on Patreon
where you can choose from three tiers. The dynamic
2.0 tier gives you access to our discord chat
server. The Fantastic 4 tier gives you two bonus
episodes each month and the X-Force tier makes you
an executive producer of this show. Lastly, the
Diner Mike podcast network tier lets you create
your own podcast using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and
consultation and get you simulation results.
Pitch the twins your ideas via email at
dynamicdualpodcast at gmail.com. Check it out at
patreon.com slash dynamic dual. Pip pip cheerio.
Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone who supports
this podcast. Guys be sure to tune in to the other
shows on the Diner Mike podcast network this week
including the console combat podcast where hosts
John and Dean simulate battles between popular
video game characters. In yesterday's episode
they pit Cloud Strife from Vinyl Fantasy versus
Ike from Fire Emblem. Over on the Max Destruction
podcast hosts Scotty and Gilly pit your favorite
action heroes from film and television against
each other. This week the brothers are pitting the
tick against Goliath from Gargoyles. And on the
Senjo World podcast hosts Zachary Hepburn
speculates on fights between fan favorite anime
and manga characters. In his next episode Zach is
going to reveal who would win between Yukonda from
D. Grayman versus Tokia Mikagami from Flame of
Reka. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or click the
link in our show notes to listen to all of the shows
in the Dino Mike podcast network. But with that out
of the way quick to the no prize. A no prize is an
award Marvel used to give out to fans. Our version
the Dynamic Dual no prize is a digital award that we
post on Instagram for the person that we feel gave
the best answer to our question of the week. Last
week we asked you guys how did you find Dynamic Dual
and how long have you been listening to the show.
And this is coming off with the news that Jonathan
and I will be ending this podcast in January of 2026
as it currently exists. Basically it's not going
to be a weekly show anymore because Jonathan and I
have been doing this for 10 years. We started on our
30th birthday and we thought our 40th birthday
would be a good time to retire the show. So we're
going to stop doing weekly episodes but we're
still going to review the latest Marvel and DC
comic book movies that come out to theaters
because we want to retain our Rotten Tomatoes
credentials as critics. So basically this was a
horrible question though because there was no way
we could pick an answer. So this week there are no
honorable mentions and there's really no winner.
We appreciate everyone who called in and we're
going to play all of your answers because you guys
are all winners. Yeah everyone's a winner. You get
a no prize and you get a no prize and you get a no
prize. Let's go ahead and hear from the callers
starting with Cyrus Moore who said hey guys. Cyrus
Moore I found you guys in 2019. I was in a pretty low
place and I was just going through Spotify trying
to find a DC podcast that would tickle my fancy and I
just happened to stumble upon you guys and I've
just been listening every day since 2019 and
haven't missed an episode and I love you guys and
thank you for always making a great show. I
appreciate it. Not going to lie one of the most
heartwarming things about doing this podcast is
hearing feedback like this where we helped bring
some kind of joy to someone's life. Yeah and he
jumped in at the right time too because 2019 is when
the show probably started getting good. It took us
a few years of trying to nail this formula before we
finally got it. And not saying this show is good. It
could be better. It could be better. It can always
be better. Mostly by this year we'll nail it. Yeah.
Year 10 is our year. Year 10 is when the show really
gets good. Finally. Thanks Cyrus more. Our next
answer comes from Lorenzo Valdez who said this is
Lorenzo Valdez calling in once again. I've
actually only been listening to your podcast for
the last couple of months. I think I found out about
your podcast via an advertisement that you guys
had on one of DC's new official podcasts either DC
studio showcase or DC high volume Batman. Clon of
forever and always. Yeah the podcast that he heard
an ad for us on was DC high volume. DC's reps reached
out to us and wanted to promote that show on our
podcast and also let us promote our show on theirs
which has happened a couple of times like Marvel's
Wolverine podcast the Long Nights also did that.
Yeah we've been pretty lucky over the years to hear
from reps from Marvel and DC themselves
specifically within the podcast space. But all
I'm saying is we actually got listeners from the DC
one. Thanks Lorenzo. The next caller is Eli who
said this is Eli and I've been listening since
March of 2020. You guys got me through the pandemic
and straight through high school but when the
pandemic started I got kicked out of school and
started looking and so I needed something to
listen to during my nine hour shifts at the
warehouse. So I blew through all you guys's
previous episodes pretty quick and started
listening to the weekly uploads. The pandemic
year 2020 when that all started I wasn't even sure
this podcast was going to survive everything that
was going on then just because everything was
really weird and we managed to get through that
year largely by just reviewing older Marvel and DC
films which thankfully there was a large backlog
of content for us to look at because we know that
Marvel and DC weren't putting out anything new at
that time. So yeah a lot of listeners found us
during that time when a lot of people were
listening to podcasts. Yeah and you and I actually
started recording separately around that time
because for a long time we were recording in the
same room. Right but then like everybody else you
know we started hopping on zoom calls and stuff to
collaborate. Great answer Eli our next answer
comes from CJ Kraft who said. Hey guys CJ Kraft here
I've been listening so long I'm not sure when I
started. I know it was around the show's beginning
because it was before the first retooling. I can't
believe it's already been 10 years every Tuesday
the entertainment's been top notch. I don't know
what I'm going to do with you guys gone. You'll be
missed but I'll look forward to the episodes we do
get. Thanks guys. Yeah CJ Kraft is one of our
original listeners I think he's been with us for a
long time and he's reached out time and again and
we've been looking enough to hear from him because
he's a talented writer and we promoted some of his
books on this podcast as well. Yeah for anyone who
hasn't listened to the show from the very start
when CJ is talking about the retooling he's
talking about our first year where we were
actually a bi-weekly show and we called ourselves
the DC Marvel Battlecast. That's right yeah
that's real old school. Thanks CJ our next answer
comes from Alex Albrough who said. Hey guys found
you in early 2023 when I was having to drive a lot and
I had a Marvel podcast I liked and was looking for a
DC podcast to learn more about those characters.
Found this one where I could learn about both and
imaginary battles between the two and got hooked
pretty instantly. I went through your whole
library except for movies and shows I haven't seen
yet in about a year and a half and now I'm all caught
up and look forward to listening every Tuesday.
Congrats on the podcast guys and happy early early
40th birthday. I do not want to turn 40 so everybody
just hold off on their birthday wishes for now. I am
not looking forward to that actually I've already
started telling people that I'm 40 because I might
as well be you know 39 really you're 40. Thanks for
listening Alex and thanks for your answer our next
answer comes from Matt from Texas. Hey guys Matt
from Texas. The first time I heard about your
podcast was on the TV a movie trivia podcast with
Brian Sheehan where Joe was a special guest for the
Captain America first Avengers back in 2022. I
jumped over here that was about a year and a half ago
and just started listening and binged through
every single one of your episodes and have loved
every single one of them. Good job guys. Yeah Brian
has had me on his TV and movie trivia podcast as a
guest for about four or five episodes I think and
I've had a blast every time. I haven't gone on his
show for a few months now maybe almost a year so I got
a remedy that I'll have to reach out to him again
because I really love his podcast and he has great
trivia questions and he's a really cool dude. I was
on his podcast in the fall of last year as sort of a
tie into the Joker sequel that was coming out. We
did trivia on the first Joker movie and you could
see how hyped I was for the Joker sequel and I feel
like the episode is very dated now because of how
bad the Joker sequel actually was. I gotta go back
and listen to it and just laugh at all of your
misplaced enthusiasm. Thanks for the call Matt.
Our next answer comes from Christian Robito who
said, Hey y'all it's Christian Robito. I've been
listening to this podcast for about two or three
years now. My favorite part of this podcast has
definitely been the dual episodes. It's been fun
listening to fictional fights between
characters that we all love. I especially love the
banter between you two. It's been fun to hear but
really this podcast has just been a good way to tune
out from the real world and all the stress and
everything that entails and just have fun
listening to nerdy stuff. Thanks for everything.
Y'all hope to hear from you soon. Yeah, I'm not sure
which episodes I prefer creating the duels or the
reviews. I know this podcast started with duels
because you and I have been arguing about these
characters fighting since we were little kids but
being film critics has also been a dream of ours
also since we were younger. Right. I think it
depends on what episode we're currently doing.
Like if we're currently doing a dual episode, I
think man, I can't wait to get to a review and when
we're doing a review, I think man, I can't wait to
get to a duel. So it's been a nice balance of having
both formats available. We're doing a lot of duels
this year just trying to do every single character
under the sun and I'm actually really enjoying it.
It's a lot of work but it's always fun to do. Thanks
Christian. Our next color was Rysiel. Who said?
Hey guys, this is Rysiel. I've been listening to
you guys for apparently like nine years now
because I remember starting like right around
when you guys started. I found you guys on
accident. I'm just sick of listening to music
sometimes while I'm sitting at work. So I just
started searching for something nerdy,
something DC related and you guys are the only one I
listened to that doesn't sound like the comic book
nerd like, oh actually. So yeah, that's about it.
See you. Well, Jonathan still sounds like that. I
think that's fair. But actually, have you noticed
that a lot of these colors are saying that they were
searching for a DC podcast when they found this and
not a Marvel podcast? Well, yeah, I mean, Marvel
has a lot of fans. So there's a lot more Marvel
podcasts and DC fans are kind of like solitary
figures who don't really go out at night or put
together podcasts. So they're harder to come by.
I'm sorry DC has some amazing podcasts. You don't
know what the fuck you're talking about. Way to
profile DC fans. I will profile DC fans all day
long. Okay, want to hear my profile of a Marvel fan?
Nope. Too bad because you're going to hear it.
Marvel fans are stupid. They're just really dumb.
Why did you use the thesaurus for that one? They are
ignoramuses. Thanks for calling in Rizio. Our
penultimate answer comes from Brian Rochester.
Who said? Hi, it's Brian. I found Dynamic Dual by
Random Searching for different podcasts about
Marvel and DC. And I think the first episode I
listened to was the iVampire versus... I don't
forgot about the vampires, but it's been a great
show. Yeah, that was Andrew Bennett iVampire
versus Dracula. It was Marvel's version of
Dracula. We put that out in October of 2023 as kind
of like a spooky October Vampire Dual episode. I
still contend that Andrew Bennett is the absolute
worst name for a vampire and a DC character in
general. It's just a fucking name. Andrew
Bennett. So dumb. Well, as compared to something
like Niko Minoru? Yeah, at least that's like
unique and cool sounding. Niko Minoru will
straight up stab your ass. Andrew Bennett will
sell you flood insurance. What is Blade's real
name again? Eric Brooks. That's wild because that
is the exact name of my accountant. Touche.
Touche. Well, I mean at least he has the name Blade,
which is still better than iVampire. Thanks for
the call, Brian. Our final answer comes from our
friends at Max Destruction, twins Scotty and
Gilly. Who said? Scotty Macho here. Gilly Macho
here. Max Destruction. I want to say my favorite
episode you guys didn't air because I want to bet
against Gil when you did the stats for me against
Martian Manhunter versus Vision and DC Guys Won.
Sorry, I got my bet back when we did Century versus
Zod and I won. Yeah, so we're listening to you guys
for five to six years now and it's sad to see you guys
go from the battles, but at least we still have the
movie reviews. And at least we still have Max
Destruction with your guys's dope episodes.
Yeah, I'm really looking forward to this week's
The Tick versus Goliath Dual episode because
Jonathan and I watched both of those cartoons
growing up as kids. You guys do great. I think you
kind of stole our whole stick when it comes to twins
talking about versus battles, but we'll let it
slide because you guys are awesome. Also real
quick, I'm confused because we actually did do a
Martian Manhunter versus Vision episode. Yeah, I
think you said that maybe we didn't air it, but
yeah, that was an episode back in like 2018, I want
to say. I do want to give a special shout out to
Spider Frank who left us a message on Spotify
comments who wrote, I've been listening since
2016 when I was 12 years old and now that I'm 21, it
feels like I'm losing a great friend. I'll dearly
miss the dual episodes, my favorite part of the
show and over the years, I forgot to say thank you.
I'm not crying, you're crying, right? Fucking
gutted from that answer. Thank you so much, Spider
Frank, for writing to us. That answer hurts on
multiple levels because I feel bad that the show is
ending in January, but also I feel bad because you
were 12 years old when you started listening and
now you're old enough to drink, so we have been
doing this for a while. Those are all the answers
and now that we've gone through all of them, I hope
it didn't seem like a big circle jerk on behalf of
Jonathan and myself, but we truly wanted to
spotlight the people who took the time to give us a
call and leave such touching answers. It means a
lot to us and we can't wait to continue making
episodes for you guys throughout the rest of this
year because like we said last time, we got some
good ones in the works, including this Mr. Mixi
Spitalik vs. Impossible Man dual episode, but
speaking of duels, that brings us to our question
of the week. What Marvel or DC character that we
haven't done a duel with yet, are you still hoping
we get to by January? We've done so many
characters, but we're looking specifically for
characters that we have not done duels with. Yeah,
just a reminder that the calendar is already set by
our executive producers, but we're interested in
seeing how much that calendar aligns with
listener expectations. Recording an answer at
dynamicduel.com by clicking on the red
microphone button in the bottom right hand corner
of the screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message can be up to 30 seconds
long and don't forget to leave your name in case we
include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a Dynamic
Dual No Prize that we'll post to Instagram. Be sure
to answer before June 14th. But now it's time for
the main event of this episode, where we pit the
nigh-impetent imp characters of Mr. Mxyz
Spitalik vs. Impossible Man. Okay, Mr. Mxyz
Spitalik vs. Impossible Man. I think I'm saying
Mxyz's name right. I've heard a number of
different ways, but that's the pronunciation I
remember from the Superman 90s cartoon, in which
Mxyz made a few appearances voiced by Gilbert
Godfrey. Yeah, Impossible Man has made a few
appearances in Marvel cartoons as well. I'm
wondering if we should just refer to the
characters as Mxyz and Impey as Impossible Man is
sometimes known in the comic books from here on out
for this episode, because it is really hard to say
in Mr. Mxyz Spitalik. Oh yeah, no, I'm totally fine
with that. He's often referred to as Mxyz in the
comics. Or is that too cutesy for these two badass
characters? I guess they're not really badass.
They're both jokesters, right? They both like to
play pranks. They both like to have fun. Although I
always say that Mr. Mxyz Spitalik is a little bit
more devious in his pranks than Impossible Man is.
Yeah, Mxyz is definitely a villain in DC. He's
sometimes partnered with the good guys, but it's
pretty rare. Now Mxyz has also had several
live-action appearances in Smallville and the
Supergirl television series. I'm guessing we've
never seen Impossible Man in live-action. No, we
have not yet. He's kind of ridiculous looking. He
kind of looks like a pickle. He looks like Pickle
Rick. I'm Pickle Rick! Now, to explain the
methodology behind our duels, let's go to our
sentient duel simulator, Alfred Jarvis 9000.
AJ9K, tell our listeners how you go about
determining a winner in our duel matchups. Yes, of
course, sir. The way I determine a winner between
the contestants is by running 1000 Monte Carlo
simulations using the characters statistics. A
Monte Carlo simulation is a probabilistic model
used to determine outcomes through random
sampling. In this case, I randomize the
statistics along a normal distribution as a way to
simulate the many variables that can occur during
battle. The stat parameters are based on the
official Marvel power grid from which the DC
characters statistics are extrapolated.
Additional stat categories are included such as
range, damage potential, versatility and
perception in order to create a more detailed and
accurate simulation. The results of the 1000
simulations provide a percentage of wins for each
character. The contestant with the higher
percentage is declared the victor as they have a
higher probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither character should win
100% of the matches. The comic book stories have
shown that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman, so the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks, AJ9K.
Before we run the simulations though, we'd like to
break down each character's histories and
abilities before improvising a scenario on how we
imagine one of the 1000 simulations would play out
beat for beat. And I believe it's my turn to go first
with the Marvel character backstory, so let me
tell you guys all about Impossible Man. Born on the
perilous world of pop-up in the 10th galaxy, the
alien later dubbed Impossible Man belonged to a
communal species whose members shared a single
group mind and could instantly rearrange every
molecule of their bodies into any form their
imaginations conceived. Restless after
millennia of surviving lethal predators, an
adventurous pop-upian transformed himself into
a starship and rocketed to Earth soon after the
Fantastic Four's debut. Landing in New York City,
he robbed a bank simply to buy lunch, then
delighted in outmaneuvering police, soldiers,
and the Fantastic Four. The thing called him
impossible, and the giddy visitor adopted the
nickname on the spot. Mr. Fantastic eventually
realized the prankster craved attention. When
every New Yorker agreed to ignore him, he declared
the planet intolerably dull and blasted off in
search of fresh amusement. You can learn more
about the Fantastic Four and their duel against
the Justice Society. He returned years later and
lured the planet-debouring Galactus away from
Earth by offering pop-up itself as sustenance.
The collective consciousness of its people
accepted the sacrifice reasoning that their
culture would endure within Impossible Man their
most adventurous emissary. Galactus consumed
the hyper-adaptive world but suffered
near-fatal indigestion, leaving Impossible Man
the lone living vessel of pop-up's mind. Inviting
himself aboard the Fantastic Four's craft, he
accompanied them home, determined to make Earth
his playground. Almost immediately, he stormed
into the fictional offices of Marvel Comics
demanding a series dedicated to his exploits. A
hasty promise from editor Stan Lee averted
disaster, and the trickster moved on to
impersonate the newly inaugurated US president,
foiling an assassination scheme involving mind
control technology and the cyborg deathlock.
Taking up temporary residence in the Baxter
building, he was ambushed by Klaw and the Molecule
Man. Recovering mid-battle, he proved immune to
sonic vibration and molecular manipulation once
he anticipated them and helped free the Fantastic
Four after Molecule Man possessed Reed Richards.
Concluding that the team took life far too
seriously, he drifted to Hollywood and gleefully
disrupted multiple film shoots until boredom
again set in. Back in New York, he visited The Thing
and sculptor Alicia Masters. Their obvious
affection inspired him to split his own essence
and create a companion, Impossible Woman.
Following Reed and Sue's example, the couple soon
produced thousands of Impossible Kids. Domestic
squabbles over who should lead the family erupted
into an intergalactic scavenger hunt. On Earth,
Impossible Man confiscated the X-Men's Mansion,
Nick Fury's eye patch, Zabu the Sabertooth Tiger,
Doctor Strange's Skylight, Iron Man's prototype
armor, and other trophies before the X-Men,
backed by Shiar and Pres LaLondra, forced the
Impossible Family to return every item and
apologize before a tribunal of alien races.
Determined to restore his bruised ego,
Impossible Man revisited the X-Mansion but found
only the teenage new mutants. Their techno
organic teammate Warlock accepted his challenge
to a global shape-changing duel that tore across
Manhattan's docks, Rio's beaches, London's
rooftops, Moscow's spires, and Tokyo's streets.
Warlock finally triumphed by altering his own
coloration, something a pop-upian could not
duplicate, prompting Impossible Man to storm
back into space. While evading a war fleet from the
planet Ergonar, he irritated the solemn silver
surfer, insisting that Harold find a sense of
humor, and secretly followed him during a
confrontation with the death-worshipping Titan
Thanos. Convinced that cosmic levity might just
yet save the day, the prankster eventually
departed in search of easier sport. Family Duty
resurfaced when Impossible Woman demanded a
summer vacation on Earth for their 4682
offspring. They scattered around the globe to
sightsee, Impossible Man pestered Spider-Man
during a stakeout, impersonated occult tomes
inside Doctor Strange's Sanctum and briefly
became the Punisher's Rifle before pying the
vigilante in the face. A chaotic day at an
amusement park ended with Childe number 4682
missing, sending Impossible Man to consult the
Watcher on the Moon, scour the Microverse, and
stir up Asgard, where Queen Frigga halted the
commotion with a royal spanking. The youngster
was finally located fronting a rock band, and the
Relied Family launched a galaxy-wide concert
tour. Left to his own devices, Once More
Impossible Man infiltrated a supervillain poker
game at the infamous DynaMic's villain hangout,
The Bar With No Name, and disguised himself as an
extra ace of spades, igniting a brawl among the
hardened criminals. Feeling slighted when the
Hulk's friend Rick Jones failed to invite him to a
wedding, he mailed invitations to disgruntled
villains and rival alien empires, transforming
the ceremony into chaos. Later impossible man
badgered Cable and his ex-force team during their
island vacation into mentoring three of his
apathetic, impossible teens. However, the kids
stayed glued to their hollow screens instead of
training until a colossal crustacean burst from
the lagoon and swatted their father clear through
a cliff. The shock of seeing impossible man
injured finally spurred them to fight alongside
the ex-force and after helping subdue the beast,
they teleported off, calling themselves
Impossible X, clad in pouches and straps tactical
gear pad or doctor cables. You can learn more about
ex-force in their duel against the outsiders.
Returning to Earth under the guise of the Silver
Surfer, Impossible man warned of the parasitic
Homojian, aliens who merged with native
populations. During the battle, he was
vaporized, reforming in sight Spider-Man's
lungs as microscopic vapor that Spidey vomited
into a towering Papupian conglomerate that
separated the parasites from their hosts. The
Fantastic Four negotiated a compromise with the
Homojian that transplanted into the new
exhaustible Papupian biomass and the fused race
left peacefully. Later Impossible man was in a
Himalayan village suffering from hiccups that
were triggering uncontrollable
transformations. A visit from the Thing was able
to frighten the hiccups away after which
Impossible man attended Grimm's long-delayed
Bar Mitzvah. Seeking profit, he partnered with
the showman assassin Arcade to market
self-morphing toys made from his own tissue, but
switched sides when those toys attacked the human
torch. You can learn more about Arcade in his duel
against the Riddler. During a reality-rending
uprising led by the Japanese death god Amatsumi
Kaboshi, Impossible man tried to distract the
deity with slapstick forms but was unraveled into
nothingness, yet his intangible consciousness
soon recovered. Observing a later clash between
Hulk, Red Hulk, and the telepathic Titan Xemnu,
Impossible man used a Valizian compounder to fuse
the two hulks into a single behemoth so they could
defeat Xemnu before separating them. Paternal
concern returned when Impossible man implored
Mr. Fantastic's science organization known as
the Future Foundation to educate his introverted
genius son, whom he lamented was far too possible.
In exchange, Impossible man supplied the
Foundation with intelligence on the time lost
Fantastic Four. He later celebrated with the
reunited Richards family on the moon. Most
recently, while on a journey of
self-improvement, Impossible man attempted to
master the creed discipline of Zen fascist yoga
within the Dark Dimension. His meditation
destabilized multiple realities until Doctor
Strange and Beast persuaded him to desist,
whereupon he departed once more for parts
unknown. And that's Impossible man.
Powers-wise, Impossible man is of the Papupian
race, giving him the innate ability to rearrange
and convert the molecules of his body into
anything, mimicking most of their properties.
This includes the ability to separate himself for
the purposes of self-duplication or manifesting
separate entities. He can increase or decrease
his mass between beings the size of Galactus or
down to the microscopic. He can also use his
molecular shifting power to fly, teleport, and
even produce energy or force. One drawback of
Impossible man's power is that he traditionally
can't alter his color outside of his green-purple
scheme across the tonal spectrum. When he uses his
power to shift his form or teleport, it produces a
loud pop sound. And that is the Impossible man.
Wait, so you're telling me that Impossible man is
not a reality warper? No, but through his powers he
can mimic a lot of other abilities, even things
that you wouldn't think that shape-changing
could accomplish, like telekinesis. One time he
pretended to be magneto and was able to simulate
his powers of magnetism. Essentially, I believe
by reducing offshoots of his own matter into
molecules that could affect other matter. The
dude sounds more like Martian Manhunter than
Mixie. Not gonna lie. Impossible man is not only
far more durable than Martian Manhunter because
he's not a fucking wuss when it comes to fire, but
also his molecular shape-shifting ability is far
more versatile. I'll just say this now. I don't
think it's going to be versatile enough because
Mixie Spindelik I think is way more powerful. Let
me get into his backstory. Mr. Mixie Spindelik
hails from the fifth dimension, a plane of reality
so advanced that its inhabitants and technology
appear as magic to those in the third dimension.
Though a being of immense power, Mixie adopted the
appearance of a mischievous imp, a diminutive
figure often dressed in eccentric attire,
including a bowler hat and outlandish colors.
Drawn to Earth out of sheer curiosity and a desire
for amusement, Mixie took a particular interest
in Superman, whose sense of justice and order
stood in stark contrast to Mixie's chaos and
whimsy. You can learn more about Superman in our
Superman vs. Dr. Doom episode. On Earth 2, Mixie
Spindelik plagued Superman with unpredictable
tricks and reality-altering antics, defying the
laws of physics and common sense using fifth
dimensional technology. Incapable of defeating
Mixie through conventional means, Superman
discovered that saying Mixie Spindelik's name
backward would banish him to the fifth dimension
for a mandatory period of 90 days. This became a
recurring tactic in their confrontations with
Mixie always returning once the banishment
window expired. On Earth 1, a new incarnation of
Mixie Spindelik emerged, targeting Superman
both in Metropolis and retroactively during his
youth as Superboy in Smallville. In one
encounter, Superman turned the tables by
entering the fifth dimension himself, where
Mixie was running for mayor. Despite Mixie's
attempt to trap Superman there by tricking him
into saying Namropus or Superman backwards,
Superman escaped by saying Lelac, his Kryptonian
name spelled backward. The imp's last notable
appearance before the Crisis on Infinite Earths
occurred was when he revealed himself as the
mastermind behind Superman's recent adversity.
Claiming boredom after millennia of impishness,
Mixie chose to embrace true malevolence, using
his power to empower other villains and ensnare
the fortress of solitude. Upon being discovered,
he took on a grotesque true form that caused pain in
others to behold. When Superman accidentally
banished him to the Phantom Zone while Mixie
Spindelik said his name backward, the
dimensional collision tore the imp apart.
Distraught over causing Mixie's death, Superman
depowered himself using gold kryptonite and
retired. Following the multiversal reset, Mixie
remained a reality-defying trickster, though
was revealed to be a sane psychological
researcher from the fifth dimension who came to
Earth to study human behavior. Initially
rational and curious, repeated exposure to the
three Stooges films warped his mind and
transformed him into the maniac being known as
Mixie Spindelik. At one point, Mixie visited the
Joker for advice on how to better torment
Superman. The Joker tricked the imp into giving up
99.9% of his power, allowing the Joker to gain
control over reality itself and reshape the world
into a grotesque nightmare. Rendered nearly
powerless, Mixie wandered Metropolis in a daze
until he recovered enough sanity to aid Superman
and Steel in escaping Earth and confronting the
Joker. With assistance from the Spectre, Mixie
helped reverse the damage and restore the world.
You can learn more about the Joker and his duel
against the Green Goblin. Later, Mixie was
captured and imprisoned by the deranged Superboy
Prime, who sought to use the imp's power to
recreate Earth Prime. The ritual failed due to the
sacrifice of a heroic sorceress named Anathas
Arathas. Though Mixie tried to save her, he
respected her decision to atone through death. It
was during this time that he cryptically revealed
that over the ages, he had assumed many names
familiar to Earth mythology, including Loki and
Anansi. In post-Flashpoint continuity, Mixie's
presence was initially subtle. His wife, Nixleic
Spitlands, known as Mrs. Nixley, mentioned him
during her own appearances, noting that he had
fallen into a coma following a catastrophic
battle with their former court Chester, Lord
Vendictavix. In this new continuity, it was
revealed that Mixie was actually a traveling
entertainer who performed illusions for the King
of Xerph, charming both the monarch and Princess
Nixley. Jealous of the attention Mixie received,
Vendictavix attempted to assassinate him. The
attempt went awry and the King was killed instead.
Enraged, Vendictavix chased Mixie and Nixley
into the third dimension. On Earth, the couple
disguised themselves as humans and lived in
Metropolis. Mixie, performing as Mr. XXX, even
fathered a child before succumbing to an
Earth-based illness that placed him in a coma.
When Superman defeated Vendictavix's final
attack, Mixie awakened, suggesting that he had
faith in Superman's victory all along, though
whether this was sincere or a deeper part of an
elaborate ruse remained unclear. Later, Mixie
was revealed to be a captive of a mysterious figure
known as Mr. Oz, who was later revealed to be
Superman's birth father, Jor-El. Mixie believed
Superman would rescue him, though over time grew
embittered when no help came. Freaking himself,
he confronted Superman, Lois, and their son,
Jonathan, unaware that they were from
pre-Flashpoint continuity. Once he realized the
truth, he fused them with their post-Flashpoint
counterparts and retreated to the fifth
dimension, expressing fear that a greater being,
likely Dr. Manhattan, was hunting him. Later,
Mixie was contacted telepathically by Martian
Manhunter and Starman to assist the Justice
League during a sixth-dimensional, multiversal
crisis. Tricked into believing his 90-day
banishment had ended, Mixie arrived on Earth
unleashing havoc. However, he agreed to help,
once informed that the source walls collapsed
through and the entire multiverse including the
fifth dimension itself. Using his power, he
opened a portal to the sixth dimension for
Superman, explaining he had imbued Superman with
fifth-dimensional energy from their earliest
encounters. After Superman and others departed,
Mixie began erasing parts of the city until
another fifth-dimensional imp, the Batman
superfan known as Batmite, and the Legion of Doom,
intervened and subdued him. And that's Mixie's
backstory. Power-wise, Mr. Mixie Spitalik
possesses nigh-imnipotent abilities derived
from the laws of the fifth dimension, granting him
total control over reality in the third and fourth
dimensions. His powers allowed him to bend,
alter, or ignore the laws of time, space, matter,
and energy at will. He could conjure objects from
nothing, teleport across dimensions, transmute
beings or environments, and warp reality. Immune
to temporal manipulation, he cannot be undone by
time travel or erased by retroactive changes.
Though physically small, he is indestructible,
and his only consistent vulnerability is his
self-imposed rules of banishment, frequently
being just saying his name backward, which
returns him to the fifth dimension for a time. He is
a hyper-intelligent prankster and considered to
be one of the most dangerous entities in the DC
multiverse. If he's so powerful, how come he was
almost taken out by a common cold? It sounds like he
was put into a coma by some standard earthbound
sickness, something that would never happen to an
impossible man. For as powerful as you claim him to
be, he seems largely limited in what he has done,
compared to what he can do. Did you ever hear about
John Burns' fun little Easter egg where he implied
that Mr. Mixie Spitalik is impossible man when he
travels to the Marvel timeline? Like he changes
his form to look like impossible man and they're
actually the same character, across multiple
dimensions. Yeah, I was definitely aware of that,
and that's why I guess I assumed impossible man was
a reality warper, though I guess that's not
accurate. I assume that Burns' theory that he put
out there was debunked when the characters
actually met up in the Superman Silver Surfer
crossover comic. Although you could say that
since pop-upians can duplicate themselves
indefinitely, that they actually are still the
same character. Just different parts of that same
entity. And also since Mixie Spitalik is not bound
by time, so he could have been battling a past or
future version of himself. Now that we got the
characters' histories and abilities out of the
way, let's speculate on how one of the 1000
simulated matches will go. The winner is
determined by simulations, not the speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how the fight could play
out. AJ and I.K., what are the rules of our
speculation? Well, I should say there are no
rules, other than the characters have no prior
knowledge of the other going into the fight. All
they are aware of starting out is that the other
character is a threat that needs to be eliminated.
For the speculation, the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the match
itself, as no environmental statistics are
considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. Alright
then, let's get into it. Mixie and Impey, me on the
battlefield, who goes first? I think Impossible
Man would go first, because he'd just be so excited
for someone to play with. And with a pop sound, all
of a sudden he turns into a 100 foot tall birthday
cake, where each tier of the cake is the size of a
story. A birthday cake? Okay, so Mixie's probably
like, is it my birthday? What the heck? And so he'll
teleport to the top of the cake just to blow out the
candles, and the gust from his breath is going to be
so powerful that it's going to scatter the cake all
across the environment, just spreading Impey
thin everywhere. But all of a sudden, from within
the cake pops out Impossible Man, and he's like,
surprise, congratulations, you get to be my
plaything for the day. And then he transforms into
a firework rocket that shoots right into Mixie's
Biddalock and explodes into these like dazzling
green and purple fireworks. And the display is so
loud and powerful, each one being like a TNT
explosion that Mixie is just blown to smithereens
from the fireworks. Well, I don't think he would be
blown to smithereens, but let's say he's charred
and blackened from the explosion, right? So he's
going to be angry, you know, he'll probably grab
his hat and slam it to the ground and be like, that
does it. And that's when he's going to conjure a
giant vacuum that's going to suck up all of the
sparkly bits of Impey raining down from the sky.
And when the vacuum bag is full, he's going to unzip
it and dump all the sludgy green and purple goop
into a giant trash bag that he's going to tie off and
be like, time to take out the trash. And he's going
to drop kick the trash bag, sending it right into
space. Okay, so Impossible Man is in a trash bag. He
disappears from sight in the atmosphere. But then
all of a sudden, this giant green smiling face
appears in the sky and it gets bigger and larger as
it comes hurtling back down to earth because
Impossible Man teleported out of the trash bag and
then transformed into an asteroid that's in the
shape of his head. And as he comes careening back
onto the battlefield, he's like, here's Impey and
he crashes into and obliterates Mixi Spitalik
into nothing. Well, no, Mixi sees Impey careening
toward him. And that's when he rolls up the sleeves
of a baseball uniform that he's now wearing. And,
you know, he taps his baseball bat to the ground a
couple of times and swings right at the perfect
time, just smashing Impey into a whole bunch of
rocky bits. And he's like, grand slam. He's going
to start rounding the bases in this giant baseball
stadium that he just conjured up. A stadium? Yeah.
Okay. Well, after a bunch of popping sounds, all of
a sudden the stadium fills up with a bunch of
duplicates of Impossible Man who start booing
Mixi Spitalik. And the crowd then starts throwing
tomatoes, like green tomatoes, and purple banana
peels, and knives and grenades. So when he even
throws a shoe and Mixi Spitalik just gets pelted.
Well, Mixi is like, what the heck? And to protect
himself, he's going to teleport into the
Jumbotron, which, you know, has his face on it now.
And he transforms the stadium itself into like
this giant Mecca body with a screen for a face and
metal beams for limbs and cement fists and feet.
And he's just going to start stomping on and
terrorizing those. What is it? Pop-upians? Yeah,
pop-upians. Yeah. Okay. So the crowd of
pop-upians, they're going to flee this Mecca
stadium version of Mixi Spitalik. But then these
Impossible Men start climbing on each other's
shoulders. And they amass themselves into like a
giant composite Sasquatch, like a green
Sasquatch. And the beast is going to swing his arms
into Mecca Mixi, just reducing him to rubble.
Okay. Well, Mixi, he's going to climb out of this
rubble. And he's probably all dirty and cursing.
And all of a sudden a light bulb is going to appear
above his head. And he's going to pull a chain
attached to it. And that's when everything goes
black. But suddenly a spotlight flashes on in the
darkness. And we're going to see Impossible Men in
his regular form standing there just looking
around like, what, where am I? And that's when
another spotlight is going to shine on Mixi, who's
holding this badass electric guitar shaped like
an axe. And he's wearing sunglasses. And he's just
going to shred this gnarly guitar solo. So epic.
What? So powerful that it just shakes Impy to his
very core. And he's so humbled by it that he just
gives up the match. What is happening? So it's a
battle of the bands type thing. Sure. Yep. Okay.
Well, all right. Impossible Men would be game for
that. But like, he's not going to give up. He may be
impressed by Mixi's performance, but he's up for
the challenge. So Impossible Men transforms a
keyboard right in front of him. And it's like this
crazy, multi-tiered looking keyboard with keys
that don't even just go from A to G, but play a range
of notes from A to Z. Okay. And Impossible Men just
starts jamming out a keyboard solo that's so much
more epic and so otherworldly sounding, like
hitting all these chaotic notes. And then
suddenly when his solo is over, Mixi just vanishes
from sight back to the fifth dimension. Why?
Because within Impossible Men's solo, he
randomly spelled Mixi's name backwards using all
those extra music notes. What? Yeah. So part of his
solo was like K, L, C, whatever, however you spell
his name. Backwards. Well, that was convenient.
Okay, but I'm going to say Mixi, since he's from the
fifth dimension, he was able to recognize what was
going on because apparently their music notes
also go up to Z. And before Impi could finish his
solo, that's when Mixi uses his axe guitar to chop
up the keyboard into pieces and then he just
decapitates Impi with it. You think that would
kill him? I don't know. I guess not. But let's say
Mixi is so angry by what almost happened that he's
going to banish the Impossible Man to the fifth
dimension instead, so he's trapped for eternity.
Match over. I'm going to say that Impossible Man
played his solo so quickly that Mr. Mixi Spitalik
didn't even have time to react because he probably
played this with like multiple hands and multiple
arms, you know? Well, no, I mean, Mixi Spitalik
could stop time. Okay. Well, I think that's a good
place to stop. Let's go ahead and input these
character stats and run the simulations and find
out whether Impossible Man pulled off this
reverse name keyboard solo or if Mixi caught on to
him and then banished Impossible Man to the fifth
dimension. We'll find out which of these
scenarios happens when we run the simulations.
8G9K, hit it. Inputting data, running
calculations, processing results, simulations
complete. That was a fun match. These are really
fun characters. They may be one of the most fun
matches I think we've ever done on this podcast. I
mean, the sky was kind of the limit, right? So it was
kind of fun to use my imagination to try to counter
what you were doing. Even just starting off with
their birthday cake is just so unique for our dual
speculations. I don't see that ever happening
again. This was definitely a fun one. Well,
stats-wise, both characters obviously are
insanely powerful. They were both maxed out in so
many stats like speed and invasiveness,
durability and strength. But they both suck at
fighting. You don't really see either of these
guys throwing down in hand-to-hand combat in any
sort of trained or meaningful way. They just have
too much other abilities at their disposal to even
do that. Right. Yeah, both characters are
insanely versatile, although we did give the edge
to Mixi when it came to versatility. Right,
because he can warp reality as opposed to just
transform. He also got the edge in terms of
perception because he can kind of perceive things
outside of the standard three-dimensional space
time. We said he was smarter than impossible man
who's kind of childlike. And we said that Mixi
Spidalik has the edge in damage, considering he's
nearly in nipotent. Not only that, we also gave him
the edge in range, considering Mixi is not really
bound by space. Right. So with all that said,
Jonathan, who do you think is taking this one? It's
no contest. Mixi is totally going to win this. What
a dumbass! Well, what? Okay, if I'm a dumbass, then
so are 73% of our Instagram poll takers who agreed
that Mixi is going to win. You all heard me. I would
be surprised if it was not you who was in fact the
dumbass. Well, let's find out. AJ9K, the results
please. Hey, you are, sir. All right, the winner
between Mr. Mixi Spidalik and Impossible Man is
Mr. Mixi Spidalik. Oh, look at that dumbass! Am I
the dumbass though? Because although Mr. Mixi
Spidalik won 80.3% of his matches over Impossible
Man's 19.7% victory rate, in the end, according to
John Byrne, these guys might be the same
character. So Mr. Mixi Spidalik's win rate is also
Impossible Man's win rate, and I consider this one
a tie. Okay, but even if they're the same
character, you're admitting that the DC version
of the character had the higher win rate. I admit
nothing. I admit it's a tie. How is it a tie when the
percentage is differed? That's just how it works,
man, with like 5th dimensional math. If you can't
wrap your head around it, I don't know what to tell
you. We both win. Yay for Marvel. Way to go, guys. We
did it. You can't beat Crazy, I guess. But that does
it for this duel. AJ9K, help close us out. Send Joe
World and Console Combat. All right, and our next
episode is going to be a team duel. This time we're
going to find out who would win in a fight between
DC's freedom fighters versus Marvel's X Factor.
It's one of the biggest mutant teams that we
haven't gotten to yet. A lot of great characters in
X Factor, and I'm really looking forward to that
match. But that does it for this episode. We want to
give a big thanks to our executive producers, John
Staroski, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Belcom,
Mickey Matankean, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yatyn,
Austin Wizelowski, AJ Dunkerley, Nick Ibonto,
Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Speese, Dean
Maleski, Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, Josh
Leiner, Mike Williams, Oscar Galvez, and Paul
Graves for helping make this podcast possible.
We'll talk to you guys next week. Up, up, and away.
True believers. I'm pretty sure it's pronounced
Mr. Mixio spit on it, hawk-toa.