This is a DynaMic Network podcast. Hi and welcome
to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe and I'm his twin
brother Johnny DC. As you guys probably know, that
was not actually Johnny DC, that was me squeezing
my nostrils. Johnny DC will be out for the first
part of this episode because he is busy getting a
procedure done, and in case that sounds vague,
Jonathan got a kidney stone, which is super
painful, really wishing him the best here. It was
apparently too large to pass so they had to use a
laser and basically play asteroids with the thing
up in his kidney. Not a great time. I don't know how
one gets kidney stones, I think it's largely a
dehydration thing, but since I am also usually
dehydrated and I've never gotten kidney stones, I
can only assume that one actually gets kidney
stones from liking DC. So, public service
announcement to all the DC fans out there, just
switch to Marvel and you won't get kidney stones.
In this episode, Jonathan is going to be joining me
as we find out who's going to win in a fight between
Animal Man vs. The Lizard. And I'm feeling pretty
good about this one. The Lizard is one of
Spider-Man's most formidable foes and I think
he's going to be really impressive statistically
going up against Animal Man, who is probably a
lesser known DC character, but has kind of like a
cult following. He's able to tap into the
abilities of all animals. We'll see who wins later
on this episode. Before that, I'm going to break
down the latest comic book movie news that has come
out over the past month since we haven't really
gotten to the news in a few weeks due to the holiday
season. But there are two important things to talk
about including the fact that Brainiac has been
cast in the Man of Tomorrow movie and we got an
official trailer for the Wonder Man series. As
always guys, we list our segment times in our
episode description so feel free to check out the
show notes if you want to skip ahead to a particular
topic. Our artificially intelligent Duel
simulator AJ9K has a quick message for our
listeners, so listen up. Hello. These are the final
episodes of Dynamic Duel’s weekly podcast, leading
up to our grand finale on January 20, 2026. We hope
you’ve enjoyed the past ten years of Marvel and DC
duels and reviews, and we’d love for you to stick with
us as we count down these last episodes. We’re inviting
you, the listener, to help us close out the show by
visiting dynamic duel dot com over the next few weeks
and clicking the red microphone button in the
bottom-right corner to leave us a voicemail that we’ll
play during the final episode.
Tell us what first got you into DC or Marvel, how long
you’ve been listening, a favorite episode or moment, or
anything else you want to share about what the podcast
has meant to you. Your messages will be aired and
responded to on the January 20 finale. Again, head to
dynamic duel dot com and leave your final message — we
would love to hear from you. Pip, pip, cheerio! Thanks
AJ9K and thanks to everyone who takes the time to
call in and say goodbye to us in a voicemail. Be sure
to tune in to the other shows on the Dynamics
Podcast Network this week including the Konsole
Kombat Podcast where hosts John and Dean simulate
battles between popular video game characters.
They are actually doing a tribute to Dynamic Duel
by doing a DC vs Marvel themed month. So in
yesterday's episode, they found out who would win
between Deadpool from the Deadpool video game and
Lobo from Injustice. That sounds like a good one,
go check that out. Also check out the Max
Destruction Podcast where hosts Scotty and Gilly
pit your favorite action heroes from film and
television against each other. The Macho Twins
this month are also doing a tribute to Dynamic Duel
with the DC vs Marvel theme. They're going to find
out who would win in a fight between the MCU's Agent
Coulson and the Arrow vs John Diggle. That'll be on
Wednesday. And on the Senjoh World Podcast hosts
Zachary Hepburn speculates on fights between fan
favorite anime and manga characters. This month
Zach is revealing who would win between Mob from
Mob Psycho 100 and the tornado of terror from One
Punch Man. Visit DynamicPodcasts.com or click
the link in our show notes to listen to all the shows
in the DynaMic Podcast Network. But now that
that's done, onto the news! Alright in the first
bit of news we learned a few weeks ago that Brainiac
has been cast in the Superman sequel which is
titled Man of Tomorrow. The person playing
Brainiac chosen by James Gunn for the film will be,
let me check my notes here, Lars Eidinger, which of
course everybody knows who that guy is. He was in
Clouds of Sils Maria, obviously, and a movie
called Persian Lessons. Now I'm going to be
honest, I have no idea who this guy is and I don't
think Jonathan does either. He is a German actor
who I will say does not not look the part.
Apparently he did really well in his audition for
the film. Now I'm not the DC guy on this podcast so I
don't know if you guys want to hear my opinion, but I
don't think he's going to bring in any box office
dollars because he has no name recognition and I
think that James Gunn is really banking on the
characters selling the movie as opposed to the
actors themselves. Really David Cornsoit wasn't
a huge name either when he was cast as Superman. And
also I'm not really sure if a name actor is
necessary for Brainiac considering the level of
potential prosthetics or special effects that
will be applied to his performance. We don't know
if they're going to go the green skinned alien
route or the artificial intelligence route. So I
can see this role going anywhere from live action
performance to maybe just a voice role. We'll see
what happens. I will say that this casting
announcement drums up little to no excitement
though. Doesn't mean he'll be bad. We'll have a
better idea of what we're expecting from him once
we get trailers and other marketing material, but
that won't be for a while considering the movie
doesn't come out until summer of 2027. In other
bigger and better news, we got an official trailer
for the upcoming Wonder Man series starting Ya Ya
Abdul Mateen II and Ben Kingsley. The upcoming
series looks like a whole lot of fun. Absolutely
nothing like the comic books. I do appreciate the
angle that they're taking with the show though,
especially considering that Wonder Man was
always unique within the larger superhero
community as being one of the only superheroes who
was also an actor. It appears Marvel Studios has
taken that concept and run with it, making Wonder
Man more of a role that Simon Williams is pursuing
as opposed to an outright hero and member of the
Avengers. While it does take away from who the
character is on the page, I do think it provides a
unique opportunity for originality and
commentary on the state of superhero cinema in
general. They even mentioned within the course of
this trailer that Wonder Man is here to battle
superhero fatigue, which is in reference to the
dwindling box office returns of superhero
theatrical releases, at least compared to a
pre-COVID era. Simon Williams wants to play the
Wonder Man character in a movie that will be a
reboot of a Flash Gordon-esque series that aired
within the MCU, the twist being that Simon
Williams himself has superpowers. I don't know
how they're going to treat the origin of Simon
Williams because in the comic books of course
Wonder Man was a rival to Tony Stark, who was
recruited by Baron Zemo into the Masters of Evil
team who were the enemies of the Avengers, and
Simon was bombarded with ionic energy, making him
super durable, super strong. You can learn more
about Wonder Man in our Duel episode where we pay
him against Captain Adam, that was a fun one. But
this trailer doesn't give any sort of indication
that Yaya Abdul Mateen II's character is in fact a
rival to Tony Stark. So I'm guessing he gets his
ionic superpowers some other way. I don't know if
they're going to make him a mutant, but I'm hoping
that at least his origin involves Baron Zemo in
some capacity, and that his powers are ionic in
nature, otherwise the similarities to the comic
book version of Wonder Man will be too few.
Regardless of how they figure that out, what I'm
really looking forward to in the show are really
the performances of Yaya Abdul Mateen II. I've
been a big fan of his, of course he was in the Aquaman
movies, he was in the Watchman HBO television
series. I'm also a big fan of Ben Kingsley's Trevor
Slattery, even though I still despise what they
did with the character in Iron Man 3. I like how they
kind of developed him over the course of Shang-Chi
and now this show. I'll definitely be checking it
out when the show premieres on January 27th, just a
few weeks from now. But enough of me just blabbing
on in a room by myself. I gotta say doing this is
really hard without a co-host, so let's get
Jonathan on the line. Hopefully he's feeling
better and we'll get this duel started and learn
who would win in a fight between Animal Man and the
Lizard. Alright Jonathan, welcome to the show.
Glad you could join us. How are you feeling? I'm
doing well for the most part. My throat is kind of
gone right now after the forced projectile
vomiting after coming out of anesthesia. So I hate
talking. I'm not loving that I'm talking right
now, but I do it for the fans. You know, even though
we only have two episodes left before our
semi-retirement, it does seem like you're trying
your damnace to make sure that we break our perfect
streak over the past decade. Hey, I've been here
for every episode. My guy, have you? No, that's
fair. Exactly. I did miss an episode when my
daughter was born. Priorities. Yeah, I can't
believe I did that. But as you know, in this
episode, we're going to find out who would win in a
fight between Animal Man and the Lizard. And it's
really going to suck because not only did you get PP
Lazard, but you're also going to lose this match.
So it's like kind of kicking you in the nuts when
you've already been repeatedly kicked in the
nuts. I don't know what makes you so confident.
Like, to me, this is another Vixen Craven matchup.
Who won that one? Craven. Oh, shit. I think. But it
was a coin toss. He only won 502 out of a thousand
matches. Oh, wow. Well, here's where I'm coming
from. I don't think there's anything the Lizard
can do that Animal Man can't. So I think you're the
one who is in fact going to have their PP kicked in.
Well, that's just not true. There are things that
Lizard can do that Animal Man can't. Or at least I
don't think he can. And I'll tell you what those
things are as we get into our backgrounds. Also,
the Lizard has been in a movie, two movies, whereas
Animal Man has not. So Lizard's just better in
general. I think Animal Man was in Teen Titans go to
the movies. Cool. First to explain the
methodology behind our duels, let's go to our
sentient Duel simulator Alfred Jarvis 9000. AJ9K
tell our listeners how you go about determining a
winner in our Duel matchups. Yes, of course, sir.
The way I determine a winner between the
contestants is by running 1000 Monte Carlo
simulations using the characters statistics. A
Monte Carlo simulation is a probabilistic model
used to determine outcomes through random
sampling. In this case, I randomize the
statistics along a normal distribution as a way to
simulate the many variables that can occur during
battle. The stat parameters are based on the
official Marvel power grid from which the DC
characters statistics are extrapolated.
Additional stat categories are included such as
range, damage potential, versatility and
perception in order to create a more detailed and
accurate simulation. The results of the 1000
simulations provide a percentage of wins for each
character. The contestant with the higher
percentage is declared the victor as they have a
higher probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither character should win
100% of the matches. The comic book stories have
shown that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman, so the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks AJ9K. Before
we run the simulations though, we'd like to break
down each character's histories and abilities
before improvising a scenario on how we imagined
one of the 1000 simulations would play out beat for
beat. And it is my turn to go first with the Marvel
character backstory, so let me tell you all about
the lizard. Kurt Connors was born in Coral Gables,
Florida and showed an early aptitude for science
that led him into higher education focused on
biology and biochemistry. While attending
college, he met fellow student Martha and the two
eventually married and had a son, Billy. Connors
pursued a career that blended medical science
with public service, ultimately joining the US
Army where he worked as a field surgeon treating
wounded soldiers in combat conditions. During
his military service, an explosion severely
injured his right arm and the damage was so
extensive that the limb had to be amputated. The
loss of his arm ended Connors' surgical career as
he had envisioned it and became the defining
catalyst of his scientific life. After returning
to civilian work, Connors redirected his
research toward regenerative biology, focusing
specifically on reptiles whose ability to regrow
lost limbs far exceeded anything possible in
human medicine. He became convinced that the
mechanisms behind reptilian regeneration could
be adapted for human use and that the problem was
one of molecular activation rather than
biological impossibility. Working from a
laboratory in Florida, Connors developed an
experimental serum derived from reptilian DNA.
Initial animal testing appeared successful,
demonstrating accelerated tissue
regeneration. Believing he had solved his core
problem and driven by personal desperation,
Connors chose to test the serum on himself. The
experiment succeeded in restoring his missing
arm, but it also produced catastrophic side
effects. Connors' body underwent a massive
transformation, reshaping him into a large
reptilian humanoid with enhanced strength,
speed, durability, and regenerative capacity.
More critically, the transformation altered his
mental state, suppressing his human reasoning in
favor of aggressive, instinct-driven behavior.
The transformed Connors adopted the identity of
the lizard, a creature that viewed human weakness
as a flaw and increasingly saw forced evolution as
a solution. The lizard's activities in the
Florida Everglades drew public attention,
including reports of attacks and sightings that
reached New York. Spider-Man traveled to Florida
to investigate and eventually confronted the
creature. During their encounter, Spider-Man
discovered that the lizard was Kurt Connors and,
using Connors' own research notes, developed an
antidote that forced the lizard back into human
form. You can learn more about Spider-Man in his
duel against Blue Beetle. Although Connors
regained his mind and body, the cure was
temporary. Continued exposure to the
biochemical effects of the serum and the
instability of the transformation meant the
lizard resurfaced repeatedly. Connors
attempted to refine his work to eliminate the side
effects, but each attempt risked another loss of
control. Over time, the lizard emerged not merely
as a physical transformation, but as a recurring
condition tied to Connors' physiology, stress
levels, and experimental exposure. Connors
later relocated his professional life to New York
City, where he became affiliated with Empire
State University, where Peter Parker attended.
There, he worked as a researcher and professor,
earning respect within the scientific community
despite the instability of his condition. During
this period, Peter Parker came into Connors'
orbit as a student and Connors served as a mentor
and academic authority figure. Connors remained
unaware of Parker's identity as Spider-Man, even
as their lives continued to intersect through
repeated confrontations with the lizard.
Connors made ongoing efforts to control or
suppress the transformation rather than simply
reverse it after the fact. He experimented with
chemical inhibitors and neurological
suppressants designed to preserve his human
intellect during transformation or prevent the
lizard from emerging at all. These methods proved
inconsistent. Outside interference also
worsened the condition as criminals and rival
scientists sought to exploit Connors' research
for their own ends, often triggering
transformations through sabotage or coercion.
The instability of Connors' condition placed
increasing strain on his family. Martha grew
distrustful of Connors' assurances that he had
cured himself as each relapse endangered their
son and disrupted their lives. Eventually, she
took Billy and separated from Connors. Martha
later died from cancer, leaving Connors alone and
deepening the emotional consequences of his
failures as both a scientist and a father.
Connors' research was later duplicated and
misused by other scientists. Dr. Vincent Stegron
adapted Connors' work to induce dinosaur-like
mutations in himself while another offshoot of
Connors' experiments resulted in the creation of
the iguana, a mutated being who carried aspects of
the lizard's physiology and behavioral traits.
Connors was repeatedly drawn into conflicts
involving these figures, often assisting
Spider-Man in containment efforts while
struggling to prevent his own transformation.
Connors was also removed from Earth during the
large-scale conflict in which heroes and
villains were transported to an alien world and
forced into battle in a secret war by the beyonder.
Although his experience did not resolve his
condition, it further destabilized his life, and
upon returning to Earth, Connors found his
personal and professional relationships in
worse condition than before. During his research
to fix himself, Connors' young son Billy was
accidentally exposed to the lizard serum,
temporarily transforming into a reptilian form
as well. The stress caused Connors to eventually
lose control over the lizard entirely, and in his
rage, the creature killed his son. The event
completely shattered Connors' psyche, leaving
the lizard as the new dominant personality with
Connors' intelligence but stripped of much of his
emotional restraint and guilt. After Billy's
death, the lizard developed additional
abilities, including the capacity to trigger
violent, primitive behavior in others by
stimulating aggressive responses in the
reptilian complex part of the human brain. This
led to widespread chaos and made the lizard
significantly more dangerous than before.
Spider-Man ultimately defeated the creature by
using Connors' own biochemical work to counter
these effects and force the lizard into a state
where it could be subdued. Despite these events,
Connors continued to exist within the lizard's
body, experiencing his dormant condition as a
form of punishment. He was eventually confined in
high-security facilities, including the raft,
where he accepted imprisonment as a necessary
safeguard. Even in confinement, Connors'
scientific expertise made him a target for
manipulation, particularly by other imprisoned
supervillains seeking to exploit his knowledge.
Connors was later approached with the promise of
restoring his family. He was reunited with
versions of Martha and Billy, only to discover
they were clones created by the Jackal. When the
clones began deteriorating due to a viral
condition, Connors injected them with the lizard
serum in an attempt to preserve their lives,
transforming them into reptilian beings like
himself. In an effort to regain stability,
Connors returned to Empire State University
under strict conditions and accepted the
implantation of an inhibitor device designed to
regulate his transformations. This allowed him
to function publicly while limiting the lizard's
influence, and he was able to stabilize Billy's
cloned body. The inhibitor device was later
removed when Billy was abducted during an
orchestrated hunt involving animal-themed
criminals, allowing Connors to rescue his son.
Afterward, Connors again isolated himself,
retreating underground to prevent any potential
harm. His research remained focused on a
permanent solution, separating or eliminating
his reptilian alter ego. He developed a device
called the isotope genome accelerator that he
believed could split his human self from the
lizard. Connors activated the device under
coercion from Dr. Octopus, who wanted to recruit
the lizard into his new Sinister 6 team. The
isotope genome accelerator succeeded in
separating Connors from the lizard, leaving the
creature as an independent entity, and forcing
Connors to confront the consequences of finally
unleashing the lizard without his own mind acting
as a restraint. That's the lizard's backstory.
Powers-wise, the lizard has enhanced reptilian
physiology, granting him increased strength,
able to lift around 12 tons, increased speed of
around 50 miles per hour, and an increased leaping
ability around two stories. His scaly hide and
dense tissue make him nearly bulletproof, and he
has a regenerative healing factor. He can stick to
walls and surfaces like a gecko, and has
bone-crushing jaws with razor-sharp teeth and
claws that can rend stone. He can whip his powerful
6-foot-long, prehensile tail at 70 miles per
hour, and can control and communicate with
reptilian life within a 2-mile radius, even
influencing the amygdala of humans which
controls aggression, instincts, and the
fight-or-flight response. That is the lizard.
Now let me get into the backstory for Animal Man.
Buddy Baker grew up in California as an average
teenager interested in music, counterculture,
and dating his high school girlfriend, Ellen
Frazier. During a hunting trip in the Adirondack
Mountains, Buddy discovered a crashed alien
spacecraft, though before he could investigate
further, the vessel exploded, bathing Buddy in
unidentified radiation. Later, he returned home
and graDuelly discovered that he could mimic the
physical abilities of animals around him,
drawing upon their speed, strength, agility,
senses, or instincts, and scaling those traits to
human proportions. As a young man, Buddy briefly
attempted a costumed career using these
abilities to promote his band, but lacking
confidence and direction, he abandoned heroics
after little success. Buddy chose a conventional
life, marrying Ellen and starting a family, and
later realized that his powers could be used
professionally, finding steady work as a movie
stuntman where his abilities allowed him to
perform dangerous feats safely. For years, he
kept his powers compartmentalized, using them
for work while suppressing any larger heroic
ambitions. Eventually, Buddy recognized that
ignoring his abilities left him feeling
incomplete. With Ellen's cautious support, he
returned to super heroics under the name Animal
Man, determined to balance family life with a
growing sense that his powers carried deeper
responsibility. Buddy was drawn back into
heroics when he encountered the immortal man and
joined the Forgotten Heroes, a group of displaced
adventurers connected by mysterious ancient
artifacts. He participated in global and
offworld missions, including a journey into
space during the reality-altering Crisis on
Infinite Earths event that reshaped history
itself. Buddy survived, but inconsistencies
began appearing in his memories and origin.
Returning to Earth, Buddy resumed activity as
Animal Man, and increasingly focused on animal
welfare and environmental causes. He
investigated illegal animal testing, clashed
with exploitive corporations, and aided other
animal-themed superheroes such as Bawana Beast
and Vixen. Witnessing institutional cruelty led
Buddy to adopt vegetarianism and become an
outspoken activist. Eventually, Buddy joined
Justice League Europe. While serving with the
team, he gained media attention and public
support, though he resigned abruptly after a
laboratory fire started by an activist animal
rights group he was associated with, injured
innocent firefighters. Following this, Buddy's
powers became erratic. Animals died when he used
his abilities and he experienced lapses in
control. Buddy eventually became aware of two
yellow-skinned observers monitoring his
actions, beings that eventually identified
themselves as members of an alien race known as the
Tailors. They revealed that Buddy had not
survived the spacecraft explosion he
encountered as a teenager, and that his body had
been reconstructed by the Tailors using access to
the planet's morphogenic field, which was fused
into his rebuilt biological template. His
history had been adjusted to stabilize him across
shifts in reality, leaving him aware of changes
caused by universal restructuring such as Crisis
events. As Buddy absorbed this revelation,
reality destabilized further. He encountered
indiviDuels tied to erased histories, witnessed
inconsistencies in time, and he became aware that
his existence followed authored rules. During
this time, corporations threatened by Buddy's
activism arranged the assassination of his
family, and Ellen, his son Cliff and daughter
Maxine were murdered in his absence. Overcome by
grief and rage, Buddy tracked down the assassin
and the executives behind the plot and killed
them. Refusing to accept the loss, Buddy
attempted to undo the tragedy using experimental
time travel. The attempt failed, scattering him
across different eras and further destabilizing
reality. After Buddy's failed attempt to alter
time destabilized his existence, the Tailors
intervened directly and removed Buddy from
linear reality. During this intervention, Buddy
encountered Grant Morrison, the comic author
shaping his reality and he was made aware that he
was a comic book character. The Tailors soon
repaired the timeline, creating a stable
configuration in which Ellen, Cliff and Maxine
were alive while preventing further collapse.
Once the correction was complete, Buddy was
returned home at the moment after his family's
restoration. Though the specifics of the
encounter faded from conscious memory, Buddy
retained the emotional weight of their deaths and
his actions afterward, permanently altering his
outlook and ending his pursuit of power or fame. In
the years that followed, Buddy lived between
family life and limited heroics, though his
powers continued to behave unpredictably.
During one uncontrolled surge, he
unintentionally caused the death of every animal
at the San Diego Zoo. In the public backlash that
followed, Ellen took the children to Vermont to
escape scrutiny while Buddy descended into
isolation and despair. Buddy followed his family
east encountering shamans who identified him as
one of several animal masters, guardians
connected to animal life itself. They revealed
that his daughter Maxine shared his connection
and possessed greater potential. Legally
declared dead and increasingly withdrawn from
public heroics, Buddy continued acting only when
necessary, focusing on animal protection and
environmental intervention rather than
traditional superhero activity. During the
Blackest Night event in which the dead across the
universe were reanimated as Black Lantern
Zombies, Buddy was killed and became a Black
Lantern. His connection to animal extinction
amplified the Blackerings influence over him,
causing him to attack both allies and his own
family while driven by visions of predation,
decay, and death. Buddy was later freed from his
condition when the entity representing the white
light of life and creation intervened, severing
his bonds to death and restoring him. In the
aftermath, Buddy briefly served as a white
lantern. Following the Flashpoint events reset
of DC's continuity, Buddy's powers were no longer
the result of alien intervention but of his
connection to the Red, the elemental force
governing all animal life. The Parliaments of
Limbs, ancient totems representing the
collective will of animal existence, recognized
Buddy as a temporary avatar. Buddy lived publicly
as an actor and environmental advocate while
raising his family in San Diego. When his daughter
Maxine began exhibiting abilities tied to animal
life, Buddy learned the truth of the Red and its
opposing force, the Rocks, an elemental power of
decay and death. Three corrupted emissaries of
the Rocks, known as the Hunters III, targeted
Maxine, believing her to be the Red's future
guardian. To protect his family, Buddy entered
the Red alongside Maxine, where the Parliament
confirmed that Buddy was never meant to
permanently hold the mantle of Avatar. As the
Rocks' influence spread, Buddy was repeatedly
killed and restored, forced to leap through
animal forms and reconstruct himself through the
Red to return to the physical world. Each
resurrection deepened his connection to the Red
while steadily eroding his physical stability,
emotional restraint, and independence. Buddy
allied with Swampthink, the Avatar of the Green,
to confront Anton Arcane, the Rock's champion.
After being trapped within the Rock and later
escaping, Buddy returned to a world already
suffering widespread devastation. As the Rock
corrupted ecosystems and heroes alike, Buddy
fought alongside remaining defenders to contain
its spread. During the final confrontation,
Maxine willingly entered the Rock to shield her
family, demonstrating control beyond Buddy's
own. Together with Swampthink, Buddy defeated
Arcane, but the victory came at great cost.
Buddy's son Cliff was mortally wounded while
protecting his sister and died as a result. The
loss fractured the Baker family. Ellen withdrew
with Maxine, while the Parliament of Limbs
severed Buddy's connection to the Red, vanishing
him from its influence. Stripped of his powers,
Buddy continued investigating animal cruelty
and illegal experimentation, relying on
experience rather than ability. In time,
fragments of Buddy's connection to the Red
returned. He resumed limited heroic activity,
assisting the Justice League when needed and
serving as caretaker for displaced alien animal
life aboard the Watchtower. He also devoted
himself to guiding Maxine as she matured into her
role as animal girl and eventual guardian of the
Red. And that's Animal Man's backstory.
Power-wise, Animal Man is connected to the
morphogenic field known as the Red, allowing him
to access and combine the physical abilities,
instincts, and senses of any animal, while
scaling those traits to human proportions. He can
enhance his strength, speed, durability,
agility, and perception, while also gaining the
abilities to regenerate, communicate with
animals, and even reshape his body or transfer his
consciousness into animal forms. His connection
extends beyond Earth to extraterrestrial life,
allowing him to gain abilities of alien animal
life as well. And that's Animal Man. Is he able to
tap into multiple abilities at once or is it just
one at a time? Yes, he can actually. Okay, yeah. His
versatility does frighten me a little bit,
especially when you consider the fact that he can
tap into alien animal abilities, which, what,
that makes no sense. I thought the Red and the Green
were tied into Earth's fields. No, it's a
universal thing. That's why Swamp Thing could
teleport to other planets. I haven't seen Buddy do
alien life too often, because I think it's weird
for him, and it may not do it during the
speculation, but it has been done. How does he even
know what the abilities of alien animal life are?
Well, he gets sense where he's pulling them from.
That's stupid. Does it take longer to tap into them
if their galaxy's away? No, I don't believe so. It
kind of feels like it makes his power set infinite,
right? This is stupid. Wow, you sound jealous.
Like a jealous bitch. I'll be interested in seeing
how that plays out during the speculation if it
does it all. It shouldn't, is what I'll say. But now
that we've got the characters' histories and
abilities out of the way, let's speculate on how
one of the 1000 simulated matches will go. The
winners determined by simulations, not the
speculation, but it's fun to imagine how the fight
could play out. A.J. and I.K., what are the rules of
our speculation? Well, I should say there are no
rules, other than the characters have no prior
knowledge of the other going into the fight. All
they are aware of starting out is that the other
character is a threat that needs to be eliminated.
For the speculation, the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the match
itself, as no environmental statistics are
considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. All right,
then let's get into it. Animal man and the lizard
meet on the battlefield. Who goes first? I'm going
to say that the lizard goes first because he's
smart in calculating and everything like that,
but he's also ferocious, so he's going to hunch
down and zoom across the floor like a cracked out
crocodile, and he leaps an animal man and just
chomps down right down on his head. All right, but
as the lizard is coming for him, animal man is going
to quickly burrow underground like a mole, and
kicking up all that dust, it's going to be hard for
the lizard to see. So as he's like looking around
for animal man, that's when animal man is just
going to come up from the ground like a trap door
spider, pull lizard down with him, and then bite
him with this paralyzing venom. I don't think that
animal man would have teeth that were sharp enough
to get through the lizard's hide. Like bullets
can't pierce the lizard. I don't think spider
fangs can even proportionately. So animal man
tries to bite the lizard, but it's like trying to
bite through like hardened thick leather, and
because of that lizard just slashes out animal
man's jugular with his claws, and then crawls out
of the hole. Okay, but animal man, he uses the
healing ability of an axolotl to heal up his neck,
and then he's going to just fly straight out of the
hole right into the sky, and he's going to use the
sight and diving ability of an eagle, like a golden
eagle, to dive bomb the lizard at like 200 miles per
hour, and that's going to knock him unconscious.
No, lizard uses his tail like a Louisville
slugger, and spins around and just whips it at
animal man at like 70 miles per hour, but with like
way more force. So animal man gets the shit slapped
out of him, lands about 100 yards away, but
completely unconscious. Okay, but if the lizard
noticed animal man dive bombing came from the sky,
animal man's eagle like gaze is going to see that he
was spotted. So at the last second, animal man is
going to take on the weight of an elephant. So he
doesn't get knocked away, he's just going to land
splat on the lizard on the ground. Okay, that would
definitely hurt. I feel like it would hurt both of
them, right? Like if animal man is crashing into
his opponent with the speed of an eagle and the
weight of an elephant, they would both get
smashed. Okay, okay, let's go with this. Animal
man was traveling with the speed of an eagle with
the weight of an elephant, but the durability of a
cockroach, which could basically fall from like
space and be fine. So he gets to crawl out of the
small crater he probably just created back onto
his feet. No problem. Sure. Okay, so animal man is
fine. Lizard though, you know, he'll have like a
broken tail, probably broken ribs, lots of broken
bones all over his body. But you know what? He
heals. He is regenerative. And to allow him time to
do that, he's going to tap into the reptilian
complex of animal man's brain activating his
flight response. So animal man flees away from the
lizard, leaves the scene until he gets about like
two miles out, which is the range of lizards
psychic reptile control. And also the lizard made
animal man flee as slow as a tortoise. So by the time
the animal man comes back to the battle, lizards
all healed up and ready to get back into the fight.
Wait, what do you mean as slow as a tortoise? Like,
can the lizard control what reptile the human
behaves like? No, no, no, no. But like he tapped
into animal man's amygdala, which is connected to
the red and therefore connected to the greater
reptilian kingdom, right? So lizard just
inadvertently gave animal man tortoise speed
because tortoises are reptiles. It's science.
Don't worry about a right. Well, animal man, he's
going to run back to the battle with the speed of
like a thoroughbred horse. And as he approaches
lizard, he's going to do this acrobatic flip like a
monkey and he's going to spit in his face midair
with squid ink that's going to blind lizard. So
while lizard is like trying to wipe the ink away,
animal man is going to grab him from behind and just
overload him with electricity using the power of
an electric eel. So lizard just got electrocuted
to death. Match over. Okay, really like
temperatures the lizards weakness because he's
cold blooded. So it would make sense that
electricity would knock him out, but he also
causes reptiles to freak out basically. So that's
what's going to happen. He freaks out
instinctively and just like lashes out in a frenzy
of fangs and claws. And that's just going to
eviscerate animal man like he was put into a
blender just limbs all over the battlefield. And
I'm sure the animal man can like regenerate from
that. But by that point, lizard has already
psychically incapacitated animal man's
amygdala. So match over. No, no, no, no. Because
animal man, you know, with him being aware of the
meta reality of this podcast speculation, he's
just going to step out of the environment and
compress the audio waves that make up the lizards
existence until it's silent. So lizards actually
gone. What are you talking about? Is he like all
powerful? That's happening. Shh. Silence. That
would make him as strong as like a godlike
character. If he could just like control reality
like that. Hey, he's done it in the comics before he
compressed Ultraman into a comic panel. And this
is because he can tap into the reality altering
powers of alien animals or something. Well, yeah,
for a time he was outside of reality and has
remained aware of his nature. That's stupid. You
know what? I'm glad we waited this long for animal
man because he's a much worse character than I ever
thought he was. We'll go ahead and leave the
speculation there either lizard eviscerates
animal man and then prevents him from
regenerating or animal man pulls some stupid
bullshit about the fourth wall. Let's go ahead and
input the character stats, run the simulations
and come back with a winner. Agenon K hit it.
Inputting data, running calculations,
processing results, simulations complete. All
right. Yeah, this matchup was kind of comparable
to the Vixen versus Craven the Hunter Duel
matchup. The biggest difference between lizard
and Craven the Hunter, I think statistically was
fighting skill. Craven the Hunter is very adept at
hand to hand combat, whereas the lizard operates
primarily on instinct. Yeah, lizard was kind of a
one trick pony as well. Craven had a higher
versatility, but not as high as versatility as
animal man does. Yeah, there's a ton of stuff that
the animal kingdom can do. Everything from like
shooting out boiling water at their opponents to
camouflaging to stunning with electricity. It's
a lot and he could do all of it. There were a lot of
things that these two guys were comparable on,
including durability. Actually, that's it.
Lizard was much more intelligent than animal man.
Yeah, that by far was the biggest discrepancy.
Everywhere else, they were pretty much tit for
tat. So all things consider Jonathan, who's taken
this match? Well, since I did not run a poll
yesterday, because I was in the hospital. I have no
idea who our listeners would have voted for, but
I'd like to think that they would have voted for
animal man, because they're smart. I don't think a
lot of people know who animal man is. I think a lot of
people would have instant name and visual
recognition with the lizard and therefore vote
for him. Yeah, but I feel like most people who are
aware of the lizard are so because of the awful
Spider-Man movie, and it would just leave a bad
taste in their mouth. They wouldn't vote for him.
You might be right. I do feel like the Spider-Man
movies undersold the lizard, but let's go ahead
and see who won. AJ9K, the results, please. Here
you are, sir. All right, the winner in the Duel
matchup between animal man and the lizard is
animal man, because he sucks, because he sucks.
That's why he won. And it wasn't that close. Out of
1000 simulated matches, animal man beat the
lizard 68.6% of the time, whereas the lizard only
won 31.4% of his matches. Not a strong showing, for
as impressive as the lizard is statistically, he
just, I guess, cannot compete with all the powers
of the animal kingdom and also that bullshit alien
power animal thing, whatever. Yeah, animal man is
a pretty unique character. What about Vixen? He's
more unique than Vixen. The dude met Grant
Morrison. Grant Morrison is a bum. You know what?
I'm just gonna say it. I'm sick of Grant Morrison
and all of his weird ideas and dumb meta bullshit.
Because of this match, I will forever no longer be a
fan of his. I guess Batman and Deadpool met him
recently too, which is so dumb. The guy has got to
get over himself. He's just, he's got to get over
himself. Fuck you, Jonathan. Why me? Just
because. Let's go out and end this. That does it for
this Duel guys. AJ9K, help close this out. Thanks
for listening to Dynamic Duel. Visit the show's
website at dynamicDuel.com and follow us on
Instagram at Dynamic Duel podcast. Don't forget
to listen to the other shows in the Dynamite
podcast network, including Max Destruction,
Senjoh World, and Konsole Kombat. All right, guys,
like we said earlier, there's only two episodes of
the podcast in its current format left, and these
next two are huge. Like it does not get bigger.
That's right, our next episode is going to be a duel
between DC and Marvel. What does that mean? You'll
have to tune in next week and find out. It's our last
Duel episode. It's our last team Duel episode. So
we're going out with a bang. It is the duel to end all
duels. That does it for this episode, guys. Thanks
again to our former executive producers, and
we'll talk to you next week. Up up and away, true
believers. Partition level data corruption and
who boy? Let me tell you that blockage is painful.