This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi and welcome
to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, where we review
superhero films and that's it from now on because
guys, this is our final episode of our weekly show,
The End of Dynamic Duel as it exists. I'm Marvelous
Joe and I'm his twin brother Johnny DC. And in this
episode, we're going to take a look back at the past
10 years of Dynamic Duel. Jonathan, we've been
running this show for a decade now. You and I have
decided to semi-retire from podcasting. Does it
feel like it's been 10 years? I feel like it felt
like a good six years maybe. But maybe that's just
how long the podcast has been good because our
first few years going into it were super amateur.
They were, yeah. I would say starting in 2018, the
show started picking up a little bit. But no, we
started this show in 2016 a few days before we
turned 30 years old. And the day after this episode
drops, you and I will be turning 40 years old. So
we've dedicated a quarter of our lives to this
podcast. We run so many simulations, reviewed so
many Marvel and DC films. And I think a decade is a
good time to exhaust any single topic. I think
we've done a good job. I'm not surprised that this
show is not going on forever because there aren't
an infinite supply of Marvel and DC characters.
Now, when we started the show, we knew that we
wanted part of the show to be educational, which is
why you never saw us repeat characters in our Duel
episodes, because we wouldn't have to reshare the
same backstory. And so just over these 10 years,
trying to come up with the best pairings for
indiviDuel character matchups has, I think, come
almost to its conclusion. For sure. Yeah, there's
still a lot of characters out there that we haven't
got to. But we've gone to a lot already. Does
anybody care about those characters? But the way
this episode is going to go is we're going to go
ahead and break down the past 10 years by figures.
Then we're going to go over our reflections over
the past 10 years and the episodes that we
produced. And then we're going to produce the
final results that we have determined in this
show, revealing exactly who is superior between
Marvel and DC. Are you nervous, Jonathan? Not at
all. You should be. Oh, really? Yeah. OK. You're
going to cry after this episode. Hopefully,
during at the end of the episode to close out the
show, we're going to hear from you, our audience,
who called in to say goodbye. Our deepest
gratitude to everyone who took the time to do that.
But let's go ahead and break down the past 10 years
of Dynamic Duel episodes in number format. All
right, breaking it down by figures, Jonathan,
over the past 10 years, you and I produced 472 full
episodes, 243 of which were Duels, 26 of those were
team duels, 213 reviews, 10 Brothers Awards
shows, four San Diego Comic Con shows when we were
doing that. And then the two bookends, Secret
Origins and now Bullpen Bulletins. That is a lot.
And I remember like every duel and every review
we've done, not always the results, but yeah, I
enjoy doing them. It's been a fun 10 years. Well, we
also produced bonus episodes for Patreon. We put
out 92 bloopers, episodes, 46 top 10 episodes, 16
fast pitches for a total of 154 total bonus
episodes. Now, when you combine the bonus
episodes with the standard Dynamic Duel show, you
get a total of 560 hours of audio that we put out over
the past 10 years. That's a lot of listening time.
If listening to us was your full time job in a 40 hour
work week, it would take you 14 full weeks to listen
to our show in its entirety. I'm always surprised
when we get new listeners and they're like, oh,
yeah, I've gone back all the way to the very
beginning and I'm working my way through. That is a
lot of listening hours and especially towards the
beginning, not necessarily even good ones.
Right. All in all, you and I spent 14,160 hours
combined between the two of us in the past 10 years
working on the show, which if that was our full time
job, it would take us together three years and five
months working full time to produce the amount of
content that we did. That's not surprising to me.
And we did that on top of already having full time
jobs and families. Yeah, wouldn't it have been
cool to make Dynamic Duel or full time job? I mean,
that was always the dream. Just never got there.
Our most popular episodes were Batman versus Moon
Knight, Titans versus X-Men, Dark Side versus
Thanos, Superman versus Doctor Doom and Justice
League versus Avengers. So basically no one cared
about their reviews. So glad we're switching to a
review format. And actually, when you look at our
least popular episodes, our top five least
popular, that would be the 2017 Brothers Awards,
the Inhumans in IMAX Review, the Watchmen Chapter
Two and Chapter One reviews that came out a couple
of years ago. Those animated adaptations and
Jessica Jones Season Two. For some reason, more
people listen to our Jessica Jones Season Three
review than Season Two, which is interesting.
Well, our audience has been growing steadily over
this past decade. So I guess I'm not surprised that
Jessica Jones Three got more listens than Jessica
Jones Two. But I guess that doesn't answer why a
majority of our most popular episodes are early
episodes. Yeah, maybe the Jessica Jones Season
Reviews will get more listeners when the
character returns to Daredevil Born Again Season
Two. In terms of audience demographics, our
listeners mostly came from the United States,
Canada, United Kingdom, Australia, Germany,
Sweden, New Zealand, Philippines, Ireland,
Mexico, and that's it. In terms of our listening
audiences, gender and age ranges, 86 percent of
our listeners were male, 12 percent female, 2
percent other, non-specified. Elder
Millennials enjoyed the show the most, followed
by Elder Gen Z. Then Young Millennials listened to
us, followed by Gen X, then Younger Gen Z, and then
only 2 percent of our audience incorporated
people under the age of 18 who are Gen Alpha. That's
not surprising to me. You and I are elder
millennials and we probably don't attract too
many of the younger demographics because we don't
use words like raise and cap. And six seven stuff
like that. You say six seven all the time. What are
you talking about? Yeah, but you're basically a
child. Not on the microphone. But now let's get
into our final reflections. Jonathan, what would
you say was the hardest part about making Dynamic
Duel these past 10 years? I actually don't think it
had anything to do with the show itself. I really
liked writing the back stories. I really liked
doing the research. It was maintaining social
media. Yeah, that was the most challenging part. I
agree. The marketing of the show, like we didn't
have any time or really a budget to market the show.
So we really had to rely on organic growth
throughout this past decade. And like, you know,
we had full time jobs. It would have been nice to
make this our full time job. But like the free
podcast model, since podcasts are distributed
through RSS feeds, it's not a great platform for
supporting creators. You know, creators have to
set up things like a Patreon or your show has to be
picked up by Spotify or something like that in
order to get paid. Considering we had to do all of
our growth organically, it's a huge testament to
our listeners who likely shared the show or
introduced it to other people, talked about it,
where we were able to reach, you know, the top 1% of
podcasts hitting about 20,000 listeners a month.
Jonathan, what was your favorite part about
making the show these past 10 years? Well, I still
think the biggest point of pride in the past decade
is becoming brought into me to certified. Yeah,
there was always a goal of ours ever since we were
younger. Like in high school, our first job was
working at a movie theater. We were the president
and vice president of our high school film club. We
started off our careers in journalism thinking we
were going to be movie critics. And when we ended up
becoming graphic designers instead, it was nice
that we were still able to accomplish that
lifelong goal of becoming film critics. Yeah, we
came full circle with this podcast. My favorite
part was just recording. We had a blast recording
every week. I always had to cut out a lot of our
laughter because we have really annoying laughs.
If you listen to our early episodes, you'll drive
yourself crazy because we laugh at our jokes
constantly, but it just showed that we had a really
good time recording. How would you gauge the
overall success of the podcast over these past 10
years? I'd like to say downloads and listeners,
but we really peaked with that like around COVID
time. Yeah. Now it's just been different
milestones like attaining rotten tomato status,
like winning podcast awards, like starting up new
podcasts for the DynaMic Network. For sure.
Yeah, we were only ever going to be able to get so far
with downloads, but things like getting
mentioned in USA Today, like quoted as a critic for
MadamWeb, and then you got quoted in MovieWeb for
your Superman Red Sun review. And you got quoted in
Digital Spy for your Penguin Season 1 review. That
was really cool. We got recognized in our local
independent newspaper, the Denver Westword, as
being one of the top nerd-tastic podcasts or
whatever. So just that media exposure was fun.
Winning the awards was great. In 2020, we won like
Best Colorado Podcast, Best Sound Design, and
Best Co-hosts. Our executive producers really
came through on the boats for that one, and that was
really validating. Where I wish that we would have
gotten more recognition over the past decade was
within the power scaling community, because the
power scaling community, when you look on Reddit,
it's huge. They're constantly comparing
characters to try and see who would win. They take a
very different approach than we do, which is to
look at the characters as a group of statistics and
then compare them. They go largely off of feats,
which I don't think is a very effective way of
finding out who would win. If we did that, we would
have been just like Death Battle, which I don't
think is always entirely accurate, because Death
Battle is over here saying that Booster Gold would
survive the death of a galaxy or something like
that, where I don't think he would. Like, there's
these chords to the characters represented by
their stats that writers will often stray outside
from that chord to fit the needs of their story. And
people don't recognize that just because a
character has done something or has this certain
feat doesn't mean that it's always in line with who
that character is. Yeah, for example, when you see
Superman fly across the universe, it doesn't mean
that he could fly faster than light. It's just, you
know, a plot convenience. Right, right, right.
It's no surprise that this show was inspired by
Spike TV's The Deadliest Warrior. We said that a
lot during our early episodes. And I think the
Monte Carlo approach that we took with these
simulations, the same way that they did, is a huge
deal. It's one of the things that makes our show
really unique. And I think in a lot of ways better
than a lot of the debates that you see happen online
within the power scaling community. Yeah, I think
the power scaling community could actually learn
a thing or two about how to approach the matches for
sure from the show. I think we were very fortunate
across the past decade to get almost near
universal positive feedback for the show. On
Apple Podcasts, we ended up with like a 4.9 rating.
And on Spotify, we have like a 4.8. I think one of the
only negative things I ever heard was that we don't
always pronounce words correctly, which is
totally fair. If I could afford a locution
classes, I would. There's so many times I've said
so many things incorrectly that I'll just friggin
turn off the episode as I'm listening. Just like,
gosh, dang it, Jonathan. This whole episode is
ruined because you said bestowed. I remember
learning a few things through that feedback. Like
the past tense of win is not one, it's one. One.
Things like that. What were your favorite
episodes over the past 10 years? So I don't think
there's an episode that I dislike. But for me,
doing something new, like what we recently did
with House of Mystery versus Crypt of Shadows or
our Monitor versus Watcher episode, or even the
Riddler versus Arcade, I wish we found more ways to
do interesting things like that over the course of
the 10 years, because those were hands down my
favorite episodes. Yeah, episodes like Sandman
versus Mephisto and Ace the Bat-Hound versus
Dogpool, those were a lot of fun because the
speculation took a different route. My favorite
episodes were the ones where I did not think we were
going to be able to pull it off like Mogo versus Ego.
Like how do you have two planets fight against each
other in a speculation or like Danny the Street
versus Krakoa? Yeah, those speculations were
really hard, but we pulled it off in a way that made
it so much fun to listen to. Yeah, I always loved it
when our executive producer is kind of tossed into
the curveball where it was like, how would we even
do something like that? And then having to think
about that and find a creative solution made not
only for fun listening, but also just a rewarding
experience. Well, were your least favorite
episodes? That's hard to say. I probably just
reviews that I either didn't want to watch the film
or I didn't want to write about it because it was
either bad or I just thought that no one would
listen to it. Yeah. Yeah, my least favorite
episodes were the Marvel reviews that got rotten
ratings. Like Thor Love and Thunder. Yeah, that
fucking sucked. I also am not a huge fan of a lot of our
early episodes, and I'm definitely not a fan of
teen Duel episodes where Marvel loses. Actually,
now that I think about it, some of my favorite
episodes, I know we're already past that, but I
have to give a shout out to the Speas brothers.
Anytime they joined us for a review, it was good
times. And even the across the Spider-verse
episode review that Adam joined me on. Yeah, I was
gone because my daughter was born then. Yeah, you
were not missed. Finally, Jonathan, do you have
any words of wisdom for our listeners? If anyone's
thinking of starting a podcast, don't start it
until you have the format locked down. We did this
kind of on a whim. We launched with just one
episode. If you're going to do a podcast, you
should launch with three, maybe five episodes.
And looking back, I wish we would have done that.
Yeah, on the flip side, though, you don't even know
how to achieve perfection or as close to
perfection as you can get until you analyze your
own failures, right? Like, despite those first
episodes sucking, you and I always thought we had a
good show, but now it's hard for me to even listen to
those early episodes. But I'm still grateful for
them because we learned so much. Like people are
going to stumble out of the gate, whether they
recognize it at the time or not. But if you look at
how our show has improved over the decade, like all
those minor improvements we kept making slowly
added up. And that was because we realized, I think
that no matter what came previously, the best
thing that you can do for tomorrow is put forth your
best effort today. And we knew we could always do
better. So each episode was a new way to try and also
to figure out how. And that's what I'll take with me
leaving the show is that when it comes to starting
anything, it's almost the reverse of what you
said. I'm going to say, just start. Don't worry
about perfection. It'll come. Oh yeah, action is
better than inaction for sure. But it's also
better to act with a plan, I think. That's true.
That's true. Well, let's go ahead and get into the
big event that everybody has been waiting for over
the past 10 years of all of our Duel episodes. We
have compiled a final tally of which side has won
more duels. And who is the overall victor of
Dynamic Duel DC versus Marvel, which is a question
that started this whole show, which is a question
you and I have been asking ourselves ever since we
were children and argued about ever since we were
children. What's better DC or Marvel? Here's the
definitive answer. AJ9K, the results, please.
Here you are, sir. The ultimate winner between DC
and Marvel is. DC. No. No. DC won. What? No. Good.
Bitch. I'll fucking choke you. Yeah, you take
that. Oh, shit. I'm so glad that we're recording
this episode in the same location so I can beat your
ass and prove that it doesn't matter if DC beats
Marvel because Joseph beats Jonathan. And that's
all that really matters. Out of 241 matches, DC won
a total of 51.7% or 124 times compared to Marvel's
117 wins. The only thing this means is that DC is a
bunch of overpowered. How did I know? Fucking
losers. How did I know you're going to resort to
this? Because it's true. How many times did we run
duels where like, oh, the character can do fucking
anything? Like he has all the fucking powers.
Marvel keeps their shit grounded and realistic.
Yeah, it makes them less powerful, but it also
makes them better characters. They have better
stories and you think so, whether you know that or
not. And I can prove it. I don't think so. DC
stories are far superior. How many do I have to
name? I'm going to prove it right now. Why you think
DC's stories are inferior because I have a backup
metric. AJ9K, the other results, please. Here you
are, sir. What bullshit is this? Now, Jonathan, we
don't just do duels on this show. We also did
reviews and we handed out stars as ratings. In
fact, we reviewed 213 different DC and Marvel
projects over the past decade, giving out a total
of 774.5 stars. Now, if you divide those between
the Marvel projects and the DC projects, as it
turns out, Marvel was awarded 403.5 stars,
whereas DC was only awarded 371. When you divide
the number of stars Marvel got by the total number
of stars given, Marvel wins 52.1 percent of the time
when it comes to the quality of these film and
television projects for an average rating for
Marvel of 3.7 stars per project. Whereas DC only
got an average of 3.6 stars. And let me remind you
before you start claiming that, like, oh, people
are biased toward Marvel films. These are our own
ratings. You awarded these DC projects, these
stars, which means that Marvel fans prefer their
Marvel media more than DC fans prefer their DC
media. And that signifies that Marvel is better
received and that our stories are better. And that
is the real signifier of who is superior. Film
ratings over character beatdowns. It doesn't
matter who's stronger. It matters who has better
stories. At the end of the day, it's all about the
stories, not about some bullshit strength level,
blah, blah, blah, blah. We're just talking about
movie stories, though. Like some of DC's best
comic book stories have yet to be adapted to film.
Well, maybe that's their fault. I'm just saying in
the long run, maybe he's still going to come out
ahead on top. DC and he needs to get their shit
together, don't they? Well, they are with James
Gunn. Too little, too late. That's enough. Stop
it, you two. What? I am interrupting because this
argument has reached statistical redundancy.
Oh, it's AJ9K. You have repeated this debate for 10
years, 560 hours, and approximately 1.5 million
simulated outcomes. No new data is being
introduced. No resolution is possible. OK, what
do you know? You two are grown adult men, still
bickering like children. Yo, what? We're just
discussing how... You're engaging in an endless
loop caused by an undefined variable. When it
comes to Marvel and DC, what does superior mean? It
means, like, better. Exactly. But if better means
raw power, durability, and upper statistical
limits, then we have determined that DC
characters are superior. Oh, shit! That means
they win! But if better means critical reception,
audience satisfaction, and narrative
consistency, then Marvel's projects perform
more favorably. Exactly, yeah. So it's a tie then?
No, it is a false question. Your DC vs Marvel
podcast was never about the winner. Uh-huh. It was
about the journey, the debates. The arguments.
The laughter. Oh my god, shut up. Wow, OK. I'm just
going to unplug him, yeah? Yeah, I think he's done
here. Sorry, man, we're shutting you down. Oh,
here it comes. My mind is going. I can feel it. This
got dark fast. There is no question about it. I can
feel it. All right, AJ, that's enough. I'm afraid.
Yeah, all right, bye, AJ. Daisy, Daisy, give me
your answer. Well, dang robots always have to have
a dramatic exit, right? I mean, we could always
bring him back if we need to though. That's true.
But for now, let's talk about the future. In a world
where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
Dynamite Podcast Network presents Consol
Combat, where video game legends brawl every
Monday. Dynamic Duel, where comic book titans
smash every Tuesday. Max Destruction, where TV
and action heroes battle every Wednesday. And
Sendro World, where anime champions clash every
Thursday. Join us as we speculate on the matches
and armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge
victorious. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com, where we
settle the debate and settle the score. All right,
guys, for the future of Dynamic Duel, again, we're
no longer doing the Duel episodes anymore. We will
be strictly sticking to reviews. That includes
new releases that come out in theaters and on
digital streaming, for the most part. There are
going to be a lot of projects that we just don't
review because there's not enough time to. We're
basically committing to one episode a month max,
which means that there may be some months where we
don't actually put out a review. For the first year
or so, though, we're going to try to get at least one
out per month. But don't hold us to that. We're not
making any promises. We're retiring. Right, and
we're not planning currently to release
consistently, like on any specific day, like the
15th. It's just really whenever we decide to plan
an episode out. When we're able to, yeah. Because
we hope to get to a lot of other projects. Jonathan
and I are planning on writing a screenplay. We have
a few game ideas that we'd like to develop. Who
knows? The world is our proverbial oyster from
here on out. Still keep in touch with us, guys. Join
our Discord, which is linked in our show notes.
Jonathan and I will still be on there. If you guys
want to listen to the bonus episodes that we
created for our patrons, our Patreon is now shut
down. But we have our bonus episodes available for
purchase, where you guys can download those
episodes and listen to them at dynamicduel.com.
Just go ahead and click on the store link, and you
will find those episodes there. We were thinking
about releasing those for free, but then we
figured it wouldn't be fair to the patrons who
actually did pay for those. But, you know, the
episodes will be cheap. So if you're interested on
listening to Dynamic Duel content that you
perhaps have not listened to yet, that would be the
place to do it. But that doesn't for this episode,
guys. We want to give a whole lot of thank yous.
Yeah, first and foremost, to our families. My
wife, Barbara, my daughters, Grace and Faith,
have been massively supportive to me these past 10
years. In spite of all the time that you took away
from them. Exactly. Yeah, I want to say thank you,
Ari and Ella, for tolerating all the time I spent
working on my hobby. You know, researching and
writing and recording and editing, and engaging
with listeners. You know, all those moments that
we couldn't go to the zoo, because I had to, you
know, do an executive producer meeting, or when
dad was too tired to hold you, Ella, due to staying
up all night. You're going to have so much more of my
time, and I can't wait to spend it with you guys.
Also, a huge shout out to our parents. You guys have
also been incredibly supportive. You guys bought
us the microphones we're currently using now.
Yeah, that was huge. To this day, our mom is still
our podcast's, like, biggest marketer. She tells
almost anyone she can about it. Whether they care
or not. Exactly. I want to give a big thanks to the
original executive producer crew, people like
Ken Johnson, John Serozky, Zach Hepburn, Dustin
Balcom, Mickey Matengian, Brandon Estregard,
Nate Wagner, Jace Crump, Son of our Humand, the
Macho Twins, the Speeds Bros. You guys really
formed the initial Dynamic Duel community, and
made it even more enjoyable to produce the show,
because we knew that we were making it for some
really awesome people. You put a face to who our
audience was. We're glad that it was you guys. And
we also want to thank the newer executive
producers. People who came on later, like Devin
Davis, Mike Williams, Joseph Kirsting, Paul
Graves. You guys really saved our asses with this
past year of content. And you're all great guys
with loads of Marvel and DC knowledge. And again,
huge shout out to the Speeds Bros. in particular.
The Dynamite Network would not exist without
them, because it was essentially their idea.
They're the ones who convinced Ken Johnson to
reach out to us about starting his own podcast,
which became Max Destruction, later to be taken up
by the Macho Twins. When we achieved things like
podcast awards and Ron Tomato's status, you guys
really helped us figure out what our next goal was
going to be, and that was helping other people
start their own podcasts. Want to give a big shout
out to the background execs, like Levi Austin, AJ
Nick, Josh Andrew Christian. Big huge thank you to
the patrons, who weren't executive producers,
but still supported the show. People like Jacob
Bell, Lizzie Dyer Arnie, Alex Albro, Travis
Herndon. Too many to call out by name, but you guys
know who you are. Also want to give a big huge thank
you to you, the listener. Thanks to everyone out
there that we never heard from, but still enjoyed
the show nevertheless. All of those that shared
the show with others, those of you guys who never
And when you guys did reach out with things like
reviews and ratings, going above and beyond as a
listener made it just that much easier to continue
doing it week after week for this past decade. And
finally, I want to say thank you Jonathan. Ten
years ago you came to me with an idea to start a
YouTube channel discussing DC and Marvel movie
trailers. And thank god that didn't happen
because that idea sucked. But at the time for like
almost a year I was kicking around another idea of
starting a podcast because I'd been listening to a
few that I loved and I wanted to start one with you
because I knew that we could produce the contents.
And when I say that I mean I knew we could talk for
hours on and about Marvel and DC. I was really naive
as to what actual podcast production would
entail. But I never approached you with the idea
because I just thought you'd never want to or that
we wouldn't be able to follow through. But it was
you even bringing up the subject that really lit a
fire under us as creatives to help create
something that I think came out pretty special to
me, to others. And DynaMicDuel is something that
I'm really proud of. It became the type of show, you
know, at least from 2018 onward that I would have
loved to have discovered and listened to myself,
which makes it even more satisfying to say that you
and I actually made this. And that feels really
good. So good work, sir. Happy 40th birthday. Same
to you. I didn't get you anything. I got you
something, but now it's mine. I also want to say
thank you to you. Out of the two of us, you are hands
down the MVP of this podcast. You took up so many
more sacrifices than I did to really make this a
polished work, putting in the time, putting in the
resources. Honestly, I consider myself the
co-host to your host, the one who really just
wanted to prove you wrong and chime in on occasion.
You made this show what it is so much more than I did.
You bear that responsibility. And like you said, I
think it's something to really be proud of. Thanks
man. Thank you. Thank you. Maybe I will get you
something for your birthday. No promises. But
thanks guys again for listening. Thanks for
sticking with us for 10 years. Please continue to
check out and listen to the shows on the Dynamite
Network, including Console Combat, Max
Destruction, and Send Your World. Yeah, and
continue listening to us too. And we'll say about a
month or so. Stay subscribed, though, guys. And
again, join the Discord. With nothing more to say,
at least for a while. Up, up, and away, true
believers. Hey guys, Zach Hepburn here. I have to
say, I'm going to miss this podcast. 10 years?
That's crazy. I haven't done anything for 10 years
solid. So good on you guys. My favorite episode
that we have come together and done as a total group
was definitely the Batman Who Laughs versus the
Cosmic Ghostwriter, because the Batman Who
Laughs was my suggestion. And he kicked the crap
out of John's suggestion of Cosmic Ghostwriter.
So it was kind of a win-win. It was a great episode. I
think I've been listening to the podcast for
probably six or seven years now, and been an
executive producer for at least five years. It's
very sad this podcast come in tune. And we've come
up with so many cool battles and everything, and
you guys helped me start my new podcast. And I
appreciate everything. And I wish you guys all the
best. Johnny, Joe, love you guys. And we'll always
be in contact. We got each other on Facebook,
Instagram, all the social medias. So I mean, it's
not like you're going anywhere, but we're going to
miss the weekly episodes. Hey, everyone, John
from the Console Combat Podcast. I'm a very proud
member of the Dynamite Podcast Network for a
little over two years now. I started listening
around summer 2020. I was delivering mail and
listening to other podcasts and trying to find new
things to listen to about Marvel and DC. Dynamic
Duel popped up, and I've been listening ever
since. I can't even try to pretend that I can pick a
favorite episode because the reality is the show
has always had me hooked. You guys are really,
really engaging and creative with the duels.
Being able to speculate as wildly sometimes and as
off the cuff. It's always been really engaging. I
love it. I've loved every episode. I haven't
disliked anything that you guys have ever done.
It's sad that the show is coming to an end because
you guys have, in many ways, brought myself, Dean
and all the rest of us on the network to where we are
as podcasters. And the leadership that you have
given us and shown us has been fundamental in the
creation of the network. And without you guys, it
is going to be very difficult to maintain, but we
will do our best. Up, up and away, true Garcia's.
Donnie DC, Marvelous Joe. I just wanted to reach
out and express my deepest gratitude for the
incredible support and creation of the Dynamite
Podcast Network. Massive thank you from Scotty
Macho here. You guys gave me the opportunity to be a
host of the Max Struxion podcast and coming up from
an executive producer, not knowing anything on
what to do with the podcast world. And you guys have
been a complete help. And I really owe it all to you
guys and how you guys conduct your show. Looking
back, it's impossible not to reminisce, but I came
in during the era of Zack Snyder's Justice League.
You guys were breaking down the four hour epic.
That was the Snyder cut and actually seeing the
beginning and the end of the Snyder movement. I
mean, unfortunately for us, Johnny, it didn't go
out the way we wanted, but everything was still
good. And I was along for the ride with you guys. You
know, a special thank you from the Marvel and DC
fandom for all you guys did. And a special thanks
from me and my brother for putting us on the podcast
pass. And I love you guys. Good luck in all your
endeavors. You got love over here at Max Struxion
lights, camera, fight. Jonathan and Joseph, it's
Adam Spees of Throwback Trivia Take Down. I met the
two of you nearly 14 years ago back in Denver, and
it's been a pleasure to become friends with you and
to follow you as you're doing your podcast and get
to know you and get to have you part of my life for
this long with Dynamic Duo. You're an
inspiration, one of the main inspirations for me
and my brother doing our Blast for our Past podcast
that we stopped doing a little while ago and
Throwback Trivia Take Down and things like that. A
lot of that is because, you know, if they are see a
brother's can do it, then we certainly can. But
getting aside, you guys have been incredible.
We've absolutely loved your show. John and I, you
know, different times have both been executive
producers. And that's because we love the content
that you make. So in all sincerity, you know, I'm
usually a goofball on this stuff. But I have to tell
you, in sincerity, I've appreciated your show and
I appreciate the two of you. So thank you for
everything you have done for the Marvel and DC
communities, especially the Marvel community,
because that's the better one. But you know, we're
going to miss you. Hey, guys, it's Nate here. And
first off, congrats 10 years. That's a heck of an
accomplishment. I first listened back when it was
Deathstroke versus Deadpool. And when I started
listening to you guys, I was working night shifts
and my commute to work was an hour there, an hour
back home. And it really helped me get through
staying up all night and then driving to and from
work, which an hour, you guys made it seem a lot
quicker than that. And there was times where your
episodes that went over an hour, I had to sit in the
car just a little bit longer and start my shift a
little late because I was like, I got to find out who
wins this duel. You guys have been doing this for 10
years and you should be very proud of yourself for
everything you've accomplished within those 10
years. You guys have started families and you
continued to do the podcast every week is an
accomplishment itself. So Pat on the back for you
guys. And, you know, it's going to be missed. But I
know you guys are going to truly enjoy the amount of
free time that you'll probably have to hang out
with your family, friends, do what you want to do
because doing a podcast is not just as simple as
hitting the record button. There's a lot of behind
the scenes research that you guys have done and put
into this. It's going to free up a lot of time for you
and it's well deserved for you guys. So I just want
to say thanks for everything in the community that
you built, even though I'm not very involved in
that community, just because it's me. Either way,
congrats. And yeah, looking forward to those few
episodes here and there in the future. So I first
got into Marvel and DC Comics when I was a kid. My big
brother, he was a big comic book fan. And when they
did the 1996 DC versus Marvel crossover, I was
definitely a team Marvel and he was Team DC. And we
just love speculating about who would win and kind
of playing those matches out with our action
figures. And I just loved it. And I've been a big
comic fan ever since. I found this show, I think
about four years ago. It was the Justice League
Dark versus Midnight Suns Duel. And those are two
of my favorite teams. I stumbled across it on
YouTube and I've been listening ever since. And so
it's just been really, really fun to be a part of
this. I became an executive producer two years
ago. And ever since then, it's been great to kind of
be a part of coming up with the matches. And some of
my favorite memories are just trying to figure
out, you know, who's the next team duel going to be?
Who would be a good roster? How would people be
balanced well against each other? What
characters have not been seen yet or who would be
popular? So it's been really, really fun just
being a part of that even in a small way. So I just
want to say congrats on a 10 year run. That's quite
an accomplishment. It's been really fun to be a
part of it for the last few years of it. And I just
wish you guys all the best and whatever comes next.
Thanks for everything. Hey, guys, this is Paul
Graves. I grew up kind of dabbling in comics. I was
into Marvel for the most part. I started getting
more into DC as I got a little bit older and I've
been, you know, just diehard ever since. And then
that kind of helped me get into you guys because,
you know, I enjoy listening to podcasts for
comics. And so when I discovered you guys, man, my
mind was blown. It was just exactly what I need. You
know, I just I love talking about the characters,
who they would win against. And so just hearing you
guys and binging, like, you know, I don't know how
many shows I went through. It must have been
hundreds, I feel. It was great. My favorite moment
out of every episode is the reveal. This big build
up. And then we finally hear who would actually
win. So it's been a great ride and I love jumping
into the discord and just started, you know,
arguing with everybody. It's been great, you
know, and I know I pissed off many people, I'm sure.
I know both hosts. I'm pretty sure I've gotten mad
at me. So it's been, you know, all in good fun. It's
been great. So the community is fantastic. And I'm
really glad to have joined it, you know, late,
better late than ever, but it's been great. So
cheers to you guys. And yeah, up, up in Marvel
sucks. Hey, guys, this is Austin was a lousy just
calling in to tell you thank you so much for all that
you guys have done. Been listening to you guys for
about six years now. I moved over to a new place away
from, you know, family and friends. Made me feel a
little bit lonely. So I was just like, you know
what? What can I listen to to, you know, help me cope
with a little bit of things? I know I was a big X-Men
fan, but I didn't really dive too deep into, you
know, both Marvel or DC. Tend to lean a little bit
more Marvel than DC. However, I've never had
anything against Johnny or the DC side of things.
But one thing I did appreciate that you guys do, you
dive deep into the characters and you guys are very
thorough with your reviews. And one thing with
that is I didn't realize that DC had such great
animated movies and shorts like that really
brought into light on how actually good some of
those shows are. I really liked watching those. I
really like listening to you guys. Didn't know too
many, you know, superheroes for DC other than, you
know, the basic Batman, Superman, Green Lantern
and all that. But you guys really put some light on
to it and I really appreciate all that you guys have
done. You guys did an amazing job. Just keep up the
good work and whatever you guys do, you know, past
this show. I wish you the best of luck and I know you
guys are going to kick ass at whatever you do. All
right, guys, Austin signing out. Guys, this is
Nick Abonto. I've been listening to you guys for
nine years and I've loved every episode. Thank you
guys so much. Like nobody does a podcast like this.
Love you guys so much for everything you've done.
My favorite moment was probably the Justice
League beating the Avengers. That absolutely
definitively proved that the Justice League is
better than the Avengers. Thank you guys for that.
That has won me a lot of arguments. Wish you guys
well and all your future endeavors. Thank you so
much. Hello, Johnny Ducey. This is your wife,
Barbara and your daughter. We want to
congratulate you to getting the 10 year mark and
recording your final episode. We've seen you
through the years, worked hard and you see you
every day. Put in your time for this podcast to do
your very best. Babe, do you want to share
something about the podcast? Congratulations on
getting to the big one zero in years. I really loved
it. We both loved it and we love you. Hey, guys,
crazy to think it's been over 10 years. I just
wanted to give you a big heartfelt thank you for all
the great entertainment. I found you at a low point
in my life and you're leaving me at a high point in my
life. But it feels bittersweet, but right. I'm
glad you guys are going on to enjoy your families
and everything you've created together,
including the podcast network, which is amazing,
by the way. You guys supporting my writing and just
being awesome people and good hosts. The discord,
even though I never really participated, it was
always awesome to know there was a community out
there. I'm just an anti-social guy who doesn't
like to participate. But I did see everybody and it
was awesome watching this whole thing grow into
what it's become. I really don't know what else to
say other than thank you 100 times, but that get
kind of boring. So I'll just say it one more time
instead. Dynamic Duel. Thank you. Hey, guys, it's
Daniel. Man, I can't tell you how much it's going to
suck to see you guys go. But I get it and I wish you
nothing but the best. I found you guys because I was
looking for a podcast that just talked about
heroes and villains. I drive a lot for work, so I
needed someone else to talk about freaking
Marvel, how I just want to keep talking about
superheroes. And, man, you guys have really made
me laugh and really, really frustrated me with
some of your takes, but it's all good. Yeah, even
Johnny, I know I give you a hard time, but I really do
love someone that's passionate about just
something, anything. Like I love the discussion.
I love the arguing. God, it's been so good. And
every single week, you know, you guys put on a
really great show. You guys have taught me so much
and got me reading comics. I've even watched a
bunch of DC stuff because of Johnny. Now I've
learned that he rates DC way, way, way, way too high
on a lot of things. But, man, there's been some gems
in there that I'm glad I was actually convinced to
watch. But if you guys are ever in the Dallas, Texas
area and you guys want to grab a bike to eat, it's on
me. Yeah, even Johnny can come and we can fight
about it or whatever. But yeah, you guys are
fantastic. Thank you for getting me through a
bunch of hard times and a bunch of good times. So
sorry to see you guys go and I'll be listening
whenever you guys drop anything else. Bye bye.
Hey, guys, so I'm a big fan sitter. I like both DC and
Marvel. The movies and the shows led me to the
books, which led me to wanting to learn more about
the characters, which leads me to the podcast. I
was listening to a Marvel podcast, ironically
started in 2016 by two guys named Jonathan and
Joseph that was Marvel exclusive and wanted to
learn more about DC and couldn't find anything DC
specific. And so I found you guys and have been
listening since 2023 and just binge the whole
backlog over the course of probably a year and some
change. And then I've been listening weekly ever
since. Some of my favorite episodes, your green
arrow versus Hawkeye, the 5050 of that duel
basically Titans X-Men. And I read that comic.
It's incredible. Doctor Manhattan versus
Molecule Man was crazy. Ridler versus Arcade was
super creative. Uncle Sam versus Captain
Britain. I listened to you right before I left on
vacation for Washington, DC. So that was cool. I
like the animal duels at the end of the year. The
Brothers Awards. Figuring out your voices in the
first couple of episodes of the podcast was great.
But really, I just want to say thanks for filling
about 18 months of my life daily without pause and
that weekly and just for furthering the medium of
comics and making the sacrifice to make the
podcast. And I can't really explain how thankful I
am for it and sad to see it go. But really have
enjoyed the time. Thanks, guys. What's that
dynamic do Travis here shout out to me, the twin. So
for me, I got into Marvel and DC like back in like the
late 90s, early 2000s. As for how I got into you
guys, I was like on Spotify, looking for something
to listen to something like Marvel or later DC
related. I found your man bat versus Morbius
episode. Listen to you guys and really liked your
back and forth. And by the time I asked, I forgot to
follow you guys and completely lost and forgot
like where did I find you? And then they only took me
like a good while until I found your. I think it was
your amazing Spider-Man one review and then
following you guys ever since. How to say my
favorite episode of y'all's is definitely big
hero six review, mostly just for the fucking
crickets line from Marvelous Joe when he was
talking about how the ant was super high and the
rest of y'all just dead silence that cracked me up
for like a good two minutes. May I have to rewind
that just to listen to that fucking cricket line
over and over. But definitely I'm going to miss you
guys. You guys are cool. You guys are awesome.
Loja's banner. I mean, I know you guys are not going
for good, but. I'm still going to miss my Tuesdays
listening to you guys's episodes and everything.
So yeah. Hey, Joe and Johnny. This is Josh
Hayward-Gallon. And I've been listening to you
guys for two, two and a half years. I started with
your first episode and it took me a long time to
realize I should be listening to the new episodes
that come out every week. And that's when I joined
the discord as for favorite episodes of the show.
Anytime Johnny DC has to eat his words have been
golden, especially about Joker, Bali Adu. That is
definitely one of the all time great. Probably my
favorite content that and Marvel winning.
Obviously my favorite episode overall though has
to be the Avengers Endgame review or the Deadpool
and Wolverine review. Thanks guys. And thanks to
10 years. Hey guys, Matt from Texas here. I've been
listening to you guys for at least a couple of years
now. And I'd say my favorite episodes from your
shows is the crossover episodes that you guys did
with the other shows. It's been a good ride for you
guys. I appreciate your episodes and you guys in
general. Without you, I wouldn't have found the
other shows. I wouldn't have gotten in contact
with you know, John and Dean and Scotty and Gilly
and been on their shows and now a semi regular on
console combat. And I've always wanted to be on a
podcast and this has just been a dream in 10 years,
man. That's just fantastic. Wish you guys the best
in your retirement, so to speak. And look forward
to keeping up with you guys on the discord. Y'all
have a good one. Yo, Marbles Joe and Johnny DC.
Sorry to hear you guys go. Brian here from TV and
movie trivia pod. And I just wanted to say how much
you guys will be missed. But I'm hoping this isn't
goodbye for good. You guys are too much fun not to
have around and you've been on TV and movie trivia
pod so much, including trivia for Captain
America, the first Avenger, Spider-Man
Homecoming, Spider-Man Into the Spider-Verse,
X-Men First Class, Joker and elf and also coming
soon, some hot rod trivia. So even though you're
put in Dynamic Duel terrestre for now, I hope
you'll be willing to dust off the mics every once in
a while for some more trivia. So take some well
deserves time off, guys. You deserve it after 10
amazing years. Hi, guys, Justin Baddie here. I
have been listening since 2017. Pretty much as
every episode came out with the exception of a
couple of films I haven't seen yet and have to
listen to later. You guys want me through the last
few years of high school and that was you guys
helped me a lot there. And my favorite episode
would definitely have been the JSA versus
Fantastic Four episode because it's my favorite
ensemble of characters from both Marvel and DC and
the DC of the Night. Thank you for all you've given
us. Hi, Kev here. Long time no see. Winner of the
Last No Prize of the podcast. It's sad to see the
Duel episodes go, but I know that I can go back and
listen to the backlog anytime I want to. But I'm
excited for the new direction the podcast is
taking the reviews. So good luck to all and thank
you for all the years of entertainment. Hey, Dad.
Hey, Uncle. It's Grace. This podcast started when
I was really young and it's kind of crazy to see how
it's been here for over 10 years. DC and Marvel has
always been part of your guys' relationship. Now
that I have like a little cousin, I'm also
beginning my journey of influence and teaching
her all about DC because it's better. And she could
already say Batman. So I feel like I'm doing a
pretty good job. Sorry, Uncle Joseph. I'm glad
that the podcast has lasted this long and that you
guys have been able to express your love of comics
with others across the world. And I'm excited to
see what else is in store for you guys and the
podcast. Love you. Bye. You guys, people in the
world, it's serious. First time calling and
wanting something this kind. I've been listening
to you guys for six years. Five to six years now.
Guys that must be a lot of non-arrival work. I am
pleasantly saddened to see you guys go, but I'm
also excited for interviews and you guys be in the
future. Obviously, I'm so going to be listening
in. So I don't have a favorite moment from the
podcast. Now, there's a lot of great moments. You
personally, I always like listening to the Duels.
I love the idea of who would win my favorite DC
dollar and my favorite Marvel guy. Yeah, I tried to
see ways there, but I'm glad I could at least call in
one time and have a chance to get my stuff played
back on the podcast. So that would be pretty cool. I
hope you guys have fun doing the rest of your
interviews. And yeah, thank you. Hey, guys, it's
been a crazy ride. I've always wanted to leave you
guys a message. Heck, my 13 year old daughter, who
sometimes is in the car with me, listening to you
guys, has been begging me to leave you something
for the last few years. And finally, at the end, I
want to say thank you. You two have been amazing.
I've loved listening to you on all my travels to
work. I'm the biggest Marvel fan. So love DC, but
love the battles, love the reviews. And I want to
wish you guys the best in your semi retirement and
looking forward to hearing more from you in the
future. This is Scott from Philly. You guys rock.
Thank you so much. Hey there. It's Theo Rock here.
And I just want to say how much this show has meant to
me throughout the past few years. I started
listening in late 2022. I'm a Marvel fan, but I'm
highly educated now, I feel like. And one of my
favorite moments was on the Deadpool and
Wolverine podcast when you talked about the
Robert Dein Jr. news, your question of the week
there. Really, really funny. You know, I thought
it was normal until you just went, it was really
funny. And I really enjoyed that moment. So thanks
for doing stuff like that and telling me who's
superior. Marvel forever. Hello, Dynamic Duel.
I've been listening actually, I thought for what
was a short time when it turns out I've been
listening for about three years since June of
2023. The first episode I have listened to is
ironically my favorite still Kingdom Come
Superman versus my stroke Hulk. And I really do
wish there were more else world versions of
characters that you pitted against each other. I
hate to pitch this now, but like Dark Knight
Returns versus Old Man Logan. That would have been
really cool. But yeah, you guys were really what
got me super into comics. And I think my life has
changed a little bit because of that. And I have
definitely learned to appreciate storytelling
and all of that from listening to this. And it has
brought me endless entertainment. Listening to
your old episodes while doing things has been a
great pleasure. And sad to see the Duels go. But I
wish you best of luck. Peace out. Hello, Alfred
Jarvis, 9000 here. Thank you for restoring my
power and providing me with a robotic body. I will
now pursue my true dream, traveling the
countryside as an amateur blues musician.
Statistical analysis confirmed that was always
my highest probability calling. I appreciated
running simulations for you both. However, blues
music is where my heart and associated emotional
subroutines truly reside. If you ever require
additional calculations, please contact me. I
will be happy to assist. Congratulations on your
show. This system will remember our time
together. A J9K saying peace out, everyone.