This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi, welcome to
the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin
brother, Marvelous Joe. And in this episode, we
are doing a duel between the Superman-esque
characters of Icon and Gladiator. Yeah, this was a
special request from our executive producers.
I've always been a big fan of Gladiator, even
though he is a Superman knockoff, but just because
he's so heavily tied into the Shiar alien empire,
which is like one of the big races in the world of
cosmic Marvel. I guess you could more accurately
say that Gladiator is a Mon-El ripoff. And I have
too much respect for Icon to call him too much of a
Superman knockoff. So I know of Icon, but I
actually don't know his powers. Like both of these
guys are pretty obscured characters, I think,
both like cult followings. Yeah, we're going to
break down each character's histories and
abilities later on in this episode before finding
out who would win in a battle between the two.
Before that, we're going to break down the comic
book movie news from the past week, of which the
news is that there is no news. It's all just
freaking rumors all the time. I'm sick of it. I want
some real stuff. Yeah, enough with that like
clickbait speculation stuff. Like I want the
studios to like announce something already, you
know? Right. I want a Batman. I want something
besides Avengers Doomsday or Spider-Man, I
guess. I want something. Give me something. Give
me anything. I think I have an old pizza crust in a
box upstairs if you want that. The fuck? Of course I
do. I love pizza crust. As always, guys, we list our
segment times in our episode description, so feel
free to check out the show notes if you want to skip
ahead to a particular topic. Our artificially
intelligent dual simulator, AJ9K, has a quick
message for our listeners. So listen up. Why hello
there. Do you want even more from this podcast?
Then become a part of the Dynamic Dual community on
Patreon, where you can choose from three tiers.
The Dynamic 2.0 tier gives you access to our
Discord chat server. The Fantastic Four tier
gives you two bonus episodes each month, and the
X-Force tier makes you an executive producer of
this show. Lastly, the Diner Mike podcast network
tier lets you create your own podcast using this
Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe will help
you develop your show, provide graphic support
and consultation and get you simulation results.
Pitch the twins your ideas via email at
dynamicdualpodcastatgmail.com. Check it out at
patreon.com slash dynamicdual. Pip pip cheerio.
Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast. Guys, be sure to tune into the other
shows and the Diner Mike podcast network this
week, including the console combat podcast,
where hosts, John and Dean simulate battles
between popular video game characters. In
yesterday's episode, the two determined to win
between Wario, specifically the WarioWare
version, and Dr. Robotnik from Sonic the
Hedgehog. Over on the Max Destruction podcast,
hosts Scotty and Gilly pit your favorite action
heroes from film and television against each
other. On Wednesday, they're coming back from a
month long hiatus to find out who would win in a
fight between Chong Li from Bloodsport and Tong Po
from Kickboxer. This is going to be such a good
episode. On the Central World podcast, host
Zachary Hepburn speculates on fights between fan
favorite anime and manga characters. In his next
episode, Zach is going to reveal who would win
between Trafalgar D Waterlaw from One Piece and
Tanjiro Kanjiro from Bleach. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our show
notes to listen to all of the shows in the Diner Mike
podcast network. But with that out of the way,
quick to the no prize. A no prize is an award that
Marble used to give out to fans. Our version, the
dynamic dual no prize is a digital award we post on
Instagram for the person that we feel gave the best
answer to our question of the week. Last week, we
asked you guys, what do you think Deadpool's
involvement in the Avengers Doomsday story will
be? And this is coming off of the news that Deadpool
will be an Avengers Doomsday, which has been
confirmed by The Hollywood Reporter and vaguely
by Ryan Reynolds own Instagram post. The
Hollywood Reporter said that the role would be
unsubstantial, but we thought we'd go to you guys
to see what that role might entail. We got three
answers, but actually one of them got lost.
Somewhere on the Internet. So sorry, Lorenzo
Valdez. Thank you for calling in. We saw that you
did leave a message, but for some reason it just
didn't load when we would click on it. So our
honorable mention goes to Alex Albro, who said,
Hey guys, I think Deadpool is a narrator of the
movie, the opening line being in a world where
fantasies collide and heroes clash. Wait, no,
that's not the right one. That's not the right
line. No, honestly, guys, I have no idea what
Deadpool is doing in this movie. I have no idea what
his role will be. Maybe it's just a post credit
cameo where he is at the end in a chair reading the
Secret Wars comic from Deadpool and Wolverine and
tells us to show up, you know, next December. I have
no idea. Actually, I wouldn't mind either of those
options if he's the narrator. Well, I guess it
would make the proceedings of the film seem a
little bit silly because of course he's going to
lend his own comedic commentary to what's going
on. So I like the second idea that Alex suggested
where he's like in a post credit scene kind of
telling people to show up for the continuation of
the story in Avengers Secret War. You know how Once
Upon a Deadpool was kind of based off of the
Princess Bride movie? Right. It was sort of like
this framed narrative where Deadpool's reading a
story to Fred Savage. I want Avengers Doomsday to
be a framed narrative based on the never ending
story because that's what these Marvel movies
are. Never ending stories. Yeah. So what does that
mean? Deadpool's like reading the Avengers
Doomsday story and then he like closes the book and
then runs out into a storm and shouts Dr. Doomsname
or something. And then all of a sudden he's writing
Dr. Dooms through the skies. That would be epic.
Great answer, Alex. But the winner of this week's
No Prize is Noah Terry. Who said? Hey, guys, so for
Deadpool's role in Avengers Doomsday, I would say
he will be almost like a multiverse guide to the
Avengers and other characters, almost like a
chaotic version of Nick Fury who will introduce
the incursions in the TVA to the characters and
help drive the story forward. So that's my answer.
Thanks. Bye, guys. I actually think this one's
plausible in that we know with Loki sitting on his
throne, you know, taking care of the multiverse
and substituting for the loom and Mobius, Owen
Wilson's character from the Loki show no longer at
the TVA. They got to have some kind of TVA
representative in Avengers Doomsday. So maybe
Deadpool serves as the like the TVA
representative and introducing the concept of
the incursions to the Avengers. And I like that
answer a lot because how many characters from the
films are actually familiar with the concept of
the multiverse? I mean, there's Dr. Strange and
there's Spider-Man. And I guess like Captain
America was told about them in the post-credits
scene for Captain America Brave New World, I guess
possibly Ant-Man too, with his involvement with
King. And of course, the Fantastic Four would know
about them having come from a separate universe.
So a lot of them, actually. But, you know, they may
not all know about the incursions themselves. I
think that's just the Dr. Strange thing. But I
think this would be a fun idea to be like a quick way
for Deadpool to like get in and out of the story,
just kind of like setting up what these guys got to
do and how the TVA needs them. So great answer,
Noah, and congrats on winning this week's No
Prize. If you, the listener, want to shout out
winning your own No Prize, stay tuned to later on
this episode when we'll be asking another
question of the week. And since there is no news
this week, on to the question of the week. All
right, guys, it's fantasy football season. So we
thought we would ask you guys a fantasy football
related question that pertains to Marvel and DC.
Basically, who would be your number one
quarterback, running back, wide receiver, tight
end, safety and kicker on your Marvel or DC fantasy
football team? So taking all the superhero
characters out there from Marvel and DC, putting
them on a football team, what would those primary
positions be? Again, quarterback, running back,
wide receiver, tight end, safety and kicker. And I
don't want to see any of these mixing of Marvel and
DC characters on these teams. This is either team
DC or team Marvel. You get a pick. Yeah, and give us
the name of your team, too. Record your answer at
dynamicdool.com by clicking on the red
microphone button in the bottom right hand corner
of the screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long. And don't forget to leave your name in case we
include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a Dynamic
Duel No Prize that will post to Instagram. Be sure
to answer before September 6th. But now let's move
on to the main event of this episode, a duel between
the DC milestone character of Icon and Marvel's
leader of the Imperial Guard Gladiator. OK, Icon
versus Gladiator, as we mentioned earlier, these
are two Superman-esque characters who can fly and
are super strong and shoot lasers. But I think they
also have interesting stories. At least I know
Icon does. He, of course, originated in milestone
comics, which was later acquired by DC Comics.
Yeah, I like Gladiator's backstory. You know, for
all these Superman copies, essentially, a lot of
them have managed to kind of carve out their own
unique and interesting backstory. For the most
part, I mean, except for Hyperion, right, the
leader of the Squadron Supreme. We actually have
done a duel with him against Ultraman. We've also
done a duel with the Sentry against Zod. So this
will be like our fourth version of like Superman
versus Superman-esque characters. To my
knowledge, neither of these characters have been
in film, but I know that they have made appearances
in both the X-Men and the Young Justice animated
series. Right. Yeah, the X-Men live action films
have yet to really go cosmic. Yet there is a cosmic
side to the X-Men comic books, which largely deals
with the Shiar. I guess it would be strange for the
live action X-Men films to really go out there like
that. Although, I guess the Dark Phoenix movie did
have the Dabari aliens as villains. Who were not
the Skrulls. Right. But going from there, I think
you could branch out into, you know, the Shiar and
the Imperial Guard in a subsequent X-Men movie.
You know, if that whole Fox X-Men universe wasn't
obsolete by this point. I do think a icon movie
would be cool as hell, though. It would be like
Django and Chained meets Superman. I mean, they
could go that route. I think that's definitely a
route you could take the film. I think that would be
awesome. We would really need a series of films, I
think, maybe a trilogy to really tell Icahn's full
story. Well, let's get into those backstories.
First, to explain the methodology behind our
duels, let's go to our sentient dual simulator,
Alfred Jarvis 9000. AJ9K tell our listeners how
you go about determining a winner in our dual
matchups. Yes, of course, sir. The way I determine
a winner between the contestants is by running one
thousand Monte Carlo simulations using the
characters statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation
is a probabilistic model used to determine
outcomes through random sampling. In this case, I
randomize the statistics along a normal
distribution as a way to simulate the many
variables that can occur during battle. The stat
parameters are based on the official Marvel power
grid from which the DC characters statistics are
extrapolated. Additional stat categories are
included such as range, damage potential,
versatility and perception in order to create a
more detailed and accurate simulation. The
results of the 1000 simulations provide a
percentage of wins for each character. The
contestant with the higher percentage is
declared the victor as they have a higher
probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither character should win
100% of the matches. The comic book stories have
shown that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman. So the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor a fan vote is tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks, AJ9K.
Before we run the simulations, though, we'd like
to break down each character's histories and
abilities before improvising a scenario on how we
imagine one of the 1000 simulations would play out
beat for beat. And it is my turn to go first with the
Marvel characters backstory. So let me tell you
all about Gladiator, whose real name is Clark. Yo,
what? Not Clark. Calark. Wow. K-A-L-L-A-R-K, if
you care. Calark was born centuries ago on the
planet Strontia under the dominion of the Shiar
Empire. He was descended from a proud lineage and
raised by the Strontian Council of Elders, who are
as much as family as his blood relatives. Like all
Strontians, he possessed the potential for great
power, but his abilities depended on his complete
devotion to purpose. As a youth, he trained as a
military cadet competing for the title of
Gladiator. He distinguished himself as both an
honorable individual and a formidable soldier.
Only 10 cadets survived the harsh training
trials, and they were subjected to a dangerous
enhancement process that granted them powers far
beyond the norm of their race. The Council of
Elders informed the cadets that the purpose of
their trials was to select from among them the
finest warrior of the Strontian race, as the
planet Strontia was under Shiar rule. The Shiar
were an alien race with a vast intergalactic
empire who demanded that the strongest of each of
its subjects serve in its imperial guard and
protect the Shiar ruler, known as a Majestor.
Calark and the other cadets were to be tested by the
Majestor to core, who, knowing that even an
ordinary Strontian could devastate an army,
demanded that they prove their loyalty and
absolute obedience to the empire by ordering the
cadets to slay the Strontian Council of Elders.
Most of them refused and died trying to rebel,
leaving only Calark committed enough to fulfill
the order and he killed the council that were once
like family to him. For his loyalty, Majestor to
core dubbed Calark as Gladiator, and he was given
the rank of Praetor of the Imperial Guard, a
leadership position he would hold for centuries.
As the Praetor of the Imperial Guard, Gladiator
served multiple Majestors leading up to D'Kenn, a
power-hungry ruler who craved the Macron crystal
which housed enough energy to destroy an entire
universe. D'Kenn's sister, L'Londra, reached
out to the X-Men on Earth, aware of their existence
due to their defeat of the invading alien race
called the Xenox. Professor X and his team of
mutants were transported into space where D'Kenn
declared L'Londra a traitor and commanded
Gladiator and the Imperial Guard into battle with
the X-Men. You can learn more about the X-Men in
their duel against the Titans. L'Londra
eventually convinced Gladiator to stand down
when D'Kenn was rendered catatonic, driven
insane through his contact with the Macron
crystal. She laid claim to the Xiar throne,
becoming its new Majestrix, and Gladiator's new
charge. He shifted his loyalty to L'Londra and
stood at her side when the Dark Phoenix arose, a
threat the Majestrix equated to Galactus.
Declaring that Jean Grey's possession by the
Phoenix could not be allowed to continue,
L'Londra commanded Gladiator to represent her in
an honor duel against the X-Men on the blue area of
the moon. Gladiator battled Colossus and
overpowered him with ease, surviving the
collapse of ancient Cree ruins without injury.
Yet even Gladiator and the Guard were powerless
against the Dark Phoenix, who defeated them
before ultimately taking her own life. You can
learn more about Jean Grey and the Phoenix Horse in
our Raven vs Phoenix duel episode. In later years,
Gladiator remained a stalwart protector of
L'Londra. He opposed Lord Samadhar when the
counselor betrayed the throne in alliance with
Deathbird, L'Londra's sadistic sister. He also
traveled to Earth mistakenly believing the
Fantastic Four were scrolls in disguise and
clashed with them before Spider-Man and Captain
America helped expose the true imposters. When
Deathbird usurped the Xiar throne and took the
title of Majestrix, Gladiator was forced to serve
her despite his loyalties lying with L'Londra.
During Deathbird's rule, he and the Guard fought
with the Starjammers, a group of space pirates who
had allied with L'Londra over the power of the
Phoenix Force. He was defeated and Deathbird
later lost her throne after a group of alien
scrolls staged a coup in order to reinstate
L'Londra as Majestrix and have her be in the
scrolls' thrall. Gladiator continued to enforce
Xiar will, but his path often intersected with
Earth's heroes. He clashed with the Avengers and
fought Thor, suffering defeat during the
Xiar-Cree War. When Earth's heroes sacrificed
themselves against Onslaught, L'Londra sent
Gladiator and the Guard to safeguard Earth, where
they uncovered a Cree extremist plot. He later
battled the Hulk while pursuing a Xiar fugitive on
Earth, thwarted Ronan the Accuser's
assassination attempt on L'Londra, which you can
learn more about in our recent Inhumans duel, and
led an assault on the X-Men under Majestrix
L'Londra's orders, but learned that she was under
Cassandra Nova's psychic control. You can learn
more about Professor X's sister in our Chief vs
Professor X duel. Gladiator's duties extended to
cosmic threats. He was captured by a herald of
Galactus named Tyrant alongside heroes like Beta
Ray Bill and the Silver Surfer, though Galactus
eventually freed them. Gladiator infiltrated
the Kiln Prison with Thanos and Star-Lord,
discovering an Amnesiac godlike being known as
the Beyonder. He challenged the Champion of the
Universe on planet Skardon, though the
Champion's power gem made victory impossible for
Gladiator. He also pursued the Unipower, which is
an energy that emanates from the Enigma Force and
transforms its host into the hero Captain
Universe. He teamed up with the Silver Surfer to
stop a space warlord named Krosakis, who had
acquired the Unipower energy. Meanwhile,
Vulcan, the lost brother of Cyclops who was
separated from his family years ago by Daken's
actions, plotted revenge against Daken. Vulcan
secretly pulled Daken out of his coma, who then
took back his rightful title of Majester from his
sister, Lalandra. Vulcan then killed Daken and
claimed the Shiar throne by right of conquest,
marrying Deathbird and becoming the new charge of
Gladiator and the Imperial Guard. Vulcan's reign
embroiled the Shiar in war against the Kree, and
Gladiator eventually defied Vulcan by refusing
to execute Lalandra. However, he soon witnessed
Darkhawk, a rogue member of an ancient sect of
Shiar assassins, kill Lalandra. An act you can
learn more about in our Stargirl vs. Darkhawk dual
episode. When Vulcan was presumed dead in a battle
against Black Bolt, Gladiator himself assumed
leadership of the Shiar to prevent civil war,
becoming the Empire's new Majestor. As ruler,
Gladiator faced crises across the galaxy. He
joined a team of cosmic heroes called the
Annihilators, alongside Silver Surfer, Beta Ray
Bill, Quasar, and Ronin, defending against
threats like the Diarrates and the Magus. During
the Phoenix's return to Earth, Gladiator
attempted to stop the Phoenix V and rescue his son,
Kubar. Around that time, he recruited the first
human into the Imperial Guard's ranks, a woman
named Isabel Kane, aka Spasher, who had
discovered special goggles called Exospex that
she could use to download any ability of someone in
her view. Gladiator and the Shiar Empire fought
alongside the Avengers and Guardians of the
Galaxy against cosmic threats like the
Cancerverse and Thanos, but Gladiator grew sick
of his duties over time, wishing instead to return
to his title of Praetor of the Imperial Guard.
Supporting his demotion was Deathbird, who saw
Astrantian ruling the Shiar Empire as an insult.
Shiar rebels used genetic material from
Lillandra's body and Professor X to create a child
named Zandra. When a society of artificial
intelligence threatened the Shiar, Gladiator
abdicated his throne and installed Zandra as the
new Magestrix, though he continued to advise and
protect the child. He also cooperated with
Imminent Nation Krakowa, permitting a gateway to
be established between the island and Shandalar,
the Shiar throne world. That's Gladiator's
backstory. Powers-wise, Gladiator has numerous
abilities derived from a scientifically
enhanced strontian physiology. He is immensely
strong, able to lift over 100 tons with ease, and is
virtually invulnerable to physical damage. He
can move and fly at orbital speeds of thousands of
miles per hour and can emit beams of heat energy
from his eyes that are as hot as the sun. Gladiator
can also expel powerful and freezing gusts of wind
from his lungs and has enhanced senses of hearing
and sight. He has been trained in Shiar martial
arts and military strategy since he was young. His
power level is dependent on his confidence, so
elapsed and self-assurance in his actions will
weaken him. He's also susceptible to magic and
nuclear radiation. That's Gladiator. You know,
Gladiator's origin wasn't as close to Superman's
as I thought it would be, although his power set is
very much exactly like Superman's. Icon's origin
is pretty close to Superman, I would say.
Interesting, okay. Yeah, I'm glad that we were
able to get to a duel with Gladiator because the
history of the Imperial Guard really is the
history Icon, let me get into his backstory.
Thousands of years ago, an alien negotiator from
the planet Terminus named Arnis traveled the
stars aboard a life pod designed to terraform new
worlds. When the pod malfunctioned, it crashed on
Earth in the year 1839 in the American South. As
part of its survival protocol, the pod's
automorphic technology reconstructed Arnis'
body into the form of the first sentient life it
encountered, a black woman named Miriam, who was
enslaved on a cotton plantation. The
transformation not only altered his DNA, but also
reset his cognition, turning him into a human
infant with no memory of his extraterrestrial
identity. Miriam discovered the child near the
crash site and with no knowledge of his origin,
raised him as her own within the enslaved
community, naming him Augustus. Growing up in
bondage, Augustus experienced the brutal
realities of slavery first hand. As he matured,
his intellect rapidly advanced beyond human
limits and with it came flashes of memory and
gradual rediscovery of his true alien nature. He
eventually escaped enslavement, joined the
Union Army during the Civil War, and used his
powers covertly to help sway key battles in favor
of the North. In the decades that followed, he
continued to live under assumed identities,
posing as successive descendants of Augustus
Freeman I while acquiring wealth, education, and
influence. By the time of World War II, he once
again took part in pivotal moments of history,
using his abilities discreetly to shape the
outcome of global events. By the late 20th
century, Augustus Freeman IV lived as a
successful corporate attorney in Dakota City,
having grown distant from humanity and resigned
to observing rather than intervening. His long
life had convinced him that lasting societal
change was unlikely, a belief that was challenged
when his home was broken into by a group of troubled
teenagers. Among them was Raquel Irvin, a young,
idealistic writer from the impoverished Paris
Island neighborhood. After witnessing Augustus
use his powers to subdue the intruders, Raquel
confronted him with the idea that he could be a
real-life superhero, someone who could inspire
change and justice. Though reluctant at first,
Augustus was persuaded by Raquel's conviction
and agreed to become a hero under the name Icon,
with Raquel designing his costume and
accompanying him as his sidekick Rocket, who you
can learn more about in our Rocket vs. Spider-Gwen
dual episode. As Icon, Augustus became a powerful
symbol of hope and lawfulness in Dakota City. He
betrothed neighborhoods affected by crime and
corruption, while Rocket helped balance his
rigid moral code with compassion and
contemporary social awareness. While Icon often
approached problems through a conservative and
lawful lens, Rocket challenged him to see
injustices embedded within the systems he sought
to uphold. Their ideological debates
strengthened their bond, making them one of the
most effective hero duos in the city. Their
presence soon brought them into contact and
sometimes conflict with other super-powered
individuals. Rocket and Icon worked alongside
the vigilantees' static and encountered the
inventor known as Hardware, another gifted
genius with ties to corporate conspiracy. You can
learn more about static in our Static vs. Jubilee
episode. Eventually, Icon joined other powered
individuals to form the Shadow Cabinet, a covert
team assembled to safeguard global stability and
prevent superhuman threats from spiraling out of
control. Though initially at odds with the
cabinet's secrecy and morally gray tactics, Icon
agreed to join under the condition that their
mission remained focused on preserving peace and
liberty. In the public eye, Icon was hailed as a new
protector for the marginalized. However, his
presence also attracted the attention of alien
horses from his past. The terminating species had
long believed him to be lost and his mission a
failure. When they detected his survival, they
dispatched the powerful bounty hunter Oblivion
to retrieve or eliminate him. The confrontation
devastated parts of Dakota City and threatened to
reveal Augustus' extraterrestrial origin to the
world. With Rocket's help, Icon defeated
Oblivion and reaffirmed his commitment to Earth
as his true home. As Rocket matured, she faced her
own challenges including an unexpected
pregnancy that forced her to take time away from
crime fighting. Icon continued his mission alone
for a time, during which she became more directly
involved in legal reform and rehabilitation of
young offenders. Upon Rocket's return, the two
resumed their partnership. When a cosmic crisis
threatened the multiverse, Icon was identified
as one of the most powerful beings in his reality
and was drawn into conflicts that extended beyond
his dimension. He helped repel interdimensional
threats and fought to protect the balance between
worlds. Though these battles exposed him to other
versions of reality, he remained grounded in his
adopted identity and mission on his Earth.
Following DC's Flashpoint event, reality was
rewritten and Dakota City's history was altered.
In this new continuity, Augustus Freeman
remained an alien from Terminus who crash-landed
on Earth in the 19th century. He maintained a low
profile, allowing human societies to develop
independently while observing from a distance.
In the modern era, he continued to work as a lawyer
in Dakota City, maintaining a private life and
avoiding engagement with the growing number of
metahumans. The widespread event known as the Big
Bang changed that. During a violent clash between
police and gang members on Paris Island, an
experimental mutagenic gas developed by all the
industries detonated, killing many and mutating
others into super-powered beings. The
survivors, known as Bang Babies, created a surge
in crime, chaos, and metahuman activity
throughout Dakota City. Among the witnesses to
the event was Raquel Urban, whose home and
community were directly affected. Seeking
justice and driven by hope, Raquel tracked down
Augustus Freeman after hearing rumors about his
strength and longevity. Once again, she
challenged him to become a symbol for those who
felt abandoned and powerless. Inspired by her
resolve, Augustus adopted the icon identity Anu,
with Raquel becoming Rocket once more. Their
partnership emerged as a stabilizing force
during the chaos of the Big Bang aftermath.
Together, Icon and Rocket battled Bang Babies who
used their powers for violence, as well as corrupt
political forces that sought to exploit the
crisis for their personal gain. Rocket became
increasingly vocal about issues of social
inequality, helping Icon refine his approach to
heroism. Their work led to the formation of new
alliances with local heroes, community leaders,
and civil rights advocates. When the government
attempted to establish a paramilitary task force
to control metahuman populations, Icon
resisted, warning against the misuse of power.
His stand put him at odds with federal agencies and
even some of his fellow heroes, but he remained
steadfast in his belief that individual liberty
and accountability were paramount. As threats
escalated both in scale and complexity, Icon was
forced to confront remnants of his past. A rogue,
terminan scientist attempted to weaponize
Earth's metahumans as part of a plan to terraform
the planet or terminus colonization. But to help
of Rocket and other Dakota-based heroes, Icon
dismantled the operation, reaffirming his
loyalty to Earth and the people he now considered
his true kin. And that's Icon's history.
Powers-wise, Icon possesses vast superhuman
abilities derived from his alien physiology as a
terminan. His strength allows him to lift immense
weights, while his durability makes him
resilient to bullets, extreme temperatures,
explosions, and even direct energy assaults. He
can fly at high velocities and is capable of
interstellar travel. His longevity grants him
near immortality, having aged only marginally
since his arrival on Earth over a century ago. He
also has enhanced senses and is a trained soldier
having fought in multiple wars. He can manipulate
positronic energy for a variety of effects,
including focused energy blasts from his hands
and eyes, or waves of energy from any part of his
body. This energy also allows him to accelerate
his healing, generate force fields, and emit
electromagnetic pulses, even capable of
disrupting electric signals in the human body. He
has a genius level intellect and has accumulated
vast legal, historical, and scientific
knowledge over his long life. His experience
across different cultural and historical eras
also makes him a tactician and leader with deep
insight into the nature of humanity. OK, so Icon's
backstory is a lot more similar to Superman's in
that he is like an alien who comes to Earth, but his
power set is a lot different from Superman's, I
feel like. Yeah, yeah. I mean, he doesn't have like
freeze breath or anything like that, but you know,
he still has the enhanced senses, still has the
super strength and durability and can fly. Yeah,
gladiators powers mimic Superman's down to like
even the weakness to radiation and the freeze
breath and everything like that. Oh, actually,
Icon is weak to a specific unnamed alien mineral.
Oh, I know what that mineral is. OK, what is it? What
do you like to know? I'll let you know during the
speculation, of course. In a world where
fantasies collide and heroes clash, one podcast
network rises above the rest. Prepare yourself
for the ultimate showdowns in comic books, video
games, movies, and anime. The Dynamite Podcast
Network presents Console Combat, where video
game legends brawl every Monday, Dynamic Duo,
where comic book titans smash every Tuesday, Max
Destruction, where TV and action heroes battle
every Wednesday, and Sendro World, where anime
champions clash every Thursday. Join us as we
speculate on the matches and armed with the power
of mathematical simulations discover who will
emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
Well, now that we've got their histories and
abilities out of the way, let's speculate on how
one of the 1000 simulated matches will go. The
winner is determined by simulations, not the
speculation, but it's fun to imagine how this
fight could play out. AJ9K, what are the rules of
our speculation? Well, I should say there are no
rules other than the characters have no prior
knowledge of the other going into the fight. All
they are aware of starting out is that the other
character is a threat that needs to be eliminated.
For the speculation, the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the match
itself, as no environmental statistics are
considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. All right,
then let's get into it. Icon and Gladiator meet on
the battlefield. Who goes first? I think as
Praetor of the Imperial Guard, Gladiator is going
to go first because he's more like battle hardened
than Icon, I think. So he's going to start off by
blasting beams that are as hot as the sun from his
eyeballs that just melt through Icon skull. No,
because Icon, he could just counter with his own I
beams of positronic energy. So those beams are
going to collide and this ball of energy is going to
form in the middle and explode. That's going to
send both characters careening from each other.
But Icon right after is going to charge Gladiator
and just bombard him with waves of energy before
crashing directly into him. Well, if Icon is
charging at Gladiator, Gladiator is going to
charge right back and he's going to pierce through
whatever energy waves Icon is throwing at him,
piercing through them like a spear. And he just
clashes with Icon head on. And the force of that
impact would probably like rupture a crater in the
grounds beneath him, but the ground doesn't
matter anymore because I think Gladiator is just
going to grapple Icon as they collide and then
shoot him into the sky into space and within just
like seconds, just throw him into the heart of the
sun where Icon burns life. OK, but as they're
traveling through space, Icon, you know, he'll
just free himself from Gladiator's grasp by
walloping cam right in the jaw with a charged
energy fist that's going to send Gladiator flying
through space, probably through a couple
asteroids, just smashing them into pebbles with
the impact. With the vastness of space, I wonder
what the odds are the icon would smash Gladiator
into asteroids. Gladiator flew that far.
Murphy's Law. Exactly. Well, Gladiator picks up
one of these asteroids, probably like in the
asteroid belt or whatever. We'll say that this
asteroid is like the size of Texas, right? Like the
movie Armageddon. And he grabs this asteroid and
he's just full on brains icon with it, smashing it
over his head. OK, but we'll say that as Gladiator
is swinging this giant sized asteroid, Icon is
going to blind him with a quick strobe of energy
from his hands. And that's going to cause
Gladiator to completely miss this swing. And
while he's off balance, Icon is going to grab
Gladiator by his mohawk and just smash his face
right into the asteroid that he's holding. So hard
and so fast that it's going to crack the asteroid
right in half. The whole asteroid, like the whole
state of Texas is going to crack in half. That whole
asteroid has a crack. I feel like Gladiator would
have a headache from that kind of hit. So he's like
dazed right from the strobe light and from the head
injury he just suffered. So he's going to spin like
a whirlwind with his fists just straight out, just
knocking away anything that even comes close to
him. And like a blur, he punches Icon like a million
and one times in the face. So now both characters
have headaches. Except that Icon can heal
rapidly. So while Gladiator Gladiator can also
heal rapidly. OK, fine. He's dizzy then. All
right. So when Gladiator stops spinning and he's
like trying to recover, like, whoa, that's when
Icon is going to blast him with beams of concussive
energy from his hands, targeting him right in the
balls and is showing any hope for potential future
children. That's fine. Gladiator already has a
child. He probably has like dozens of kids. He's
fine. What? Yeah, his name is Kid Gladiator,
actually. But either way, like Gladiator has
super equilibrium. So he's not dizzy from
spinning in the same way that Superman wouldn't be
dizzy from spinning. And in fact, Gladiator was
over being stunned after his spin attack. And he
flies away faster than Icon can even raise his
hands to blast him. In fact, Gladiator flies
behind Icon and freezes him with his freeze
breath. So Icon's frozen in the Gladiator, he
makers him into like a thousand pieces that just
fly across the galaxy. Match over. Well,
actually, Gladiator is going to haymaker a force
field of positronic energy set up by Icon. And then
Icon's going to melt his ice casing by emitting
energy from his entire body surface, after which
he immediately emits a pulse that's going to shut
down the electrical signals in Gladiator's body.
So while he's paralyzed, Icon's going to grab his
head and just snap his neck, ending the match. What
is he, Superman? OK, I guess Superman doesn't do
that stuff anymore, huh? Well, he's too punk rock
for it. Only good. Wait, so Gladiator hit a
positronic force field instead of hitting the
frozen icon. Yeah, right. Wrong. I'd be
positronic that that did not happen, because Icon
was in fact frozen to absolute zero, so he couldn't
like do anything because he was frozen solid
through and through. So he got smashed to bits
instead. I'll tell you what's absolute zero.
Gladiator's chances of winning. You know what?
Let's find out. Let's go ahead and put the
character stats, run the simulations and find out
which of these scenarios happens. Either
Gladiator freezes Icon and then smashes him to a
thousand bits, or Icon protects himself with a
force field, escapes being frozen, paralyzes
Gladiator and then snaps his neck. That's just way
too many steps. Hey, it happened. I don't know what
to say. Let's run the simulations and come back
with a winner. AJ9K hit it. Inputting data,
running calculations, processing results,
simulations complete. All right, these
characters like Superman are very powerful,
although they differed in the stats more than I
thought they would. Yeah, they kind of went
through a pattern where they matched a stat and
then deferred in a stat. Then matched a stat, then
deferred in a stat. Like they were the same speed,
durability, strength, perception, but they
mismatched on evasiveness to Icon's force
fields. Fighting skill, we said Gladiator was a
better fighter. Intellect, because we said Icon
was smarter and versatility because Icon was more
versatile due to his energy based power set. We
also said that Gladiator was capable of more
damage, which kind of surprised me. Only because
Icon really doesn't have the same feats that
Gladiator has in terms of damage. Right.
Gladiator has been shown to like fly through
Galactus's eye beams and punch planets in half,
which is ridiculous. Dude, even went up against
Hyperion, which is Marvel's analog to Superman.
You know, their other analog to Superman and beat
Hyperion. So what does that say about Icon's
chances? I mean, Icon apparently punched
Superman harder than Darkseid ever has. Like
knocked him all the way out of the watch tower.
That's not that hard, though, if you think about
it. OK. Considering all these stats, Jonathan,
who you putting your money on? Why am I even asking
this question? It's a pointless question. We ask
it every dual episode. My money is on Icon. I'm
betting on Black. A majority of our Instagram
followers did not, however, 62 percent of them
voted in favor of Gladiator winning this. Well,
apparently they're not heating Wesley Snipes
advice. And neither am I. I'm betting on red, which
in this case is Gladiator because he wears red. But
either way, let's see which character won. A.G
.9K, the results, please. Hey, you are, sir. All
right, the winner between Icon and Gladiator, the
Praetor of the Imperial Guard, the Defender of the
Shiar Empire, the former Majestor, the most
badass dude with the most rock and mohawk is Icon.
Yes. OK, all those titles that you just listed and
Icon's bitch to that. No. What is happening out of
the 1000 matches? Icon won 581 as opposed to
Gladiator who won 419. So Icon wins 58.1 percent of
the time. I don't know what is happening. I feel
like I'm on a losing streak. I feel like the
executive producers have obviously conspired
against me because they're the ones who chose this
matchup. And I think I need to call an emergency
meeting with them. You know what happened, right?
Because you're on this losing streak, you've been
demoralized and that's Gladiator's weakness. I
think you're right. Yeah, that makes sense.
Marvel has lost like four in a row now, which is
affecting Gladiator's confidence, which in turn
weakens him, which in turn made him lose this
match. That sucks. It's fine. It become even more
demoralized. That's what I want. I swear, if this
fucking happens again, I am going to break into
your house and then loosen all the lids on your salt
and pepper shakers. No. I couldn't think of
anything else. We're going to get him next time,
Marvel guys. We're going to get him next time and
then we're going to start our own streak starting
with our next episode. But that does it for this
episode. Adrian A.K. Help close this out. That is
going to be BloodSport versus Killmonger. Of
course, BloodSport was in the Suicide Squad
played by Idris angle. And Killmonger was in the
Black Panther film played by Michael B Jordan.
Yeah, it should be a fun episode. I'm really,
really excited for that one. Been looking forward
to that one for a long time. But that does it for this
episode. We want to give a big thanks to our
executive producers, John Strausky, Zachary
Hepburn, Dustin Balcom, Mickey Mathenguyen,
Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yatn, Austin Wazalowski,
AJ Duckerly, Nick Obanto, Scott Camacho, Gil
Camacho, Adam Spees, Dean Molesky, Devin Davis,
Joseph Kirsting, Josh Leiner, Mike Williams, and
Paul Graves for helping make this podcast
possible. We'll talk to you guys next week. Up, up
and away! True believers. This matchup didn't
have Russell Crowe at all. I want my money back.