This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi and welcome
to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe and I'm his twin
brother Johnny DC. And in this episode we're going
to find out who would win in a fight between the
Greek God-powered characters of Mary Marvel and
Hercules. You know, Hercules is not Greek
God-powered, he is the Greek God of Strength in
Marvel. Oh interesting, I didn't realize he was
promoted above Demi-God. Yeah, that is correct. I
do have to say though that even with his godhood, I
think this is a mismatch, probably as big of a one
that was Rey vs. Havoc. Because Mary Marvel has all
of the powers and Hercules is just some strong
dude. So... Isn't it going to be funny when
Hercules beats the shit out of Mary Marvel and then
you're going to be like, oh I was so stupid for
thinking this is a mismatch? No, I don't think
that'll be funny. It'll be funny when Hercules
wins. But before we get into that duel matchup
guys, where we input their stats and run
simulations to see who would win in a fight, we're
going to break down the latest comic book movie
news this past week, of which there was quite a bit
because a lot of studios had their upfront
presentations to potential advertisers. So in
addition to the Superman official trailer, which
sure, yeah that came out last week, we got the Iron
Heart official trailer last week guys, hell yeah.
We also got the teaser for the upcoming Spider-Nor
television show starring Nicholas Cage, and we
also learned that Kristen Ritter will be
returning as Jessica Jones in the next season of
Daredevil Born Again. A lot of great Marvel news
and some rinky-dink DC news, but excited to get
into it. You doing this just tells me how buttery
you are, how good the Superman trailer was. You
know it and you're hard to be true. As always guys,
we list our segment times in our episode
description, so feel free to check out the show
notes if you want to skip ahead to a particular
topic. Our artificially intelligent duel
simulator, AJ9K, has a quick message for our
listeners, so listen up. Thanks AJ9K and thanks to
everyone who supports the podcast. Guys, be sure
to tune into the other shows on the DynaMic Podcast
Network this week, including the console combat
podcast where hosts John and Dean simulate
battles between popular video game characters.
In yesterday's episode, they speculated on who
would win in a fight between Joel Miller from The
Last of Us versus Leon Kennedy from Resident Evil.
That's going to be a good one. Over on the Max
Destruction podcast, hosts Scotty and Gilly, pit
your favorite action heroes from film and
television against each other. They're on a brief
season break, but they will be returning this
June. On the Senjoh  World podcast, host Zachary
Hepburn speculates on fights between fan
favorite anime and manga characters. On
Thursday, Zach is going to reveal who would win in a
fight between Sunraku from Shingra La Frontier
versus Kirito from Sword Art Online. He's finally
feeling better guys, he got the cast off, so we're
glad that he's back with us. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our show
notes to listen to all of the shows in the Dynamite
Podcast Network. But with that out of the way?
Quick to the No Prize! A No Prize is an award that
Marvel used to give out to fans. Our version, the
Dynamic Dual No Prize, is a digital award that we
post on Instagram for the person that we feel gave
the best answer to our question of the week. Last
week we asked you guys, cast any Saturday Night
Live actor as a Marvel or DC superhero, who would
you cast and why? And this is coming off of the news
that Tim Meadows is going to have a role in the
upcoming Peacemaker season 2. We got quite a
number of answers, so we're going to break down
this week's 3 honorable mentions before
revealing the No Prize winner. Our first
honorable mention goes to... by Dear Bangura and
Cyrus Moore. They both gave the same answer so
they're sharing an honorable mention. They
said... I think it'd be pretty interesting. Yeah,
Andy Sandberg is one of the all-time Saturday
Night Live greats in my opinion. I love the Lonely
Island and what they did with their digital
shorts. I think he would totally kill it as Booster
Gold. He may not have the physique to play a
superhero, but I don't think you really need that
when you're playing a comedic character like
Booster Gold who has this high-tech weaponry. It
could work. It could totally work. And you know
what? Have your Metacony play Ted Corden, Blue
Beetle. I could see that working. I could also see
Jason Sudeikis in the role of Ted Corden, Blue
Beetle, since he's been a fancast as that
character for a while. But you know, both Jason
Sudeikis and Andy Sandberg were on SNL at the same
time. You're talking about Andy Sandberg's
physique, but he actually had a pretty good
physique in the movie Popstar and in Brooklyn
Nine-Nine. I think Brooklyn Nine-Nine was a great
show. He really proved himself as a leading man for
a sitcom series like that. And since we know that
Booster Gold is going to be a TV show set in the DCU, I
think Andy Sandberg could totally carry that.
He'd be fantastic. Great answer by Dyr and Cyrus.
Our next honorable mention goes to Travis
Herndon. Who said? What's our dynamic news?
Travis here. Shout out to Manevele Twin. So my
answer would be Kenan Thompson as Night Thrasher.
I think he would be an interesting character for
him to play, especially if you go to comedic route
with him. Kind of like making him Marvel's
equivalent of kickass or vigilante from
Peacemaker. I think Kenan Thompson could pull it
off and you know, you can maybe have him like a
season two of She-Hulk or something as like this
goofy vigilante or something being sued. I love
this idea. At first I wasn't quite sold on the idea
of Kenan Thompson playing a superhero when I was
first listening to Travis's answer. But then when
he pitched the idea of making it kind of like
kickass or vigilante from Peacemaker, I was
instantly sold. I was like, that's exactly how
Kenan should approach this character of Night
Thrasher, who of course is one of the founding
members of the new Warriors team for Marvel. Yeah,
I don't know much about Night Thrasher. Does he
have any powers? No, he's like a master martial
artist. He's a street vigilante in the true sense.
Okay, yeah, that sounds perfect then. Night
Thrasher will be a member of your team in our
upcoming Infinity, Inc. vs. New Warriors team
duel episode, which spoiler alert is going to be
our next episode. So look forward to that. Great
answer, Travis. Our final honorable mention goes
to Mike Williams. Who said? Hi guys, Mike Williams
here. I don't necessarily see anyone I would cast
as a hero, but I see David Spade. I think he would
make a decent arcade. The villain out of Marvel
who's always taunting the X-Men and Spider-Man.
Well, that's my take. As always, make mine Marvel.
Thanks. We got a lot of great answers for this
particular no prize, but this is one of the only
answers where as soon as I heard it, I really
couldn't imagine anyone else in the role. If
Arcade ever makes live action appearance in the
MCU as a villain for the X-Men or maybe like in a
special presentation since I couldn't see him
really holding his own film as a villain, they
would have to cast David Spade in my opinion,
because he would be so perfect for that. Yeah, when
I think of Arcade, he definitely has the voice at
the very least of David Spade. Yeah, I guess if they
went in animated route, but I think he also has the
look minus the red hair. They would just have to dye
David Spade's hair red. But speaking of a lot of
great answers, we want to give a huge shout out to a
bunch of people who called in this past week. You
guys came out of the woodwork and we truly
appreciate it. So shout out to Brian Rochester,
who said that Chris Catan should play Slapstick. I
don't know if the MCU is ready for a character like
Slapstick just yet, but Chris Catan could totally
do the voice for the character because I think
you'd have to go animated for that. Carter Pitts
said Andy Sandbrook should play Trickster, the
Flash villain. Colby Hinches cast a new gods film
with people like Mikey Day as Mr. Miracle and Billy
Crystal as Oberon. Jose Marcial said John Mulaney
should play Snowflame as a cocaine joke. Although
I don't think John Mulaney was ever part of the cast
officially. He was just a writer at SNL. Cat
Stevenson cast the Avengers with SNL characters.
Lorenzo Valdez said Eddie Murphy should play Gus
Gorman, who was the character that Richard Pryor
played in Superman 3. Travis Bailey, who gave a
shout out to his good twin Travis Herndon, said
that Damon Waynes should bring his blank man
character to either the Marvel or DC Universe. But
the winner of this week's No Prize is Paul Graves,
who said... I'm really wishing that I cut that last
part out of his message. I can't censor the truth.
Now, Martin Short has to be one of my favorite SNL
alums of all time. He and Steve Martin are one of the
greatest all time comedy duos ever. And I could
totally see Martin Short playing a character to
perfection like Mr. Misk Spitalik. Yeah, this
answer really stood out to me as well because once I
heard it, I really couldn't imagine anyone else in
the role. Now, of course, I think it was Gilbert
Gottfried who voiced the character in the
Superman cartoon series from the 90s. And he would
have been a great Mr. Misk Spitalik too. But Martin
Short, I think, has the look and the personality, I
think, to tackle a character like that. Yeah, and
despite him being older, he still has quite a bit of
physicality to him too. Oh, for sure. The guy can
move around. He's very spry. Great answer, Paul.
You win this week's No Prize. If you, the listener,
want to shot at winning your own No Prize, stay
tuned to later on in this episode when we'll be
asking another question of the week. But now that
that's done, on to the news. OK, so last week Warner
Brothers finally gave us the first official
trailer for Superman, James Gunn's first DCU film
that's hitting theaters in mid July. Now, we've
had a teaser trailer, which I thought was really
good and an extended version of that. But I feel
like this is the first trailer we've seen where we
finally get to see David Corn Sweat's acting
approach to the character. The trailer starts off
with Clark Kent and Lois Lane. I think in Lois'
apartment, maybe their shared apartment,
they're clearly a couple. But she gets to
interview him for the first time as Superman,
considering he did something fairly
controversial and that he stopped a war abroad to
help save lives. And Rachel Brosnahan, as Lois
Lane, totally kills it as a reporter. You know, she
definitely asks Clark the tough questions enough
for him to get fairly upset. But it's also kind of
cool just to see how much character David Corn
Sweat is going to bring to the character of Clark.
Just in contrast, it made me feel like Henry
Cavill's past performance was a little bit more
muted and maybe a little bit more generic. Like
this Superman seems much more like a real person.
Yeah, it was a really interesting start to the
trailer. It went places I didn't think it was going
to go, but it seems like the film is going to speak
to, you know, the larger issue of superhero ethics
and the role of Superman within modern society,
which is not something any of the other Superman
films have really done. Well, I think Zack Snyder
actually tried to approach ethics in his films.
But just the way this interview was set up, I feel
like it's going to be a little bit more successful
in having the audience ponder these questions. I
didn't really like the editorializing that Lois
Lane kind of did with her questions. It seemed just
a little bit antagonistic, but I guess that's kind
of who Lois Lane is. Oh, absolutely. Yeah. And I
mean, it looks like a lot of people are
antagonistic towards Superman in this trailer,
including the US military, including Lex Luthor,
who has sided with the engineer apparently to
invade the fortress of solitude, which I didn't
love seeing that in this trailer. I think I figured
that it was going to happen, but this is going to be
the third or fourth movie now where Lex Luthor has
broken into the fortress. Oh, yeah, there was
Superman 2 famously and also Superman Returns
with Kevin Spacey's version of Lex Luthor. But
Nicholas Holt plays a pretty damn good Lex Luthor,
I think. Yeah, just watching Kim perform, I have to
feel like his acting is coming from a very real
place of him just missing out on the role of
Superman because he was next in line after David
Cornswet to get the role. So he's probably like,
fucking David Cornswet. The engineer looks
interesting. She's made up entirely of like
nanobots and can transform her limbs and stuff
into deadly weapons. She kind of comes across as
like the Faiora of this movie. But we also get to see
like Miss Tess Mocker, like doing a selfie with
Superman fighting a monster in the background. We
get to see a lot of supporting cast, including Ma
and Pod Kent. Actually, Pod Kent, Jonathan Kent
get some voiceover in this trailer, which is kind
of cool. They're very, very like Kansas farm
couple. Like more so, I feel like than any other
depiction of them that we've seen on screen. For
sure. Yeah, I liked how human they were presented
where Ma Kent was like, I cleaned your boots. I'll
go get them. It was funny. Of course, we also get to
see the Justice League in this trailer with Green
Lantern, Hawk Girl, Mr. Terrific. And we get to see
them display some of their powers like Green
Lantern kind of flicking some soldiers with a
giant green hand. And we also get to see
Metamorpho, who looks like is caged with Superman
in this like glass prison. And he's keeping him
there by turning his hand into Kryptonite, which
is pretty wild. Yeah, Metamorpho is a good guy,
though. So Lex Luthor must be manipulating him in
order to create that Kryptonite. Yeah, it kind of
looks that way. Maybe by the end of this,
Metamorpho will join the Justice League. We also
get to see Ultraman in this trailer. I think that's
Ultraman. People keep calling him Ultraman. I'm
still not 100 percent sure if that's the actual
Ultraman, you know, from Earth 3 or if that's like
Lex's battle suit or what it is. No idea. There's
still a lot to the story that I feel like we don't
know anything about yet. Well, speaking of battle
suits, Superman fights another guy wearing a like
juggernaut almost ask battle suit in this
trailer. Yeah, one that has heat vision. Yeah. Is
that Lex Luthor's battle suit? Is it someone
else's? No idea. But he also fights a Kaiju. I feel
like Superman is just going up against everybody
in this movie. Oh, yeah. Yeah, this movie is going
to be all over the place, I feel like, which I'm kind
of concerned about, but we'll see how James Gunn
handles it. I didn't love the way the trailer ended
with the end joke with, oh, you have a dog and then
there's crypto. It's cute, but it's also
Marvel-esque to me. Like, I don't need that kind of
end stinger joke in my DC trailers. Well, DC is just
trying to copy a successful formula, and that is to
say, you know, they're ripping off Marvel. Just
give me more epicness. All right. I don't need the
jokes. I need the epicness. And it looks like this
movie is going to be pretty epic. It comes out in
July 11th. Can't wait to see it. Super stoked. Way
more stoked for this than some shit show like Iron
Heart is probably going to be. Why are you dissing
on Iron Heart? Because they released the trailer
the same day that Warner Brothers released the
Superman trailer, knowing that it was going to
just get buried. Like, who does that? All I know is
that it looks like people are hyped for the Iron
Heart trailer, and I would consider myself one of
them. But let's talk about it. So the trailer
starts off really hammering home that the series
is executive produced by Ryan Coogler, who, of
course, directed the Black Panther films. With
the latter film in the series actually debuting
the character of Riri Williams, where she goes to
Wakanda and builds the Iron Heart suit of armor. Of
course, she doesn't get to take it back with her. So
this Iron Heart series, I think, is her trying to
rebuild and improve upon her designs. She goes
into this elevator in the trailer where it
suddenly starts filling up with gas. And we hear
from the hood who's played by Anthony Ramos that
this is an interview pitch to see if she can get out
of this deadly trap. The way she gets out of it is a
little strange because instead of disarming the
gas bomb and putting on the gas mask, she, I guess,
stops the elevator. Man handles one of the handles
off of the side of the elevator and then uses it as
leverage to pry open the elevator door, which
seemed a little low-tech from my perspective. You
would think that she would do something a little
bit more crazy, like, I don't know, turn the
elevator into a jet that shoots out of the building
or something. I don't know. That's just off the top
of my head. I don't know if that's a good example.
But manhandling the doors open was not that
impressive to me in terms of a tech solution. Yeah,
it literally wasn't a tech solution unless you're
going back to caveman tech. But they called her a
genius for her actions there. I guess she passes
her interview by performing these actions. It did
take some out-of-the-box thinking, which can
definitely be considered genius inventive
thinking. You know, she's going to MIT. We see her
working on New Iron Man armor. She says she wants to
build something iconic, which was a little bit of a
strange adjective to me because I think to be
iconic, you know, you're building something that
is a symbol, but it also implies a sort of
originality. But we know that the Iron Heart armor
is heavily inspired by the Iron Man armor. I
thought the same exact thing. To me, an icon is set
apart from everything else and really is a legacy
character for Iron Man. Right, yeah. She takes on
Tony Stark's legacy and I hope they address that in
this series. I think to not bring up Tony Stark at
all would be a mistake. And what was really
interesting is that in the comic books, Tony
Stark's consciousness depicted as an AI hologram
really served as a mentor for Riri as she was
building the suit of armor. They kind of became
like colleagues in a sense in that way, which was
really nice. I think that's what fans want and
expect from this series. And my concern is that
they're not going to address Tony Stark's legacy
at all. I mean, eventually Riri becomes her own
character, but we don't want to lose sight of that
legacy, I think. From the previous look at this
show that we got, I think last year at D23, we
learned that the series is taking on kind of like a
set it off type plot where Riri temporarily
becomes a thief in order to get the money to fund her
work, building the Iron Heart armor. Therefore,
she partners with Parker Robbins, a.k .a. the
hood. Who seems pretty cool in this trailer too? We
see that he can bend his magic bullets like he can in
the comic books. The source of his powers are magic
based in nature. He gets the hood from Mephisto and
rumors are that Mephisto will be making an
appearance in this series, which is interesting
because we'll get that magic versus technology
angle here. There was one shot that I thought was
pretty cool, if not a bit derivative, where it
looks like Riri is going to get run over by a semi
truck and the armor comes to save her. And then she
does like a superhero landing and punches the
truck over her. We've seen that a lot in these
superhero shows. So it wasn't that original to see
it again. I'm really hoping that they take this
series in a direction to make it worth the
investment that Marvel Studios has put into it.
Because I don't know if there's a whole lot of
demand for this series, but if it's good, then I
don't think people will care that there wasn't a
lot of demand. Very true. And you've mentioned the
investment that Marvel has put into this and it
does look like they put quite a bit of money. The
show looks really good, I would say. I don't mean
just the special effects, but just the
cinematography alone. Yeah, it's very
cinematic. The end stinger after the title card,
we see Riri go into some guy's bunker. The
character is Joe McGillicuddy, who is an original
character to this series. I don't remember that
name from the comic books. And I didn't even know
that Alden Ehrenreich was going to be in this show.
So it was pretty interesting that he shows up.
Yeah, I almost wonder if he's like a stand in for
Tony Stark as that kind of mentor type figure.
Maybe. He does have like guided missiles in his
bunker or something like that. So he might be some
kind of weapons designer like Tony Stark was.
We'll see. The show comes out in about a month. The
first three episodes are going to launch on June
24th on Disney Plus. And then we're going to get the
remaining three episodes in the weeks after that.
It is surprising that they're debuting the show
with like the first half of the entire season. I'm
really looking forward to the show. I hope it's
good. All I know is that the trailer was better than
the Superman trailer. And all I know is that you
know that you are lying to yourself. But that
brings us to our question of the week. Who had the
better official trailer last week? Superman or
Ironheart? Obviously the answer is Ironheart,
Team Marvel, step up, call in with your answer. Let
us know why Superman is no good. Record your answer
at dynamicduel.com by clicking on the red
microphone button in the bottom right hand corner
of the screen. Which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long. And don't forget to leave your name in case we
include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a dynamic
duel no prize that we'll post to Instagram. Be sure
to answer before May 24th. Speaking of Marvel
trailers, we got the first official teaser for
Spider Noir, which is a series that's going to
debut on Amazon Prime and stars Nicholas Cage as
Spider-Man. The Noir version of Spider-Man as he
was depicted in the Spider-Man into the
Spider-Verse animated movie. Now it's strange is
that this hasn't officially been released by
Amazon. Like it's not under official YouTube
channel or anything like that, which I thought was
strange. Yeah, the trailer was debuted during
their upfront presentation. And I don't know if it
was supposed to be publicly released, although
the version that some channels have put out looks
pretty official. It's pretty damn cool looking.
It's giving Sin City vibes. Oh, yeah. That's the
first thing I thought when I saw this and I was
instantly sold. Like these 30 seconds to me are way
better than the entire Iron Heart trailer. In the
trailer, we hear a guy talking about how this
version of New York, I think it is, needs a hero. And
we hear Nick Cage say, well, I hope it finds one.
There's a spider that crawls by his foot and it
looks like we see his spider sense tingling at one
point. It also crawls on his hand and we see him beat
the shit out of some bad guys. The camera work is
really damn interesting, especially for a noir
project like this, because the camera is very
dynamic. We see Spider-Man flipping on walls and
sliding across the floor. And there's one part
where he's hiding behind a bad guy and he clicks his
goggles on, which glow kind of like headlamps,
which I think makes for a really damn cool visual.
Yeah, it looks badass. And we really haven't seen
this kind of style of filmmaking since Sin City and
Frank Miller's The Spirit, although I never
really watched that. That was a horrible movie.
I've heard. But I mean, it looks really cool. So I'm
glad to see that it's being used once again for this
because this feels like it's the perfect project
for that style. It kind of looks like a great mix of
Spider-Man and Batman. I'm actually surprised
that DC has never thought to produce a noir series
with Batman like this. Well, Amazon Prime
actually does a noir style version of Batman
already in Batman Caped Crusader, the animated
series produced by Bruce Tim. If they ever did that
in live action, I think they could totally do a
similar style to this. Absolutely, yeah. That
would be cool. I think one of the coolest things
about this teaser was the title card for
Spider-Nor. I really like the font that they
chose. It's very noir looking. Yeah, it's like an
art deco kind of style, but it's wonky. Yeah, the
font weight is shifted over. That gives us some
interesting character. And it's all set in
shadow, too. It's really cool looking, real
atmospheric. We learned that the show is coming
next year in 2026. So I'm really looking forward to
that. Speaking of the upfront presentations by
Studios, we learned this past week from Marvel
that Kristen Ritter will be joining the cast of
Daredevil Born Again Season 2, reprising her role
as Jessica Jones. Which means that since
Daredevil Born Again took on the continuity of the
Netflix Daredevil series and that version of
Daredevil and Jessica Jones teamed up in The
Defenders, that means that the Jessica Jones
series is also part of the MCU continuity and we'll
get to see that character return with all of that
established backstory. So these characters
won't be meeting each other for the first time in
season 2. They'll be meeting again and maybe
that'll even lead to a reformation of The
Defenders. But hopefully without Finn Jones. Or
he could come back and pass on the mantle of Iron
Fist onto a character like Lin Lee, the Sword
Master, or something like that and establish that
Iron Fist legacy. I think that would be a cool way to
use him if he came back. But it would make sense for
some heroes to show up in season 2 since we know that
at the end of season 1, Daredevil is putting
together basically a team to go up against the
Kingpin, who's the mayor of New York. Yeah, I have
trouble seeing how Kingpin is going to stand a
chance against a group of superpowered
vigilantes like Jessica Jones and The Other
Defenders, unless Kingpin himself starts to hire
out superpowered individuals, which will be
pretty cool. That would be pretty cool. I'd like to
see that. There's a lot of speculation to be had
here. I really hope they bring back Mike Coulter as
Luke Cage and then bring on some other street
heroes like Moon Knight or something like that.
Bring in Oscar Isaac and stuff like that. Who
knows? The sky's the limit. If Kristen Ritter is
coming back as Jessica Jones, who knows who else we
might see. We don't know the specific date, but
it's been said that the season is going to debut in
March of 2026, so a year after the first season came
out. If you guys listen to this show a lot, you'll
know that we rated Daredevil born again season 1, 4
stars out of 5, so I'm really looking forward to
season 2. The Dark Knight's definitive DC comic
stories adapted directly for audio for the very
first time. New episodes every Wednesday,
wherever you get your podcasts. But that does it
for all the news for this episode, so let's go ahead
and move into our main event, where we find out who
would win in a fight between the Greek God-powered
characters of Mary Marvel and Hercules. Alright,
Mary Marvel vs. Hercules. Now, we decided to do
this episode because Hercules is a big-time
Avengers character in the comic books. He's the
most known for being a part of that team, as well as
the champions. But, you know, he's a prominent
Marvel character who's fought alongside of a lot
of other Marvel characters. So we wanted to give
him his due. He did make an appearance at the end of
the Thor 11 Thunder movie played by Brett
Goldstein. Who knows if we're going to see that guy
again? But I really hope we do because he's an
awesome character, and all he knows is that he's
going to beat the crap out of Mary Marvel. People
say this. I don't know why they're smoking crack.
Because there's no way that's happening. People?
What people? Everyone who's claiming that
Hercules is going to beat Mary Marvel. He's
strong, and that's it. I'm pretty sure. I've seen
the Disney movie. That's all he does. Now, Mary
Marvel, of course, is the sister of Shazam,
initially his twin sister, and later on his
adoptive sister. But we have seen her on screen,
just like Hercules, of course, played by Grace
Caroline Curry in the Shazam films. If she's such a
great DC character, then why is she named after
Marvel? Because the original Captain Marvel did
not belong to Marvel, it belonged to Fawcett
Comics, who was bought by DC. Mary Marvel has gone
through a few name changes throughout the years,
especially since the new 52 relaunch of DC
continuity, like Lady Shazam. But they didn't
quite stick. It's because everybody knows that
Marvel's better. I'm just going to say that. And
Mary Marvel's going to learn that today. But to
explain the methodology behind our duels, let's
go to our sentient dual simulator, Alfred Jarvis
9000. AJ9K tell our listeners how you go about
determining your winner in our dual matchups.
There are many variables that can occur during
battle. The stat parameters are based on the
official Marvel power grid from which the DC
characters statistics are extrapolated.
Additional stat categories are included such as
range, damage potential, versatility and
perception in order to create a more detailed and
accurate simulation. The results of the 1000
simulations provide a percentage of wins for each
character. The contestant with the higher
percentage is declared the victor as they have a
higher probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither character should win
100% of the matches. The comic book stories have
shown that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman, so the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks, A.J .9K!
Before we run the simulations though, we'd like to
break down each character's histories and
abilities before improvising a scenario on how we
imagine one of the 1000 simulations would play out
beat for beat. And it's my turn to go first with the
DC characters' backstory, so let me tell you all
about Mary Marvel. Now, Mary Batson was the twin
sister of Billy Batson, born to archaeologists
C.C. and Marilyn Batson. While Billy remained in
the United States, Mary accompanied her parents
on an archaeological expedition to Egypt, funded
by the villainous scientist Thaddeus Savanna.
There, Theo Adam murdered the elder Batson's and
kidnapped Mary, leaving her in the care of his
sister, Sarah Prim, back in America, where it was
arranged for Mary to be illegally adopted by Nick
and Nora Bromfield. Renamed Mary Bromfield, she
grew up in a wealthy, idealic environment unaware
of her true origins, though she was haunted by
reoccurring dreams of a brother she had
forgotten. Meanwhile, Billy grew up in foster
care and on the streets before being granted the
power of the wizard Shazam, allowing him to
transform into the hero formerly known as Captain
Marvel and better known simply as Shazam. You can
learn more about him in our Shazam vs Black Bolt
dual episode. Billy and the wizard searched for
Mary for years without success, with Billy's only
clue to her identity and whereabouts being her
favorite toy, a tiger doll named Takitani that had
been sent back from Egypt with the Batson's
belongings. As luck would have it, Mary entered a
regional spelling bee in Fawcett City, where
Billy, now working for Wiz Radio, was the MC. After
rescuing Mary from a kidnapping attempt as the
hero Shazam, Billy noticed her resemblance to his
sister and confirmed her identity through
private investigation. The truth revealed Billy
delivered the Takitani doll to Mary, who was again
kidnapped by the same thugs. When Mary opened the
package and saw the doll and the papers proving her
identity, Takitani came to life and instructed
her to speak the word Shazam to save her brother.
Upon doing so, she was struck by magical lightning
and transformed into the divinely powered hero.
Mary defeated the Canepers and reunited with
Billy, joining him as a member of the Marvel family
under the name Mary Marvel. Mary fought alongside
her brother Billy and his friend Freddy Freeman,
the hero known as Captain Marvel Jr., against a
variety of magical and superpowered threats in
the universe known as Earth Five. After the
multiverse collapsed into one universe
following the crisis on Infinite Earths, Mary now
shared her power with Billy and Freddy, resulting
in a sometimes tense dynamic between the three
since the balance of magical energy shifted
depending on whoever invoked the magical word of
Shazam. At one point, a disruption in the cosmic
balance of magic prevented the marvels from
reverting to their mortal forms, forcing them to
journey to the Source Wall at the edge of the
universe to repair the broken nature of magic
itself. Mary later joined the Super Buddies, a
team of former Justice Leaguers and participated
in several adventures before traveling with
Supergirl. Mary was killed by a cursed dagger in
the Garden of Eden but was eventually resurrected
by one of Supergirl's allies. Following the death
of the wizard Shazam, Mary lost her powers,
causing her to fall from the sky. Though she
survived, she fell into a coma and was cared for by
Freddy. Upon awakening, Mary was unable to access
her powers. Ignoring warnings, she traveled to
Gotham City and encountered Black Adam, who
transferred his power to Mary, transforming her
into a darker version of herself with a black
costume and mystical power. You can learn more
about Black Adam in our Black Adam vs. Apocalypse
dual episode. Seeking guidance with her newfound
power, Mary turned to Zatanna, Clarion the
Witchboy, and finally Eclipse, who at the time was
possessing Jean Maureen. Eclipse corrupted Mary
and attempted to offer her to Darkseid as a
concubine, though Mary rebelled and overpowered
her. Realizing the corruption her new powers had
caused, she rejected them, transferring the
tainted lightning into Eclipse. Both women fell
into the ocean, but Mary washed ashore on the
Mosquera, where she helped expose the deception
of Granny goodness, who had been impersonating
the goddess Athena to manipulate the Amazons. You
can learn more about Granny goodness in our
Darkseid's Elite vs. Black Order team dual
episode. After journeying through the
multiverse with the challengers of the unknown,
Mary eventually returned to Earth to confront
Darkseid. Secumbing to temptation, she accepted
the return of Black Adam's powers, adopting her
black costume once again. Though ultimately
freed from Darkseid's influence by Freddy,
Mary's exposure to Dark magic had lasting
consequences. After Darkseid's defeat, she
sought to join Black Adam, informing a new Black
Marvel family, but was rejected. Resolving to
operate alone, Mary became a solo heroine for a
time. Later, however, Black Adam enlisted Mary to
join him and Isis in Seizing the Rock of Eternity,
where they stripped Billy of his power. Mary
forced Billy to say her name, transforming him
into a corrupted Black Marvel. Together, Mary and
Billy launched an assault on the Justice Society
of America, only to be defeated when Black Adam
turned against Isis. When the wizard Shazam
resurrected, all four were stripped of their
power. The wizard declared Mary and Billy
unworthy and barred them from the Rock of
Eternity. Homeless and powerless, the twins
wandered the streets of Fawcett City. Mary was
later tempted by the demon Blaze to kill Freddy in
exchange for restored powers, but ultimately
sided with her brother. Together, the three
defeated Blaze and Freddy vowed to find a way to
restore their abilities. In post-Flashpoint
continuity, Mary was no longer Billy's twin
sister, but an unrelated older foster sister
named Mary Bromfield, the eldest foster child of
Rosa and Victor Vazquez. Having run away from an
abuse of home, she became a maternal figure among
the other foster children, including Freddy
Freeman, Darla Dudley, Pedro Pena, Eugene Choi,
and later Billy Batson. When Billy was granted the
power of Shazam, he later shared his abilities
with the other foster siblings, transforming
them into the family. Mary became a red-suited
adult version of herself gifted with the living
lightning. Alongside her family, she fought
Black Adam and other magical threats across the
Seven Magic Lands, hoping to restore her brothers
from the King Kid's tyranny and battling Mr. Mind
and the Monster Society of Evil. In the aftermath
of these events, Mary began noticing a disturbing
shift in Billy's personality, who, unbeknownst
to her, was being influenced by the Batman who
laughs, who you could learn more about in our
Batman Who Laughs vs. Cosmic Ghostwriter
episode. Billy became erratic and aggressive,
distancing himself from the rest of the Shazam
family. After tracking him to a confrontation
with the war god Ares, Mary attempted to help Billy
by fighting at Ares' side against her adopted
brother. Billy feigned remorse and tricked Mary
into lowering her guard, using his corrupted
magic to infect her with the same dark influence
that had overtaken him. Mary transformed,
adopting a more volatile demeanor, until the
corrupting force lost its grip following the fall
of the Batman Who Laughs. The Shazam family lost
their powers as Billy's connection to the Rock of
Eternity weakened. Mary visited Billy at Titans
Academy, urging him to see Freddy, whose health
was deteriorating without magic. Not long after,
Mary enrolled at Vassier College, attempting to
live a normal life. However, she was summoned by
Hoppy, the magical rabbit, sent by Billy to
deliver a message that she was now the new champion
of Shazam. After stopping a bank robbery as Lady
Shazam, Mary soon discovered her foster parents
had gone missing. Transferring to Fawcett City
Community College, she began investigating a
string of disappearances tied to mysterious
magical technology. Facing villains like
Disaster Master and Babbel, Mary unraveled the
mystery behind the abductions, ultimately
discovering that Georgia's Savanna, the
daughter of Thaddeus Savanna, was responsible.
Mary rescued the kidnapped townspeople,
defeated Savanna, and fully embraced her role as
the new champion of Shazam. It wasn't long,
however, that Mary sacrificed her powers during
an attack by the goddess Hera on humanity, after
which one of Roman's recently deceased mother,
Hippolyta, now ascended to Godhood, declared
Mary worthy of her own unique empowerment.
Granting her the blessings of a new pantheon of
goddesses, Hippolyta severed Mary's dependence
on the wizard Shazam, establishing her as a divine
champion in her own right. Powers-wise, Mary
Marvel possesses the magical ability to
transform into a superpowered version of herself
by saying the word Shazam. In her earlier
incarnations, her powers derived from the wizard
Shazam and were shared with her siblings.
Currently, however, Mary has her own distinct
powersets by a new pantheon of goddesses, the
agility of Selene, the strength of Hippolyta, the
stamina of Artemis, the flight of Zephyrus, the
invulnerability of Aurora, and the wisdom of
Minerva. Though she still transforms using the
word Shazam, she no longer bears the wizard's
living lightning, though she could still summon
Zeus's Thunderbolts. That's Mary Marvel. How
does she summon lightning if she doesn't have the
power of Zeus anymore? I don't know, man. She just
does. Zeus hears her and lightning happens.
Actually, this list of goddesses is pretty close
to her original list of deities, like Pre-Crisis,
whom she derived her powers from. Oh,
interesting. Okay. And what is her current
superhero name in the comics? Mary Marvel. Okay.
All right. I just wanted to hear that. DC's really
got to get over the Marvel thing, man. Like, they
just got to accept the fact that Marvel should own
any superhero name pertaining to Marvel. Uh, no, I
think we'll keep it. She was for a while called Mary
Shazam, and that just sounds bad. That does sound
really bad. Well, let me tell you all about the
Marvel version of Hercules. Heracles
Panhellenios was born in ancient Greece as the son
of a mortal woman, Alcmenna, and Zeus, king of the
Olympian gods. Zeus seduced Alcmenna by
disguising himself as her husband, Amphitrion.
Upon discovering the affair, Zeus's wife Hera
became wrathful and tried to kill the child. Even
as an infant, Heracles displayed supernatural
strength by strangling two serpents Hera sent to
kill him in his crib. Hoping to appease the
goddess, the child was named Heracles, meaning
the glory of Hera, though it did nothing to prevent
her wrath. Heracles was raised by Amphitrion and
trained in various forms of combat. As a youth, he
accidentally killed his music teacher and was
sent away to learn to control his strength and
pursue a life of heroism. He eventually defended
the city of Thebes from a group of minion pirates
and as a reward was given the hand of the princess
Magara, daughter of King Crian. They had two
children and lived peacefully. Zeus, wanting
Heracles to prove himself worthy of immortality,
arranged for him to serve his cousin, who
instructed Heracles to complete a series of 12
impossible tasks. These would later become known
as the 12 labors of Hercules. The first labor was to
slay the Nemean lion, whose hide was impervious to
weapons. Heracles strangled the beast and wore
its pelt as armor. Next, he traveled to Lerno to
face the Hydra, a multi-headed serpent that
regrew two heads for everyone severed. With help
from his nephew Iolus, who cauterized the necks,
Heracles defeated the creature and dipped his
arrows in its poisonous blood. Additional tasks
including capturing the Arimathean boar,
hunting the sacred Serenane Hyned of Artemis, and
dispersing the Stemphalian birds created by
Ares. He cleaned the Aegean stables by diverting
two rivers, captured the Cretan bull, stole the
man-eating mares of Diomedes, and obtained the
Amazon Queen Hippolyta's Golden Girdle. He then
slew the three-bodied Gurian to claim his red
cattle and tricked the Titan Atlas into helping
him retrieve Golden Apples from the Garden of
Hesperides. The final labor was the most
harrowing, descending into the underworld to
retrieve Cerberus, the three-headed guard dog of
Hades. His success completing all 12 labors
earned him recognition from the gods, but his
return to his home of Thebes was marked by tragedy.
During his absence, Thebes had been overtaken by
an outside nobleman named Lycus, who killed King
Crian and condemned Megara and her children to
death. Blood lusted and driven mad by a curse from
Hera, Heracles killed not only Lycus, but also his
wife Megara and their two sons. Haunted by shame,
he began using the Romanized version of his name,
Hercules, to distance himself from both Hera and
his past. Hercules adventured across the ancient
world. He killed Keknos, son of Ares, who was
murdering travelers to construct a temple from
their bones. When King Glamiden of Troy refused to
pay Hercules for saving his daughter from a sea
monster, Hercules raised the city, killing the
king and all his sons saved one. He battled the
river god Acherus for the hand of Daenerys, who
would become his next wife. Eventually, Hercules
met his mortal end after Daenerys, fearing that he
had been unfaithful, unknowingly poisoned him
with what she believed was a love potion. Feeling
sympathy for his son, Zeus separated Hercules'
mortal body from his divine spirit and raised him
to Olympus as the new god of strength. Though now
divine, Hercules retained his love for adventure
and he returned to earth often. He participated in
the first Olympic games, allegedly battled
Vikings, and claimed an affair with Marie
Antoinette. During World War II, he fought for the
Greek resistance while disguised as the
Submariner to avoid punishment from Olympus for
intervening in human affairs. In the modern era,
he emerged again and met Thor, joining him on the
Avengers. Deceived into signing a contract by
Pluto, Hercules was nearly trapped in the
underworld again until Thor rescued him. He later
fell under the Enchantress's spell and fought the
Avengers before regaining his senses. Exiled
from Olympus for coming to earth without
permission, Hercules remained with the
Avengers, battling Dragon Man, Typhon, and Ares.
You can learn more about the Avengers and their
team duel against the Justice League. Hercules
became a founding member of another superhero
team called the Champions, alongside Black
Widow, Iceman, Angel, and Goshreiter. He and
Black Widow developed a romantic interlude.
Later, Hercules was beaten into a coma by the
Masters of Evil after attempting to battle them
alone while intoxicated. Zeus blamed the
Avengers for his son's coma and imprisoned them in
Hades, but Hercules awoke, cleared their names,
and brokered peace. You can learn more about the
Masters of Evil and their team duel against the
Hercules later helped fight the High
Evolutionary and Dr. Doom. He was devastated by
the apparent deaths of the Avengers during their
battle with Onslaught, a psychic entity you can
learn more about in his duel against Parallax. He
joined Heroes for Hire and Shield before
rejoining the Avengers upon the Hero's return and
fought with the team until its dissolution at the
hands of the Scarlet Witch, who split the team
apart in a fit of madness. You can learn more about
that in the 10 versus Scarlet Witch duel episode.
Without his team, Hercules fell into depression,
a moment of vulnerability exploited by Hera and
Eurystheus. They challenged him to complete a
modern version of the 12 labors, this time as part
of a reality television show. Among his
challenges, Hercules captured a Sabertooth
Tiger in the Savage Land, defeated a Hydra
genetically created by Hydra, captured the
teleporting dog Lockjaw from the Blue Area of the
Moon, fought Dragon Man, and drove Atuma's Hordes
from Atlantis. Later tasks involved surviving
Red Skull's Dust of Death, defeating the
Abomination, capturing a monster in Hawaii,
stealing Captain America's Shield, retrieving a
Doombot from Laveria, dragging a Shield
Helicarrier by Chain, and returning to the
Underworld to retrieve a flower from his former
wife, Megara. In Hades, Megara and their children
forgave Hercules for their murder,
understanding Hera's role in the tragedy, and she
gave him a flower of love. He opposed the
Superhuman Registration Act during the
superhero Civil War and joined Captain America's
Secret Avengers. In the final battle, he
destroyed the Thor clone Ragnarok, claiming it
was an insult to the real Thor. He later formed the
Renegades with Amadeus Cho, Namora, and others to
aid the Hulk upon his return from being exiled by
some of Earth's heroes to space, empathizing with
a fellow warrior. When the Skrulls secretly
invaded Earth on behalf of their alien deities,
Hercules led a team of gods from multiple
pantheons called the God Squad. This included
Snowbird, the Inuit Demigoddess, Ajek, the
Eternal, the Egyptian Godslayer Demigorge, and
Mikaboshi, the Shinto God of Chaos. Together,
they slayed the Skrull gods, Kleibin and Sigurt.
Eventually, Mikaboshi evolved into a new entity
called the Chaos King and began destroying all
realms of the afterlife. Hercules reunited with
the God Squad to seal the entity away, but he
expanded all his godly energy in the process,
becoming mortal. Hercules settled in Brooklyn,
bartending at a Greek restaurant and using
magical weapons from his brother Aerys' armory,
such as the Sword of Pellius and Perseus' shield.
During the Norse god of fear, the Serpent's
attack, Hercules helped save Brooklyn from
becoming a Hellscape and became a local hero. He
later served as a guest instructor at the Avengers
Academy and fought against a new pantheon of gods
that included the God of Data and the Goddess of
Vanity. After defeating them, he declined to
return to Olympus, choosing instead to live among
mortals. Hercules rejoined the Avengers during
their fight against King the Conqueror and later
helped a new iteration of the champions,
eventually regaining his godhood with help from
god particle scientist, Roshna Cole. He later
learned Nix, the Greek goddess of night, had slain
most of the Olympian gods, who subsequently
returned in a corrupted form. Hercules was
captured by these dark gods, but was rescued by the
Guardians of the Galaxy. After helping that team
exile the dark gods, Hercules returned to Earth
and helped the Avengers fight off a vampire
invasion. And that's Hercules' backstory.
Powers-wise, Hercules, as the Greek god of
strength, is the physically strongest of all the
Olympian gods, unable to lift well in excess of 100
tons. He is also the most durable of his pantheon,
with his invulnerability, unable to run at speeds
around 100mph and leap 100 feet in the air. His
immortality grants him limitless stamina,
regenerative healing, and toxin resistance. He
is a master combatant in Greco-Roman wrestling
and wields a number of mythological weapons,
including his indestructible adamantine mace
forged by his brother Hephaestus, the sword of
Pellius, a curved syca forged by the centaur
Kyren, the shield of Perseus, which can
temporarily turn observers to stone when the
shield's covers removed, and the bow of Hercules,
with arrows dipped in hydra blood. And that is
Hercules. Okay, so he just carries all of these
weapons around with him at all times? Usually when
I see him, he's just holding this golden hammer
club thing. Well, modern comics, Hercules is
usually depicted actually with his mace and the
sword of Pellius, but he's gone on multiple
adventures with the shield. Actually, I less
commonly see him use the bow, but it's his, it's
named after him, it's the bow of Hercules, and
yeah, he'll have it for this fight. Okay, cheater.
At the very least, he'll have the mace and the
sword, because he almost always carries those
around now. They're like strapped on his back like
an X, but we'll say that the shield covers that, and
then you know, the bow is just strapped to his side,
we'll say, I don't know. Yeah, having the sword and
the shield and the mace and the quiver and the bow on
his back is a lot. That's, it's probably too much,
you're right. I guess he won't have the bow for this
match, since yeah, it's less commonly used, but
he'll at least have his sword, his shield, and his
mace. We'll say that. Dual, where comic book
titans smash every Tuesday. Max destruction,
where TV and action heroes battle every
Wednesday, and Sendro World, where anime
champions clash every Thursday. Join us as we
speculate on the matches and armed with the power
of mathematical simulations, discover who will
emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com,
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
But now that we got their histories and abilities
out of the way, let's speculate on how one of the
1000 simulated matches will go. The winner is
determined by simulations, not the speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how this fight could play
out. AJ9K, what are the rules or speculation?
Well, I should say there are no rules other than the
characters have no prior knowledge of the other
going into the fight. All they are aware of
starting out is that the other character is a
threat that needs to be eliminated. For the
speculation, the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the match
itself, as no environmental statistics are
considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. Alright,
then let's get into it. Mary Marble and Hercules
meet on the battlefield. Who goes first? Now, I
will admit that probably because of the wisdom of
Minerva, Mary Marble wouldn't go first and would
probably wait to observe where Hercules would do.
Yeah, plus Hercules is more belligerent than
Mary, right? So yeah, he's gonna go first, and he's
gonna start out by pulling out his Mace, his
adamantine Mace, and he's gonna slam it into the
ground, which is gonna create this big
earth-shattering earthquake that's gonna open
this fissure that travels along the ground and
knocks Mary into the air with seismic force. Okay,
yeah, that's fine. Mary stays floating in the air
thanks to the flight of Zephyrus, one of her
powers, and she's probably gonna snatch one of the
boulders that are also flung upward, and she's
gonna hurl that sucker right at Hercules with the
strength of Hippolyta. Alright, so Hercules sees
this boulder being thrown at him, and he's gonna
spin around while holding his Mace out, kind of
like how an Olympian would do in the Hammer Throw
event at the Olympics, and he's gonna let go of the
Mace hurling it at the boulder, which just
explodes the rock into pebbles in the air, and the
Mace is actually gonna travel through the boulder
and slam right into Mary Marble, which is gonna
knock her out of the air, and she's probably like in
a coma now on the ground. Now, she has the agility of
Selene, so Mary's actually gonna dodge the Mace,
and she's gonna rock it down into the ground and
cause her own like miniature earthquake that's
gonna knock Hercules into the air, and that's
gonna give her this opening, and she's going to
just uppercut him right into the stratosphere.
No, no, she tries to uppercut him, but he catches
her fist as she tries to, and then he's gonna
grapple her flinging her over his shoulder, and
then position her head down to do this like pile
driver move right into the ground. So he slams her
down, and now they're both in this big crater.
Okay, well, you know, thanks to the
invulnerability of Aurora, Mary's not that hurt.
And with Hercules on top of her pinning her down,
that's when Mary is going to just call out Shazam
summoning Zeus's lightning, which is gonna crash
into Hercules and just stun the shit out of him. And
with him dazed, that's when Mary just kicks
Hercules right in the balls with all of her
strength. No, no, Hercules has his shield on his
back. So he's not going to be stunned from Zeus's
lightning, because the shield is going to protect
him. So he's going to leap to his feet, you know,
dodging this kick from Mary Marvel, and then he's
going to equip the shield of Perseus and the sword
of Pellius from off his back into his arms. And he's
going to raise the sword above his head and come
down with a mighty chop that's just going to finish
Mary Marvel off and end this match. Well, except
when Hercules is coming down on her with his sword,
Mary's gonna, you know, clap her hands together
above her, stopping the blade in her palms. And
that's when she's going to scream again, Shazam a
second time. And a lightning bullet is going to
come down, strike the tip of the blade, and that
electricity is going to move through the sword
into Hercules body and just fry his brain. And
yeah, since the lightning passed through Mary,
she probably transforms back into her mortal
form. But since Hercules is now dead, it doesn't
matter. She wins. Now, I think Hercules is too
durable to be finished with just one bolt of magic
lightning. You know, he's hurt for sure, but he's
not dead. He's on the ground, injured. And as Mary
stands up, you know, she's in her mortal form now.
From the ground, Hercules just chucks his shield
right at her, walloping her and taking her out
because she doesn't have her enhanced durability
anymore. Oh no, I mean, she saw that Hercules
didn't die from this electricity. So right away,
she's going to cry out Shazam once again, as the
shield is hurtling towards her. And the lightning
bolt that strikes her, allowing her to transform
the energy from that ricochets the shield back
toward Hercules. And it's just going to
decapitate him straight up. Okay. No, but
Hercules is not a chump who'd get taken out with his
own shield. Okay, these catches the shield as it
ricochets back toward him. But that lightning
bolt explosion, just incinerated the cloth cover
that was over the shield. So Hercules wheels the
shield again, and Medusa's face is now visible on
the front of the shield, and her eyes glow green,
and the shield turns Mary Marvel into stone. And
that's when Hercules leaps over and just double
drop kicks the Mary Marvel statue, and she gets
shattered to gravel for sure, ending this match.
Well, I mean, you're right about the lightning
bolt incinerating the shield cover, but not right
about Hercules catching it because as it was
traveling back toward him, he saw Medusa's visage
in the shield. So he turned to stone first, after
which the shield just shattered him to gravel as it
collided with him. And Mary Marvel knew this was
going to happen, because you know, she recognized
the shield cover due to her wisdom of Minerva. How
would she recognize the shield cover? Just
because the shield exists in Greek mythology
doesn't mean it's going to be like the same looking
shield with the same looking cover. Of course it
does, bro. Of course it does. And even if it wasn't
the same, Minerva would recognize it. Well, you
better recognize that's dumb. But let's find out
which of these scenarios happens. Either the
shield of Perseus turns Mary Marvel into stone and
then he kicks her to pieces, or the shield of
Perseus turns Hercules into stone as it's
traveling toward him and then crashes into him,
shattering him to pieces. Let's go ahead and find
out which of these scenarios happens by inputting
the character stats, running their simulations,
and coming back with a winner. AJ9K hit it.
Inputting data, running calculations,
processing results, simulations complete.
Okay, so this was a pretty decent matchup way
better than I thought it was going to be initially
because I figured Mary Marvel has all of the
powers, but it turned out they were pretty
comparable to Hercules. Yeah, I guess the main
difference was that Mary Marvel had the lightning
and the power of flight, but Hercules had a few
weapons that gave them the edge in a few
categories. Right off the bat, we said that Mary
Marvel was faster than Hercules. There's just no
denying that. But since we accounted for the
weapons that Hercules had in the speculation, in
these stats, we said that Hercules had a slight
edge in evasiveness because he had his shield. For
the purposes of the stats we gave him his shield,
his mace, and his sword. Yeah, Hercules also got
the edge when it came to fighting since he's an
expert in wrestling and range, surprisingly,
because Mary Marvel doesn't wield her lightning
in the same way that Billy does, especially now in
the comics. Yeah, whereas Hercules can throw all
of his weapons with great strength and accuracy.
We did give Mary Marvel the edge when it came to
perception thanks to her wisdom of Minerva,
allows her to see things that normal people
wouldn't be able to see. But for the rest of the
stats, from durability, strength, damage, and
versatility, they were even. So, Joseph, with all
of the stats and consideration, who do you think
came out on top? I'm going to give it to my boy,
Hercules. I've got to give it to him. I think what he
lacks in lightning power, he makes up for in being a
badass with his mace and a few of the other weapons
from Ares' armory. And Instagram agrees with me
because 65% of the poll takers sided with
Hercules, believing that he'll win. Which
baffles me because... Why? It's freaking Mary
Marvel. She essentially has the powers of Shazam,
this insanely powerful Superman-level
character. Yeah, but Hercules is like a
well-established Greek mythological figure,
whereas Mary Marvel's just this side character in
the Shazam comic book mythos. Hercules is a Disney
cartoon, bro. You're thinking of the wrong
Hercules that people are familiar with. Let's
find out if you and our Instagram poll takers have
any clue what they're talking about. AJ9K, the
results, please. Here you are, sir. The winner of
the matchup between Mary Marvel and Hercules
is... Fucking Hercules. Hercules, Hercules,
Hercules. He won by 577 of the 1000 matches or
57.7%. Mary Marvel won 423 of those 1000 matches.
To me, this makes sense. You know, there's some
people out there that may balk at me giving
Hercules the mace and the sword and the shield, but
a lot of current depictions have him wielding both
the sword and the mace. And even if he just had the
mace, you know, he could use that defensively in
the same way that Thor uses Mjolnir. The only thing
that just the mace would do for him statistically
is that it would lower his versatility because he
wouldn't be able to turn Mary Marvel into stone
with the shield of Perseus. So take that away, and
this is still a coin toss. So either way, you can't
discount Hercules beating Mary Marvel. I hate
that Hercules won. Like, Mary Marvel is just too
near and dear to DC fans' hearts. Hercules is just a
jerk. He's Jerkely's. Jerkely's. Now, he's a
pretty endearing character, too. He has a good
heart in the comic books. I can't wait to see him in
live action. Hopefully, you know, they do
something with the character besides just that
end credit stinger that we saw in Thor 11 Thunder.
But that does it for this duel, guys. HN9K, help
close us out. MaxDistruction, Senjo World, and
Console Combat. As I mentioned earlier, our next
episode is going to be another team duel this time,
repeating DC's Infinity Inc. against Marvel's
new warriors. Yeah, I don't know much about
Infinity Inc. I guess they're kind of a legacy team
for the Justice Society. Right. So they're like a
younger group, but sort of the new warriors, which
consists of characters like Nova, Speedball,
Night Thrasher, people like that. We'll break
down the rosters and the team's histories in our
next episode. But that does it for this episode. We
want to give a big thanks to our executive
producers, John Starosky, Zachary Hepburn,
Dustin Belcom, Mickey Muthinkean, Brandon
Essigard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yatn, Austin
Wazalowski, AJ Dunkerly, Nick Obanto, Scott
Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Spees, Dean Molesky,
Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, Josh Leiner, Mike
Williams, Oscar Galvez, and Paul Graves for
helping make this podcast possible. We'll talk to
you guys next week. Up, up, and away, true
believers. Do you, do you, do you, do you, do you, do
you, do you? Now do you think you love me, Mary
Marvel?