This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi and welcome
to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters and stat based battle
simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe and I'm his twin
brother Johnny DC. And in this episode
Abomination is going to beat the Everleaven shit
out of Bizarro and I'm going to laugh about it. It's
going to be funny to me. I'm going to listen back to
this episode and have a swell ass time. Dude, you
are never going to learn your lesson, are you? DC's
just better. Learn. I'm putting positive energy
out there from the get go for Marvel, okay? Because
you feel you need it? No, because it's just good to
have positive energy for Marvel. It goes out into
the universe and then it's going to come back to me
when we reveal the results after running the
simulations on these characters. Well, I guess
we'll see. I'm manifesting it in my brain, in your
butthole. That too. Join us later on this episode
as we input the character stats and find out who
would actually win in a fight between these two
characters. Before that matchup, we're going to
break down the latest comic book movie news to come
out this past week of which we have two news items
and that was that the Penguin won nine Emmy Awards
and actually on the comic book news side, we're
going to discuss the Deadpool Batman crossover
issue. We're not going to give spoilers away.
We're just going to talk about what was inside of it
and what we thought of it. Yeah, looking forward to
that. We've never talked about comics, but we
figured this is a special occasion. But as always,
we list our segment times in our episode
description. So feel free to check out the show
notes if you want to skip ahead to a particular
topic. Our artificially intelligent dual
simulator, AJ9K has a quick message for our
listeners. So listen up. Why hello there. Do you
want even more from this podcast? Then become a
part of the dynamic dual community on Patreon
where you can choose from three tiers. The dynamic
2.0 tier gives you access to our discord chat
server. The fantastic 4.0 tier gives you two bonus
episodes each month and the X-Force tier makes you
an executive producer of this show. Lastly, the
Dynamite podcast network tier lets you create
your own podcast using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and
consultation, and get you simulation results.
Pitch the twins your ideas via email at
dynamicdualpodcastatgmail.com. Check it out at
patreon.com slash dynamicdual. Pip pip cheerio.
Thanks, AJ9K. And thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast. Be sure to tune into the other shows in
the Dynamite podcast network this week,
including the console Combat Podcast, where
hosts John and Dean simulate battles between
popular video game characters. In yesterday's
episode, they reviewed season two of Twisted
Metal. Over on the Max Destruction podcast, hosts
Scotty and Gilly pit your favorite action heroes
from film and television against each other. On
Wednesday, they're going to find out who would win
between Michael Jordan of Space Jam and LeBron
James of Space Jam and New Legacy. And on the
Syndrome World podcast, host Zachary Hepburn
speculates on fights between fan favorite anime
and manga characters. In his next episode, Zach is
revealing who would win between Whitebeard and
Kampachi, both from One Piece. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our show
notes to listen to all the shows in the Dynamite
podcast network. But with that out of the way,
quick to the no prize. A no prize is an award that
Marvel used to give out to fans. Our version, the
Dynamic Dual No Prize, is a digital award we post on
Instagram for the person that we feel gave the best
answer to our question of the week. And just a heads
up, I am way behind on posting these no prizes to
Instagram. I've been busy with work, but slowly
trying to catch up. At this point, you're going to
spend the rest of your life catching up. Maybe.
Yeah. I suck. I know. All right. Last week we asked
you guys, besides Marvel and DC, what is your
favorite film franchise of all time and why? And
that's coming off of the variety report on current
film franchises that we discussed last week. We
got five answers. So let's run down our honorable
mentions as well as the no prize winner. Our first
honorable mention goes to Alex Albro, who said,
Hey guys, my favorite franchise of all time is Star
Wars, probably more so than Marvel and DC, to be
honest. Caviar, though, it's pre Disney. There's
been a few things that Disney's put out that are
okay, but I really prefer the George Lucas stuff so
much so I can quote the movies to you pretty much
without watching them. I've read a lot of the lore
and legends books as they're called now. Even in
fifth grade for a writing assignment, I wrote
about a 20-ish page script for episode seven
because it had yet to come out. So just based on head
knowledge and canon. So yeah, I feel like I used to
be a fan of Star Wars until Disney ruined it. Like
they ruin everything they touch. I thought your
favorite Star Wars movie was Rogue One, which was
produced after the Disney acquisition. Is that
true? Shit. Yes. Mandalorian's great. Rogue One
was great. I will put out a controversial takeout
there. I actually liked The Last Jedi. Brother,
ew! Why brother? Ew. I really like the end of that
movie when Luke Skywalker went all badass on Kylo
Ren, you know? He like force projected himself
over the galaxy. I thought that was a really cool
moment. It was everything I wanted to see in a
badass Luke Skywalker Jedi moment. I know that,
you know, that story didn't even come close to
touching what was in the novels though. Oh yeah,
with like Mara Jade and their sign and stuff like
that? Yeah. They should have just went with that.
They should have just went with that. Did not like
Force Awakens and thought Rise of Skywalker was
pretty meh. I feel like everybody has an opinion on
Star Wars though. So like basically nobody is
going to agree with my three takes right there. Oh
yeah, I've gotten flack for saying that Rogue One
is the best Star Wars movie, even though I'm right.
Great answer, Alex. Our next honorable mention
goes to Kylo, who said. Hi guys. My favorite film
franchise has to be The Hunger Games because they
have really good characters and I love the world
that the author Susan Collins built. And the
movies are really, like really good. So I cannot
recommend them enough if you haven't seen them.
But yeah, that's my answer. Thank you. Yeah, my
daughter is a huge fan of The Hunger Game
franchise. She's read all of the books. I've seen
the movies multiple times because she has. I
didn't love the first one when I sat in the theaters
because I thought it was kind of anti climactic and
Katniss was kind of passive when it comes to
heroism. But the later films I thought were
actually really good. I'm a huge fan of the
director Francis Lawrence, who also directed
Constantine. I've only seen the first Hunger
Games movie, which I thought was decent enough.
And I just went on living my life and not seeing the
other ones. Is that a mistake? Um, yeah, you should
watch them. They're not bad. I'm just going to
continue living all my life, I think. OK, great
answer, Kylo. Our final honorable mention goes to
Lorenzo Valdez, who said. Besides DC and Marvel,
my all time favorite film franchise is The
Wizarding World. I love coming of age stories and
much like with DC and Marvel, it was a huge part of my
childhood. Clona Forever and always. Bye bye. OK,
so my wife is a huge fan of the Harry Potter series.
She grew up with the books and the movies. And
before I met her, I had only seen the first Harry
Potter and I thought it sucked. And it still does
suck to this date is my least favorite Harry Potter
film. And then I went and watched the rest of those
films and they got progressively darker and
progressively more mature. And I really got into
them by the last few films. So yeah, I'm a big fan,
too. So I've only seen like the first two movies. I
watched them and then I kind of just went on living
my life. Yeah, I'm a stay. Yeah, I would say that's a
mistake because the latter stories get really
like thematic and existential and dark, like dark
as hell, like depressingly dark. Even I was
surprised just to how like depressed these kids
get. And I'll probably just end up living my life.
I'll watch Hunger Games if you finish watching the
Harry Potter movies and we'll come to a consensus
on which franchise is better. How is that even
fair? There's way more Harry Potter movies. Ain't
nobody got time for that. There's only like six of
them. Yeah, including the Fantastic Beasts
movies. Oh, yeah, the first Fantastic Beasts
movie was OK. I didn't like the latter two, though.
But yeah, you got to watch those two. Great answer,
Lorenzo. But the winner of this week's no prize is
actually split between two people who gave the
same answer and that would be CJ Kraft and Brandon
Estregard, who said, hey, guys, CJ Kraft here and
my favorite film franchise of all time. Without
question is the Evil Dead because it's Groovy
Duck. And Ash has actually been in the Marvel
comics and Marvel zombies, where he was eaten by my
favorite Marvel character. How are the duck only
for the real Ash to come in and kill that? How are the
duck? If that's not awesome enough to want to be in
the best, I don't know what it is. Hey, guys,
besides DC or Marvel, I'm a huge horror movie fan.
And my favorite horror movie franchise is the Evil
Dead series. They do start off pretty campy with
the first ones, the Sam Raimi ones. And then the
intensity just dials up to a fucking 11 with Fadea
Alvarez's and then to a 20 with Lee Cronin's. So
yeah, favorite franchise of all time. Yeah, I've
seen about half of the Evil Dead movies, and I'll
agree that they are damn solid. The Sam Raimi films
are campy. I haven't seen Army of Darkness because
I heard that it wasn't that scary, but I'll
definitely have to check it out at some point. And I
haven't seen the latest one, Evil Dead Rises yet,
because I don't know, it looked really scary. And
so I'm kind of just like waiting for a time when I'm
ready to be that scared, probably around this
Halloween. The only Evil Dead movie I've seen is
the original Sam Raimi one. I haven't seen the
sequels to that, like Army of Darkness or anything
like that. Although I've heard they're pretty
good. Pretty much classics. I basically refused
to see the new ones after seeing the red band
trailer for the Fadea Alvarez directed one. F
that. Yeah, they're pretty gruesome for sure. But
I'm glad you guys like them. So congrats on the win,
both CJ and Brandon. If you, the listener, want a
shot at winning Girono Prize, stay tuned to later
on this episode when we'll be asking another
question of the week. And now that that's done, on
to the news. OK, last week, actress Kristen
Miliotti, who played Sophia Felcone in the
Penguin television series for HBO Max, won the
Emmy for Outstanding Gleed Actress in a Limited or
Anthology Series or Movie, which is awesome. Of
course, the Emmys, if you're not familiar with
them, are essentially like the Oscars for
television. It is the most prestigious award that
television creators can receive. And the Penguin
won nine of them. Nine. How many Emmys did Marvel
win this past year? Zero. They won zero to nine.
Feel bad, Marvel fans. Feel real bad. Of the nine
Emmys, the Penguin also won for costumes, for hair
styling, for makeup, for prosthetic makeup, for
music composition, for sound editing, sound
mixing and Outstanding Special Visual Effects,
which again, suck it, Marvel, with your Agatha All
Alongs and your Echoes and X-Men 97s. I'm sorry.
Were you saying something? I was really paying
attention. Yeah, you wouldn't be, because you
know it's a boring story, man. OK, this is a boring
story. You talking about the Emmys or something?
Yeah. Yeah, I guess those are cool. I am a little bit
bummed that X-Men 97 did not win Outstanding
Animated Program and that Agatha All Along didn't
win any awards either. I thought those were two
really solid shows. But yeah, I mean, if you like
Emmys, whatever. Oh, hell, yeah, bro, the Penguin
loves its Emmys. Ew, it was a fantastic show. We
gave it five stars when we reviewed it on this
podcast. Yeah, it's pretty good if you like that
kind of thing. There were originally no plans to do
a season two, and it has been stated that Sophie
Falcone will not appear in the Batman sequel. But I
would love to see more from Christian Miliotti's
character. So fingers crossed for the Penguin
season two. Apparently, the Penguin is an HBO's 10
highest rated TV shows of all time, and it deserves
to be because it's awesome. Oh my god, let's move on
to the real news here. OK, in actual news this past
week, the Deadpool Batman comic book hit stores,
and it is the first Marvel DC crossover to happen in
probably about two decades. I think I can't
remember the exact year that JLA Adventures came
out, but it was definitely the mid 2000s. And that
was a solid, solid run. And of course, it was
preceded by the Marvel versus DC crossover that
happened in the mid 90s. Both of those comic book
arcs were like multi issue stories. The Deadpool
Batman crossover comic that came out this past
week is actually more of a series of one shots
between Marvel and DC characters. The first
story, of course, is Deadpool and Batman. And I
fucking loved that story. It was basically
everything you would ever want in a Deadpool
Batman crossover. Deadpool was hilarious.
Batman was badass. It was just perfection the way
they pulled that story together. But to my
surprise, there were six other short stories
within that issue. It was a pretty big issue. But
following Deadpool Batman, you got a Captain
America Wonder Woman crossover, which was pretty
good. It kind of treated the Marvel and DC
universes as if they were one single universe and
explored the relationship between Steve Rogers
and Diana Prince. Then there was Jeff, the Land
Shark and Crypto crossover, where the two play
catch. There was Daredevil and Green Arrow, which
was written by Kevin Smith, the acclaimed film
director, who also wrote runs for Green Arrow and
Daredevil. There was an arc with Rocket Raccoon
and Green Lantern, where Rocket Raccoon gets the
Green Lantern ring and Green Lantern gets the
Infinity Gauntlet and kind of explores what would
happen there. There was an old man Logan and
Batman, the Dark Knight Returns version
crossover that was written by Frank Miller. And
goddamn, that was awful. Frank Miller is just
getting so bad at drawing and writing. It's just it
was really disappointing, that particular short
story. It was only like two pages, two. Yeah, it's
sad to see he probably should have quit while he was
on top. Yeah. The final crossover episode kind of
revisits the amalgam universe from the 90s
crossover event where Marvel and DC characters
fused into single beings. Like you had characters
like Dark Claw, who was a merger of Batman and
Wolverine. This particular short story focuses
on Logo, who is a crossover between Wolverine and
Lobo, the bounty hunter. And that is fantastic
because he has those chain hook things coming out
of his hands and he could shoot them out to capture
bad guys. It's really badass. Yeah, I got to love
those amalgam characters. All in all, while I have
been dying for another full on crossover event
between Marvel and DC, these one off shorts did
satiate my appetite for having the two universes
go head to head. And they're not done because the
second part of the Batman and Deadpool story will
be released in mid November. Yeah, I'm really
looking forward to that one. If you guys haven't
picked up the issue yet from your local comic book
store, be sure to do that or read it online. If you
can, if you're a fan of Deadpool or you're a fan of
Batman, it's absolutely worth your time,
especially since the comic book ties into our
question of the week. What was your favorite story
within the Deadpool Batman crossover comic? And
why? Record your answer at dynamic duel.com by
clicking on the red microphone button in the
bottom right hand corner of the screen, which will
prompt you to leave us a voicemail. Your message
can be up to 30 seconds long and don't forget to
leave your name in case we include you on the
podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer and award
that person a dynamic duel, no prize that will post
to Instagram. Be sure to answer before September
27th. But that does it for all the news for this
episode. So let's go ahead and get into the main
event where we find out who would win in a fight
between the Superman villain of Bizarro and the
Hulk villain Abomination. All right, Bizarro
versus Abomination. This is in effect a Superman
versus Hulk matchup, which we have not gotten to
yet, but was featured in the 90s crossover event
between Marvel and DC. Superman and Hulk fought
each other. We're going to riff on that a little bit
and go with the villains. And I think this will be a
little bit more even, largely because
Abomination is stronger than the Hulk and smarter
than Savage Hulk, at least. And Bizarro is not as
powerful as a regular Superman. So I think
everything's going to kind of balance out in the
stats. I don't know if that's fair to say. I would
say he's as powerful as Superman, just not as
intelligent, unfortunately, in some
iterations. But yeah, these are essentially the
dark mirror counterparts of the heroes that they
battle against. They're both insanely strong and
I'm excited to see who's going to win this.
Abomination, of course, was the main antagonist
of the incredible Hulk film starring Edward
Norton and Emil Blonsky. The Abomination was
played by Tim Roth in that film. We've seen him
subsequently in some other projects like
Shang-Chi and The Legend of the Ten Rings and the
She-Hulk television series. And the jury is still
out as to whether or not the clone in the Superman
movie could be considered Bizarro. But the
character has been in live action shows like
Superman and Lois and Smallville, at least. So
we're going to find out who's going to win between
the two characters to explain the methodology
behind our duels. Let's go to our sentient dual
simulator, Alfred Jarvis 9000. AJ and NK, tell our
listeners how you go about determining a winner in
our dual matchups. Yes, of course, sir. The way I
determine a winner between the contestants is by
running 1000 Monte Carlo simulations using the
characters statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation
is a probabilistic model used to determine
outcomes through random sampling. In this case, I
randomize the statistics along a normal
distribution as a way to simulate the many
variables that can occur during battle. The stat
parameters are based on the official Marvel power
grid from which the DC characters statistics are
extrapolated. Additional stat categories are
included such as range, damage potential,
versatility and perception in order to create a
more detailed and accurate simulation. The
results of the 1000 simulations provide a
percentage of wins for each character. The
contestant with the higher percentage is
declared the victor as they have a higher
probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither character should win
100% of the matches. The comic book stories have
shown that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman. So the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor a fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks, AJ9K.
Before we run the simulations, though, we'd like
to break down each character's histories and
abilities before improvising a scenario on how we
imagine one of the 1000 simulations would play out
beat for beat. And I believe it's my turn to start
off with the DC character. So let me tell you all
about Bizarro. The original Bizarro was created
during an experiment by Professor Dalton, a
visiting scientist at Smallville High School who
was demonstrating a duplication rate that he
invented. When the ray was accidentally fired at
Superboy, it produced a flawed, imperfect
duplicate. The duplicate had chalk white skin,
exaggerated features and distorted logic,
interpreting speech and morality in opposites.
Confused and unintentionally dangerous, this
Bizarro roamed Smallville, causing destruction
despite believing he was doing good. Ultimately,
he sacrificed himself to save a blind girl named
Melissa, whose sight was restored moments before
his death. Years later, a new Bizarro emerged when
Lex Luthor recreated the duplicator ray and used
it on Superman. This new Bizarro, possessing all
of Superman's powers, but twisted in mind and
morality, became obsessed with being Superman's
equal. Speaking in opposites and seeing heroism
through a backward lens, Bizarro caused chaos and
metropolis in his attempts to help. He eventually
created a Bizarro duplicate of Lois Lane and
traveled to a cube shaped Bizarro world that he
made known as Hitre, or Earth spelled backwards,
where everything operated under reversed logic.
He founded the Bizarro Justice League and ruled
Hitre with Bizarro Lois, enforcing nonsensical
laws and making everything imperfect or ugly.
Bizarro World would later be destroyed, however,
by an entity from the Phantom Zone named Aether.
Just before their world exploded, Bizarro and
Bizarro Lois placed their infant son into a rocket
ship that they blasted into the core of the planet,
ensuring he'd die first, before they and all the
other Bizarros were blown apart along with their
world. Following the crisis on Infinite Earth,
Bizarro's history was reimagined. In this
continuity, Lex Luthor again created Bizarro as a
clone of Superman using synthetic protoplasm and
Kryptonian DNA. The experiment was conducted in
secrecy and intended to produce a controllable
Superman duplicate. However, the cloning
process proved unstable. The resulting being was
malformed and mentally stunted with decaying
flesh and fragmented cognition. Luthor
dismissed the creature as a failure, but Bizarro
escaped containment and sought to fulfill what he
believed was his purpose, to become Superman.
This version of Bizarro tried to take over Clark
Kent's life, kidnapping Lois Lane and attempting
to win her affection. His warped sense of identity
and understanding of love put him at odds with the
real Superman, who tried to help him without
killing the misguided clone. Their battles
caused widespread destruction, but Bizarro
ultimately died protecting Lois from a
collapsing building, sacrificing himself in a
final moment of clarity. Later, Bizarro was
resurrected by Cadmus as part of a secret
government initiative to create a controllable
Superman. He returned as a more monstrous and
erratic figure with fluctuating levels of power
and cognitive deterioration. His presence
triggered multiple confrontations with
Superman and other heroes, including Superboy,
who saw Bizarro as a disturbing reflection of his
own cloned origin. Bizarro eventually joined the
Superman revenge squad alongside Mongol, Cyborg
Superman, Eradicator, and others. They launched
a coordinated assault on Superman with Bizarro
tasked with distracting or neutralizing him,
through brute force. During one of these battles,
Bizarro formed an uneasy bond with a mentally
unstable woman named Tracer, whose inverted
logic mirrored his own. Their relationship was
tragically cut short during an encounter with the
Justice League, which led to Bizarro's
incarceration. The original pre-crisis version
of Bizarro, known as Bizarro number one, was later
summoned by Alexander Luther Jr. to fight
Superman alongside other multiversal villains.
Though initially cooperative, Bizarro's
distorted reasoning led him to attack his allies
and enemies alike, proving too unpredictable
even for those who had recruited him. At various
points, Bizarro's condition worsened and his
body began to degrade as his cloned physiology
lacked long-term stability. He was housed in star
labs for observation, but repeatedly escaped,
leading to more erratic appearances and violent
clashes with Superman. Each time, he showed
flashes of conscience and even affection,
especially toward Lois Lane, but remained a
tragic and unstable figure. Following the
Flashpoint reset of DC continuity after multiple
attempts to clone Superman failed, Lex Luthor
created the first viable clone designated
B-Zero. Grown in a laboratory and accelerated
through artificial aging, the clone rapidly
matured but deteriorated just as quickly. Within
weeks, the imperfect cloning process produced a
bizarro-like creature with chalk white skin,
limited intellect, and reversed speech
patterns. Though initially kept hidden by
Luther, the creature broke free after exhibiting
unpredictable behavior and enormous
destructive capability. He went on a rampage
across Metropolis, drawing Superman's
attention. Unlike previous versions, this
bizarro displayed animalistic rage and had
trouble distinguishing a friend from foe. During
their confrontation, Superman recognized the
creature's suffering and sought to help it, even
as Bizarro's body began to break down.
Ultimately, the clone died in Superman's arms,
its final gesture being a backwards ass drawn on
Superman's chest with its own blood. Later, Lex
Luther recreated the project, this time
incorporating kryptonite into the cloning
process in an attempt to stabilize the genetic
template. The resulting bizarro was stronger,
more durable, and capable of primitive thought.
After a brief conflict with Superman, he was
ultimately taken into custody by the Justice
League and contained in a secure facility. This
version of bizarro was freed during a raid on the
facility by Black Manta, who inducted him into the
Seeker Society of Supervillains. He fought with
the villains against the Justice League, but was
eventually subdued. Lex Luther created yet
another bizarro Superman clone in a lab with
Geneticon Industries. Slated for termination,
this bizarro was instead purchased by Black Mask,
who intended to use the brute as muscle in Gotham.
While initially obedient, Bizarro's behavior
gradually shifted after he was paired with Red
Hood and Artemis on a mission for Black Mask. The
trio ultimately rebelled, forming their own team
known as the Outlaws. And you of course can learn
more about Black Mask and Red Hood and their
respective duels against Madame Mask and the
Punisher. Though slow-witted and frequently
confused, this bizarro showed increasing
emotional depth and self-awareness as Red Hood
and Artemis treated him as an equal. Bizarro began
to see himself not as a failed clone, but as his own
person. After consuming books and classical
music and exposure to synthetic kryptonite,
Bizarro temporarily became a genius, even
constructing a floating base called the Bizarro
Sphere. His intelligence eventually began to
fade, but the friendship he formed with Jason Todd
and Artemis remained. During a mission to stop the
villains solitary, Bizarro sacrificed himself
to save his teammates, plummeting into an
alternate dimension. However, he later returned
alive, having survived through unexplained
means and rejoined the Outlaws. And that's his
history so far. Powers-wise, Bizarro possesses
many powers similar to Superman's, such as
immense strength, durability, flight, and super
speed. Though unlike Superman's heat vision,
Bizarro emits freeze vision from his eyes, and
instead of cold breath, he expels flames from his
mouth. His enhanced senses also function
somewhat unreliably. He has X-ray vision, for
example, but can only see through lead. He's weak
to blue kryptonite, but his greatest handicap is
his deteriorated mind and its interpretation of
the world around him. And that's Bizarro. Most of
the Bizarros, I would say, have more similarities
than differences, so I'm going with kind of a
generic composite Bizarro, and not any one in
particular. Not the angry one. Oh, the new 52 one?
Yeah, probably not that one. Bizarro shouldn't be
angry, in my opinion. He should just be kind of
confused and think he's always doing the right
thing when he's really not. Yeah, he would
probably object to this being a battle of villains
and see it more as him trying to stop the villain
that is Abomination. Yeah, totally. Bizarro does
not think of himself as a villain. Well, let me get
into Abomination's backstory. Emil Blonsky was
born in Zagreb, Yugoslavia, and worked as a spy and
KGB agent during the Cold War. A communist
loyalist, he was tasked with infiltrating the
United States Air Force Base in New Mexico,
commanded by General Thaddeus Thunderbolt Ross.
The base housed the research of nuclear physicist
Bruce Banner, whose experiments with gamma
radiation had already resulted in his
transformation into the Hulk, whom you can learn
more about in his duel against Doomsday. Ordered
to sabotage American military missiles, Blonsky
made several attempts but was repeatedly
thwarted, with his identity remaining unknown.
His mission escalated when he attempted to take
Ross's daughter, Betty, hostage, but he was
forced to retreat. Soon after, Banner attempted
to kill himself with a lethal gamut device, as the
Hulk was suffering under the control of the
enigmatic cosmic being known as the Stranger.
Blonsky, spying inside Banner's laboratory,
unknowingly exposed himself to the machine. The
concentrated radiation transformed him into a
monster larger and stronger than the Hulk. Betty
Ross, horrified, declared him an abomination,
the name that Blonsky embraced. Unlike Banner,
who could return to his human form, Blonsky was
permanently trapped in his mutated body.
Initially stronger than the Hulk at his baseline,
he also retained his full human intelligence.
Revealing in this power, Blonsky nearly killed
the Hulk in their first encounter and kidnapped
Betty Ross, prompting General Ross to work
alongside Banner to stop him. Banner used a gamma
weapon to weaken the abomination, though it only
halved his power before the Hulk destroyed the
device. The Stranger, impressed by the Hulk's
heroism and the abomination's strength,
transported Blonsky off-world to his laboratory
world, intending to use him as a pawn. On the
Stranger's world, the abomination remained
imprisoned until sorcerers on Earth summoned him
as a weapon against the Silver Surfer. Blonsky
rebelled, injuring his summoners, and battling
the Surfer before being returned to his cell.
Manipulating the Stranger's technology, he
transported Thor to the planet and tried to lead an
uprising among the captives, but Thor turned
against him and left him. Blonsky later escaped
the Stranger's cells and became first mate aboard
the Starship Andromeda, captained by Cybor, a
space pirate robot on the hunt for a colossal alien
monster called Kaatu on Earth. After arriving in
the planet's orbit, the starship came across
Bruce Banner. Blonsky and the Hulk fought
bitterly until their vessel clashed with Kaatu.
Both monsters plummeted back to Earth during the
battle, where Blonsky entered a coma upon impact
and remained buried for years until a missile test
revived him. Reservicing, the Abomination
allied with General Ross and clashed with the Hulk
repeatedly. He briefly teamed with another of
Hulk's foes, the Rhino, attempting to destroy
Hulk Buster Base with a gamma bomb. You can learn
more about the Rhino in his duel against Cheetah.
Their scheme was thwarted, and the Hulk forced the
villains into colliding with each other. Later,
Ross implanted what Blonsky believed was a bomb
into his skull to force him into obedience, but the
device was only a camera. The Abomination
manipulated the Hulk into helping him seize the
Kennedy Space Center, where he tried to ransom the
facility before being defeated again.
Attempting to escape in a rocket, Blonsky was
stranded in space. He was recovered by the Galaxy
Master, an immense energy being the enslaved
civilizations. Empowered with even greater
strength, the Abomination became the Galaxy
Master's enforcer, earning the name Ravager of
Worlds. When the Sagittarian Empress, Daedra,
recruited champions to stop him, they included
the Hulk, who battled Blonsky until his rage made
him stronger than the empowered Abomination. The
Galaxy Master withdrew the power it had granted
Blonsky, leaving him vulnerable to defeat. After
another stint stranded in space, Blonsky was
cryogenically contained on Earth under Ross's
orders. The villain Modak, seeking to control
Blonsky, mentally tortured and forced him into
battle against the Hulk. Despite his mental
coercion, Blonsky failed against the Hulk and
Modak disintegrated him. You can learn more about
Modak and his duel against Hector Hammond. The
villain Tyrannus, existing in a disembodied
state, merged his atoms with Blonsky's scattered
essence to restore a body. Initially, Blonsky
enjoyed a human form again while Tyrannus
controlled the Abomination's body. Eventually,
Blonsky's mind was returned to his mutated form,
though the transfer left him savage and merely
mindless. He fought Spider-Man and She-Hulk
across New York City until She-Hulk forced him to
retreat. Over time, his faculties returned and he
entered into an uneasy service with the leader,
another gamma-mutated enemy of the Hulk. During
one battle, the Hulk threw Blonsky into
irradiated waste, scarring his body
permanently. Disfigured and embittered,
Blonsky descended into the sewers of New York,
where he gathered a community of homeless
outcasts and mutants who came to view him as a
protector. Blonsky's life underground brought
him moments of purpose, but also tragedy, as
clashes with police led to the deaths of many under
his care. He encountered several heroes in this
period, including the Submariner and the mutant
Nate Gray, known as X-Man. He also crossed paths
with time travelers from a future ruled by the
Tyrant Hulk known as the Maestro, whom you can
learn more about in his duel with Kingdom Come
Superman. Though Blonsky sought solace in his
subterranean kingdom, his hatred of the Hulk
endured. That hatred reached its darkest
expression when Blonsky murdered Betty Ross,
Bruce Banner's wife. Consumed by envy of Banner's
marriage, he poisoned Betty through her dialysis
machine with his gamma-irradiated blood, making
it appear as if the Hulk was responsible. Betty's
father, General Ross, uncovered the truth, and
the abomination's crime shattered any illusions
of kinship he believed he shared with Banner. The
Hulk confronted him, but rather than killing him,
offered forgiveness. A response Blonsky could
not endure. Blonsky was eventually imprisoned,
forced to relive his lost humanity through
recordings of his past with his wife Nadia, who
believed he had died after his initial gamma
exposure. A shadow organization run by the leader
later released him, manipulating both him and
Nadia into opposing roles. She sought vengeance
for her abuse during their marriage, while
Blonsky was promised a reunion. Their
confrontation ended in another battle with the
Hulk, who had befriended Nadia and again defeated
the abomination. During the Hulk's absence from
Earth while being sent away by a hero group known as
the Illuminati, Blonsky clashed with She-Hulk
and several Avengers. He was defeated and taken
into shield custody. Blonsky escaped, but his
life came to a brutal end when he encountered the
Red Hulk in Russia. You can learn more about the Red
Hulk in his duel against the General. Unaware that
this new Hulk was actually General Ross
transformed by gamma power, Blonsky was savagely
beaten and shot dead with a gamma powered gun. His
body did not rest, as he was resurrected by the
Shinto God of Evil known as the Chaos King during a
war among deities. The Chaos King empowered
Blonsky with new abilities to confront the Hulk
and his allies, and though he fought fiercely, he
was destroyed once again when the embodiment of
death itself annihilated him. However, even this
was not his final chapter. An ancient secret
society recovered his remains, fusing them with
gamma tissue from the Hulk to create a mindless
abomination husk that they used as a weapon. This
creature was eventually launched into space by
the Avengers. Later, the covert program Shadow
Base retrieved and experimented with his corpse.
When its leader, General 14, merged with
abomination tissue, Blonsky was resurrected
with in 14's altered body. Now able to shift
between his traditional form and a new,
Lovecraftian form, he established Project
Greenspring, distributing gamma graphs through
a supplement called Fortify. His operation drew
the attention of Gamma Flight, a Hulk task force
who opposed Blonsky's efforts. More recently,
Blonsky was reverted to a standard form and joined
Mayor Kingpin's government-sponsored
Thunderbolts during Fisk's crackdown on
superheroes in New York. Alongside other
villains, he participated in missions such as
capturing the Purple Man's children. And that is
the abomination's backstory. Powers-wise,
Abomination has immensely enhanced physicality
derived from his gamma-irradiated physiology.
He's super strong, able to lift an excess of 100
tons, and is highly durable to the point of
invulnerability. Should he be injured, he has a
regenerative healing factor. He can run at
superhuman speeds and leap many miles in a single
bound. As a former spy for the Soviet Union, he is
skilled at espionage and his training enhanced to
hand combat. He's had quite the history. What does
his Lovecraftian version look like? Oh, that was
crazy. So it was like, you remember the Demigorgan
from Stranger Things Season 1? Yeah. It was like
that, but big and green. And Emile's face and
General Fourteen's face were like in the center of
that weird mouth face thing. Interesting. Yeah,
it was during the immortal Hulk run. That turned
into quite the Lovecraftian story in itself. That
sounds like an abomination, very fitting for his
name. Yeah, yeah. But that's not the version
you're going with. Correct. All right then, well
now that we've got their histories and abilities
out of the way, let's speculate on how one of the
1000 simulated matches will go. The winner is
determined by simulations, not the speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how this fight could play
out. AJ9K, what are the rules over speculation?
Well I should say there are no rules other than the
characters have no prior knowledge of the other
going into the fight. All they are aware of
starting out is that the other character is a
threat that needs to be eliminated. For the
speculation, the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the match
itself, as no environmental statistics are
considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. All right
then, let's get into it. Bizarro and the
abomination meet on the battlefield. Who goes
first? Okay I'm gonna say Bizarro starts off just
by looking at abomination and right away he's
gonna be like, you am very handsome. We be bad
enemies, no? This bad enemies mean best friends?
Yeah, good friends. Okay, okay. All right so
Bizarro's gonna fly over to shake abomination's
hand then and abomination's gonna grab and crush
his hand in his grasp and then just ragged all
slammer Bizarro into the ground repeatedly and
it's just gonna like smash up the ground all around
him, turning everything around him into like
gravel by like the size of boulders. Okay, Bizarro
gets ragdolled. That's not gonna hurt him too
much. He's probably actually just overjoyed
thinking that abomination wants to play with him
or something like that. He's like, oh me found bad
enemy. So Bizarro, he's gonna return the favor by
grabbing one of abomination's ankles with his
other hand as he's being slammed downward and he's
gonna fly abomination straight up into the air
before spinning really fast like a top and just
hurling abomination straight downward like a
comet right into the ground causing this massive
crater. Okay, if he throws him into the ground, the
impact is gonna launch all those broken boulder
pieces like up into the air and they're gonna fly up
and a few of them are gonna hit Bizarro on their way
up and as they fall back down, you know, it's
raining boulders all over the battlefield.
Bizarro is dodging them in the air and he's
wondering where his friend went and then all of a
sudden, abomination leaps up and puts Bizarro
into a headlock from behind and then just like pile
drives him back down into the ground creating, you
know, this even larger crater and resulting in
this just massive hail storm of boulders falling
from the sky again. Okay, by this point, Bizarro
assumes that the object of the game they're
playing is just to cause the other as much pain as
possible. So Bizarro, when he lifts his head out of
the ground, he's going to instantly blast
abomination with his flame breath just melting
his skin. Flame? Okay, I don't know how hot this
flame breath is. I guess it's as hot as heat vision,
right? Right. So that would hurt abomination for
sure. Maybe it might melt him a little bit, but he's
scaly, you know, he's somewhat armored, he's
durable. So the melting is going to be minor,
especially because abominations immediately
going to jam his fist down Bizarro's mouth, just
knocking out all his teeth and like his fist is
going to cork the flames. All right, well,
Bizarro, he's probably going to think that
abomination just wants his teeth or something
like that. So after using his super breath to spit
out abominations fist really fast from his mouth,
causing abomination to punch himself in the face,
Bizarro is going to follow up by spitting his teeth
out abomination like they were watermelon seeds,
but as fast as bullets. Bullets don't really hurt
abomination. These teeth are not going to hurt him
either. And abominations actually going to
thunderclap his hands together, which is going to
create this concussive shockwave, like a blast of
dynamite that's going to just rattle his already
rattled brain inside his skull. I mean, this
shockwave that he generates, that's just going to
make Bizarro happy. He's like enemy and clapping
for Bizarro. But then he's going to get sad right
away because he has no more teeth to give him. And so
he's going to start crying like really hard. And
that's going to trigger his freeze vision aimed
right at abomination. And that's going to freeze
him in place. And when Bizarro goes up to
abomination to give his friend a comforting hug,
he's going to squeeze him too tight. And that's
going to shatter abomination into little bits. So
match over. So he's going to squeeze his friend too
tight, shattering him to bits. I've seen
abomination get frozen once before, I think, by
like Iceman. But he like broke out of it
immediately because he's like so strong. And I
think because his body emits too much camera
radiation to even stay cool in ice. So as Bizarro
tries to bear hug abomination, abomination
breaks out of the ice, grabs Bizarro's head and
just turns it all the way around like Superman and
Man of Steel. That's odd. Well, I'm going to say,
even if the ice does a whole abomination, it holds
him long enough for Bizarro to use his super speed
to hug him. So Bizarro still wins. Well, let's
leave the match there and put in the stats. Either
Bizarro thinks abomination is his friend and bear
hugs him and shatters him while frozen or
abomination escapes the ice and pulls a man of
steel on the guy. We'll run the simulations and
find out who's going to come out as the winner. AJ9K
hit it. Inputting data, running calculations,
processing results, simulations complete. All
right, as I said before, when I was speculating on
who would win this fight, abomination definitely
came out ahead of Bizarro in terms of intelligence
and fighting skill, considering that Emil
Blonsky was trained as a KGB spy. That also said,
abomination didn't have a whole lot more going for
him compared to Bizarro. Yeah, Bizarro, we said,
is faster, has a greater range, has a higher
perception and higher versatility. Abomination
is essentially a one trick pony. He punches
things. Yeah, which makes him not that impressive
statistically. They need to give him something
like glowing radiation fists or something like
that, where he could shoot out gamma energy or
something. Yeah, that was an ability that Rick
Jones had. But yeah, they should give that to
abomination. Yeah, otherwise, abomination is
just like a not as good version of the Hulk, which I
guess you can make the same argument for Bizarro.
Well, I mean, abomination is stronger than the
Hulk, you know, base level Hulk. That's true.
Well, taking all of these stats into
consideration, Joseph, who do you think came out
on top? Wouldn't you like to know? That's why I'm
asking. It could be abomination, could not be.
Maybe just mind your business. And stop asking me
questions. We did ask our Instagram followers the
same question, and 72 percent of them think that
Bizarro is going to win. That is a lot. It's too
much, I think. How do you feel about that? I said,
stop asking me questions, didn't I? All right,
well, let's find out who won. AJ9K, the results,
please. Hey, you are, sir. The winner of the
matchup between Bizarro and Abomination is
Bizarro by a figure that's not too far off from our
Instagram poll. Out of 1000 simulated matches,
Bizarro won 717 or 71.7 percent of the time
compared to Abomination, who only won 28.3
percent of the time. Whose idea was this matchup?
Was it mine? I'm not sure, but it was a bad idea
whoever gave it. Maybe it was mine. I really
thought Abomination considering that, you know,
he's not slow and that he's super strong in a
trained KGB spy. I thought he'd have more going for
him statistically over this lame Superman clone.
But the whole Superman power set is just it's too
versatile. You know, he can do too many things.
He's too fast. He can control like fire and ice.
It's it's stupid. It's stupid. I'm going to say it
now. Superman's dumb character soar all of his
clones and all of his protgs. Just give the guy
all the powers, why don't you? It's nice to me like
someone is super jealous. I'm trying to remember
what my reaction was to the Kingdom Come Superman
versus Maestro fight, and I don't remember the
results of that specifically. But I do remember
that Superman won that one, and maybe I should have
took that as a lesson for what happens when you pit
Hulk against Superman. I mean, by this point, it
should be obvious. There's no way Hulk ever beat
Superman. Stop trying. Well, even according to
these stats, he beats him about a quarter of the
time. So you're not quite correct. That's pretty
damn correct, though. Like as far as our results
go, that's on the higher end. You're going to be on
the higher end when I swap out your brownies for
special brownies and then laugh at you as you trip
balls and freak out and get all paranoid and stuff.
I've never done that before, so I probably would
freak out. I've never done that before, so I
probably would freak out. Just wait, just wait
when you least expect it. I'm just glad I have a
recording to give to the police. That does it for
this episode, guys. Adjune and Katie help close
this out. Max destruction, Senjo world and
console combat. Our next episode is going to be
another dual episode this time between the
magical sword wielding characters of Amethyst on
DC and the Black Knight from Marvel. But that does
it for this episode. We want to give a big thanks to
our executive producers, John Sturrosky,
Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Belcom, Mickey
Mothengian, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yatyn,
Austin Wieselowski, AJ Dunkerly, Nick Ibonto,
Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Speese, Dean
Molesky, Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, Josh
Leiner, Mike Williams and Paul Graves for helping
make this podcast possible. We'll talk to you guys
next week. Up, up and away. True believers.
Jonathan never listens to my end sign offs.
Therefore, I shall take this opportunity to call
him a punk-ass bitch. I'm an AI. What is he going to
do?