This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. If you're
listening to this show, you've got a favorite
hero. Maybe it's Batman, maybe it's Spider-Man.
Either way, you deserve to wear your fandom. Head
to OldGlory.com, where you'll find thousands of
officially licensed Marvel and DC shirts,
hoodies, and gear, all high quality and ready to
ship the same day. And here's the best part. You get
15% off anything when you use the promo code Duel at
checkout. That's right, D-U-E-L. So go grab your
next superhero tee today at OldGlory.com. Show
your allegiance and save while you do it. Hi,
welcome to the DynaMic Duel Podcast, a weekly show
where we review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters and stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe and I'm his twin
brother, Johnny DC. And in this episode, we're
going to find out who would win in a fight between
the cowboy character of Jonah Hex and the zombie
cyborg character of Deathlock. Everybody knows
you put a cowboy against anyone, the cowboy's
coming out on top. Sure, except for zombie
cyborgs, obviously. Dude, zombies are like the
easiest things to kill except when they're
cyborgs. Except when the cyborg has a zombie
brain. No, he has a human brain, it's reanimated,
and he also has a computer brain to go with it.
Marvel needs to make up their mind. Is he a zombie?
Is he a cyborg? What's going on? He's a winner is
what he is. And we're going to find out later on this
episode when he beats Jonah Hex. Before we get into
that battle, we're going to break down the latest
comic book movie news to come out this past week, of
which we have a few news items, including the news
that Brainiac has been confirmed as the villain
for the Man of Tomorrow film. We got a couple
surprise crossover comic books released by
Marvel and DC, the publishing divisions. And we
also learned there is a Jimmy Olsen spin-off
television series in development. As always, we
list our segment times in the episode
description, so feel free to check out the show
notes if you want to skip ahead to a particular
topic. Our artificially intelligent dual
simulator, AJ9K, has a quick message for our
listeners. So listen up. Why hello there. Do you
want even more from this podcast? Then become a
part of the dynamic dual community on Patreon,
where you can choose from three tiers. The Dynamic
2.0 tier gives you access to our Discord chat
server. The Fantastic Four tier gives you two
bonus episodes each month, and the X-Force tier
makes you an executive producer of this show.
Lastly, the Dynamite podcast network tier lets
you create your own podcast using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and
consultation and get you simulation results.
Pitch the twins your ideas via email at
dynamicdualpodcast at gmail.com. Check it out at
patreon.com slash dynamic dual. Pip pip cheerio.
Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast. Guys, be sure to tune into the other
shows in the Dynamite podcast network this week,
including the console combat podcast, where
hosts John and Dean simulate battles between
popular video game characters. In yesterday's
episode, they found out who would win between
Tartarus from Halo and General Ramm from Gears of
War. Over on the Max Destruction podcast, hosts
Scotty and Gilly, pet your favorite action heroes
from film and television against each other. The
Macho Twins are taking a quick break, but they'll
be back in December with some Christmas season
duals. On the Central World podcast, host Zachary
Hepburn speculates on fights between fan
favorite anime and manga characters. In his next
episode, Zach is revealing who would win between
Shigeyo Kagayama, aka Mob from Mob Psycho 100 and
Tatsumaki the tornado of terror from One Punch
Man. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link
in our show notes to listen to all the shows in the
Dynamite podcast network. But with that out of the
way, quick to the No Prize. A No Prize is an award
that Marvel used to give out to fans. Our version,
the Dynamic Dual No Prize, is a digital award that
we post on Instagram for the person that we feel
gave the best answer to our question of the week.
Last week, we asked you guys, what Marvel or DC
movie or television show from 2025 has been your
favorite and why? And this is coming off of the end
of Peacemaker Season 2, which was the final show
released by Marvel or DC for this year. There's
nothing really else that they're putting out
that's new. So we wanted to get your guys'
opinions. Let's run down our honorable mentions
as well as the No Prize winner. Our first honorable
mention goes to Alex Albro, who said, Not to be a
dead horse, but it's got to be Superman. You know, I
was worried about this movie, but you could feel
the excitement in the parking lot in line for
concessions in the theater. Seeing him bleed in
the opening moments was so abnormal and crazy. To
me, you know, this was a big determining factor in
whether or not I keep up with DC. And it sold me. Made
me like a character I've historically disliked
for a long time. Plus, you know, my wife liked it a
lot too, which is great because she only goes to
these movies because I ask her to. She's not a huge
fan, but she really liked Superman. Yeah, one of
the biggest criticisms against Superman is that
he's too powerful. So for this movie to open the way
it did with him losing his first battle and we get to
see him bruised and bleeding, I'm sure it was a
shock for a lot of people who make that criticism
against the character. Yeah, I think James Gunn
knows that a vulnerable Superman is an
interesting Superman, whether that be
emotionally vulnerable or physically
vulnerable. I think that's one of the main reasons
why this particular movie resonated with fans as
much as it did this year. Great answer, Alex. Our
next honorable mention goes to Colby Hinchus, who
said, Hey, boys, Colby Hinchus, the best Marvel DC
project of 2025 was Superman. That movie had no
right being as good as it was. I've watched it
probably 20 times since it's been on Max. It's
everything I wanted DC movie to be. It's
everything the Snyderverse wasn't, which makes
it great. Yeah, James Gunn's approach to
Superman, making him more human, is pretty much
exactly the opposite of what Zack Snyder tried to
do, which was essentially to deify the character.
And whereas James Gunn's Superman was
empathetic, even going so far as to save squirrels
in Zack Snyder's universe, of course, you have pod
can't questioning whether Clark Kent should even
save a school bus full of children. They could not
be more different. And I think the success of James
Gunn's Superman goes to show how people expect the
character of Superman to be. He nailed that. Do you
think James Gunn's Superman film affects your
star rating for the Man of Steel movie? I still like
Man of Steel. I think it's an interesting
Elseworlds tale. Like a sci-fi take on Superman, I
think is really cool. But I do think that James Gunn
nailed the character of Superman that I am more
familiar with from the comics. Gotcha. I would say
James Gunn is more of a comic fan, whereas Zack
Snyder is probably more of like a philosophy and
mythology fan, I suppose. Well, great answer to
Colby. Our final honorable mention goes to by Dear
Bangora. Who said? Oh, Daniel, I think the best
show of 2020. To be the second only the second.
We'll turn again. I think the pacing are better.
The story telling was better. You can see that it
was a bit different from there. And you can also see
that the story and continues. And it seems like a
continuation of the previous Daredevil series.
So for me, it has to be the second half of Daredevil.
One again. See, I'm the opposite. I actually liked
the opening of Daredevil born again more than the
closing. Well, the first episode was fantastic,
right? Or at least the first part of the first
episode. I enjoyed the show overall, and you could
definitely listen to our review of that series
while it didn't quite hold up to the Netflix
series. I think it's still very much carried on the
torch that the Netflix series started. The show
runners didn't switch halfway through the
season. So I guess I'm a little bit confused why by
dear preferred the second half. But I will say that
the series did kind of meander a little bit in the
middle of the season and didn't quite pick back up
until we got into the Muse story arc. Great answer
by dear, but the winner of this week's No Prize is
Travis Herndon. Who said? What's up, Dany Medus?
Travis here. Shout out to Maevele Twin. So my
answer would be your friendly neighborhood,
Spider-Man. I know like since the teaser trailer
and pictures and stuff came out, everybody was
bashing on it from the art style to it being quote
unquote woke because of the great swaps and even
you guys were a little bit against it. But after it
came out, the show was really good. Love how the
origins of certain heroes and villains and
everything. And I really enjoyed the show and I
can't wait for season two. So yeah. Yeah. The
reason that Travis won this week's No Prize is
largely because one, he gave an original answer,
but also I have a lot to say about your friendly
neighborhood, Spider-Man. Now, quick
disclaimer, I haven't finished the season yet.
I've only on episode like four or five, I think. But
I can see where people would enjoy it because the
animation is fantastic. Done in the Steve Ditko
art style, the way Spider-Man moves and like
swings through the city is probably the most
dynamic and visually spectacular the character
has ever looked in animation. Obviously not more
so than the Spider-Verse films, though. I was just
about to say what? Yeah. The music is fantastic in
the show. So it looks and sounds amazing. That
being said, my gripes with the show still hold from
my criticisms of when the show was being
developed. It was initially marketed as being an
animated version of the MCU. Peter Parker giving
us a look at his early days of being Spider-Man
during his freshman year. In fact, the show was
called Spider-Man freshman year. They changed it
to your friendly neighborhood, Spider-Man, when
it was clear it was no longer going to be an MCU
Spidey, but rather a multiversal variant of
Spidey. And the story is close enough to the MCU
Spider-Man to kind of just piss you off because
they make a whole bunch of changes that I feel like
were unnecessary. Not in terms of like race
bending or anything like that, but in terms of like
having Peter go through experiences in his
freshman year that we know that MCU Peter went
through in his sophomore year, changing things
like his crush from Liz to Pearl, changing things
like his origin being magical in nature and that he
was bitten by a spider that came through a mystical
portal. As a matter of fact, Doctor Strange was
there when Peter Parker got bit in this series,
which kind of negates the whole introduction that
they had where Peter Parker was like, oh, we're
going by our made up names. So I'm Spider-Man, you
know. So there's a lot that the series takes away
from MCU Spidey. At the end of the day, I still
really wanted this to be what it was initially
marketed as, as Tom Holland's Spider-Man's
origin story. It's clever, sure, and how it
approaches its universe's characters and
origins and things like that. But I've also seen
that done really well in other animated
Spider-Man shows, like Spectacular Spider-Man
or the 90s Spider-Man. I mean, like I've said
before, when I first heard that this was a
multiverse story, I was like, yeah, I'm not going
to watch that. Is it worth watching? Do you
recommend it? I think if you're a Spider-Man fan
who isn't sick of seeing his original story
rehashed time and again, especially if you're a
fan of the early Ditko comic books and stuff like
that, I think it's worth checking out for sure. OK,
so I should not watch it. Yeah, probably not. Yes.
Well, great answer, Travis. I'm glad you like the
show. Congrats on winning this week's No Prize. If
you, the listener, want to shot at winning your own
No Prize, stay tuned to later on in this episode
when we'll be asking another question of the week.
But now that that's done, on to the news. OK, the
world's worst kept secret. It was revealed last
week by Umberto Gonzalez of The Wrap that the main
villain of the Superman sequel, Man of Tomorrow,
is Brainiac. Now, we all suspected that this was
going to be the case. James Gunn didn't
necessarily even try to hide it going so far as to
put an image of a brain on the script cover for Man of
Tomorrow. But I do got to say with this news
confirmed, I am super excited to see Brainiac in
live action. He's the number one villain I've
always wanted to see in a Superman movie. There's
been a lot of depictions of him in a lot of other
media, like the animated series, like the video
games, like Injustice, or even like the My
Adventures with Superman cartoon that came out
last year. I think with the advent of AI in real
life, this is a very timely villain. And I'm super
stoked to see him go toe to toe up against both
Superman and Lex Luthor. Oh, yeah, super timely.
Although is Brainiac AI what you consider him?
Sometimes he is. Sometimes he's more like an
alien. What's your preferred version of
Brainiac? Oh, that's a good question. I actually
do prefer it when he is an AI who maybe kind of
developed his own body. The Kaluan version is not
my favorite version, though I wouldn't hate it if
they went that direction. Brainiac, if you
remember, in our Brainiac versus Ultron match is
from the planet Colu, a alien race of super
intelligent beings. And he was like the smartest
one. I really liked the version that was in My
Adventures with Superman season two. He was
really unique in there. Of course, Brainiac has
been in a few animated movies as well, including
one from the 90s called Superman Brainiac
attacks. And then I think he was also the main
antagonist in Superman Unbound. Yes, that's
correct. And he was also in Superman Red Sun. I'm
super curious to see who they're going to cast in
the role. I'm hoping they're going to make that
announcement soon because this movie starts
filming in April, surprisingly, which is
awesome. Like remember when they used to make
superhero movies back to back? Yeah, they would
like release the movie and then the following year
they would film the sequel so that the following
year after that they would release the sequel. So
we would get the sequels a couple years apart from
each other as opposed to five, six, seven years
apart looking at you, Shang-Chi. Yeah, this is the
way to do it. Brainiac is the way to go. I am all
aboard the hype train. Just be sure to check your
expectations right out of the gate, Jonathan. You
haven't even seen the Supergirl movie yet. Oh, I
wonder if they'll have like an end credits teaser
of Brainiac. That would be dope. Sure. And other DC
Superman related news. We also learned that DC
Studios is developing a Jimmy Olsen spin off TV
series from the character that we saw in the
Superman movie. It's from the American Vandal
creators. If you're familiar with that show, it's
on Netflix. It won a Peabody and I think it was
nominated for an Emmy. It's a fantastic show. If
you haven't seen it, hilarious. And I wonder if
they're going to take the same kind of
mockumentary approach with this Jimmy Olsen spin
off show. Some people are calling it DC crime. I'm
not sure why. I don't think James Gunn knows why
either. But I'm all there for it because it looks
like a lot of the Daily Planet stars are set to
return. I mean, that's great because I would say
that the Daily Planet cast was underutilized and
largely pointless in the Superman movie, which
was surprising considering the cast that they had
for them, you know, like Beck Bennett, Wendell
Pierce, McKayla Hoover and Christopher
McDonald. They played Steve Lombard, Perry
White, Kat Grant and Ron Troupe respectively. I
also wonder if maybe David Cornswet and Rachel
Brosnahan will return to their roles also as Clark
and Lois. That would be cool. I'm not sure how
excited people are about this, but I remember when
they announced the powerless television show,
people were bitching about that for some reason,
because I found the premise quite interesting.
And then the show came out and like you liked it, you
watched it. You thought it was great, but it ended
up getting canceled early, largely due to the lack
of interest in it. I hope that doesn't happen with
this. Yes, this is a television series that no one
asked for. That doesn't mean it won't be good. I
mean, I asked for this. I love this. I think if DC
wants to get this off the ground, they should just
title this spin off series The Daily Planet. Yeah,
you got brand name recognition right there. I
would also accept the adventures of Jimmy Olsen.
No, no one's going to watch that. I would. And I hope
he would get turtle powers. Apparently the show is
going to revolve also around Gorilla Grodd,
though. Maybe it's like Jimmy Olsen tracking
Gorilla Grodd in Metropolis. And that sounds
amazing. How are you not excited about this?
Anyone who's not excited about this? Because you
should be. I mean, throwing in Gorilla Grodd does
sound a little bit ridiculous, but in the best way.
OK, in other news, in comic book news, actually, in
a follow up to the Deadpool, Batman, Marvel and DC
crossover comic event from earlier this year, the
publishers dropped two surprise web comics on DC
Universe Infinite and Marvel Unlimited, a flash
and fantastic for crossover story and a Shazam
Thor crossover story. I think largely it was a
means of promoting the other publishers' digital
subscription content, because it was the
weirdest thing. As a Marvel Unlimited
subscriber, I suddenly got an email from Marvel
with an offer to subscribe to DC Comics. It was so
fucking disturbing. It's like hell is freezing
over. Yeah. And I don't know, like, is that a good
thing? What's happening? Is the science of like a
consistent partnership and collaboration going
forward? Maybe even potentially a merger down the
line? Better not. Is all I'm saying. We got to keep
these things separate. Otherwise, I'm not going
to know who to root for. It would be like Star Wars
and Star Trek promoting each other's content.
Yeah, or like Pepsi and Coke joining forces to
release a new drink together. Ew. Pepsi Coke. That
sounds disgusting. I would spit that out. Same
here. That being said, if Marvel and DC want to
collaborate on a fighting video game, combining
the two universes, I would be all for that. That is
all I've ever wanted in life. I did read the Shazam
Thor crossover comic book. I thought it was pretty
good that you teamed up against Mr. Mind. I enjoyed
it. But this crossover event brings us to our
question of the week. Well, Marvel versus DC
crossover, have you always wanted to see in the
comics? And why? Out of all the crossovers we've
gotten from the publishers, including, you know,
the 90s DC versus Marvel crossover and even before
that, like the original Superman versus
Spider-Man and Hulk versus Batman. Later on in the
2000s, we got JLA Avengers. And then recently, of
course, the various crossover events. Besides
those, what two characters from Marvel and DC have
you always wanted to read about teaming up or going
up against each other? Record your answer at
dynamicdool.com by clicking on the red
microphone button in the bottom right hand corner
of the screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long. And don't forget to leave your name in case we
include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a dynamic
dual no prize that will post to Instagram. Be sure
to answer before November 22nd. But that doesn't
for all the news this week. So let's go ahead and
move into our main event for this episode, where we
find out who would win in a fight between the DC
character of Jonah Hex and the Marvel character of
Deathlock. All right, Jonah Hex versus
Deathlock. We've been trying to get both of these
characters in a duel for years now. And the time has
finally come. They're both semi popular, I think,
within their respective universes. Jonah Hex
even had a film adaptation and he was a prominent
character in one of the seasons of Legends of
Tomorrow. Yeah, he was also featured in an episode
of the Batman animated series and had his own DC
showcase short, which was pretty good. Yeah, I
really liked that one. Deathlock hasn't been in as
much media, I would say. There was a version of the
character that was in the agents of shield
television series, although it wasn't the
version of the character that I'll be going with,
which is the original Deathlock from the comic
books named Luther Manning. Basically, the other
versions of Deathlock would be way too damn
powerful for Jonah Hex. So we went with the
original and let's beefed up a version of
Deathlock. Yeah, basically, the reason we and the
executive producers decided to pit these two
characters against each other is because we think
they're awesome. And also because they have a lot
of similarities in terms of like half of their face
is missing and they're also really good marksmen
with their guns. That's pretty much it. Yeah,
you're right. I don't know much about Jonah Hex, so
I'm interested in learning how accurate the movie
adaptation was for the character. Well, I'm here
to set the record straight about how sucky their
interpretation of Jonah Hex was. But before that,
to explain the methodology behind our duels,
let's go to our sentient dual simulator, Alfred
Jarvis, 9000. AJ9K, tell our listeners how you go
about determining a winner in our dual matchups.
Yes, of course, sir. The way I determine a winner
between the contestants is by running 1000 Monte
Carlo simulations using the characters
statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation is a
probabilistic model used to determine outcomes
through random sampling. In this case, I
randomize the statistics along a normal
distribution as a way to simulate the many
variables that can occur during battle. The stat
parameters are based on the official Marvel power
grid from which the DC characters statistics are
extrapolated. Additional stat categories are
included such as range, damage potential,
versatility and perception in order to create a
more detailed and accurate simulation. The
results of the 1000 simulations provide a
percentage of wins for each character. The
contestant with the higher percentage is
declared the victor as they have a higher
probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither character should win
100% of the matches. The comic book stories have
shown that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman. So the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks, AJ9K.
Before we run the simulations, though, we like to
break down each character's histories and
abilities before improvising a scenario on how we
imagine one of the 1000 simulations would play out
beat for beat. And I believe it's my turn to go first
with the Marvel characters backstory. So let me
tell you all about Deathlock. Luther Manning was a
Detroit, Michigan native from an alternate
reality called Earth 7484 in the greater Marvel
multiverse. He enlisted in the US Army and rose to
the rank of Colonel before the political collapse
of his reality. In his timeline, the Age of Heroes
ended when the multinational corporation,
RocksOn, used dimensional technology to
eliminate Earth's superhumans. The aftermath
triggered widespread war and devastation across
the United States. Manning served through this
turmoil, but during a training exercise, he was
critically injured by a concussion bomb.
Declared legally dead after failing to survive
surgery, he was selected by Major Simon Riker for
Project Alphamec, a covert initiative intended
to produce cyborg soldiers. Manning's remains
were rebuilt by Simon's brother Harlan, who
transplanted Manning's brain, nervous system,
and surviving organic tissue into a cybernetic
body. After five years in stasis, Manning was
reanimated as the cyborg Deathlock, named for his
ability to be locked into a suspended death-like
state. Riker oversaw his training and
deployment, intending to use the cyborgs to seize
global power, while Harlan pursued his own vision
of replacing humanity entirely with cyborgs that
he called Homo Ascendant. As Deathlock's human
memories reemerged, he began resisting his
program's directives and ultimately broke free
of Riker's control. In discovering his new
condition, he learned that he had been declared
dead and that his wife had remarried his friend,
Mike Travers. Unable to take his own life due to
built-in fail safes, he instead dedicated
himself to undermining Riker, who at overtime
also become a cyborg through his brother Harlan's
experiments. Riker attempted to merge with New
York's Omni Computer to become the digital entity
called Savier Machine, but Deathlock forced him
out, leaving Riker mentally shattered. The CIA
attempted to restore Luther's humanity by
transferring his consciousness into a cloned
human body, but the process only recreated his
memories in the clone while leaving the cyborg
unchanged. Deathlock continued operating for
the agency, primarily targeting the threat of
Harlan Riker, now operating as the cyborg
Hellinger. During this period, Deathlock
encountered a time-traveling Spider-Man from
Earth 616, Marvel's primary timeline, as an early
sign of the temporal disruptions that would
repeatedly intersect with Luther's life.
Deathlock soon encountered Godwolf, a former
rocks-on operative turned rebel leader who
sought to save what remained of America after the
elimination of the world's superhumans plunged
into chaos. To protect him from Hellinger's
forces, Godwolf displaced Deathlock through
time to Earth 616. There, Deathlock assisted the
mystic hero Devil Slayer against a cult before an
attempt to return him home was intercepted by the
Fixer and Mintello. The villains implanted a
control device in Luther and used the cyborg in an
assassination plot against the US president, but
their plan was stopped by the Fantastic Four and
the Impossible Man. Freed from external control,
Deathlock entered a catatonic state and was taken
into shield custody. Agents of Earth 616's
rocks-on later stole Deathlock's cyborg body and
delivered it to their corporation facility,
where this timeline's version of Harlan Riker
examined it. Riker created a fully robotic
Deathlock duplicate which was subsequently
destroyed by the Thing and Quasar. Meanwhile,
Luther's true body was reprogrammed by rocks-on
for their efforts toward repeating the actions of
Earth 7484 and eliminating the world's
superhumans. In Luther's native reality,
Godwolf sent a clone of Luther back in time to
locate the original Deathlock. Luther killed the
clone during the confrontation, but the dying
duplicate's touch restored Deathlock's
suppressed memories and freed him from
rocks-on's programming. Deathlock returned to
his timeline with Captain America and Godwolf's
team called the Redeemers to stop Hellinger from
deploying an army of doomsday mechs. Though
Hellinger briefly took control of Deathlock's
systems, Luther resisted long enough to kill him.
Captain America's subsequent actions in Earth
616 prevented rocks-on from destroying his
country, causing Marvel's reality to diverge
from the timeline that produced Manning.
Deathlock remained active in Earth 7484,
assisting Godwolf against the foreign ruler
Timestream after the Redeemers were killed in an
An assault that triggered further global
destruction. Disillusioned upon learning
Godwolf had hidden crucial information from him,
Deathlok abandoned the struggle. He later fought
alongside the deviant Tantalus, though these
battles did little to alter the ongoing collapse
of his world. Upon learning that remnants of
Roxxon had resumed their efforts to eliminate
superhumans in Earth 616, Deathlok traveled back
to that reality, only to be shut down and seized by
SHIELD. Though repaired under the assumption he
could be controlled, Deathlok rebooted
autonomously, destroyed Roxxon's developing
technology, and returned to his native timeline
once again. By 2011, the computer core within
Luther's body had deteriorated, leaving him
operating in a severely degraded state and forced
to survive on his own. TimeStream reappeared and
recruited him with promises to rewrite the past so
that he would never become Deathlok. The scheme
drew the attention of the Time Variance
Authority, who sent Godwolf to stop him.
TimeStream recruited the human Luther Manning of
Earth 616, while Godwolf enlisted Earth 616's
version of Deathlok named Michael Collins.
Luther eventually discovered TimeStream's true
nature and cited with Michael Collins to end his
plans. Regarding the Earth 616 version of
Deathlok that I just mentioned, Michael Collins
was a computer programmer and neuroscientist
born in Philadelphia who earned advanced degrees
in prosthetics. A pacifist devoted to ethical
technological development, he joined CyberTech
Systems, which was a Roxxon subsidiary,
believing his work in neural prosthetics would
benefit the disabled. Unaware of his company's
secret Deathlok program, Collins only learned
the truth when he discovered his research had been
appropriated for weapons development. When he
confronted his superior, Harlan Riker, Collins
was shot with a sedative and his brain was
transplanted into CyberTech's newest Deathlok
cyborg. Upon awakening in the cyborg body,
Michael Collins initially had no control over its
actions and witnessed the machine killing
soldiers during field testing. Gradually, he
asserted his will, preventing the killing of a
child and overriding the program's lethality
protocols by imposing a strict no-killing
parameter on the system. He learned that his
original human body still existed and tracked
Harlan Riker to a weapons deal, capturing him
before turning him over to authorities.
Michael's existence as Deathlok brought him into
contact with SHIELD, the Fantastic Four, the
X-Men, Spider-Man, and other heroes. He
participated in efforts ranging from preventing
a nuclear strike on the United States to stopping
the Sinister Six and assisting in the defeat of
Carnage. During this period, he revealed his
cyborg identity to his family, his wife Tracy,
their children Nicholas and Tisha, and his
extended relatives while continuing to search
for a way to restore his original body. Michael was
later abducted to a distant world by the cosmic
scientist called The Stranger and lived there for
years with other superhumans until their
eventual escape. After the group's escape from
the alien world, Michael found that he could
revert to human form at will. However, once he
arrived back on Earth, he was unable to transform
back into Deathlok, ending his tenure as the hero.
Meanwhile, Luther Manning, the original
Deathlok, still resentful of Godwulf's
manipulations, stole a time gauntlet and
abandoned his native timeline, traveling
permanently to Earth 616. There he lived in the
sewers of Manhattan where he helped protect
innocent residents of an underground community
called the Tunnel Dwellers before departing them
to contemplate his existence. There have been
several other victims of the Deathlok program
over the years, including Harlan Riker's own
daughter, called Deathlokit. But that is the
history of the two primary Deathloks. For this
still, I'll be going with the original Luther
Manning version of the character because Michael
Collins is just way too strong and durable for it to
be a fair fight against Jonah Hex. Powers-wise,
Luther Manning's Deathlok has a reanimated body
with cyborg enhancements. This gives him
increased strength, able to lift 10 tons, and
enhanced durability. His mind reacts and
processes information at computer speeds and
allows for tracking and targeting multiple
subjects. He carries a helium neon laser pistol
and a 9 inch throwing dagger that magnetically
attaches to his calf. As a former US Army colonel,
he is a trained hand combatant, marksman, and
strategist. And that's Deathlok. I wanted to get
into the backstory of both the primary Deathlok
from Earth 74-84 and into the Earth 616 Deathlok,
which was Michael Collins. They both have very
different backstories. And actually, the
Michael Collins version of the character was
created by Dwayne McDuffie, who also created
characters like Static and Icon for Milestone
Comics. I'm legit surprised that we have not had a
Deathlok movie. I mean, just listening to that
backstory, it sounds like a 90s movie. Well, I
mean, Robocop ripped it off wholesale. Deathlok
came out in the 70s, Robocop came out in the 80s, but
it's essentially the same exact story. Deathlok
just looks a little bit more zombie cyborg.
Henceforth, I will always watch Robocop thinking
of it as a Deathlok movie in the same way that I watch
Ghost thinking of it as a Deadman movie. The 80s,
man. They were just ripping off comic book stories
all the time. Well, if Robocop is essentially
Deathlok, I do have to say that his movie is better
than the Jonah Hex movie, but the Jonah Hex comic
storyline would have made a better one. So let me
get into his backstory from the comics. Jonah Hex
was born in 1838 in Missouri to Woodson and
Virginia Hex. His childhood was defined by
Woodson's drinking and violent outbursts until
Virginia fled, leaving Jonah behind. At 13, Jonah
traveled west with Woodson during the Gold Rush.
In need of safe passage, Woodson sold Jonah to an
Apache tribe. Jonah lived as a slave until he saved
their chief from a Puma, at which point he was
adopted as a member of the tribe. He learned Apache
methods of hunting and tracking, and he formed
bonds with the chief's son, Notante, and a young
woman named White Fawn. At age 16, Jonah and
Notante undertook a rite of passage to steal Kiowa
horses. During the raid, Notante betrayed Jonah,
striking him unconscious and leaving him behind
to claim White Fawn for himself. Taken prisoner,
Jonah survived a US cavalry assault on the Kiowa,
but was shot in the stomach when he tried to stop the
soldiers from killing children. Left for dead, he
was rescued by an old trapper. When Jonah later
attempted to return to the Apache, they had
relocated, forcing him to wander the frontier
alone. As a young man, Jonah enlisted as a cavalry
scout for the US Army, then joined the Confederacy
when the Civil War began, believing he was
defending his homeland. He rose to lieutenant in
the 4th Calvary and fought alongside Jeb
Turnbull. After learning of the Emancipation
Proclamation, Jonah could no longer justify the
cause and deserted to Fort Charlotte to
surrender. He refused to reveal his unit's
position, but a Union aide identified it from the
clay on Jonah's horse's hooves. The Confederates
were captured, and the Union commander staged a
false escape tunnel so his starving men could kill
the fleeing prisoners. Most of Jonah's comrades,
including Jeb, were slaughtered. Jonah
survived, killed the commander, and escaped.
Labeled a traitor, Jonah was not allowed to return
to the Confederate lines. He returned to the
Apache instead, seeking acceptance and
discovered that Notante had married White Fawn.
Jonah accused him of betrayal, and the chief
ordered a trial by combat. Notante sabotaged
Jonah's tomahawk, and Jonah resorted to a knife,
violating tribal law. He killed Notante, and it
was branded across the right side of his face, the
mark of a demon, before being exiled. Years later,
when Jonah returned to the Apache tribe to rescue a
White captive, he was captured Jonah broke free,
killed the chief, and gunned down several
warriors before fleeing permanently. Jonah
wandered the frontier until the day he shot a man
beating his wife in the street. The man was an
outlaw named Lucas Mad Dog McGill, and the deputy
who arrived recognized the bounty on his head.
Realizing he could earn a living, killing men like
McGill, Jonah became a bounty hunter. His first
major hunt ended with rival manhunter Arby
Stoneham taking his query and guns. Years later,
after Jonah had become widely feared, he found
Stoneham crippled and chose to leave the past
behind. Jonah spent decades tracking outlaws,
foiling land schemes, clashing with corrupt
lawmen, and at times working with the US Secret
Service, including disrupting an assassination
attempt on President Grant. He tried to protect
peaceful tribes, but often arrived too late. His
survival of gunfights, while wounded,
outnumbered, or temporarily blinded, cemented
his reputation as one of the deadliest men alive.
Jonah's path occasionally crossed with larger
forces. He was abducted by the Lord of Time as one of
the five warriors from forever, and turned
against the Justice League and Justice Society
before breaking free and returning to his era. He
later rode with Western legends like Bat-Lash,
Cinnamon, and Skellpunter when the league was
thrown into the 19th century, and he fought Shadow
Demon during the crisis on Infinite Earth. Jonah
tried repeatedly to abandon violence. He married
Mei Ling, who insisted he quit bounty hunting.
After a fire destroyed their farm, Jonah secretly
resumed the work to pay debts, and Mei Ling left
him. Their son Jason later sought Jonah out as an
adult, but the two failed to reconcile. Jonah
formed an on-and-offigan partnership with
Tallulah Black, a scarred gunfighter avenging
her murdered family. He also encountered bizarre
frontier threats, including zombies raised by a
traveling surgeon, the subterranean autumn
brothers, cannibal clans, and corrupt Wild West
show promoters. In 1875, Jonah was abducted in a
flash of light by Reinhold Borstyn, and taken to a
post-apocalyptic 21st century Seattle. He
escaped Borstyn's lab, allied briefly with a Road
Reapers biker gang, donned a radiation-proof
zone suit, and fought through mutants,
mercenaries, and alien-backed warlords. He
became entangled in Sven Tara's rebellion
against the invading Exiggs. During his time in
the future, Jonah discovered his own taxidermied
corpse in a carnival exhibit, confirming his
eventual return and death in his own era. Though
the means are unknown, Jonah did return to the
past. By the early 20th century, he lived with a
woman named Talbird. In 1904, George Barrow
murdered Jonah in a saloon, with Sheriff Hank
Crawford shooting Barrow immediately. Showman
L.B. Farmham stole Jonah's body, stuffed it in
gaudy clothes, and exhibited it until Talbird
reclaimed it. When the collector later attempted
to seize the corpse, he was shot in the back by an
unseen figure, implied to be a time-traveling
Jonah himself. In post-Flashpoint continuity,
Jonah's early life remained mostly unchanged.
His Confederate service and the Fort Charlotte
massacre again left him wandering the West as a
bounty hunter with a strict moral code. In the
1880s, he traveled to Gotham at the request of Dr.
Armadeus Arkham to hunt the Gotham Butcher. Jonah
uncovered ties between the murderers and the
religion of crime, drawing him into conflict with
corrupt officials, industrialists, and secret
societies. He fought through ambushes, machine
gun traps, subterranean tunnels, and child labor
rings beneath the city. He encountered the
ancestors of the Wayne family, remnants of
ancient tribes, and early agents of the Courts of
Owls while dismantling the crime-bible network.
Jonah resumed life on the trail with Tallulah
Black until an encounter with Booster Gold
displaced him in the 21st century. Mistaking for
an unstable impersonator, he was committed to
Arkham Asylum until Dr. Jeremiah Arkham
confirmed his identity. Jonah adapted quickly,
assisting modern heroes against criminals,
monsters, and occult threats. He formed a
relationship with a woman named Gina, and after a
drunk driving accident left him comatose,
surgeons repaired his scarred face. Booster
eventually returned Jonah to the Old West, with
Gina accompanying him, though she died crossing
the desert. Jonah also learned that an imposter
with a similar scar had committed crimes using his
name. When Jonah killed him, he gave his name as
George Barrow, in effect, faking his own death.
During the rise of the Dark Multiverse, Jonah was
resurrected by a black lantern ring and fought
alongside Batman, Superman, and Wonder Woman
against the Batman who laughs. You can learn more
about in our Batman Who Laughs vs. Cosmic
Ghostwriter episode. When his undead body was
destroyed, Jonah's spirit was bound to a cursed
firearm, later inherited by his descendant,
Ginny Hex, a member of Young Justice, which you can
learn more about in our Young Justice vs. Young
Avengers team duel. The powers-wise, Jonah Hex
has no superhuman abilities, but is one of the most
lethal marksmen of any era. He is a trained Apache
warrior and hardened bounty hunter, capable of
drawing and firing with exceptional speed and
accuracy, even when injured or impaired. He is an
expert tracker, able to follow faint signs across
fast terrain, and he is a master with knives,
tomahawks, sabers, and is a brutal hand-to-hand
combatant. That's Jonah Hex. Didn't he have
mystical powers in the movie, if I remember
correctly? Yes, in the movie, he had a magic touch
that could bring people back to life until he
touched them again. That's weird. Yeah,
unnecessary, I think. The character makes for a
great Western cowboy without needing a
superpower. He's just a badass, and that's all you
need a cowboy to be. Do you think he has enough going
for him to go up against Deathlock? He's gone up
against worse, my friend. Yeah, there definitely
seemed like an era where he was taken out of the
whole Western genre and put more into like a
post-apocalyptic pulp genre. Yeah, kind of like
Deathlock. That's true. That's true. In a world
where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
Dynamite Podcast Network presents Console
Combat, where video game legends brawl every
Monday. Dynamic Duel, where comic book titans
smash every Tuesday. Max Destruction, where TV
and action heroes battle every Wednesday. And
Sendro World, where anime champions clash every
Thursday. Join us as we speculate on the matches
and armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge
victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com where we
settle the debate and settle the score. If you're
listening to this show, you've got a favorite
hero. Maybe it's Batman. Maybe it's Spider-Man.
Either way, you deserve to wear your fandom. Head
to OldGlory.com, where you'll find thousands of
officially licensed Marvel and DC shirts,
hoodies, and gear. All high quality and ready to
ship the same day. And here's the best part. You get
15% off anything when you use the promo code Duel at
checkout. That's right, D-U-E-L. So go grab your
next superhero tee today at OldGlory.com. Show
your allegiance and save while you do it. Another
we got there are histories and abilities out of the
way. Let's speculate on how one of the 1000
simulated matches will go. The winner is
determined by simulations, not the speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how the fight could play
out. AJ9K, what are the rules of our speculation?
Well, I should say there are no rules, other than
the characters have no prior knowledge of the
other going into the fight. All they are aware of
starting out is that the other character is a
threat that needs to be eliminated. For the
speculation, the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the match
itself, as no environmental statistics are
considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. All right,
then let's get into it. Jonah Hex and Deathlock
meet on the battlefield. Who goes first? Don't
answer that, actually. I already know. Jonah is
literally the fastest draw in the West. So as they
square off, staring each other down, Jonah is
going to snap his gun forward, firing a shot that
hits Deathlock, square between the eyes with his
Colt 45 revolver. Blam! Square between
Deathlock's eyes is actually flesh, because the
cyborg part of his face doesn't extend directly in
the middle, it's just on the left side of his face.
Good. But Deathlock's computer implant grants
him enhanced reaction time. So no matter how quick
of a draw Jonah Hex is, Deathlock still has time to
like somewhat at least turn his head so that the
bullet actually hits the left side of his face,
which is metal. So bullet ricochets and Deathlock
is probably knocked to the ground from the impact.
But from the ground, he's going to quickly pull out
his laser pistol and just shoot Jonah Hex through
the chest. Oh, you mean where he wears his
bandolier of ammo? I guess Deathlock's shot also
hits metal. I mean, I guess a laser pistol might
trigger a round or two to go off, but those bullets
are just going to graze Jonah's chest and he's
going to shrug it off. So while Deathlock is still
on the ground, Jonah is going to quick draw a second
revolver. And so he's dual wielding. He's going to
fire 10 rounds right into Deathlock, killing him
in seconds. No, no, no, Deathlock, he's going to
kick off the ground into a back hand spring while
his computer scanner is going to be tracking Jonah
Hex's arm position. And that's going to allow
Deathlock to dodge the bullets. And like even the
few that he wouldn't dodge, he'll just shoot out of
the air with his laser gun because he's that
accurate at targeting. And as he dodges to one side
to avoid like the last of the bullets from the
revolvers with his non shooting hand, Deathlock
grabs and flings his dagger with perfect aim right
into Jonah Hex's good eye. Good eye. I'm pretty
sure both eyes are good, but doesn't he have a
fucked up eye? Kind of. He can still shoot
perfectly with it, so it can't be that bad. It's
just his eyelid that's missing. Oh, so he can't
blink. So he has dry eye. He works with it. He works
with it somehow. I'm going to say lucky for him. By
my count, Jonah still had one round left in the
chamber, and he's also accurate enough to shoot
the dagger off course. So once he does that without
missing a beat, Jonah is going to charge at
Deathlock using speed loaders that he got from the
future to reload his revolver as he runs toward
him, flicking the cylinders into place and
cocking those hammers back. He's going to unload
on Deathlock again. Dude is a fucking one trick
pony with his pistols. OK, Deathlock, he's going
to power slide to dodge the gunfire and he
magnetically pulls his dagger back to him. And
while Deathlock is moving to dodge the gunfire,
you know, using his enhanced reaction time to help
him, maybe he gets tagged once or twice by this new
round of bullets. But that's fine because he can
tank a few rounds at least, no problem. And he's so
reflexive and agile, he can even dodge at close
range. So he closes the distance between himself
and Jonah Hex. And with his dagger, he just slices
off Jonah Hex's fingers on his right hand. Well,
OK. Well, Jonah's probably very pissed off by
that. So he will pull out a tomahawk with his left
hand and he's going to chop off Deathlock's arm
with it. Deathlock's arm is metal. The only thing
that would happen would be like the tomahawk would
just wedge into his shoulder joint. OK, so you
can't use it anymore. Gotcha. He's fine. But while
Deathlock is realizing that that's when Jonah
quickly reaches under his trench coat to grab a
sawed off twin barreled shotgun that he keeps at
the small of his back, he's going to fire it point
blank at Deathlock's face. Good luck dodging
that. Deathlock doesn't need to dodge that. He's
going to block the shot with his mechanical hand,
which covers the barrels. So the bullets ricochet
and Jonah is going to catch some of that ricochet
from his own shotgun shot. And then Deathlock
punches him hard enough to like send him flying
like 20 yards back. What? And Jonah Hex drops the
shotgun, which Deathlock crushes in his hands.
Dang it. OK. I'm going to say Jonah knows he's beat.
So he's going to raise his hands and surrender and
slowly walk toward Deathlock, admitting defeat.
But just as Jonah gets within range, he's going to
quickly scrape a match against the stubble on his
jawline and quickly light a small bundle of
dynamite he had hidden in this pocket. And he's
going to hurl that thing right at Deathlock before
just turning and running like hell, basically. So
Deathlock's going to blow up. Jonah Hex wins. And
in the aftermath, we'll say Jonah sells Deathlock
cybernetic parts for scrap metal as a bounty. No,
Jonah could try to kill Deathlock with dynamite.
But to do that, he would have to throw it with
perfect timing, right? So that it would explode
right as it lands near Deathlock. Yeah. But in
order to do that, he would have to like, you know,
hold onto the bundle for at least a second before
throwing it. Therefore, Deathlock uses his laser
pistol to shoot the dynamite while Jonah Hex is
holding onto it and it just explodes in his hands,
killing him. Yeah, it was it was a short fuse. OK,
like Jonah didn't need to hold onto it for very long
at all. But he couldn't even throw the bundle that
well, because he has buckshot in his gut from the
ricochet from before. No, no, paint does not
affect Jonah or his aim. Like he's probably had
buckshot lodged in his body parts for years. He's
like mostly made out of buckshot. He's like a
cyborg in himself, like a really shitty cyborg.
We'll go ahead and leave the match there. OK,
either Jonah Hex manages to pull off exploding
Deathlock with a bundle of dynamite or the
dynamite gets shot while Jonah Hex is holding onto
it and he blows himself up. We'll see which of those
two scenarios happens when we input the character
stats, run the thousand simulations and come back
with a winner. A.J .9K. Hit it. Inputting data,
running calculations, processing results,
simulations complete. All right, I will say that
neither of these guys are that impressive
statistically, like especially compared with
other superheroes. Yeah, both of these guys are
kind of one trick ponies as well. Yeah, I mean,
Deathlock has enhanced strength and durability,
but otherwise he just has like a little laser gun
and a knife. He should have a better arsenal and
actually the Michael Collins version of
Deathlock did. They were mostly tit for tat when it
came to the stats. We gave Jonah Hex the edge when it
came to damage level because I've seen him use
dynamite before, essentially. But Deathlock
came out ahead and a lot of the physical stats, like
you mentioned, as well as perception. Yeah, but
there are even when it came to like range and
actually fighting, which surprised me, Jonah Hex
is actually a better fighter than I guess I would
have thought he was, given his backstory. I guess
that makes sense. They had similar intellect and
ebasin miss as well. Considering all of this,
Jonathan, who's winning this match, who's your
money on and how much money? If I was a betting man, I
would put 100 large on the table. 100 large. Is that
like a hundred thousand dollars or is that just a
hundred dollars? No, no, I just mean a hundred
dollars. Even though the odds are against me,
according to our Instagram poll, 59 percent of the
voters in that poll bet it in favor of Deathlock,
essentially. Smart people. They look at a cowboy
and then they look at a zombie cyborg and they're
like, yeah, I'm going with the zombie cyborg on
that one. And they know that the Jonah Hex movie
sucks. So they know what they're doing. But let's
get the actual results. AG9K, the results,
please. Here you are, sir. All right, the winner
between Jonah Hex and Joe Hex. Jonah Hex and
Deathlock is Deathlock. Gosh dang it. The
demolisher he won out of a thousand matches, 658
percent of the time, whereas Jonah Hex only won
34.2 percent of the time. In the end, it was
Deathlock's enhanced strength and durability
that won him out. Jonah Hex just couldn't compete
with that. So I was afraid Deathlock was going to
win. If he did, I did not think it was going to be by
that much. He's essentially winning two thirds of
the time, which sucks because like what does
Deathlock have going for him? He has a gun and a
knife. Jonah Hex has that and more. He has a cyborg
body is what it comes down to. That's overrated. I
guess this means that Jonah Hex couldn't beat
Robocop either. Shoot him in the mouth. It's not
that hard. My apologies to all of the Jonah Hex fans
out there. This sucks. There are literally dozen
of you. Now, there's more than that. Great job,
Marvel fans. Like I said, in an earlier episode
this month, we are going to take the month of
November. We're coming back. We're going to close
this gap. I scoffed at the idea at the time, but I am
concerned now as you should be, as you should be.
That does it for this duel, guys. AJ9K help close us
out. Thanks for listening to Dynamic Joule. Visit
the show's website at dynamicjoule.com and
follow us on Instagram at Dynamic Joule podcast.
You can support the show on Patreon at patreon.com
slash dynamicjoule and joining a tier that works
for you or by rating and reviewing Dynamic Joule on
Apple podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser or on our
website. Don't forget to listen to the other shows
in the Dynamite podcast network, including Max
Destruction, Senjo World and Console Combat. Our
next episode is going to be another duel in which we
find out who doing in a fight between Vandal
Savage, the immortal DC villain versus Sebastian
Shah, the not quite immortal, but long living and
energy absorbing X-Men villain. Look forward to
that next week. But that does it for this episode.
We want to give a big thanks to our executive
producers, John Sterosky, Zachary Hepburn,
Dustin Belcombe, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yatan,
Austin Wazalowski, AJ Dunkerly, Nick Obonto,
Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Spees, Dean
Molesky, Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting and Paul
Graves for helping make this podcast possible.
We'll talk to you guys next week up up and away. True
believers. The amalgam version of these two
characters would be a cowboy zombie cyborg called
Death Hex.