This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi, welcome to
the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin
brother, Marvelous Joe. And, whoa, look at that up
in the sky! It's a bird! It's a plane! Oh, it just
landed. Oh, it looks like it's actually a comic
book. Where did that come from? Mortal Kombat vs
Street Fighter. I didn't know they made this
title. Oh, look, it's published by the DynaMic
Network. What?! Well, let's open up the comic book
and see what's inside. Duel Max Destruction will
give you shadow kicks and sonic booms as Johnny
Cage goes head-to-head with Colonel Guile for
round three. Finally on Senjoh World, Evil Reigns
Supreme as Revenant Liu Kang's Fireballs clash
with Evil Ryu's Hadoukens in the final round. It
begins now! Listen each day for a new fight. But
only on Senjoh World will you learn which universe
survives and which becomes my personal well of
souls to claim. Whoa, that's one of those talking
comic books! Yeah, I bet you guys were expecting
another Marvel vs DC episode on this special April
Fool's week at the network. But like last year when
we gave you guys Godzilla vs Ultraman, we're
diving into other franchises yet again and giving
you round two of the Mortal Kombat vs Street
Fighter tournament. And strangely enough, both
Mortal Kombat and Street Fighter have dipped
their toes into the worlds of DC and Marvel. That's
right, famously there was a Mortal Kombat vs DC
video game as well as some tie-in comic books, but
also DC has published several Mortal Kombat comic
series. Yeah, and with Street Fighter there's the
famous Marvel vs Capcom video game series which
included X-Men vs Street Fighter all the way
through Marvel vs Capcom 3 along with some tie-in
comics as well. So this will be a fun episode, be
sure to listen to round one of the Mortal Kombat vs
Street Fighter tournament over on Konsole Kombat
and then tune into Max Destruction tomorrow for
the third round in the tournament and then get the
final results in the Senjoh World podcast on
Thursday. Before we get into our main event
though, we're going to break down the comic book
movie news from this past week of which there was
just one major news item and that was the cast
reveal for Avengers Doomsday. Yeah, a lot to talk
about there. Can't wait to discuss it, but as
always we list our segment times in our episode
description, so feel free to check out the show
notes if you want to skip ahead to a particular
topic. Our artificially intelligent dual
simulator AJ9K has a quick message for our
listeners, so listen up. Why hello there. Do you
want even more from this podcast? Then become a
part of the dynamic dual community on Patreon
where you can choose from three tiers. The dynamic
2.0 tier gives you access to our Discord chat
server, the Fantastic Four tier gives you two
bonus episodes each month and the X-Force tier
makes you an executive producer of this show.
Lastly, the Diner Mike podcast network tier lets
you create your own podcast using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and
consultation and get you simulation results.
Pitch the twins your ideas via email at
dynamicdualpodcast at gmail.com. Check it out at
patreon.com slash dynamicdual. Pip pip cheerio.
Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast. But with that out of the way, quick to
the no prize. A no prize is an award Marvel used to
give out to fans. Our version, the dynamic dual no
prize, is a digital award we post on Instagram for
the person that we feel gave the best answer to our
question of the week. Last week we asked you guys,
what Marvel or DC actor whose performance was
hidden by practical or special effects would you
like to see play another character? And this was
coming off of the news that Colin Farrell is in
talks to play Sergeant Rock for that upcoming
movie, Colin Farrell being the guy who plays the
penguin in a largely unrecognizable role in the
Batman franchise. Let's break down our three
honorable mentions before revealing this week's
no prize winner. Our first honorable mention goes
to Matt from Texas. Who said? Hey guys, Matt from
Texas. The actor I would like to see is Matt Damon
since he was in two different Marvel movies,
Deadpool 2 and the sequels of Thor. I would like to
see him show up as an actual character, probably
Nighthawk of the Squadron Supreme, just to play
off of his friendship with Ben Affleck. Ben
Affleck being Batman, he could play the Marvel's
version of Batman. That'd be awesome. Yeah, Matt
Damon has been at the top of a lot of people's lists
to play his superhero role for decades now. I
remember way back in the day when they were
thinking about making an Iron Fist movie, Matt
Damon was the lead rumored contender for that
role. And to this day, he still has yet to play a
Marvel or DC superhero, despite making some cameo
appearances in both Deadpool 2 and Thor Ragnarok
and Thor 11 Thunder. I feel like the guy can't turn
down a cameo, which is wild. Since his often screen
partner and friend, Ben Affleck, played Batman in
the DCEU, it would be kind of hilarious to have Matt
Damon play Marvel's Batman counterpart from the
Squadron Supreme, Nighthawk. And it kind of met a
gag to the audience. Even if it just ends up being
another cameo, where in one of the upcoming
Avengers movies, we see the Incursions
destroying these other worlds and we get this
glimpse of the Squadron Supreme being destroyed
by an incursion, I think that would be entirely
worth it. Yeah, Hyperion could be Henry Cavill,
Power Princess could be Gal Gadot, but make
Nighthawk Matt Damon. There you go. We know Henry
Cavill is up for these Marvel cameos. Apparently.
So good answer, Matt. Our next honorable mention
goes to Travis Herndon. Who said? What's up,
dynamic dudes? Travis here, shout out to me, with
twins. So my pick would have to be Ada Wale, Alec
Kono'i. I probably butcher his last name. But the
actor who played Killer Croc in the Suicide Squad
movie, I mean, he had, and I think he'd be the
perfect pick as Tombstone. He has the attitude. He
has to hide, give him the sharp teeth, the white
skin and the hairstyle. And I think he can make a
pretty sick tombstone for a Spider-Man MCU movie
in the future. Yeah, Ada Wale, Akanoye Agbaje has
played multiple roles for both Marvel and DC. He
was Killer Croc, like Travis said, but he was also
Curse in Thor of the Dark World. So the guy has
always just been covered up in prosthetics and
hasn't really got the chance to shine as a Marvel or
DC character. Now, he'd also be wearing a lot of
makeup for Tombstone if you played that role, but
considerably less so. Basically, just slap some
white makeup on him and he's good to go. Yeah,
that's all you really need. I think he'd be great
for the role. He'd be one of my top picks if they ever
cast Tombstone in live action, which, you know,
who knows, the character showed up in the Into the
Spider-Verse movie, so he could show up in live
action, possibly in Spider-Man 4 or 5 with Tom
Holland. I wouldn't mind that at all. Yeah, give
the guy a shot. Great answer, Travis. Our final
honorable mention goes to Christopher Minotti,
who said, Hi guys, Christopher Minotti. My choice
would have to be Paul Bettany, who obviously
played his vision. I'd like to see him play Mr.
Freeze. I think that would be really cool. Paul
Bettany has, if you ever saw the Da Vinci Code, he
played the kind of tragic villain in that one, and
he was amazing in it. And I just think that it would
be amazing. He would do an amazing job as Mr. Freeze
because of that. Yeah, I keep hearing rumors that
Mr. Freeze is going to be the villain for the second
Batman film in Matt Reeves' Batman Universe. I
don't know if that's true, but if it was, Paul
Bettany would make a fantastic Mr. Freeze. I think
he would do well in that universe as well. Yeah,
based alone, even on his role in the Da Vinci Code.
Yeah, he was also in Firewall, I believe. He played
a great villain in that movie. He's just a
fantastic actor. And he's also really pale and has
got features, which I think is perfect for the
character of Mr. Freeze. Yeah, I could totally see
that. Great answer, Christopher Minotti.
Everybody had great answers this week. I was like
uncertain if it was even a good question of the
week, but you guys came through. Quick shout out to
Lee Tapscott, who also called in saying that Doug
Jones, who played the Silver Surfer, should play
Plastic Man in the DCU. But the winner of this
week's No Prize is Colby Hentges. Who said? Hey,
boys, Colby Hentges. I would like to see Bradley
Cooper, everybody's favorite Rocket Raccoon,
play a different Marvel superhero. But here's the
thing, I'm going to stick it behind special
effects again. Because I'd like to see him play
Johnny Blaze, the ghostwriter, maybe teaching a
young Robbie Reyes the ropes or some kind of
Midnight Sun's spirit of engines movie. Yeah, I
really like this answer. I think a lot of people are
bringing up like Ryan Gosling for the role of
Johnny Blaze, but I could totally see Bradley
Cooper in this role. And I think, you know, his
voice was nearly indistinguishable as Rocket
Raccoon. So despite the fact that he's lent his
talents to the Marvel Cinematic Universe, I think
he could do so in live action as the character
Johnny Blaze, who turns into ghostwriter. Yeah,
if all of the actors that could play ghostwriter, I
think Bradley Cooper would be by far the best one to
do so. But too bad because apparently, according
to a certain scooper who has seen an early version
of the Superman movie, Bradley Cooper has already
been cast as Jor-El in James Gunn's DC Universe.
That doesn't mean he couldn't play Johnny Blaze
because we all know Jor-El dies. It's a small role.
His fate is to not live and send his only son to
Earth. Well, until they make the Superman prequel
where they show everything that happens on
Krypton. Okay, okay. No, I still think that
Bradley Cooper would make a great Johnny Blaze
and, you know, the whole Jor-El thing that hasn't
been confirmed yet. So we'll see if that actually
comes out to be true. But great answer, Colby
Hitches. You win this week's No Prize. If you're
the listener, want a shot at winning your own No
Prize, stay tuned to later on in this episode when
we'll be asking another question of the week.
Another that's done? On to the news! Alright, this
past week we got a major cast announcement for the
upcoming Avengers Doomsday film, which has now
begun production. It is a massive cast list that
dwarfs even the size of Avengers Endgame in
Infinity War. And suffice to say it was an exciting
time this past week getting to see all the names
that would be in the film. Yeah, it took hours to get
through. Holy shit. It could have been a tweet.
Yeah, it could have been a tweet. It would have been
a long list, but I'll say that the engagement that
Marvel got from this slow reveal of a camera
panning across different chairs with the actors'
names on them, it was kind of a brilliant move.
Everybody was talking about it at the time. It was
hard to be at work at the same time that this was all
happening. But I'm going to go ahead and run down
the list in the order that they were revealed, and
we'll talk about them as we go. The first name on the
first chair that we saw was Chris Hemsworth, and my
initial reaction to that was, of course. We all
figured that Thor would be back. Chris Hemsworth
has to be there as the sole returning
representative of the original Avengers team.
Hopefully he can redeem the character from how
fucking goofy he was in Thor 11 Thunder. Yeah, that
bow god of dumpling still gets me as everything
that's wrong with Marvel right now. The next name
that was revealed was Vanessa Kirby, who will be
playing the invisible woman in the upcoming The
Fantastic Four First Steps movie. This was kind of
a surprise in that I didn't know necessarily that
The Fantastic Four was going to show up in
Doomsday. I mean, I had a good idea, but the fact
that we're getting both the Avengers and The
Fantastic Four in one film was big enough news to
get me excited. Yeah, because the Fantastic Four
members are not typically Avengers characters,
right? So I was surprised by this, but also not so
surprised because obviously Dr. Doom will be the
villain in Avengers Doomsday, and wherever
there's Dr. Doom, you also expect there to be
Fantastic Four. Yeah, it does seem like even
though The Fantastic Four get their powers in
another dimension, as we'll see in the upcoming
Fantastic Four movie, they eventually make their
way to the primary Marvel Cinematic Universe. The
sacred timeline is at work. After that, we've got a
reveal of Anthony Mackie and Sebastian Stan.
Anthony Mackie wasn't surprising. Sebastian
Stan also wasn't, but it's cool to see him so
frequently now since he had that cameo in Brave New
World, and of course, he'll show up in the
Thunderbolts movie, and we'll see him again in
Doomsday. Then we got Letitia Wright, who's going
to be in the movie playing Black Panther. I wasn't
sure if this film was going to reveal the new
T'Challa actor and who's going to play that new
version of Black Panther. It looks like we're
going to get Letitia Wright again as Shuri's Black
Panther. Which is fine because I really liked her
as the character in Black Panther Wakanda
Forever. Yeah, and I'm sure these two Avengers
films, the way I imagine it's going to play with
time and reality, will allow for a natural
introduction to a young T'Challa donning the
mantle of Black Panther. Or an older T'Challa, as
we saw in the concept art for Avengers Secret Wars.
Yeah, right. Next up was Wyatt Russell as US Agent.
I think my first reaction there was that, okay, so
he's going to survive the events of Thunderbolts.
I really was expecting prior to this announcement
that a lot of the Thunderbolts characters were
going to die in their battle with the Century
during the course of that film. But, you know, as we
go through this list even further, we realize that
that's not the case. Yeah, it looks like a majority
of the Thunderbolts are going to survive, which,
spoiler alert, I know, right? But that is kind of
cool that not only is this going to be an Avengers
film, it's also going to be a fantastic four film
and a Thunderbolts film. Next up, we learned that
Tanok Kwertha was going to be reprising his role as
Namor the Submariner. And that's pretty cool
because Namor has had a lot of dealings with Doom
over the years, sometimes as an ally. But it'll
also be interesting since the Fantastic Four is
going to be in this movie to see if he has any
interactions with Sue Storm since he has a big old
crush on her. Yeah, this is one of my favorite
announcements that they revealed because I love
the MCU adaptation of Namor. Like, they did a way
better job with the character than the comics ever
have. I agree. Yeah, he's definitely one of
Marvel's more interesting newer additions. And
you know, he's been an adventure in the comic
books, so whether he joins the side of the good guys
or teams up more with Doom will be interesting to
see what side he falls on. Next on the cast was Ebon
Moss Bakrok, who was expected once we got the
announcement of Vanessa Kirby. Again, it's just
nice to see the Fantastic Four here. But then we got
news that Shang-Chi, played by Simu Liu, is going
to show up again. And at that point, I think I got
really pumped and excited because I think
everyone else was kind of expected. But I've been
dying to see Shang-Chi again in a Marvel project
since that film came out because I was such a huge
fan of that movie. And I think we've been long
overdue to get an appearance from him again within
these stories. Yeah, 100%. Rae and I saw that. I was
like, it's about damn time. Then Florence Pugh was
announced to return as Yelena Bolova the White
Widow. Again, I was like, okay, so she survived
Slender Bolts too. But after that, I think the
biggest shock so far was the announcement of
Kelsey Grammer returning as Beast. That was huge
because we last saw him in the end credit scene of
the Marvel's movie. And when I saw this, I
immediately assumed that that world that Monaco
Rambo ended up in was going to either perish in an
incursion or find their way to the MCU. This either
meant that Beast was going to be a member of the
Avengers as he has been in the comic books. Or we
were going to get the X-Men. I was more thinking the
former rather than the latter. I thought we were
just really going to get Beast showing up in this
Avengers film. But I was shocked to say the least by
later announcements. I was shocked that we didn't
get Teyona Paris on this cast list. I know. Yeah,
that's a little weird. We'll talk about the people
who didn't show up and how that surprised me. The
next one to be announced was Louis Pullman as the
Sentry. That completely shocked me because the
Sentry or the Void rather is the primary
antagonist of the upcoming Thunderbolts movie.
So something happens there where he's not
necessarily defeated, but instead he's reformed
or something like that. Or they managed to destroy
the Void without destroying the Sentry. Or he gets
imprisoned and in the course of Doomsday he
escapes or something like that. Who knows what's
happening? All we know is that the Thunderbolts
don't kill the bad guy in that upcoming movie,
which I think it was a terrible spoiler. I wish they
would have saved all the Thunderbolts cast
announcements for later on after the movie was
released. That way we didn't get any of these
spoiler stuff. Well, I mean, as far as we know,
Julie Louise Dreyfus could be the main antagonist
of the Thunderbolts. She was on this cast list. I
don't think she would be, but you're probably
right. Next announced was Danny Ramirez as the
Falcon, which was no surprise because Anthony
Mackie was already announced and the Falcon is
Captain America's sidekick. Then we got Joseph
Quinn as the Human Torch. Again, no surprise. And
David Harbour as the Red Guardian, which at that
point I was like, okay, so everybody in the
Thunderbolts basically does live. I was
surprised to see Winston Duke return as Mbaku just
because the character status has been really
elevated within the Marvel Cinematic Universe.
Yeah, I mean, by the time this comes out, he'll be in
more Avengers movies than Black Panther movies.
That's true. Wow. That's kind of surprising. Next
up is Hannah John Kammon, who played Ghost in
Ant-Man and the Wasp and is reprising the
character in the upcoming Thunderbolts movie. It
looks like she lives too. And then actually a big
announcement that I guess wasn't surprising, but
one that I absolutely loved was that we get to see
Tom Hiddleston back as the character of Loki. It
makes sense because at the end of Loki Season 2, we
see Loki, you know, sitting on his throne kind of
overseeing the multiverse. So if Doomsday deals
with incursions, there wouldn't be any doubt that
we would see some kind of appearance from Loki as
these universes are colliding and getting
destroyed. I'm wondering if he even kicks off the
whole story. Yeah, probably. You keep saying
incursions, though, but I don't know if I believe
that just because Benedict Cumberbatch was not in
this cast list. He doesn't need to be in the movie
for there to be incursions. Well, he was our
introduction to incursions at the end of
Multiverse of Madness. So I have a hard time
believing that if incursions were involved, he
would not be like the main character. Why? Because
he would need to introduce the audience to
incursions because the character of Clea was the
one that introduced that to the Marvel Universe in
general. No, Clea didn't introduce it. Dr.
Strange had to help Clea with an incursion, but
Loki could also introduce the concept of
incursions. It doesn't have to be Dr. Strange.
Okay, Loki's inclusion didn't make you sad at all
that they're revisiting a story arc that had
already been perfectly resolved? No, I expect it
to seem more of Loki by the end of Loki season two.
And I don't think his appearance here ruins the
ending of that show because comic books, by their
very nature, have stories that go on and on and on.
The conclusion of one arc doesn't diminish the
character's inclusion in another. The next
announcement was a big one. I got really excited by
it. We get to see Patrick Stewart reprise his role
as Professor X. By this point, I was like, okay,
that's two X-Men. We're definitely going to get
more. And hopefully this time he lives and he
doesn't get his neck snapped by the Scarlet Witch
was my thought. Well, yeah, considering it looks
like Scarlet Witch is not in this movie, it's a safe
bet that that's not going to happen. I think by the
time this next announcement rolled around, Ian
McKellen as Magneto, I was full on screaming with
excitement because I think I knew where they were
starting to go with these announcements with the
back to back reveal of Professor X and Magneto. I'm
not going to lie. I was pretty underwhelmed by this
list or not really impressed by the list up to this
point because I was just like, okay, just everyone
in the MCU so far. Gotcha. Don't need to watch
anymore. But once they said Ian McKellen, I was
like, holy shit, how did they get him to come back?
You know, he hasn't played the role in quite some
time, but he was the perfect Magneto. And it's
really interesting to see that they got him back
into the role for this film. Yeah, they basically
have him until he's fucking 90. I have no idea how
old he is by now, but he's got to be close to 90. Oh,
yeah, he's 85 years old. There you go. The next
announcement had me laughing on the floor because
while this whole thing was going on, I posed a
question to our patrons on the discord. Like, who
do you want to show up in this movie that you think is
not going to? Like you think has no chance. And one
of our executive producers, Brandon Estregard,
said, I know there's absolute zero chance of this
happening, but if they bring back Alan Cumming as
Nightcrawler, I will shit gold for three days
straight. And I remember reading that thinking
that there was no way in hell that Alan Cumming was
coming back. And then all of a sudden his fucking
name showed up on that chair. And we all messaged
Brandon saying like time to start shitting
because Alan Cumming is back as Nightcrawler. And
that was just, I was floored. I was floored. By that
point, I couldn't work anymore. And I was just
glued to my screen on the Marvel YouTube channel,
just waiting to see who else was coming back. Yeah,
that's about the time when I dipped off of the
discord because all the Marvel fans started
talking about how they were coming and all the
different coming jokes. I was like, I'm out. We
were just really happy. Rebecca Romain was
announced next. Glad to see that she's coming
back. It is interesting that they're bringing
back the original X-Men lineup and not, you know,
the first class lineup. So we're not getting James
McAvoy or Michael Fassbender or Jennifer
Lawrence. You know, we're getting the original
actors, including James Marston, who's coming
back as Cyclops, which is really exciting. I
really want to see James Marston given his due as
the character because he kind of went out like a
punk ass in X-Men The Last Stand. And in the first
two movies, he didn't have a whole lot to do. So I'm
hoping that, you know, we see James Marston in the
classic Cyclops outfit and that he's a total
badass. Yeah, considering what Marvel Studios
was able to bring us with X-Men 97, I have total
faith that they can do Cyclops justice in a way that
Fox couldn't. Right. Like how they couldn't do
Channing Tatum justice with the character of
Gambit until Deadpool and Wolverine. And
speaking of Channing Tatum, he was the next one
announced. I think we all knew that Channing Tatum
was going to come back as Gambit. I didn't know it
was going to be this soon because we never got to see
Gambit interact with the rest of the X-Men team. He
only made that one, you know, brief appearance in
X-Men Origins Wolverine and that was super lame.
This will be much more exciting and much more true
to the character in the comic books. I just had a
ball watching him in Deadpool and Wolverine and I
want to see what the team dynamic is like with
Channing Tatum in the role here. Yeah, that said
Channing Tatum's role in Deadpool and Wolverine
was fairly comedic, I would say. So I'm interested
to see how that changes or maybe doesn't change for
this movie. Considering Ryan Reynolds was not a
part of the cast. Yeah, we only have two names
announced left. I think I was expecting like 10
more names. I thought that announcement was going
to go on for like hours longer. And then we got Pedro
Pascal as Mr. Fantastic, which of course he was the
final member of the Fantastic Four that they had
yet to announce. And we all knew that was coming.
But then we got Robert Downey Jr. as Dr. Doom. And at
that point I knew that was it. That was the final
cast member that was going to be announced. We
already knew that of course Robert Downey Jr. was
going to be in this movie. For the record, I'm still
fucking livid that they cast Downey in this role.
Because I don't want the Victor Von Doom on the
screen to just be a Tony Stark variant. I still
really wish this was a different actor. Well, what
if they never show his face? If they never show his
face, I'll be a little bit more lenient. So they
better not ever show his face basically. But if
that's the case, then, you know, why get Downey Jr.
just for his voice? That doesn't really make
sense. Well, just because he's a good actor. I
don't know, it may kind of be like the whole penguin
and Sergeant Rock scenario, like our question of
the week. Where one actor plays two different
characters, but one of them is heavily covered up
in makeup or CG. If they completely make Downey
unrecognizable in the role, then I'll accept it.
Because then I'll just see Doom, you know. So yeah,
that might be acceptable. That was the entire cast
list. I want to give a quick spotlight on the
characters that I thought would have been
announced, but have not been. There was some
discussion on social media between Robert Downey
Jr. And, you know, the official Marvel account
about how there will be more names in the movie
besides just this list. But I was really surprised
that, you know, people like the Hulk or She-Hulk
aren't going to be in the film. Spider-Man, Dr.
Strange, Scarlet Witch, Vision, Hawkeye. It
would have been really cool to see the Disney Plus
show characters like Moon Knight and Daredevil
show up. Really surprised we didn't get any of the
Marvels like Captain Marvel or Photon,
considering where Photon ended up at the end of the
Marvels film. Yeah, we didn't get any of the young
Avengers or Star-Lord, really anyone we saw in the
concept art for Avengers Secret Wars. Yeah, so it
kind of seems like they're dividing a lot of their
characters between these two films. Like the
characters that don't show up in this movie like
the Hulk are going to have a lot more screen time in
Avengers Secret Wars, where we saw in the concept
art like there's going to be Hulk and She-Hulk and
Vision and Star-Lord and Dr. Strange. So I guess
that's just a way to save money, but that being
said, this cast is already fully stacked and it
would be hard to see where they could possibly even
insert additional characters. But Jonathan,
considering that this is now not only an Avengers
film, but an Avengers slash Fantastic Four, slash
Thunderbolts slash X-Men film, how jealous are
you on a scale of 1 to 10? Uh, zero? Why would I be
jealous of that? Because that's the equivalent of
getting a Justice League slash Justice Society
slash Suicide Squad slash Titans movie, which you
will never get. You will never get this. You'll
never get this. You'll never get this. Uh, well,
when you put it like that, I just have to say I also
don't want that because that's too many teams in
one movie. There's no such thing. There's no such
thing and you're lying to yourself. Unless it was
like a crisis movie, then I could maybe see it. And,
well, frankly, this may be Marvel's crisis movie,
to which I just have to say a ripoff. Secret Wars is
not a ripoff of crisis. Sorry. Yes, it is, bro. Like
a multiverse coming together and then like
reforming into one universe. That's crisis.
Yeah, I don't see the comparison. I don't see the
comparison. I don't know what you're talking
about. Now who's lying to themselves? But
Avengers Doomsday comes out in a little over a year
from now on May 1st, 2026. So it'll be really
exciting to see what news comes out going forward.
But speaking of the Avengers Doomsday cast, that
brings us to our question of the week. The bottom
right hand corner of the screen, which will prompt
you to leave us a voicemail. Your message could be
up to 30 seconds long. And don't forget to leave
your name in case we include you on the podcast.
We'll pick our favorite answer and award that
person a dynamic dual no prize that will post to
Instagram. Be sure to answer before April 5th. But
that does it for all of the news for this episode. So
now let's go ahead and move on to our main event.
Joseph, go ahead and grab that Mortal Kombat vs.
Street Fighter comic one more time. You know, the
one that talks. Let's see what Shang Tsung has to
say. It has begun. Okay, this is round two of our
Mortal Kombat vs. Street Fighter Dynamite
Network crossover event for April Fool's Week.
Yeah, looking at this comic book here, it looks
like this matchup round two is going to be between
Raiden and M. Bison. That's pretty cool. We have
the Thunder God going up against the wielder of
Psycho Power. Yeah, interesting matchup. I'm
really excited for Raiden. He was the protagonist
of the Mortal Kombat vs. DC Universe comic book
series, as well as one of the protagonists of the
video game. He also made an appearance in
Injustice 2, which is a DC fighting video game and
probably has my favorite version of the Raiden
character. Yeah, so there's a lot of crossover
between Mortal Kombat and DC. There's a lot of
crossover between Street Fighter and Marvel as
well. As I mentioned earlier, there's the Marvel
vs. Capcom video game series, but that whole thing
was started with the X-Men vs. Street Fighter
video game of which M. Bison was the primary
antagonist along with Magneto. So kind of like our
last April Fool's episode, which was Godzilla vs.
Ultraman. Godzilla had ties to the DC comics and
Marvel had their own line of Ultraman comic books.
It's nice that things are still able to be tied to
the Marvel and DC universes. Absolutely. But to
explain the methodology behind our duels, let's
go to our sentient duel simulator, Alphard Jarvis
9000. A.J .9K, tell our listeners how you go about
determining a winner in our duel matchups. Yes, of
course, sir. The way I determine a winner between
the contestants is by running 1000 Monte Carlo
simulations using the characters statistics. A
Monte Carlo simulation is a probabilistic model
used to determine outcomes through random
sampling. In this case, I randomize the
statistics along a normal distribution as a way to
simulate the many variables that can occur during
battle. The stat parameters are based on the
official Marvel power grid from which the DC
characters statistics are extrapolated.
Additional stat categories are included such as
range, damage potential, versatility and
perception in order to create a more detailed and
accurate simulation. The results of the 1000
simulations provide a percentage of wins for each
character. The contestant with the higher
percentage is declared the victor as they have a
higher probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither character should win
100% of the matches. The comic book stories have
shown that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman, so the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks AJ9k. Before
we run the simulations though, we'd like to break
down each character's histories and abilities
before improvising a scenario on how we imagine
one of the 1000 simulations would play out beat for
beat. And I believe it's my turn to go first, so let
me go ahead and tell you all about the Street
Fighter character M. Bison. Little is known about
the early life of M. Bison, including his birth
name or nationality. As a young man, he was a
martial artist who once wielded soul power, a
spiritually aligned energy based on positive
emotions and balance. He trained under a master
capable of manipulating psychopower, a darker
supernatural energy force rooted in negative
emotions like hatred and aggression. Obsessed
with becoming the strongest martial artist in the
world, Bison murdered his master and discarded
soul power entirely, embracing the corrupting
influence of psychopower. He journeyed on a quest
for power, defeating numerous martial artists
and absorbing their knowledge and techniques,
eventually gaining control over a criminal
syndicate known as Shadalu. At some point, Bison
became aware of the secret assassination martial
arts style of Ansatsuken and sought out its
practitioner, Gouken. Upon confronting him,
Bison fought Gouken, but was unsatisfied when the
master chose not to utilize techniques like the
Hadouken Fireball or Shoryuken Uppercut.
Disappointed by the encounter, Bison cursed
Gouken for withholding the true potential of his
style and turned his attention toward Gouken's
students, famed warriors Ryu and Ken. As the
leader of Shadalu, Bison began expanding his
organization's global influence, carrying out
human experimentation, military operations,
and assassinations, such as the murder of
Interpol Inspector Dori, who came too close to
learning the syndicate's secrets. Bison later
fought Dori's daughter, Interpol Officer Chun
Li, and revealed to her that he was responsible for
her father's death, for which she swore vengeance
against him. Bison pursued Ryu after the fighter
defeated Sagat, one of Shadalu's newly recruited
lieutenants. Intrigued by Ryu's power, Bison
sought to recruit him to the syndicate. When Bison
finally tracked him down, he offered to make him
the most powerful fighter in the world by infusing
him with psychopower, but Ryu refused. In a covert
operation, Chun Li and Air Force officers Charlie
Nash and William Gile, longtime Wingman and
friends, infiltrated Shadalu's base to destroy
it. During the assault, Bison mortally wounded
Charlie by punching him through the chest, a
pivotal moment for Gile, who vowed revenge.
Charlie stayed behind to ensure the base's
destruction, sacrificing himself while Gile and
Chun Li escaped. As Bison's reliance on
psychopower intensified, the strain began to
degrade his physical body. Anticipating this, he
commissioned his scientists to create a
replacement host, leading to the creation of
Kami, a clone derived from Bison's own DNA. Kami
was placed among the dolls, a group of elite female
assassins brainwashed to serve Shadalu and each
implanted with fragments of Bison's
psychopower. Kami, however, began developing
self-awareness and defected. Bison responded by
dispatching his lieutenant Vega to retrieve her.
When these efforts failed, he renewed his
interest in taking over Ryu's body as a more
suitable vessel. In pursuit of Ryu, Bison learned
of Akuma, Goken's younger brother who had fully
embraced the dark side of Ansatsuken, fueled by
killing intense and unrestrained aggression.
After defeating Akuma, Bison dismissed his power
as inferior to his own and declared it only a matter
of time before he controlled Ryu. To provoke the
fighter, Bison captured Ken, Ryu's closest
friend, and subjected him to brainwashing,
pitting the two against each other. Ken
eventually broke free of Bison's influence and
urged Ryu to end Bison's tyranny. Bison fought Ryu
once more, overpowering him and attempting to
convert him once again. Sagat, witnessing these
events, objected. Bison offered Sagat his
long-desired rematch with Ryu, hoping the
encounter would cause Ryu to give in to his dark
side. Ken intervened, however, breaking Bison's
mental hold. Ryu regained control and, with
encouragement from his friends, defeated Bison
with a Mezu Shoryuken, a more powerful variant of
the traditional Shoryuken uppercut, enhanced by
spiritual force. Bison fled to his Psycho Drive, a
powerful machine used to amplify his Psycho Power
in order to restore himself. Meanwhile, Kami
rallied the remaining dolls to rebel against
Bison. When Bison reappeared, he declared them
expendable and warned that their psychic
connection to him meant they would die if he did.
Kami accessed the Psycho Drive and severed the
link, freeing the dolls. Bison's control over
them collapsed, but he remained a looming threat.
In the years that followed, Bison rebuilt
Shadalu, establishing a new base in Thailand. To
draw out Ryu, he hosted the World Warrior
Tournament. His plans were interrupted when
Akuma suddenly appeared and killed him with a
Shungoku Satsu, a devastating finishing move
that targets the soul. Refusing to surrender,
Bison unleashed all of his Psycho Power in a
suicidal blast. However, his soul persisted,
waiting for a new host. Prior to these events,
Bison had ordered Shadalu to create a line of
advanced androids. Seth, or Unit Number 15, rose
to prominence among these androids and attempted
to lead Shadalu after Bison's death. Seth was a
synthetic being programmed to emulate and
improve upon human martial arts styles, acting as
a contingency vessel for Bison. Eventually,
Bison reemerged in a weaker body, rejecting the
advice of his scientists to wait for a more
suitable vessel to return. He declared that
Seth's actions were part of his plan all along and
quickly dispatched his rogue creation.
Meanwhile, Bison deployed seven satellites
capable of unleashing devastating
electromagnetic pulses to plunge the world into
chaos and fuel his Psychic Power. After one such
satellite destroyed a major North American city,
Bison personally arrived on site, now fully
powered and easily overcoming Chun Li. Kami
rescued her and the two retreated. As panic spread
worldwide, Bison's power reached unprecedented
levels. Charlie Nash, who was resurrected using
bio-enhancement, confronted Bison and was again
defeated, but he succeeded in absorbing much of
Bison's Psycho Power and sacrificed himself to
weaken the dictator. In the final battle, Ryu,
having achieved the power of nothingness, a
serene spiritual state that nullifies negative
energy, confronted Bison and overpowered him.
Laughing, Bison attempted one final attack, but
was consumed by his own dissipating Psycho Power
and vanished. Despite the destruction of
Shadowloo, remnants of Bison's influence
endured. In time, a nameless man appeared in Metro
City, exhibiting violent tendencies and
wielding Psycho Power. With no memory of his past,
he wandered until his power led him to a ruined
Shadowloo Lab. There, an echo of his past self was
released by a malfunctioning lab device, and the
nameless Bison absorbed it and regained his full
power and memories. Speculating that his
survival was due to his soul transferring into one
of his many contingency bodies, he acknowledged
that while Shadowloo had fallen, his ambition for
global domination endured. And Bison's history
also includes interactions with the Marvel
Universe in the Marvel vs. Capcom video game
series. In X-Men vs. Street Fighter, Apocalypse
began abducting powerful mutants and street
fighters for experimentation. In response,
fighters from both universes joined forces to
stop him. In this conflict, M. Bison allied
himself with Magneto in a temporary partnership
aimed at world domination, though Bison harbored
intentions to betray Magneto and seize power for
himself. In the video game sequel Marvel
Superheroes vs. Street Fighter, Apocalypse
returned as the main villain, expanding his reach
to not only mutants and street fighters, but also
superheroes and villains from across the broader
Marvel Universe. His experiments resulted in
monstrous fused beings such as Cyber Akuma. Once
again, Bison took part in the battles against
these threats, pursuing his own ambitions amid
the chaos. The crossover continued in Marvel vs.
Capcom, Clash of Superheroes, where Onslaught, a
psychic entity born from Charles Xavier and
Magneto, threatened the multiverse. Bison
appeared among the characters drawn into the
conflict. Further crossover events such as
Marvel vs. Capcom 2, New Age of Heroes, involved
the emergence of the reality-threatening being
called Abyss. In Marvel vs. Capcom 3, Fate of Two
Worlds, interdimensional tampering awakened
Galactus. And in Marvel vs. Capcom Infinite, the
fusion of Ultron and Sigma using the Infinity
Stones created Ultron Sigma, who merged the
Marvel and Capcom universes into the converged
realm. In these events, Bison was among those
affected as the two universes collided. And
that's in Bison's backstory. Powers-wise, M.
Bison wields Psycho Power, the supernatural
psychic energy fueled by hatred, rage, fear, and
destruction. With it, he can perform feats of
telepathy, including mind reading, psychic
hallucinations, and controlling the minds of the
weak-willed, or stronger minds with
technological assistance from the Psycho Drive.
His power also enhances his physicals, granting
him increased strength with enough force to punch
a hole through a man, increased speed with the
power to teleport, and increased durability. If
his body is destroyed, Psycho Power allows his
soul to live on, wherein he can transfer it to
another physical form such as a cloned body or
another adequately strong host like Ryu. Bison is
a commanding leader of a manipulation. Bison is
also a master martial artist who incorporates
Psycho Power into his own unique fighting style
characterized by powerful strikes,
unpredictable movements, psychic pressure, and
aerial mobility. And that's in Bison. So he's
essentially a really powerful telepath. Yeah,
telepath with some telekinetic abilities as
well. Okay, gotcha. Now, correct me if I'm wrong,
his name isn't actually in Bison in the Japanese
version of the game, because I remember there was
some copyright thing with M. Bison being the name
of a boxer character I think that was playing on
Mike Tyson. Right, yeah, in Japan M. Bison is known
as Vega. Okay, that's right, and Vega is Balrog,
and the boxer Balrog is actually M. Bison.
Correct, yeah, the three didn't name swap, but in
the United States, you know, Vega is the Spaniard
with the Wolverine Clause, and Balrog, of course,
is the boxer. Gotcha. Okay, well, what does the M
stand for? Motherfucker. It has not actually been
revealed what M stands for. It's just part of the
mystery of the character, but a lot of fans think it
stands for master Bison. Okay, this is
interesting. Yeah, it's like one of Street
Fighter's major antagonists going up against one
of Mortal Kombat's primary protagonists or
champions. Right, yeah, I think this is a great
matchup. Let me get into the Mortal Kombat side of
things by telling you about the history of Raiden.
Now at the dawn of Earthrealm's history, Raiden
was chosen by the Elder Gods to serve as its divine
protector. When the Elder God, Shinok, sought to
conquer Earthrealm and rule it for himself,
Raiden led the defense against him in a
cataclysmic war. The conflict devastated large
swaths of the realm, wiping out entire
civilizations. With the Elder Gods aid, Raiden
defeated Shinok by stripping him of his powerful
amulet and banishing him to the Netherrealm. To
prevent Shinok's return, Raiden built a temple of
the elements in the mountains of Nepal, where he
hid the amulet and appointed four elemental gods
as its guardians. Millions of years later,
Shinok's follower, the sorcerer Quan Chi,
manipulated the assassin's sub-zero into
stealing the amulet for him. The Raiden was able to
sense the theft and with Sub-Zero's help was able
to recapture the amulet and prevent Shinok's
return. Soon after, Shang Tsung invited
Earthrealm warriors to compete in Mortal Kombat,
a tournament between realms that, if lost, would
allow Outworld to invade Earthrealm. Aware of the
danger, Raiden took on human form and entered the
tournament to ensure Earthrealm's survival.
When Earthrealm's champion, Luke, defeated
Shang Tsung, the threat was temporarily ended.
However, a year later, Raiden received another
invitation, this time to a tournament in
Outworld. Knowing the treachery of Outworld's
ruler, Shao Khan, Raiden warned the surviving
champions of the Shaolin Temple and then traveled
alone to Outworld to confront the threat. After
Earthrealm's victory in the second tournament,
an unexpected convergence emerged between
Earthrealm and another universe populated by
powerful beings such as Superman, Batman, and
Wonder Woman. As this dimensional collision
intensified, it caused rage and instability to
spread among fighters from both worlds. Raiden
initially believed these newcomers to be
invaders, aiding Shao Khan, and fought several of
them, including Captain Marvel and Batman,
before realizing that they were also acting in
defense of their own realm. The true threat was
revealed to be Dark Khan, an interdimensional
fusion of Shao Khan and Darkseid, created when
Raiden blasted Shao Khan with a lightning strike
through a portal at the same moment when Superman
struck Darkseid with heat vision into a boom tube.
With their combined energies and rage fusing
between the universes, Dark Khan sought to merge
and conquer the two worlds. Raiden eventually
worked alongside the DC Universe's champions to
bring an end to the chaos, later confronting Dark
Khan alongside Superman, defeating the merged
entity and restoring balance to both universes.
With their crisis resolved and their realms
restored, Raiden returned to Earthrealm, though
he did return later to the DC Universe on a mission
to stop Brainiac's conquest of it, fearing
Earthrealm would be next. You can learn more about
Brainiac in our Brainiac vs. Ultron episode and
Darkseid and his duel against Thanos. It wasn't
long after his defeat that Shao Khan enacted a new
scheme to merge Earthrealm without world by
resurrecting his queen, Sindel, within
Earthrealm itself. Her rebirth gave him an excuse
to violate the rules of mortal combat and invade
the realm directly. As Earthrealm's protector,
Raiden was unable to fight without giving up his
godhood. Choosing Earthrealm's safety, Raiden
relinquished his immortality and fought
alongside its champions. When Liu Kang defeated
Khan once more, Raiden's godhood was restored.
Soon after, Shennock escaped from Netherrealm
and began a second war against the Elder Gods.
Caught off guard, many of Earthrealm's gods were
killed. Raiden assembled a force of mortals to
fight alongside him, led once again by Liu Kang.
Together they defeated Shennock's forces and
Raiden was elevated to the status of Elder God. He
passed the role of Earthrealm's protector to the
Wind God, Bujin. Years later, when Liu Kang was
killed by Shang Tsung and Quan Chi, now calling
themselves the Deadly Alliance, Raiden
petitioned the Elder Gods to intervene. When they
refused, he relinquished his status and returned
to Earthrealm to stop them himself. Despite his
efforts, Raiden's warriors were slaughtered in
battle against the Tarkhautans. Desperate,
Raiden confronted the Deadly Alliance alone, but
was defeated. As Shang Tsung and Quan Chi prepared
to face each other, the Dragon King Onaga appeared
and reclaimed his lost throne. Recognizing the
hopelessness of the situation, Raiden
sacrificed himself by unleashing a massive
explosion of godly energy. Onaga survived,
however, and Raiden's essence reconstituted in
Earthrealm, now corrupted and embittered.
Disillusioned by how humanity treated its realm,
Raiden became increasingly harsh and
authoritarian in his judgment. He blamed
Shunjinco, a warrior manipulated into gathering
the Kamidagu relics that freed Onaga and nearly
killed him in rage. Shifting his focus, Raiden
exhumed the corpse of Liu Kang and took it to a
temple once belonging to the necromatic Kuon
sect. Using enchanted bindings and the sect's
resurrection magic, Raiden revived Liu Kang's
body and imbued it with his power, turning it into a
mindless revenant to enforce the will. The undead
Liu Kang carried out Raiden's orders, targeting
those Raiden deemed responsible for
Earthrealm's peril. When Shinnok offered an
alliance, promising Earthrealm's safety in
exchange for Raiden's cooperation, Raiden
feigned acceptance to learn his plans. He also
struck a deal with Shao Khan, agreeing to
eliminate the demigod Taven to ensure Earthrealm
would be spared if Khan conquered the other
realms. Raiden confronted Taven on a Dina's
doorstep of what was defeated. Meanwhile,
Raiden's former allies began to take notice of his
instability. Fujin and Kung Lao joined forces to
confront him and the revenant Liu Kang. Before a
resolution could be reached, the timeline ended
in the Battle of Armageddon. Raiden and Shao Khan
were the last warriors standing. As Khan prepared
to strike the final blow, Raiden used the last of
his power to send a message into the past. He must
win. In the altered timeline, Raiden received
fragmented visions of the future and tried to
prevent Armageddon by altering events. Though
well-intentioned, his interference had dire
consequences. Many allies, including Kung Lao,
Smoke, and Kitana, were killed. Liu Kang blamed
Raiden for their deaths and during a
confrontation, Raiden accidentally killed him
in self-defense. When Shao Khan attempted to
merge Earthrealm and Outworld outside of Mortal
Combat, the Elder Gods intervened, empowered
Raiden, and allowed him to destroy Khan, though
the lives that were lost left Raiden deeply
shaken. During the Netherrealm War, Raiden and
Sonya Blade stormed Quan Chi's fortress. There,
Raiden combined divine and dark magic to restore
Sub-Zero, Scorpion, and Jax to their human forms.
During Shennok's return, he pleaded with the
Elder Gods to destroy the fallen Gods' amulets.
They refused, but permitted him to seal it using
the blood-bound Kamidogu Daggers. Raiden
allowed each dagger to pierce him, then entrusted
them to his champions. With the Chaos Realm,
Denizen Havok used blood magic to corrupt the
daggers. Raiden invoked the same magic to trace
the threat, but was again corrupted, this time by
Havok himself. Under Havok's control, Raiden
helped turn Rako into a blood god and later
enslaved Malina. Though Havok was ultimately
defeated, Raiden no longer entrusted himself
with Shennok's amulet and gave it to Sonya Blade
for special forces protection. Soon after,
Shennok invaded Earthrealm. Raiden and Fujin
defended the Jinsai Chamber until Cassie Cage
sealed Shennok away, but Raiden's exposure to the
Gods' corruption changed him. He descended into
the Netherrealm, delivering Shennok's
still-living head to Liu Kang and Katana as a
warning. He would now destroy all threats to
Earthrealm without mercy. Two years later,
Raiden led an assault on the Netherrealm, losing
Sonya in the process. His violent methods alarmed
his allies and when a temporal disturbance
brought younger versions of fallen warriors into
the presence, the corrupted Raiden vanished,
replaced by a pure, younger version of himself.
This Raiden joined Liu Kang in confronting
Kronika, the keeper of time. On the break of
turning dark again, Raiden experienced visions
of his endless battles with Liu Kang and realized
they had been manipulated across timelines. He
merged his essence with Liu Kang, transforming
him into a fire god who defeated Kronika. In Liu
Kang's new timeline that he created, Raiden was
reborn as a humble farmer in Fengyan. After
winning Outworld's tournament, Liu Kang granted
him an amulet that allowed him to control
lightning. Raiden helped defend the realms
against Shang Tsung, Quan Chi, and Titan Shang
Tsung. Later, when Sub-Zero attacked the Wushi
Academy and fell to Titan Havoc's corruption,
Raiden helped subdue him and placed him in the
Temple of the Elements to await a cure. And that's
Raiden's history so far. Now there have been
various versions of Raiden throughout his
history, but the version I'm going with for this
match is the God version from the Mortal Kombat vs
DC Universe and Injustice 2 video games and
comics. Powers-wise, the Wise Raiden possesses
control over electricity and weather,
channeling divine lightning to attack enemies
and teleport. As a god, he is capable of flight,
immortality, and dimensional travel. His skills
in martial arts, particularly in hand-to-hand
and staff combat, make him formidable even
without his powers. That's Raiden. You know, with
every DC backstory that you give, you always have
to go through multiple timeline iterations of
these characters. You know, post crisis, post
flashpoint, it seems like the characters in
Mortal Kombat are no exception, as you have to keep
going through multiple iterations. Yeah, you
could say that. They even had their own flashpoint
event that reset continuity. In a way that seems
pretty apt considering you're the DC guy, I'm
really glad that I don't have to do that as the
Marvel guy because I like to think of just one
version of the character. And while Bison has
certainly gone through changes in the course of
his history, dying on several occasions, the
version that I'm going with for this matchup is
probably the one from Street Fighter 5, not when he
was super powered by the satellites or anything
like that, but the most recent version where he
doesn't have his cape, but rather he has that long
jacket. All right, well now that we've got their
histories and abilities out of the way, let's
speculate on how one of the 1000 simulated matches
will go. The winner is determined by simulations,
not the speculation, but it's fun to imagine how
this fight could play out. AJ9K, what are the rules
of our speculation? Well, I should say there are no
rules other than the characters have no prior
knowledge of the other going into the fight. All
they are aware of starting out is that the other
character is a threat that needs to be eliminated.
For the speculation, the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the match
itself, as no environmental statistics are
considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. All right,
then let's get into it. Raiden and M. Bison meet on
the battlefield. Who goes first? I think M. Bison
is going to go first because he's so evil. So like
with this like sinister grin, he's going to rush at
Raiden, just covering the distance between them.
Okay, and as Bison runs toward him, Raiden is going
to slam his energized fist into the ground,
sending an electric current through it that's
going to just race right towards Bison's feet and
shock him. No, Bison leaps over the ground current
and is going to stomp down on Raiden's head with
both of his feet in a move that's called Skull
Diver, and he bounces off of Raiden's head back
into the air, knocking off Raiden's signature
hat. Oh, shit. No, you didn't. Before Bison is
going to land on the ground, I'm going to say Raiden
does this vicinity blast move that's like this
electrified sphere of electricity that is going
to knock Bison out of the air. It's like an aerial
counter. And that's when Raiden does his front
he's got a car electric fly attack, and he's going
to fly into Bison while electrified and shove him
backward. I think he was more like, yeah, no, it's
more like, hey, you got a baby. It's different.
When Bison sees Raiden flying at him, he's going to
counter with his own flying attack. It's this
flying corkscrew move called psycho crusher
charged with his flaming purple psychopower, and
Raiden and Bison are going to fly into each other
and the two moves are going to cancel each other
out, and they're both going to ricochet off in this
like lightning psychopower energy explosion.
Oh, yeah, I was wondering which of those two were
more powerful. They have a lot of similar moves.
Yeah. Okay, well, once Raiden is back on his feet,
he's going to instantly teleport behind him by
Bison by phasing through the ground, and he's
going to uppercut Bison, knocking him into the
air, and that's going to allow Raiden to pull off
this like devastating martial arts combo that
Bison is going to be helpless to defend against as
he's, you know, juggled in the air with a series of
punches and kicks, and Raiden's going to end the
combo by grabbing Bison by the neck and just
sending a surge of electricity through his body
for dropping him. Okay, Bison's hit by this combo.
But before Raiden can finish by electrocuting
him, Bison's actually going to get out of the combo
by teleporting behind Raiden and doing a slide
kick. It's kind of like a slide tackle that sweeps
Raiden off of his feet onto the ground, and then
Bison's going to just stomp into him repeatedly
with a series of kicks. That's kind of like Luke
Hanks flying bicycle kick, but it's more stompy,
and Bison's going to finish off by kicking off
Raiden doing this backflip and landing on the
ground. Okay. Well, as Raiden is getting back up,
that's when he's going to hurl a bolt of lightning
at Bison, which shocks and stuns him in place, and
that's going to allow Raiden to surround Bison
with a series of static traps. They're these like
small electrified orbs of energy that are
connected by arcs of lightning. Let's take a full
Bison into walking into them, because as he comes
out of being stunned, he's going to read Raiden's
mind with his telepathy. So he knows, you know,
what these are not to move, and then he's going to
shoot out this quick expanding like orb of psycho
power, like a force field from his body. It's
called the psycho burst, and that is basically
going to dissolve these static traps. And with
them gone, Bison is going to leap from his force
field with the scissor kick, which is like a front
flip double kick. Well, actually, just as that
scissor kick is about to land, Raiden's going to do
a electric storm move where this lightning bolt
from the sky crashes down on him and electrifies
Bison, just stunning him. So that's when Raiden's
going to grab him by the neck with one hand,
electrocuting him still. And with his other hand,
he's going to plunge it right into Bison's
abdomen, just grabbing his spine and overloading
his whole body with so much electricity, that
Biden's just going to explode. And there's bones
and blood everywhere. Fatality. I'm going to say
that Raiden meant to do a fatality, but he got his
inputs confused. And he actually performed a
Mortal Kombat friendship instead of a fatality.
So instead of electrocuting him, Raiden summons
just this mini version of himself. And both Bison
and Raiden are like, what? Kid Thunder? Right. And
Bison takes advantage of the distraction by
straight up punching Raiden in the gut with a
psycho power charged fist, and then grabs Raiden
and charges him full of psycho power, which is
going to psychically take over Raiden's mind and
flood him with all this negative energy that's
going to transform him into like evil Raiden. And
now he's just one of Bison's lieutenants in the
Shadow Loose Syndicate. Okay. So either Raiden
inputs the fatality correctly and he overloads
and Bison with electricity, or he gets a wrong and
then Bison overloads Raiden with psycho power.
Correct. Taking over his mind and turning him into
evil Raiden. Well, you know what? Kid Thunder will
avenge him. Let's go ahead and find out which of
these two scenarios happens by inputting the
character stats, running the simulations, and
coming back with a winner. AJ9K, hit it. Inputting
data, running calculations, processing
results, simulations complete. All right. That
was a lot of fun. I was surprised during the course
of this match, just how similar Raiden and Bison
were, because they could both teleport. They both
have like these flying attacks. They both have a
lot of energy moves, and they could both like grab
you and charge you with that energy. There's a lot
of stuff that they have in common. Yeah, they even
do like energy orb traps. Yeah. One of M. Bison's
moves is to trap you in these psycho power orbs.
It's a little copy cat-ish, I think, on behalf of
Mortal Combat, because everybody knows that
Street Fighter was the first and best. No, I'm
sorry. Mortal Combat has very much surpassed
Street Fighter in the fighting genre. Have you
played one of the newest Mortal Combat games?
They're awesome. No, I haven't, because I don't
play lame games and I don't read lame comics. You
read Marvel, bro. Yeah, you do. The characters
were nearly identical in almost every stat
category, including evasiveness, because they
could both teleport and erect like energy
shields. They were both evenly matched when it
came to fighting, as well, obviously. They're
both expert fighters, as they are major
characters in a fighting video game. They're both
highly durable. They're both pretty damn strong.
Very intelligent and very versatile with the
powers that they have. We did give the edge to
Raiden when it came to range, because, you know, he
could hurl lightning bolts. Yeah, he
incorporates a lot more long range attacks than M.
Bison does. We also gave the speed edge to Raiden,
though Bison got the edge when it came to
perception, because he does have those
telepathic abilities. So taking all of this into
account, who do you think came out on top, Joseph?
I'm going to say my boy Bison has got this. He's
going to beat Raiden and incorporate him into
Shadowloo. And I would say that the Instagram
followers agree with me just because Jonathan
forgot to post the Instagram poll. I didn't
forget. This is like a surprise April Fools
episode, bro. I'm going to spoil it. I say Raiden
wins. Well, let's find out. AJ9K, the results,
please. Hey, you are, sir. You dumb robot. These
aren't the results. This is just that comic book
that showed up. Oh, whoa. Why is it glowing? It's
flying back into the air. It looks like it's
transforming into a video game console and then
flying out of my hands back up into the air. I know
you guys can't see this, but I'm describing it to a
T. Just trust me. All right. There it goes. Right
through an Outworld portal. Wild. I wonder where
it's going to end up. Well, it looks like we won't
get the results for this matchup today, folks.
You'll have to tune into the Max Destruction
podcast tomorrow for around three of the
tournament where they're pitting Gile against
Johnny Cage. And then on Thursday, tune into the
Senjo World podcast where round four is going to
determine the winner between Evil Ryu and
Revenant Liu Kang, as well as provide all the
results from these tournament matches. Yeah. And
we finally find out which franchise is better,
Mortal Kombat or Street Fighter that does it for
this duel. AJ9K help close us out. Thanks for
listening to Dynamic Joule. Visit the show's
website at dynamicjoule.com and follow us on
Instagram at Dynamic Joule podcast. You can
support the show on Patreon at patreon.com slash
dynamicjoule and joining a tier that works for you
or by rating and reviewing Dynamic Joule on Apple
podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser or on our website.
Don't forget to listen to the other shows in the
Dynamite podcast network, including Max
Destruction, Senjo World and Console Combat.
Yeah, don't forget to listen to Console Combat,
Max Destruction and Senjo World for the rest of
this Mortal Kombat versus Street Fighter
tournament. Our next episode, guys, is going to be
another duel where we find out who'd win in a fight
between Ratcatcher, who you may remember from the
Suicide Squad film, and Squirrel Girl. It's
basically rats versus squirrels. But that does it
for this episode. We want to give a big thanks to our
executive producers, John Sturrosky, Zachary
Hepburn, Dustin Balcom, Mickey Mithangian,
Brandon Estregard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi
Aitin, Austin Wyselowski, AJ Dunkerly, Nick
Obanto, Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Spees,
Dean Molesky, Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, Josh
Leiner, Mike Williams and Oscar Galvez for
helping make this podcast possible. We'll talk to
you guys next week. Up, up and away, true
believers. Your soul is mine.