This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Alright guys,
the clock is ticking, the holidays are just weeks
away and if you still haven't finished your
shopping, now's the time to act. So head to
OldGlory.com where you'll find officially
licensed Marvel and DC shirts, hoodies and gear.
Perfect for every fan on your list. They ship fast
but time's running out to get your gifts before the
holidays hit. So go now and use the promo code Duel
at checkout to save 15% off your entire order.
That's D-U-E-L at OldGlory.com because even
superheroes can't stop the holiday countdown.
Hi, welcome to the DynaMic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by
comparing their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Marvelist Joe. And I'm his twin
brother Johnny DC. And in the countdown to the
final episodes of this podcast, we're at number 6,
that means there are 5 episodes left after this
one. Which is Parasite versus Sauron, the
Superman villain against the X-Men villain?
Yeah, he's basically a pterodactyl man who lives
in the savage land and also, like Parasite, has the
ability to drain the life energy from his victims
through contact. Yeah, you mentioned last
episode that it was a crime that we had not yet
gotten to a Shadowcat duel. It is an even bigger
crime that it took us so long to get to a Parasite
duel. He's like one of Superman's biggest
villains. Nah, to me that's more like a
misdemeanor, whereas not getting to Kitty Pride
was basically a felony on behalf of the show. Well
not getting to Parasite is a felony with a higher
sentencing, I don't know. Before we get into that
matchup guys, where we input the character stats
and run simulations to find out who would win,
we're going to break down the latest comic book
movie news that came out this past week, of which we
have one news item and that is the Supergirl
official teaser trailer. As always, we list our
segment of times in our episode description, so
feel free to check out the show notes if you want to
skip ahead to a particular topic. Our
artificially intelligent duel simulator, AJ9K,
has a quick message for our listeners, so listen
up. Hello, these are the final episodes of Dynamic
Jules Weekly Podcast, leading up to our grand
finale on January 20th. We hope you've enjoyed the
past 10 years of Marvel and DC Jules and reviews,
and we'd love for you to stick with us as we count
down these last episodes. We're inviting you, the
listener, to help us close out the show by visiting
dynamicjule.com over the next few weeks and
clicking the red microphone button in the bottom
right corner to leave us a voicemail that we'll
play during the final episode. Tell us what first
got you into DC or Marvel, how long you've been
listening, a favorite episode or moment, or
anything else you want to share about what the
podcast has meant to you. Your messages will be
aired and responded to on the January 20th finale.
Again, head to dynamicjule.com and leave your
final message. We would love to hear from you. Pip
Pip Cheerio. Thanks, AJ9K, and thanks to everyone
who takes the time to call in and leave a voicemail.
Be sure to tune into the other shows and the
Dynamite Podcast Network this week, including
the console combat podcast, where hosts John and
Dean simulate battles between popular video game
characters. In yesterday's episode, they found
out who would win between Lancer Big Daddy from
Bioshock and Paladin Dance from Fallout. Over on
the Max Destruction Podcast, hosts Scotty and
Gilly pit your favorite action heroes from film
and television against each other. On Thursday,
the Macho Twins are learning who would win in a
fight between Dex from Predator Badlands and the
Mandalorian. And on the Sanjo World Podcast, host
Zachary Hepburn speculates on fights between fan
favorite anime and manga characters. In his next
episode, Zach is revealing who would win between
Shigio Kageyama, aka Mob, from Mob Psycho 100, and
Tatsumaki, the tornado of terror from One Punch
Man. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link
in our show notes to listen to all of the shows in the
Dynamite Podcast Network. But now that that's
done, on to the news. OK, so last week, DC unveiled
the official teaser trailer for the Supergirl
film, which is coming out June 26th next year. Of
course, we saw Supergirl at the very end of the
Superman movie that came earlier this summer. She
took crypto with her at the end of the movie, and now
she's going to have her own adventure. Crypto
kicks off this trailer, which is nice to see
because I was a huge fan of the character in the
Superman movie. What was not nice to see was how
filthy the living condition Supergirl lives in
is. Dog piss and alcohol all over the floor. Bitch,
you nasty. Yeah, I can smell it through the screen
almost. It's not pleasant, but that's her
character, right? She's kind of depressed. Yeah,
and the women of tomorrow graphic novel, she is
depressed, having lost crypto and having
witnessed the loss of it, which we partly see in
this trailer as the city that she lived in erects a
force field to protect the city. It doesn't fully
work. I think the ground shielding didn't protect
them from the radiation. But the line that Ruthie
asks when what was it like to lose everything in a
day and Supergirl responds with Krypton didn't
die in a day. The gods aren't that kind. It was
actually a line from the comic, and I really liked
the way that Millie Alcock delivered it here.
She's going to do a pretty good job as Supergirl. I
feel like especially this version of Supergirl,
who again is depressed and just kind of trying to
fight it back with alcoholism, essentially, when
she's celebrating her 23rd birthday and saying
it's going to be the best yet, although that's not a
hard bar to clear. You really felt it in her
performance. Yeah, I think she's going to do
better with the drama in the role, better than the
action, I think. Although, you know,
Kryptonians, they don't need to be buff. It's not
where they get their strength from. I think my
issue with Millie Alcock is just how she's selling
the action more than do I believe she's actually
doing this stuff? Oh, I'm not even going to
disagree with you. Like when she's going up
against the guys in that bar brawl with like the
axe, it wasn't really convincing that she was
going to be able to take them, especially since it
appeared they were able to match her strength
wise. And then at the very end, when she's like
pulling on that machine connected to a cable, I was
like, I don't think you quite sold that there.
Well, I think maybe that was a special effects
issue at the end there because centrifugal force
doesn't work that way. Like the string would have
to be taught going straight out in order for her to
maintain that swinging momentum. It was just
strange. Right. Yeah. Like physics wise, she
would just be pulling that piece of machinery
toward her and not in an arc. Exactly. I think it's
just hard for people to believe that this
character has the strength to swing a battle axe
with one arm when it looks like the actress is
struggling to do that herself. I'm guessing the
more physical stuff will be done with CGI. And of
course, there's always her powers like heat
vision, which we get to see in this trailer, along
with characters like Kram of the Yellow Hills, who
is the villain of this movie. And Lobo, played by
Jason Momoa. We don't get a good look at him. But
from what we do see, holy shit, he's going to nail
this. He was born to play this role. Yeah, it was
just a brief glimpse, but it looks spot on.
Regarding the look of the movie as a whole,
Jonathan, how do you feel about DC straight up
Xeroxing Marvel's Guardians of the Galaxy? And
they're not doing anything with it anymore. May as
well continue the franchise over at DC. I mean, I
was actually really surprised as to how much this
looked like Guardians of the Galaxy, considering
the fact it's not directed by James Gunn. It's
directed by Craig Gillespie, who also directed
films like I Tania and Corella, which I thought
were great movies. Well, it's just confusing me
because when I look at the Woman of Tomorrow comic,
it's a gorgeous looking book. It's very colorful,
very organic looking alien worlds, almost pastel
in its color palette. This is not that. These are
straight up reused Guardians of the Galaxy sets.
That wouldn't surprise me. I'm guessing the
director, maybe at the behest of James Gunn,
wanted to make it look more like a James Gunn movie
so that it looks like it fit more with the world that
the Superman movie established, as opposed to
looking more like the comic, which is very alien,
very organic, very colorful, like you mentioned.
Well, does that mean that every DCU project in live
action is going to have to look like James Gunn made
it? Like, is the upcoming Clayface movie going to
be like Slyther or something like that? Oh, dude, I
hope so. You just sold me on that. I guess I was the
wrong comparison. All in all, I think this was a
good teaser, not the best teaser I've ever seen by
any means. But it was enough, I think, to get people
excited. And honestly, I can't wait to see
people's reactions and theaters to this. Right
now, I only know my reaction and like my daughters.
They're excited. I'm excited. So when you say that
this teaser was enough to get people excited, are
you referring specifically to just you and your
daughters? Because I don't know anybody else
who's excited by this. Not even people on the
discord got excited by this. There was like zero
conversation about it. To be fair, I was in the
hospital the day this came out. So I would have been
talking about it a lot. Why are you giving us your
excuses? Because I was in pain in the ER. Again, why
are you giving us your excuses? Because I have them
to give. Well, you're out of the hospital within
like a day. So maybe you should be talking about
this on the discord. It's also been my daughter's
birthdays for the past two days. Oh, my God, so many
excuses. Yeah, bro. Yeah. You can't judge the
success of a trailer based on how many people are
talking about it in our own podcasts discord. I've
seen plenty of discussion online about it. Most of
it is good. Like I said, no one thinks this is the
greatest teaser trailer of all time, but it's
passable. All right. It's like a B minus. That's DC
for you. That's DC. I can't wait for the new
Avengers Doomsday teasers that are coming to
theaters. Apparently there's going to be four
different teasers and they're all going to be
attached in front of Avatar, Fire and Ash in
theaters. Are you serious? I did not know that. So
it looks like I'm going to go see Avatar four times
in theaters and hope I get to see each one. You're
going to have to go to like four different
theaters. I don't know, man. It's kind of
bullshit. That reeks of desperation, I must say.
For Avatar. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, that's what I meant.
Yeah. I'll just wait till it's all online. Well,
we'll see if that happens. Maybe it'll be recorded
by somebody on their phone or something. Who
knows? It better be. When is Avengers coming out
next December? OK, well, I imagine the teaser for
that is going to be super, super short compared to
this one. Yeah. Of course, Supergirl again, comes
out next summer on June 26th. So look forward to our
review of it then. Right, because it'll come out
after this podcast ends, but we're still going to
be reviewing new films when they come out. That's
right. But that does it for all the news for this
episode. So let's go ahead and move into our main
event where we find out who would win in a fight
between the Superman villain, Parasite and the
X-Men villain, Sauron. All right, Parasite
versus Sauron, these are both parasitic beings,
obviously. I mean, the guy's name is Parasite, but
in the sense that they absorb or siphon life energy
from their victims, it makes them stronger and
Sauron that manifests differently, I think, than
like someone like Rogue or Parasite, because
although Sauron can obtain the mutant powers of
people he siphons life energy from, largely, it
gives him the ability to like shoot out the energy
he absorbs in the form of like thermal energy,
which is pretty unique. Oh, like lasers? No, like
it looks more like electricity that comes from his
hands or fire from his mouth. Interesting. I did
not know that. Actually, I don't really know
anything about Sauron. He's a pretty dope
villain. Like out of all the characters from the
Savage Land that we could have gone with, I guess we
probably should have gone with Khazar or K-Zar,
however you want to pronounce it. But in the end,
I'm glad we went with Sauron, largely because what
defines the Savage Land are its dinosaurs, its
prehistoric life. And also, he's probably just
the biggest badass. That's like not human to come
out of there. Yeah, for a while we were considering
pitting Khazar or Khazar against either Warlord
or Commandy, which I think would have been cool.
That would have been cool. This is better. Yeah, if
we never did a Parasite duel in these 10 years, I
would have been really pissed off. We would have
failed as a podcast. Pretty much, pretty much. I
think there are many versions of Parasite that
have existed. So I'll be interested in seeing
which one you go with. It'll be Rudy Jones. He's the
primary one, I would say. Although, I'll go into
the backstory of a few others. OK. The movie
adaptation of this guy was very confusing, I have
to say. But also hella good, am I right? Before we
get into their backstories to explain the
methodology behind our duels, let's go to our
sentient duel simulator Alfred Jarvis 9000. AJ9K
tell our listeners how you go about determining a
winner in our duel matchups. Yes, of course, sir.
The way I determine a winner between the
contestants is by running 1000 Monte Carlo
simulations using the characters statistics. A
Monte Carlo simulation is a probabilistic model
used to determine outcomes through random
sampling. In this case, I randomize the
statistics along a normal distribution as a way to
simulate the many variables that can occur during
battle. The stat parameters are based on the
official Marvel power grid from which the DC
characters statistics are extrapolated.
Additional stat categories are included such as
range, damage potential, versatility and
perception in order to create a more detailed and
accurate simulation. The results of the 1000
simulations provide a percentage of wins for each
character. The contestant with the higher
percentage is declared the victor as they have a
higher probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither character should win
100% of the matches. The comic book stories have
shown that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman. So the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor a fan vote is tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks, AJ9K.
Before we run the simulations, though, we like to
break down each character's histories and
abilities before improvising a scenario on how we
imagine one of the 1000 simulations would play out
beat for beat. And I believe it's my turn to go first
with the Marvel character backstory. So let me
tell you all about Sauron. Millions of years ago,
in the era of dinosaurs and the supercontinent
Pangea, an alien race called the New Wally
constructed a refuge for Earth's prehistoric
life in what is now Antarctica. When an asteroid
impact wiped out most of dinosaur life, this
preserve remained protected, allowing its
ancient species to survive unchanged. Over time,
shifting geological land masses and glaciation
formed an enormous crater that concealed what
came to be known as the Savageland. Spanning 350
square miles, its sheer icy walls isolated the
tropical basin from the frozen continent around
it, hiding the region for millennia, except
through secret tunnels, though pockets of early
man did stumble upon the Savageland, becoming its
native inhabitants. In modern times, Carl Lycos
was born the son of an explorer and spent his early
youth accompanying his father on expeditions. As
a teenager, he joined his father on a journey to
Tierra del Fuego, an archipelago at South
America's southernmost tip. There, they
assisted a wealthy client, Dr. Anderson and his
daughter, Tanya. During his expedition, Tanya
wandered into a cave and was attacked by mutant
pterodactyls that originated from the
prehistoric Savageland. Carl intervened,
driving the creatures off with his walking stick,
but in the struggle, he was bitten. Dr. Anderson
saved Carl's life, but the wound left him changed.
During his recovery, Carl discovered that he
could drain the life force of living beings
through touch, accidentally killing his dog. The
need for this life energy became persistent, and
in secret, he found himself periodically
compelled to extract it from animals to survive.
After Carl's father died shortly after the
expedition, Dr. Anderson took him into his home as
thanks for saving Tanya. Over the years, Carl and
Tanya grew close, but her father forbade a
relationship due to Carl's lack of wealth,
determined to win his approval. Carl pursued
medical training and became a physician,
geneticist and hypnotherapist. He treated
patients with hypnosis while secretly siphoning
their energy, rationalizing that he took only
enough to weaken, never to kill. During this
period, he collaborated with Professor Charles
Xavier, who became aware of Carl's condition, but
kept his secret. When Havoc was nearly killed
after losing control of his powers in a battle with
sentinels, the X-Men brought him to Carl's
Manhattan practice, believing him trustworthy
due to Xavier's association. You can learn more
about Havoc and the X-Men in their respective
duels against the Ray and the Titans. While
treating Havoc, Carl siphoned part of his life
force, but absorbing mutant energy triggered an
unprecedented transformation. He mutated into a
half humanoid pterodactyl with human
intelligence and powerful hypnotic abilities.
Shocked, he attacked the X-Men before escaping to
Dr. Anderson's home in an attempt to plead for
Tanya's hand in marriage. However, Tanya and her
father recognized Carl for the monster he had
become, forcing him to flee. Carl returned to
Tierra de Fuego, where horrified by his actions,
he attempted to starve himself to death. However,
Tanya pursued him, arriving with the X-Men close
behind. Carl felt the pull to drain Tanya's life
energy, but instead ran, falling over a cliff,
unable to locate him. Tanya and the X-Men presumed
Carl dead. However, he survived unconscious on a
ledge below and eventually wandered through
subterranean passages into the Savage Land.
There, he lived in human form by feeding only on
lesser animals, keeping his Sauron persona at
bay. He became an ally to the Jungle Lord, Khazar,
and provided medical care to his companions for
many months. When the X-Men later became stranded
in the Savage Land, the presence of mutant life
energy overwhelmed him, and he preyed on the team.
After absorbing Storm's energy, he reverted into
Sauron again, though he soon returned to human
form. After the X-Men departed, Magneto took an
interest in the Savage Land and began
experimenting on local inhabitants, creating a
mutated army to help him control the region.
However, his campaign was stopped by Khazar.
Tanya eventually learned Carl had survived the
fall and traveled to the Savage Land with
Archangel and Spider-Man. They found him, but the
Savage Land mutates captured them and used one of
Magneto's genetic transformers to mutate
Archangel, Spider-Man, and Tanya into
animalistic forms. When the machine was
destroyed, Carl drained their altered life
energies to restore them. The process worked, but
he involuntarily transformed into Sauron again
and joined the mutates in opposing the X-Men. The
X-Men defeated them and returned Carl to the
United States, where Professor Xavier appeared
to cure him. Carl and Tanya reunited, hoping to
build a normal life. The attempt ended when the
mutant Toad abducted Carl and Tanya in order to
recruit Sauron into his new Brotherhood of Evil
Mutants, whom you've learned more about in their
duel against the Flash Rogues. Toad forced Carl to
drain Tanya's life energy, killing her and
transforming Carl into Sauron once more.
Enraged, Sauron joined the Brotherhood and
helped them attack X-Force, Cable then shot
Sauron and discarded his body, though he
eventually recovered. He later battled
X-Factor, marking the beginning of several
renewed clashes with the X-Men. You can learn more
about Toad in his duel against the Trickster and
more about X-Force and X-Factor in their
respective duels against the Outsiders and the
Freedom Fighters. Sauron returned to the Savage
Land and took leadership of the Mutates. In one
effort to increase his power, he had them kidnap
Havoc, hoping to use his energy to sustain
himself. When Cyclops, Phoenix, and Polaris
attempted a rescue, Sauron placed both Summers
Brothers in an energy transfer device. The
combined energies mutated him further,
enlarging him and increasing his strength.
Phoenix confronted Carl on the psychic Astral
Plane, where his human consciousness seized
control and cast his Sauron persona into an
internal abyss. As a result, Sauron's physical
form became trapped in a feral, non-sentient
state. Sauron later recovered fragments of his
human mind and used this clarity to escape the
Savage Land by stowing away Ancazar's transport
to New York. He sought out the X-Men again, but was
defeated and turned over to Shield. Eventually,
he was incarcerated within the Weapon X program,
subjected to their experimentation, and forced
to capture and recruit other mutants, though the
program eventually collapsed. Carl was then held
in the superhuman prison called the Raft, where he
escaped during a jailbreak, prompting the
Avengers to pursue him back to the Savage Land.
After briefly holding the New Avengers team
hostage alongside the mutates, Sauron was shot in
the head by Black Widow. He survived by having
previously absorbed Wolverine's healing
factor. During the Skrull's secret invasion of
Earth and their infiltration of the Savage Land,
Sauron fought the Skrulls alongside Khazar, his
wife Shanna, their pet Sabertooth Tiger Zabu, and
the native tribes. Sauron later appeared at a
gathering of Wolverine's enemies, hosted by
Sabertooth, where Wolverine fought and defeated
the assembled villains. Sauron then joined the
Hellfire Club's new school, the Hellfire
Academy, as a staff member, serving as the
school's science instructor. Sauron eventually
partnered with Dr. Vincent Stegron, a former
Shield scientist who experimented with dinosaur
DNA recovered from the Savage Land. Together,
they plan to transform humanity into dinosaurs,
battling Spiderman and students from the Jean
Grey School. Their alliance crumbled due to
jealousy over their infatuation with the student
Shark Girl, leading to an internal conflict that
caused their powers to cancel out, petrifying
both. Later, Carl resumed laboratory work to
enhance control over his transformations. Now
able to store mutant energy, he transformed into
Sauron at will and confronted the Scarlet Spider,
a clone of Spiderman before being defeated and
restrained for authorities. However, he escaped
and maintained a lab in Staten Island, helping
defend it against Null, a dark primordial deity
you can learn more about in his duel with White
Lantern. Joining his fellow mutants on the
Sentient Island nation of Krakowa, Carl then
joined the team X-Men Green, which took an
environmentalist stance, fighting on behalf of
planet Earth. After the fall of Krakowa, Carl
returned to the Savage Land, where he was later
imprisoned by Khazar. And that's his backstory.
Powers-wise, Sauron is a mutate with the ability
to drain life energy or any thermal energy source
directed at him through touch contact.
Initially, the energy would involuntarily
transform Carl into a pterodactyl form, though
through his medical and genetics expertise, he
developed the ability to transform at will by
storing the energy in his cells. With his
pterodactyl physiology, he gains enhanced
strength, able to lift around 10 tons,
durability, and flight. He has a beak full of sharp
teeth along with talons on his hands and feet.
Siphoning a victim's life energy leaves them
feeling drained, and Sauron can expel excess
energy from his mouth via fire breathing or energy
emissions through his hands. With his eyes,
Sauron can hypnotize victims to induce
hallucinations. When he drains mutants, he
absorbs their mutant powers temporarily, though
to a lesser extent than rogue. If he runs out of
energy, he will revert back to his human form. The
extent of his intelligence while in pterodactyl
mode varies. He typically retains his intellect
as Sauron Okay, so he is a little bit more going for
him than I initially thought. Good. I also forgot
that he had a human form. I thought he was just full
pterodactyl all the time. Nope. Initially, he was
supposed to be like a bat creature, but they
couldn't get that past the comics code authority
because that would have been too vampire like. So
the writers turned him into a pterodactyl, which
in turn influenced the entire savage land to be a
prehistoric refuge. Interesting. Well, that
sounds like it would have been too close to Morbius
anyway. Right, exactly. Well, now that we've
heard about Sauron, let's get to the character
everyone's here for. Parasite. The earliest
individual to bear the name Parasite was Raymond
Maxwell Jensen, a laborer whose exposure to
radioactive material at a research facility
mutated his body into a parasitic organism
capable of absorbing life energy, memories, and
powers through physical contact. Jensen
repeatedly confronted Superman, draining
portions of Kryptonian power before his body
destabilized and disintegrated. Though
believed destroyed multiple times, Jensen's
cells repeatedly reconstituted, establishing
that a human body could persist as a living energy
absorbing entity. Years later, a new incarnation
emerged in Rudolph Rudy Jones, a janitor employed
at the Pittsburgh branch of Star Labs. Believing
valuable materials were hidden within secured
waste containers, Rudy forced one open and was
exposed to experimental radiation. The accident
transformed him into a bald, green-skinned
mutant whose body could no longer sustain itself
naturally. Rudy discovered that he had to drain
life energy directly from other beings in order to
survive, leaving victims as burned-out
skeletons. Unlike Jensen, Rudy's hunger was
constant and unavoidable, and without feeding,
his body rapidly deteriorated. Rudy fled
confinement and became known as Parasite,
quickly drawing the attention of Superman after
draining multiple victims. When Parasite made
contact with Superman, he absorbed Kryptonian
energy on a massive scale, gaining superhuman
strength, durability, and heightened
intelligence. As the stolen energy dissipated,
Parasite weakened again, driving him to
repeatedly seek out Superman as his most potent
source of sustenance. Parasite's earliest
confrontations with Superman were erratic and
driven by immediate hunger. He was repeatedly
captured and incarcerated, only to escape as his
absorption abilities weakened power systems and
guards alike. Attempts to stabilize or cure his
condition failed, instead altering his
physiology. Medical interventions changed his
skin color from green to purple, and expanded his
absorption capabilities to include non-living
energy sources such as electricity and heat.
During a volatile standoff involving Firestorm,
Parasite was deployed despite objections from
those overseeing the operation. Once released,
he immediately lost control, feeding
indiscriminately and endangering multiple
combatants. When he attacked Firestorm
directly, the disparity in power left Parasite
severely injured and near death, though subdued,
Parasite later exhibited further psychological
changes. Parasite's fixation on Superman
intensified during a crisis in which Superman
struggled to contain an overload of solar energy.
The confrontation carried both beyond Earth,
where Superman released a massive burst of heat
vision. Parasite absorbed the blast entirely,
triggering a violent mutation that increased his
size and strength. In this state, he could drain
inertia from moving objects and siphon energy
through mental contact, making telepathic
attacks ineffective. The transformation also
increased his metabolic demands, forcing more
frequent feeding. While imprisoned afterward,
Parasite absorbed a scientist tending to him,
though he was not consumed completely, and
instead the mind of Dr. Torval Freeman remained
within Parasite, significantly increasing his
intelligence. From that point forward, Parasite
employed more calculated tactics, relying less
on uncontrolled rampage and more on planning and
deception. Parasite later aligned himself with
other adversaries targeting Superman,
repeatedly testing how his absorption
interacted with altered forms of Kryptonian
power. In one encounter, Superman's unstable
energy nearly killed Parasite. In another,
Parasite attempted to feed on Supergirl and was
defeated. These encounters informed Parasite's
subsequent tactics and feeding strategies. A
significant change occurred when Parasite was
contracted to drain excess electromagnetic
energy from an electrical being known as Strange
Visitor. Exposure to this energy altered
Parasite permanently, allowing him to retain
absorbed intellects and hold stolen power for
extended periods. Later, he absorbed a
shapeshifter, getting the ability to replicate
victims perfectly at the genetic level,
including voice, appearance, and biological
traits. With these abilities, Parasite shifted
tactics. He stalked Lois Lane and Jimmy Olsen,
seeking leverage over Superman rather than
immediate power. By posing as an elderly civilian
and engineering brief physical contact with
Lois, Parasite confirmed Superman's secret
identity. He abducted Lois and replaced her,
maintaining the impersonation through repeated
contact. During this period, Parasite provoked
confrontations with Clark Kent and later struck
Superman while still disguised as Lois,
revealing the deception. The scheme ended during
a physical assault on Superman. Over time,
Parasite had unknowingly absorbed Kryptonite
radiation present in Superman's system. The
accumulated poisoning overwhelmed him, made
flights, paralyzing, and killing him before he
could disclose Lois' location. Superman later
recovered Lois from Parasite's hideout. Despite
his apparent death, Parasite later resurfaced in
St. Rock, Louisiana. There, he used his abilities
to temporarily drain other villains of their
powers in exchange for payment, allowing them to
evade detection. Though his appearance and
speech differed noticeably from earlier
encounters, he was confirmed to be Rudy Jones,
having regenerated from his apparent death.
After the Flashpoint event reset continuity, a
new Parasite emerged in the form of Joshua Michael
Allen, a courier living in Metropolis. Allen's
transformation began when he attacked a
Parasitic creature during a battle,
electrocuting both it and himself. Though he
survived, his body deteriorated rapidly. While
undergoing examination at Star Labs, an
explosion killed the attending scientists and
transformed Allen into a skeletal, hairless
organism that drained life energy
uncontrollably. Unable to endure the constant
hunger, Allen attempted suicide, but Superman
intervened. Contact with Superman temporarily
relieved his pain, initiating an obsession with
metahuman energy. Allen was imprisoned and later
aligned with criminal groups to gain access to
stronger power sources. His abilities evolved,
allowing power replication with minimal contact
and size increase, proportional to absorbed
energy. Rudolph Rudy Jones later reappeared as
Parasite in this continuity, demonstrating
greater caution than in earlier incarnations and
refusing to absorb energies he believed would
destroy him. He was forcibly recruited into
suicide squad operations and deployed on a
mission to capture the new Swamp Thing, during
which he fed on the green and was violently purged
of the stolen energy, leaving him mutilated and
abandoned. Jones later returned under
supervision, equipped with a device that
regulated his hunger and allowed limited
employment. He assisted Superman during major
threats and was seemingly killed while fighting
Doomsday, surviving by absorbing residual
energy. His most unstable mutation allowed him to
divide into autonomous duplicates capable of
infecting other beings, increasing his threat
level while also accelerating his physical
collapse. And that's Parasites. Powers-wise,
Parasite absorbs life energy, memories, skills,
and superhuman abilities through physical
contact and can train non-living energy sources
such as electricity, heat, and solar radiation.
Absorbed power temporarily enhances his
strength, durability, size, and intellect
before dissipating, requiring continual
feeding. He can perfectly mimic victims down to
their DNA and regenerate. Later incarnations
could also divide into duplicates, though he
inherits the weakness of those he drains,
including vulnerability to kryptonite when
absorbing kryptonian energy and excessive
absorption destabilizes his body. That's
Parasite. Why didn't I know that he has
shapeshifting abilities? He didn't always have
them. He only attained them because he absorbed a
shapeshifter for a time. But does he consistently
have shapeshifting abilities now? Maybe. Okay,
fucking dumb. It is unique that he's actually one
of the few energy absorbers that can shapeshift.
Like, Rogue can't do that. Well, no, his whole body
is just weird, though. He's almost like Clayface
in a way in a few iterations where he's just like
this amorphous blob almost. Can you describe the
version you're going with for this match a little
bit better? Yeah, sure. I mean, he's going to start
off in like a normal humanoid-ish size and
physique, but of course purple in color. Okay. All
right, that works for me. I don't think we've ever
put two energy absorbers against each other. Like
the most recent match we did was with Sebastian
Shaw, but that was against Mandel Savage, and of
course we've done Rogue and Superboy. So I have no
idea how this is going to end, but let's find out.
Did we think this battle through enough? Like,
they're both energy absorbers. What are they
going to absorb from each other? The ability to
absorb energy? It's like pooping back and forth
forever. I don't know if you like it. Podcast
Network presents Console Combat, where video
game legends brawl every Monday. Dynamic Duel,
where comic book titans smash every Tuesday. Max
Destruction, where TV and action heroes battle
every Wednesday. And Sendro World, where anime
champions clash every Thursday. Join us as we
speculate on the matches and armed with the power
of mathematical simulations, discover who will
emerge victorious. Visit DynamicPodcast.com
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
All right guys, the clock is ticking. The holidays
are just weeks away, and if you still haven't
finished your shopping, now's the time to act. So
head to OldGlory.com, where you'll find
officially licensed Marvel and DC shirts,
hoodies, and gear. Perfect for every fan on your
list. They ship fast, but time's running out to get
your gifts before the holidays hit. So go now and
use the promo code Duel at checkout to save 15% off
your entire order. That's D-U-E-L at
OldGlory.com, because even superheroes can't
stop the holiday countdown. Well now that we've
got the characters, histories, and abilities out
of the way, let's speculate on how one of the 1000
simulated matches will go. The winners
determined by simulations, not the speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how this fight could play
out. AG9K, what are the rules of our speculation?
Well I should say there are no rules, other than the
characters have no prior knowledge of the other
going into the fight. All they are aware of
starting out is that the other character is a
threat that needs to be eliminated. For the
speculation, the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the match
itself, as no environmental statistics are
considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. Alright
then, let's get into it. Parasite and Sauron meet
on the battlefield? Who goes first? I'm actually
guessing Parasite might go first, because at his
base level, he's probably not as intelligent or as
calculating as Sauron is. Basically, Parasite,
he's just gonna be hungry, so he is going to lunge
for Sauron, grabbing one of his wings, and
draining his life energy, as well as his
intellect. You think that Parasite can cover that
distance of 50 meters between them before Sauron
takes to the sky? I don't think that's gonna
happen. Parasite's not gonna be able to touch
Sauron, and while Sauron's looking down on
Parasite from the air, he's gonna use his gaze to
hypnotize Parasite into a trance that keeps him
still. And with Parasite just standing there,
Sauron's gonna land down behind him and grab his
skull with both hands and just drain his life
energy. Well, I mean, Sauron's physical contact
would actually allow Parasite to drain him as
well, though. And this match is over. They just
both drain each other to death forever,
apparently. Well, I mean, I imagine there would be
some kind of energy feedback loop that would
probably cause both of them to overload and be
violently repelled from each other, like an
explosive force. So now Parasite is like 15 feet
tall, inject with a huge mouth of razor sharp teeth
and wings. That doesn't sound right to me. I don't
actually think Parasite would gain any benefit
from absorption if that energy is just going back
and forth between him and Sauron. My guess is that
they wouldn't overload by touching each other,
because where would that excess energy come from?
Like, they're absorbers, they're not
generators. I think that it would actually be a net
energy gain for each side, like nothing would
happen. So absorption alone probably wouldn't be
a factor in this match. They'd have to resort to
other abilities. But I mean, Parasite gets larger
by absorbing any energy. Like maybe he wouldn't
get the wings or any of Sauron's unique abilities,
but the energy moving through him, I think, would
make him smarter and stronger. What? Why? Like,
you don't get any energy that Parasite absorbs
would be taken from him via Sauron's absorption.
Okay. Okay. So how would Sauron defeat Parasite
then? Easy. Sauron rips Parasite's face off with
his claws, obviously. Okay. So you mean he
physically touches him? Awesome. With each
slash, Parasite is just going to get stronger. But
Sauron would also get stronger with each slash
two. You know what, we got to find a way for them to
actually absorb each other. That's the only way
this is going to work. But we'll say that the one who
is absorbing is the one who initiated the contact.
So they can't touch each other. The one who's doing
the strike is the one that absorbs. Does that make
sense? How about that? So we'll go back to the
initial narrative where Sauron takes to the air
hypnotizes Parasite into submission and then
lands behind him and then drains him with his
claws. So this is going to leave Parasite weakened
because he's not going to be absorbing from
Sauron's touch. And then Sauron is just going to
fry Parasite to a crisp with his flame breath,
finishing him off. Okay. So Parasite will just
absorb the thermal energy from the flame. And
that's going to restore him probably beyond what
he started out as because I'm going to say Sauron
emitted much more energy than he drained. What? So
now Parasite is, we'll say he's like eight foot
jacked monster who uses his longer reach to grab
Sauron by the wrists, draining his energy because
he's the one who initiated the contact while also
spreading Sauron's arms apart until they pop from
the sockets. All right. But while Parasite is
holding Sauron's arms out, he's going to kick his
legs forward and snatch Parasite by the chest with
his talons. And he's going to start draining back
the energy that Parasite stole from him. That's
going to cause Parasite to let go of Sauron's
wrists. So Parasite loses energy. He shrinks down
in withers. He's sees what the game is here. He's
going to put some distance between them. So he's
going to fly like 50, 100 yards away. And he's just
going to start tearing up the environment below
him, like slashing out the ground, tearing it up
into like small chunks of earth. You know, he's
could lift 10 tons. He's strong enough, but he's
going to pick up some of these chunks and then fly
into the air and then just start dropping and
pelting Parasite with the stones, basically
stoning him to death because he knows he has to keep
his distance and Parasite can't do anything Okay,
except in the brief moment Parasite held Sauron,
he caught glimpses of some of Sauron's memories,
particularly of Tanya. So with the last amount of
his energy, Parasite is going to transform it to
her. And that's going to trick Sauron's
animalistic brain and prevent him from attacking
her with the stones. And when Sauron flies down to
meet her, that's when Parasite is just going to
grab him by the throat and drain him. And he's going
to gain wings in the process. So he flies up to the
sky holding Sauron by the neck. And when Sauron
becomes so drained that he reverts back to human
form, that's when Parasite is going to drop him,
causing Carl to fall to his death. Match over. That
was a pretty solid move. But I'm going to say that
right before turning back into Carl, Sauron with
the last of his strength just rips out Parasites
throughout with his beak while they're flying in
the air. So Parasite, you know, he's in pain. He
drops Sauron who glides safely to the ground, but
Parasite crashes down and then bleeds out. Wait,
so you're saying that Sauron did that with the last
of his energy? So he still reverts to human form and
still fell when Parasite let go? I'll allow this. I
didn't mean it was like the last last of his energy.
I mean, he still had some in the tank, you know, he
was running on fumes, basically. But he could
still do it. Parasite could use some of his stored
energy to actually regenerate. You know, he's
come back from death that way several times. Yep.
But the key phrase there of what you just said is
that he died, meaning Sauron wins, meaning match
over. No, because I mean, what really happened is
that he dropped Carl. So, well, we'll leave the
match there. This was a tricky one. Either
Parasite absorbed so much of Sauron's energy
while flying up in the air that he causes Sauron to
revert back to Carl and then drop some down to the
ground, or Sauron, before reverting back into
human, rips out Parasite's throat and Parasite
dies that way. Not likely. We'll go ahead and input
the character stats, run the simulations, and
come back with a winner. AJ9K hit it. Inputting
data, running calculations, processing
results, simulations complete. All right, whose
idea was this matchup? Was it yours, Jonathan?
Because I feel like it was one of yours. It may have
been mine, and I think I'm realizing why now we kept
pushing this match off. This was not easy
considering Parasite's stats are so fluid and
variable. Yeah, really, Parasite is only as good
as the character he's going up against. When he
goes up against huge powerhouses like Superman,
his stats are off the charts. But when he's going up
against someone like mid-level, I would describe
Sauron as, you know, Parasite stats are
mid-level. That being said, you can never know at
what given time what Parasite's stats are,
because it's all based on how much energy he's
absorbed from his opponent. Basically, what
we've done energy absorbers in the past, like
Rogue or Sebastian Shaw, will average their stats
between their base level and their potential. So
that's what we did here. Now, Parasite has some
pretty impressive feats in the comics, but
considering that Sauron is not as powerful, like
you mentioned, as Superman or someone even like
Firestorm, and on top of that, basically has the
same abilities as Parasite in terms of
absorption, this didn't really go in my favor, I
feel like. Well, Parasite really had one main
thing going for him over Sauron, and I believe that
was durability. Yeah, base level durability for
Parasite is fairly high. But Sauron, you know, he
had the intellect thing going for him. He had the
versatility because not only can he, you know,
slash you with his talons, burn you with his
fireballs or shoot you with energy or hypnotize
you, he has like all this shit going for him outside
of just the power of absorption. Whereas Parasite
doesn't, he has to actually absorb the ability
before he has it. So with all that said, Jonathan,
who do you think is winning this match? Well, let's
see, I'm hopeful. Just as our Instagram followers
are, 62% of them voted in favor of Parasite in the
poll that we put up on Instagram. Well, I think a lot
of those poll takers are probably considering the
fact that Parasite is a Superman villain, so
they're putting him at Superman levels without
actually considering exactly how his powers work
in any singular matchup. But let's see if I'm
right. AJ9K, the results please. Here you are,
sir. Alright, the winner between Parasite and
Sauron is Sauron. There's only one Lord of the
Rings and he does not share power, not even with
Parasite. Because out of the 1000 matches that
they fought, Sauron won a whopping 662, damn,
whereas Parasite only won 338, so 66.2% over
33.8%. I'm not surprised by this, I'm hurt for
sure, but not surprised. Although I feel like a lot
of people will be. Yeah, well, really Jonathan,
what you needed to do was have Parasite go up in a
match with Superman and drain all of his energy and
then go into this match with Sauron where he would
have just wiped the floor with the dinosaur. But
since that is not really something that we do in
this podcast, yeah, Parasite just basically ate
ass. Did you say he ate ass? Or ate shit? That's what
I meant to say. Ew, so you're saying Parasite ate
Sauron's ass? Oh my god, get over it, you're so
obsessed with this, just move on. I already know
you're running visuals in your head and
everything. Well, let's leave it on that note.
That'll do it for this duel. AJ9K, help close this
out. Thanks for listening to Dynamic Duel. Visit
the show's website at dynamicduel.com and follow
us on Instagram at Dynamic Duel podcast. Don't
forget to listen to the other shows in the Dynamite
podcast network, including Max Destruction,
Senjo World, and Console Combat. In our next
episode, dropping just two days before
Christmas, we are pitting the legion of super pets
against the pet Avengers. That's right, it's
going to be seven pet animal characters against
seven pet animal characters. It should be a fun,
crazy time. So join us for that holiday episode
next week. I want to give a big thanks to our
executive producers, John Strausky, Zachary
Hepburn, Nathaniel Wagner, B. Viayetan, Austin
Wazalowski, AJ Dunkerly, Nick Obanto, Scott
Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Spees, Dean Maleski,
Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, and Paul Graves for
helping make this podcast possible. We'll talk to
you guys next week. Up, up, and away! True
believers?