This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi, welcome to
the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Johnny DC and I'm his twin
brother Marvelous Joe. And in this episode we are
doing another spooktober duel, this time pitting
the dark sorcerers of Felix Faust and Baron Mordo
against each other. Yeah, basically my wife told
me that if Marvel doesn't fucking win one, then
she's gonna divorce me. So there's a lot writing on
this one. Literally she said like in the last
episode she was like, I'm sick of this shit. So
we're really writing on this one guys. Baron
Mordo, I think has a good chance of winning this. I
don't think that's right. I think DC is gonna get
another win. I think you're fucked. I think you're
a fuck. I think that's a compliment. I'm not 100%
though. But we're gonna run the stats and figure
out who's gonna win between those two characters
later on in the episode. Before that we're gonna
break down the comic book movie news of which there
was quite a bit because we had New York Comic Con
this past week. So we got a Wonder Man official
trailer, a Bat Fam official trailer. We learned
that Marvin Crandon Jones III is going to play
Tombstone in Spider-Man Brand New Day. And we
learned that Batman Nightfall animated films are
in the works. As always we list our segment times in
our episode description so feel free to check out
the show notes if you want to skip ahead to a
particular topic. Our artificially intelligent
dual simulator AJ9K has a quick message for our
listeners so listen up. Thanks AJ9K and thanks to
everyone who supports the podcast. Be sure to tune
into the other shows on the Dynamics Podcast
Network this week including the console combat
podcast where hosts John and Dean simulate
battles between popular video game characters.
And yesterday's episode they celebrated their
100th episode with a special Colin show. I
personally was not able to call in at the time they
were live streaming but I did send a voice note in.
Super proud of those guys for making 100 episodes.
It's not easy to do for a podcast. So be sure to tune
into that. It's a huge deal. Over on the Max
Destruction Podcast hosts Scotty and Gilly pay
your favor action heroes from film and television
against each other. On Wednesday they're going to
find out who would win between Hugh Jackman's
Wolverine and the Creeper from Jeepers Creepers.
That'll be a fun one. On the Central World Podcast
hosts Zachary Hepburn speculates on fights
between fan favorite anime and manga characters.
In his next episode Zach is revealing who would win
between Whitebeard and Kanpachi both from One
Piece. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or click the
link in our show notes to listen to all of the shows
in the Dynamics Podcast Network. But with that out
of the way quick to the no prize. The no prize is an
award that Marvel used to give out to fans. Our
version the Dynamic Dual No Prize is a digital
award we post on Instagram for the person that we
feel gave the best answer to our question of the
week. Last week we asked you guys what do you think
has been the scariest moment in a Marvel or DC film
or TV series and we asked this because it's
Halloween season. Got a lot of great answers let's
run down our honorable mentions as well as the no
prize winner. Our first honorable mention goes to
Travis Herndon who said what's up dynamic dudes
Travis here shout out to Mabel Twin so my scariest
moment would have to be watching the Flash movie no
it's like not but my answer would have to be
Guardians of the Galaxy volume 3's Rockets
backstory just while it's not like a spooky scary
thing just seeing like what rocket and the rest of
the animals there had to go through with the
experimentation and the body modifications that
is kind of scary to watch especially if you're an
animal lover so that's my pick Rockets backstory.
Yeah that was really creepy in like a body horror
sense the experiments that the animals went
through under the high evolutionary was not just
like creepy to look at but it was also really
uncomfortable to think about in terms of like
animal torture you had Lila the otter who's like
arms were missing and then Tiefs who if I remember
correctly had wheels and then there was Floor the
rabbit who they gave like spider legs and like
removed its entire jaw it was truly horrifying
yeah great answer Travis our next honorable
mention goes to Mason Thompson who said what's up
y'all um I kind of had to think about this but once I
thought about it immediately the trench attack
from Aquaman oh my gosh seeing that it just gives
like jaw vibes or like 30 meters down like just all
of them surrounding them terrifying dude had me
butt clenched all right thanks peace I too was butt
clenched during that scene it was really well done
by horror master James Wan who directed Aquaman
I've been feeling the trench were put into that
movie specifically for that scene so that he could
exercise his horror talent in the movie I haven't
seen the movie too many times but yeah that scene
does stick out to me I remember just seeing like the
entire swarm of trench like there were so many more
than you could possibly fathom down in those
depths and I was really like nervous for how
Aquaman was going to get out of that well even
before that when they're still on the boat and
they're climbing on board and like breaking
windows and stuff like that that was why great
answer our next honorable mention goes to Alex
Albro and by Dear Bangora who gave the same answer
and that is hey guys I know it's iconic but the
scariest moment in a Marvel movie for me honestly
is the blood rave and the first blade movie it's
just freaky to look at man especially for the time
you know it's just scary image odd way to start a
movie I'm not sure I was there for it kind of made me
freak out a little bit going into the first blade
movie you know I'm just out here trying to ice skate
uphill not take a literal blood bath thanks guys
bye dynamic doll I think the scariest moment has to
be the blood rave during blade I think that was
terrifying just to be put in that position and be
surrounded by vampires and when blood pouring
must be extremely devastating this is Badiere
thank you yeah I feel like the blood rave scene is
kind of like a pop culture touchstone like a lot of
people know about the blood rave scene probably
even if you haven't seen the blade movie I think but
I remember like seeing the movie in theaters when I
came out in 1998 and Jesus I was only like 12 years
old but I remember the guy at the club and like all of
a sudden stuff started dripping on him and he was as
confused as the audience was and then we realized
that it was blood and I just remember being like
holy shit like oh oh no no because it all started and
then it turns out literally every single other
person at that rave was a vampire like he was the
only human that was nuts I was like this is so
nightmarish like what a crazy concept for it to be
just raining blood on you and just you're totally
fucked like there's no way you're getting out of it
and then of course blade shows up and saves the day
but uh yeah it was it was pretty freaky on that first
watch and then on subsequent watches it kind of
became cool because you knew that blade was coming
and that you were about to get a great action scene
but yeah that first time was really unsettling
it's still my favorite scene from a blade movie and
it was like the first blade movie scene yeah they
just nailed it right out the gate for sure great
answer alex and by dear but the winner of this
week's no prize is Lorenzo Valdes who said I would
say that the scariest moment in a marvel or dc movie
is in the dark night when they're in mayor Garcia's
office and the imposter batman slams against the
window and I picked this moment because that's a
movie I've seen so many times and yet over and over
and over again the moment works as a jump scare for
me clon of forever and always bye bye I still
remember physically jolting out of my seat when
the imposter batman slammed against mayor
Garcia's window I was not expecting that it kind of
came out of nowhere it's like the ultimate jump
scare within a superhero film for sure I could even
concede that this is definitely the scariest
moment out of all the marvel and dc films I remember
jumping in my seat too and you know it's like unfair
because you're not expecting it because the dark
night is not a horror film I remember like not
appreciating it in the theaters when it happened I
was like I didn't sign up for this shit like what's
going on here is this a scary movie now am I gonna
have to expect this later on but no I thought I
thought it was a really effective moment in
selling the shock of the jokers actions and how he
is just chaos incarnate yeah you never quite knew
what he was gonna do and when he was gonna do it and
the video that was attached to the imposter batman
of the joker torturing him that was also pretty
terrifying yeah there are a lot of terrifying
joker moments in that film but that is the standout
one so great answer Lorenzo Valdes you win this
week's no prize if you're the listener want to shot
at winning your own no prize stay tuned to later on
in this episode when we'll be asking another
question of the week and now that that's done off to
the news all right this past week was new york city
comic con where we got a lot of marvel television
news they had an entire panel alongside the marvel
animation division we got some looks at daredevil
born again season two where we got to see a trailer
that also featured jessica jones although that
trailer wasn't featured publicly it was leaked
but we'll wait for that to be officially released
so that people could see it there was also news
about vision quest and x-men 97 and your friendly
neighborhood spider-man season two but the main
news that we got that was officially released was a
trailer for wonder man which is a television
series that's going to be debuting in january of
2026 its release date got pushed back a little bit
from its original december date and i gotta say i
knew that they were going to focus on simon
williams as an actor within this wonder man series
and that wonder man was basically a role that he was
going to play that's all fine you know simon
williams is one of the only superhero actors in
marvel comics and it is definitely a unique
approach and angle that we haven't really seen
before within these marvel shows and films that
being said my biggest takeaway from the wonder man
trailer was that this does not feel at all like a
superhero show and it seems intentionally to be
that way like they were trying to do something
completely different within the genre i don't
quite know if i like the idea or not just based on
this trailer i mean i'll say that the show looks
good for what it is i kind of like how meta it is how
this auteur film director is recreating the
wonder man popular television series from either
like the 70s or 80s i don't know it looks like flash
gordon to me which is pretty interesting but you
know the origin of wonder man from the comic books
is that he was kind of like a tony stark rival whose
business was driven into the ground he went to
prison for shady business dealings and then baron
zemo offered him a chance to get back at tony stark
by undergoing an experiment that turned his body
into ionic energy i mean we go into his backstory in
our captain adam versus wonder man dual episode
this looks completely removed from that now maybe
that whole backstory will kind of be loosely
adapted into the fictional backstory of the
wonder man character within the series that
they're adapting in this show and that would be
great but that's definitely not going to be the
origin story for yaya abdul matine the second's
character yeah it makes me wonder if we're
actually going to see yaya abdul matine as wonder
man and is he going to throw hands i'm not convinced
by this trailer i don't know if we'll see yaya in his
ionic form i'm sure we'll definitely see him in the
wonder man suit i'm assuming that at some point his
character will get superpowers that are similar
to wonder man's power set from the comic books and
then he'll be an actor who played the role of wonder
man who became a superhero during the filming
process and then goes on to fight evil after making
this movie i feel like it's not going to be that way
just because they anticipate the audience
expecting something like that and i think they
want to do something completely different with
this yeah they might pull like a she-hulk or
something where there is no big fight between good
versus evil in the show's climax and maybe subvert
it in some way but that wouldn't be satisfying just
like how the end to she-hulk wasn't satisfying i
hope they don't do that i hope this character
becomes an actual superhero and doesn't just play
one i love that ben kingsley is returning as trevor
slattery like that was one of my favorite parts of
this trailer just seeing him as that character
again his trevor slattery is great for sure i'm
wondering if simon williams gets the role of
wonder man in this movie then who is trevor gonna
play considering that he also auditions for the
same part i guess we'll find out when the show comes
out on january 27th in dc news we got the official
trailer for prime videos bat fam animated series
this is a spinoff of the holiday film they put out a
few years ago mary little batman which we reviewed
which i thought was great for the family after
watching this trailer i'm less enthused by the
whole approach they decided to take with this show
when i hear bat fam i think nightwing red hood robin
bat girl that whole cast of characters but based on
this trailer we're getting a pyrachonetic named
claire alfred's niece alicia a ghost of rossel
ghoul a geriatric man bat it's just fucking weird
the bat fam nobody asked for exactly exactly and
again i love the charming animation style the
character designs are actually pretty great
especially when it comes to like killer croc and
clay face and stuff like that but it's just so
different from what i was hoping they would do that
it's really hard to get excited about this show
well i mean one of the appeals of mary little batman
was seeing how that particular art style depicted
characters that you know and love like batman like
the joker it was all just part of the magic right and
yeah you're right seeing characters like clay
face and killer croc adapted in this style looks
like a whole lot of fun i also was really hoping to
see how they were going to take the characters that
were used to seeing the bat family and depicting
them in that art style too like i imagine that
nightwing would be like really buff and then like
they really focus on his glutes right and red hood
would be real like emo you know always having his
head down and stuff like that it would have been
cool to see in the style of animation absolutely
and so we have these characters in the trailer and
i'm just left wondering why like why would you take
a stable of characters that are beloved amongst
comic fans and just completely disregard it i'll
probably still end up watching this show because i
have prime and why not and i may actually find the
humor and storytelling charming but i can't
stress enough how much they dropped the ball and
how disappointed i am that this should have been
something very different yeah i mean you may end up
liking it but even if you do you're still gonna
wonder what could have been if they gave you more of
what you wanted all in all there's a lot of
questionable decisions for this show and with
wonder man so that brings us to our question of the
week regarding the wonder man and batfam series
trailers what the fuck did i just watch wrong
answers only i guess a good way to approach this
question is if you had to retitle these shows to be
more in line with your own personal thoughts on the
trailers what would they be called record your
answer at dynamic duel dot com by clicking on the
red microphone button in the bottom right corner
of the screen which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail your message could be up to 30 seconds
long and don't forget to leave your name in case we
include you on the podcast we'll pick our favorite
answer and award that person a dynamic duel no
prize that will post to instagram be sure to answer
before october 18th in other marvel news we
learned this past week according to deadline that
marvin jones the third aka crondon is going to play
the crime boss tombstone in the upcoming
spider-man brand new day film tombstone being a
spider-man villain a street level spider-man
villain one of the enforcers of the magea crime
family the character appeared in the spider-man
into the spider-verse film where he was actually
voiced by marvin jones the third so it'll be cool to
see him now play that role in live action i mean if
you could do it any differently from how he played
to bias wail in the black lightning tv series i'm
skeptical that's right yeah he did already play dc
villain who is very similar at least i guess an
attitude if not in power set i don't know what to
bias wail's powers are actually well he's a albino
gangster essentially a crime boss well that's
what tombstone is he's exactly you know gangster
okay all right well we'll see how this goes i'm sure
he'll take a somewhat different approach from his
role in black lightning but it's cool that he'll
have done both in marvel and dc live action villain
role when this film comes out the inclusion of
tombstone definitely reinforces the idea that
this is going to be a street level film which is very
interesting to me yeah it's gonna have tombstone
in it it's gonna have the punisher in it it's gonna
be a very different type of film than what we've
been getting from the spider-man franchise i
think it's gonna be more grounded maybe that'll be
pretty interesting to see execs have made some
comments that there are some like story tie-ins
from daredevil born against season two if you want
to learn more about tombstone go ahead and check
out our dual episode where we pit him against
blockbuster and hopefully we'll get to see what
the character looks like either in like set videos
or an upcoming trailer or something like that
again the movie is gonna come out in 2026 on july
31st in dc news my favorite news to come out of new
york comic con it was revealed that the batman
nightfall storyline is being put into production
as a multi-part animated film part one is coming
out next year in 2026 and it's going to focus on bane
really seeing batman's rogues gallery from
arkham asylum and batman's quest to capture all of
them nightfall is one of my favorite stories from
the comics it spanned multiple batman series
written by some of batman's best writers from
history including doug moanch chuck dixon ellen
granton denny o'neill and peter david of course it
includes the famous breaking of batman's back by
bane and the rise of asriel as a new armor-wearing
tech focused batman i'm sure we'll see asriel's
rise in part two but i can't wait to see the whole
storyline played out on screen i never thought we
would get an animated adaptation of that so it's
exciting to see them start to take a look at some of
the popular comic book story arcs and adapt those i
was actually surprised by this news because i
thought that james gunn was only going to start
featuring animated projects that tied into his
dcu projects like creature commandos that could
be the case for this for all we know this could be a
prequel of sorts or like a flashback-esque story a
prequel to the dcu version of batman possibly
interesting it would be a good way to get much
needed exposition and backstory out of the way
that way people could just jump right in with a live
action movie whenever that comes out i mean since
we've already seen batman get his back broken on
film in christopher nollens the dark knight rises
i'm sure there's no real need to retread that same
territory in live action so this approach may just
get that out of the way i am skeptical that this is
actually true it's interesting speculation
whether it is or isn't i'm still pumped for it
because again that's a fantastic storyline it's
the equivalent of the death of superman in my book
just a pivotal moment in batman's career yeah
where stakes actually meant something exactly
just how we didn't know if superman was going to
come back we didn't know when bruce wane was going
to return to the cowl we weren't told how many parts
the story was going to be told in but it's at least
two if they do three i'm here for it my body is ready
but then does it for all the news for this episode
let's go ahead and move on to the main event where we
find out who is going to win between the dc and
marvel sorcerer characters of phoenix foust and
baron mordo okay phoenix foust versus baron mordo
as i stated earlier in the episode these are two
dark sorcerer villainous characters within dc
baron mordo of course was played by chouatelle in
the dr strange films we haven't seen phoenix foust
in live action that i'm aware of but he has been
featured pretty frequently in animated works
yeah he had a really cool badass fight scene
against zetana in just asly dark i want to say the
film was right this is going to be kind of similar to
our dr fate versus dr strange dual episode i think
but considering that these characters are both
villains we're going to dabble more into the dark
magic side of things yeah i think it'll be pretty
fun to explain the methodology behind our duels
let's go to our sentient dual simulator elford
jarvis 9000 aj9k tell our listeners how you go
about determining a winner in our dual matchups
yes of course sir the way i determine a winner
between the contestants is by running 1000
montecarlo simulations using the characters
statistics a montecarlo simulation is a
probabilistic model used to determine outcomes
through random sampling in this case i randomize
the statistics along a normal distribution as a
way to simulate the many variables that can occur
during battle the stat parameters are based on the
official marvel power grid from which the dc
characters statistics are extrapolated
additional stat categories are included such as
range damage potential versatility and
perception in order to create a more detailed and
accurate simulation the results of the 1000
simulations provide a percentage of wins for each
character the contestant with the higher
percentage is declared the victor as they have a
higher probability to win any given battle in an
equitable pairing neither character should win
100 of the matches the comic book stories have
shown that there's even a way for batman to defeat
superman so the confidence rate of my method falls
in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material my
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias feats are not the whole
consideration nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner thanks aj and iak
before we run the simulations though we'd like to
break down each character's histories and
abilities before improvising a scenario on how we
imagine one of the 1000 simulations would play out
beat for beat i believe it's my turn to go first with
the marvel characters backstory so let me tell you
all about baron morto carl amadeus morto was born
in the transylvanian village of varfondra to
baron nicolai morto and baroness sarah crawler
his grandfather viscount hindrack crawler of
bavaria sought revenge against the allied powers
after world war two and attempted to steal
nicolai's emerging magical power through a spell
of transference when the spell failed crawler
ordered his daughter to marry nicolai so that
their child could serve as a conduit for the power
he craved sarah complied and nine months later
gave birth to carl raised in a cold household
carl's father was obsessed with restoring his
homeland to feudal glory while his mother
regarded her son merely as a pawn in her father's
schemes when crawler ordered sarah to kill her
husband she obeyed and fled with carl to bavaria
where crawler trained his grandson in black magic
after learning the truth of his father's death
carl swore vengeance on both his mother and
grandfather and vowed to rebuild a world ruled by
his own power as a young man morto traveled to tebet
to find the ancient one a powerful sorcerer said to
guard the secrets of true magic in the ancient ones
himalayan sanctuary morto's body aged slowly
under the effects of the mountain's mystical aura
though the ancient ones saw darkness in his new
pupil's heart he chose to teach him anyway hoping
to guide him toward wisdom while studying ancient
scrolls morto learned of the dread dor mamu the
ruler of the dark dimension against his master's
orders he contacted dor mamu finding himself to
the demon's influence morto returned to bavaria
sacrificing both his mother and grandfather to
dor mamu before continuing his studies under the
ancient one plotting to one day sacrifice him as
well you can learn more about dor mamu in his duel
against the demon trigon when another student
steven strange arrived seeking healing for his
injured hands morto viewed him as a rival upon
discovering morto's plot to kill their teacher
strange tried to warn the ancient one but morto
silenced him with a binding spell the ancient one
was aware of morto's treachery all along and freed
strange who accepted apprenticeship to stop
morto's schemes you can find out more about
morto's attempts to defeat strange in the ancient
one's temple morto's first attempts to defeat
strange included astral projection schemes and
hypnotic control of servants to poison the
ancient one strange continually foiled those
plans proving himself the superior sorcerer
morto lured strange into traps across europe
manipulated ectoplasmic warriors and even
imprisoned the ancient one but each student was
forced to leave the ancient one morto's first
attempt to kill strange was defeated seeking
greater power morto appealed to dor mamu He
simplified his abilities and sent him to destroy
Strange. Together they pursued Strange across
dimensions, but Dormammu turned on Mordo for
interfering in his duel with Strange and banished
him to the dimension of demons. Strange later
freed Mordo while rescuing other victims, and the
ancient one imprisoned him anew. Freed again
after the defeat of the entity called Zom, Dr.
Strange persuaded Mordo to help contain Zom's
scattered evil essence, convincing him to act as
the vessel for the dark power. Once empowered,
Mordo betrayed Strange, attacking him with
overwhelming might until Strange used the staff
of Polar Power to absorb his excess energy and
banish him. Mordo resurfaced, pretending to be
Dr. Strange during the Sorcerer Supreme's brief
loss of power, but Strange regained his strength
and exposed the deception. Obsessed with
uncovering ultimate magical truths, Mordo
pursued the time-traveling wizard C. Sneg to the
dawn of creation, witnessing the reconstruction
of the universe itself. The sight drove him
insane. Strange took him into his care, but Mordo
later escaped and renewed his pursuit of dark
power. When he robbed the San Gabriel Archives at
the Vatican, he attempted to unleash the Chaos
Demon by sacrificing 13 victims, including the
witch Jennifer Kale, but he was defeated by her and
Manthing, whom you can learn more about in his duel
with Swamp Thing. Mordo's lust for power often
drew him into the service of other dark entities.
He created the spectral being Azrael and sent him
to slay Dr. Strange, later manipulating Manthing
to do the same. During a battle that spanned time
itself, Mordo returned to the mid-20th century
and was ensnared by a plot involving Dormammu and
his ancestor, Crowler. Dormammu turned against
both Crowler and Mordo, destroying them before
Strange used their conflict to banish the demon
once more. Afterward, Mordo was recruited into
Mifisto's group called the Legion Accursed. You
can learn more about Mifisto in his duel against
Sandman. In time, Mordo's constant dealings with
infernal entities took their toll and he
developed terminal cancer. Desperate for a cure,
Mordo made simultaneous bargains with both
Mifisto and Satanish, promising each his soul.
When Mifisto and Satanish arrived to claim him,
their conflict threatened to consume all reality
until Strange exploited the demon's greed to
sever their hold on Mordo, freeing him though
leaving him spiritually weakened. Seeking
redemption, Mordo returned to Tibet, confessing
his sins to Dr. Strange and asked for forgiveness.
Strange granted it and Mordo died from cancer in
peace. He was subsequently pulled from the time
stream and recruited by the cosmic collector to
join the villainous offenders team alongside Red
Hulk, Tarix, and Tiger Shark. Mordo and the group
battled Strange and the defenders across time and
space before being returned to the exact moment
from which he had been taken. Years later, Mordo
resurfaced in South America, kidnapping a
politician to lure his daughter, the
Mune...Monee...Saint Kroy, so he could siphon
her life energy to sustain himself. Monee tricked
Mordo into thinking he had been cured and allowed
him to leave, deluded. Not long after, Mordo
appeared to die in Brazil, slain by Thor's
enchanted axe, but his body later vanished. Mordo
reemerged during the period when the Empirical, a
fanatical science cult, purged magic from Earth.
Having survived by pledging himself once more to
Dormammu, he attacked a weakened Dr. Strange in
New York, briefly overpowering him before
Strange was abducted by the villain Nightmare.
Mordo and Dormammu clashed again, and when
Dormammu attempted to destroy Strange, Mordo
added his power to his old foes, helping banish
Dormammu to Shumagorath's realm. Despite this
uneasy alliance, Mordo quickly turned on
Strange, and was defeated once more. When Hydra
seized control of the United States, a
dark-forced dome enclosed Manhattan. Baron
Mordo was appointed caretaker of the city and
occupied the Sanctum Sanctorum, where he
enslaved the Elder God Pooorg as his guardian. He
captured several heroes, including Daredevil,
Luke Cage, and Iron Fist, but lost control when Dr.
Strange, Spider Woman, Ben Uruk, and Kingpin
rallied against him and reclaimed the Sanctum.
Following these events, Mordo continued serving
Dormammu's race, the Valtines, as an enforcer. In
this role, he destroyed the demon Barashtak and
freed Strange's former apprentice, Casey
Kinmont, corrupting her with dark power and
sending her against her mentor. After Strange
restored Casey's soul, she banished Mordo back to
the Void where he remains, alive, scheming, and
eternally plotting vengeance against the
Sorcerer Supreme. And that is Baron Mordo's
backstory. Powers-wise, Baron Mordo has access
to a near-limitless number of spells and
abilities. Through magic, he can project mystic
energies as powerful bolts or protective
shields. He can read and cast thoughts, cast
illusions, and hypnotize. He can teleport and
fly. He can also turn invisible and intangible,
and project an incorporeal copy of himself called
his astral form. Mordo can transmute matter,
war-priality, and materialize objects. He has
limited time control abilities such as slowing,
freezing, and even traveling through time. Also,
he can invoke extra-dimensional deities for any
number of spells and often utilize his black
magic, including necromancy, the magic of the
dead. Baron Mordo is an expert in the occult and is a
skilled martial artist, having been trained by
Tibetan monks. He has occasionally carried or
manifested a dagger for ritual sacrifice. And
there you go. The whole time I was listening to that
backstory, I was like, Are you looking off my
sheet? Because there are a lot of similarities
between Baron Mordo and Felix Faust. It makes
sense, because Felix Faust is a total ripoff of
Baron Mordo. I'm sorry, what? Felix Faust came out
in 1962, my friend. Well, Baron Mordo came out in
1963. Exactly! Dammit! Let me get into Felix
Faust's backstory. Felix Faust was an ancient
sorcerer whose recorded history dates back to
around 5000 BC, when he rose within the African
Empire of Kor. There, the realm's ruler, King
Namo, served as both monarch and guardian of the
mystical Flame of Life, a source of
near-limitless magical energy. Obsessed with
seizing that power, Faust delved into forbidden
rites, mastered the dark art of black magic, and
summoned legions of shadow spirits to wage war
against Namo's kingdom. His sorcery poisoned the
skies and drained the land, but Namo absorbed the
Flame into himself, turning its power inward to
banish Faust's soul to another dimension. For
millennia, Faust's disembodied spirit endured
imprisonment, sustained only by its hatred and
hunger for lost magic. In the 1920s, an occultist
named Dekan Drake uncovered records of Faust's
confinement and sought to release him, believing
he would be rewarded with power. When Drake opened
the dimensional gate, Faust devoured his soul and
possessed his body. Though restored to life,
Faust's magic was greatly reduced, forcing him to
rely on familiars, grimoires, and packs with
demons to channel power. Determined to reclaim
his former strength, he spent decades hunting
cursed relics and manipulating occult
societies. Over time, he fathered two children,
Sebastian and Fauna, both born with traces of his
arcane lineage. In his relentless pursuit of
power, Faust later attempted to sacrifice
Sebastian's soul to the demon Nibiros, but the
ritual backfired and beowing his son with magical
abilities of his own. Faust sought to regain his
lost abilities by summoning and controlling the
demons three. Abnegazar, Wrath, and Gast,
ancient reality-warping entities imprisoned
beneath the earth. To gather the relics that bound
them, the red jar of Calythos, green bellow Uthul,
and silver wheel of Nyarlath, he magically
enslaved the Justice League to retrieve them.
Once freed, the demons turned on Faust, and
Aquaman destroyed the spell's control circle,
ending the attempt and sending Faust to prison.
Over time, Faust's reliance on infernal power
deepened. He repeatedly sold and repurchased his
soul, each deal eroding his power further. In
desperation, he attempted to deceive Miron,
ruler of Hell, by offering an innocent girl's soul
instead of his own. Miron sought through the trick
and condemned him to a dimension reserved for
magicians who abused the laws of magic. After
centuries of torment, Faust escaped back to
earth, his sanity and power both unstable. He
returned to prominence as an enemy of the Justice
League and as an ally of various villainous
factions, including the Injustice Gang and the
Seeker Society of Supervillains, serving as
their arcane specialist. During this period, his
strained relationship with his son Sebastian
escalated. When Sebastian joined the outsiders,
Faust sent demonic agents to capture him, and in
the ensuing conflict, he recovered two of the
demon 3's relics, but Halo and Looker destroyed
them before he could harness their power. You can
learn more about the outsiders in their duel
against X-Force. Faust's ambitions reached
their peak in a ritual known as the Black Baptism.
He assembled infernal covens across the globe to
siphon the life-horse of Earth's magicians into a
single rite that would reset all magic under his
control. Demon assassins abducted mystics
including Zatana and Deadman to power the
ceremony. The Justice League, aided by Blue Devil
and Sebastian Faust, disrupted the ritual. At its
height, Felix attempted to absorb the captured
souls, but Sebastian severed the conduit,
collapsing the spell. The backlash stripped
Faust of his stolen power and scattered his
followers, forcing him back into hiding. Years
later, Faust resurfaced posing as Dr. Fates,
attempting to deceive a long-aided man into
trading his soul to Niran in exchange for
resurrecting his wife. Ralph Dibney saw through
the ruse and reversed the trap, binding both Niran
and Faust inside the Tower of Fates. Faust
eventually escaped, but his reputation amongst
occult circles fell even lower. You can learn more
about elongated man in Our Elongated Man vs Medusa
Duel episode. Following his escape, he allied
with Professor Ivo, Solomon Grundy, and Dr.
Impossible, posing as Deadman to trick Red
Tornado into inhabiting a human body, while
stealing the android's original shell for
experimentation. Faust later joined Talia El
Ghul and Cheetah in an attempt to recruit Black
Alice into the Seeker Society of Supervillains.
When she refused, she turned his own power against
him, using it to resurrect her mother. During
Black Adam's quest to revive his wife Isis, Faust
interfered again, replacing Isis' bones with
those of Ralph Dibney to sabotage the
resurrection spell. He later revived the real
Isis himself and held her captive until she broke
free. You can learn more about Black Adam in his
duel against Apocalypse. Faust remained aligned
with the Seeker Society assisting in the creation
of the android known as Genocide by collecting the
mystical elements needed for her construction.
After the Flashpoint reset, Faust's history was
rewritten. He was reimagined as the son of Majika,
one of Earth's first sorcerers and an heir to a long
lineage of dark magicians. In the 1500s, he allied
with Vandal Savage and trained an apprentice
named Aurora, pursuing immortality through
forbidden magic. During this period, he
encountered time-traveling heroes Robin and
Superboy, who disrupted one of his rituals and
forced him to retreat. In the modern era, Faust
became obsessed with finding the books of magic, a
compendium set to contain all arcane knowledge.
To acquire the secrets of the damned sorcerer Nick
Necro, Faust sold his soul to a demon trading his
mortality for Necro's power. The pact granted him
vast new abilities but left his body pale and
corpse-like. Together with Nick Necro and Dr.
Mist, he sought to seize the books of magic from the
Justice League Dark. Their scheme was undone by
John Constantine and Faust was captured by Argus
and confined within their Black Room facility.
You can learn more about the Justice League Dark
and John Constantine and their respective duels
against the Midnight Suns and Brother Voodoo.
During the crime syndicate's invasion, Faust was
conscripted alongside Necro to construct a
magical weapon called the Thaumaton, designed to
harness and destroy divine energy. Working
beside Enchantress, Sargon the Sorcerer, Blue
Devil, and Zatana, Faust helped power the device
until the Justice League Dark sabotaged it in a
battle at Nanda Parbat, leaving him powerless
once more. Faust later reappeared among the
Occult Underworld when industrialist Henry
Bendix attempted to hire sorcerers to kill
Midnighter and Apollo. He declined the offer,
unwilling to serve others' agendas. His powers
gradually returned and his ghastly form faded.
The extra-dimensional entities known as the
Otherkind began consuming magical beings, Faust
was among their victims. Bound nearly mindless by
Zatana and Wonder Woman, he regained just enough
awareness to reveal a clue to the Sorcerer
Mordor's location, reverie trading again into
obscurity. That's Faust's backstory so far.
Powers-wise, Felix Faust is a master sorcerer
with expertise in soul magic, necromancy, and
infernal packs. His abilities include
spellcasting, energy projection, elemental
manipulation, illusion, telepathy,
teleportation, and summoning entities such as
the Demon's Three. He can bind, transfer, or
resurrect souls, create magical constructs, and
scry across great distances. Faust's power is
largely drawn from external sources, like
familiars, relics, grimoires, or demonic
patrons, due to the degradation of his natural
magic reserves. He is vulnerable to pure divine
magic and cannot safely channel it without a
medium. Though physically frail, he compensates
with defensive wards, decoys, escape spells, and
other occult resources. That's Felix Faust. What
a coward. Uh, it fucking works, kinda. Like Baron
Mordo, he doesn't have the greatest history of
success. That's the problem with villains and
their backstories. It just turns into a long
string of failures over time because the hero
always wins. Pfft, lame. But villains should not
be discounted, or at least Baron Mordo shouldn't
be. And especially Felix Faust. Mike Podcast
Network presents Console Combat, where video
game legends brawl every Monday. Dynamic Duel,
where comic book titans smash every Tuesday. Max
Destruction, where TV and action heroes battle
every Wednesday. And Cendro World, where anime
champions clash every Thursday. Join us as we
speculate on the matches and armed with the power
of mathematical simulations discover who will
emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com,
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
But now that we've got their histories and
abilities out of the way, let's speculate on how
one of the 1000 simulated matches will go. The
winner is determined by simulations, not this
speculation. But it's fun to imagine how this
fight could play out. AJ9K, what are the rules of
our speculation? Well, I should say there are no
rules. Other than the characters have no prior
knowledge of the other going into the fight. All
they are aware of starting out is that the other
character is a threat that needs to be eliminated.
For the speculation, the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the match
itself, as no environmental statistics are
considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. Alright
then, let's get into it. Felix Faust and Baron
Mordo meet on the battlefield. Who goes first? You
always go first, so I'm going to go first this time.
Baron Mordo is going to start off by pulling out
this dagger from his cloak, and he drags it across
the palm of his hand, drawing blood, and that's
going to summon this giant tentacle that erupts
from the ground beneath him. It's going to be like
20 yards long, and it just smacks the shit out of
Felix Faust, sending him flying across the floor
and breaking all of his ribs. Alright, well if you
have a dagger, I'm going to say Felix Faust at least
has a small grimoire that floats in his hand. So as
that tentacle is coming out of the ground, Faust's
book is going to flip to a specific page that he's
going to read from, and it's going to ignite that
tentacle on fire and cause it to screech in pain and
then just return back to the ground. And once it
does that, Faust flips to another page, and
recites a spell that causes Baron Mordo's dagger
to melt and it just slips out of his grasp into a
puddle on the ground. Okay, so the dagger becomes a
puddle. We'll say like the puddle's the size of a
manhole cover, and Mordo casts a spell on it, and
out of this puddle leaps this silver skeleton
who's holding a sword, like a cutlass, and then
like five more skeletons pop out of this puddle,
and all six of them charge at Felix Faust and just
stab his ass repeatedly. Okay, but Faust, he's
going to counter with a spell on his own shadow
that's going to cause it to duplicate, and from the
shadows emerge these dark like magic Faust clones
that are all going to blast the silver skeletons
with these eldritch fireballs, and that's going
to make those bones scatter all over the
environment. Okay, but Mordo is going to compress
all of these shadow clones into a shadow ball of
like dark energy, and it's going to continue to
press until it becomes like this magical
singularity, like a black hole that pulls Faust
into it and sends them to like this dark dimension
of pain and spikes, like an iron maiden dimension
where he's pierced for the rest of eternity.
Actually, Faust divined from the scattered
silver skeleton bones that Mordo was going to
attempt to put him into a dark dimension. So he was
prepared. He just turned invisible and from his
cloak, he pulled out this small doll that grew in
size and that got sucked into the dark dimension
instead. And each time that doll gets pierced,
it's actually Mordo that feels the pain because
it's like a voodoo doll. Okay, well, once Mordo
starts feeling the spikes from this voodoo doll,
he's going to pull out of his cloak a tarot card and
it's basically the same thing as like a magic Uno
reverse card. So instead of Mordo feeling pain
from getting pierced, it's Faust because the
voodoo doll now represents Faust and Faust is
getting poked and it causes him to drop out of his
invisibility. Shit. Okay. Well, once Faust
starts to feel the piercings of his flesh, he
telekinetically positions the doll within the
spike dimension so that it's pierced in a specific
way, like a stigmata combined with his chakra
points. And that's actually going to amplify his
power. So with these glowing lines connecting
these pierced points on his body, this third eye is
going to appear glowing on his forehead. And from
it, he shoots this massive sized beam of magic
energy straight at Mordo. And this can't be Uno
reversed, by the way, because the card gets
destroyed. Well, wouldn't destroying an Uno
reverse card just destroy yourself? No, because
it's like a draw for wild type of counter magic
energy. Shit. Okay. So the card gets destroyed.
Mordo gets knocked down from the blast, but he
manages to quickly throw up a magic shield. That's
like in the shape of this mouth, like a fanged mouth
that feeds on Faust's third eye energy. It's going
to absorb it and feed it back to Mordo. And this
absorption is going to drain Faust. It's going to
turn him into like this desiccated corpse. And
like his soul just gets sucked right out of his
third eye. And then he falls to the ground, just
dead. And Mordo is like glowing with all this red
evil energy that was fed to him. Well, that's funny
that you think Faust needs his soul. So Faust's
body falls to the ground and splatters,
basically. And it's going to get absorbed into the
earth. But suddenly from beneath Mordo,
thousands of these tiny human veins and arteries
quickly spurt from the ground and cover him in like
a net. And that's going to leech into a skin and that
glowing red energy suddenly turns black as
Mordo's magically poisoned. And slowly his
facial features are going to turn into that of
Felix Faust, who is taking over Mordo's body. And
since he's the last one standing, he wins the duel.
Well, I think Baron Mordo would realize that he's
being magically poisoned by these veins and
arteries from the ground. So he's going to drink a
potion that he pulls from his cloak and it's going
to cure him of his magic poison. And he just pukes up
Faust, who's just this like gross pile of biomass
on the ground. And therefore Mordo wins. No, but
this biomass is going to grow Faust's head and like
a semblance of a human body, like like the creature
from the thing. OK. And from that creature's body
emerges a bell, wheel and a jar, which are going to
summon the demons three. And under Faust's will,
they're going to reshape reality so that Baron
Mordo's mind like inverts itself, revealing his
darkest secrets and fears. And he's going to live
out eternity tormented by his own nightmares. So
Faust wins. That's that's some dark shit, kind of
like a nightmare that Felix Faust wakes up from
because this whole battle was just a hypnotic
illusion that Felix Faust was experiencing while
in reality he's bleeding out from being
sacrificed by Baron Mordo to Dormammu. Really,
you're going to pull the whole it was all a dream.
Yep. Baron Mordo sacrificed Felix Faust to
Dormammu. And that's what really happened. I
guess we can leave it there. Either that happens or
we don't take the lazy way out and Felix Faust
actually traps Baron Mordo and his own
nightmarish hell. Let's leave the match there and
put the stats run the simulations and come back
with a winner. A G9K hit it. Inputting data,
running calculations, processing results,
simulations complete. All right. I mentioned
earlier that these characters had similar
backstories and it's not really any surprise they
had very similar stats. They're basically the
same character, like speed, versatility,
invasiveness, durability, perception,
intellect, strength, range, damage, their
feats, their stats were all exactly the same. They
differed in one category, however, and that was
fighting skill. Surprisingly, Felix Faust is one
of the weakest fighters in DC, whereas Baron Mordo
does not really fight, but it is established
canon. And this is reflected on Marvel's official
power grid stats for him that he has some fight
training from Tibetan monks. Considering that,
Jonathan, tell me who you think is winning this
match. It's of course going to be close. I can only
pray for a statistical miracle, essentially. I
will say that Instagram thinks that Felix Faust is
going to win. 60% of them voted in his favor in our
Instagram poll. Well, I think that's just a bunch
of DC fans on Instagram jumping on the bandwagon
because DC has won a few recently. They're going to
learn today. They might not going to lie. Well,
let's find out. HG9K, the results, please. Hey,
you are, sir. All right. The winner between Felix
Faust and Baron Mordo is Baron motherfucking
Mordo. Yeah. Congratulations. You're going to
stay married. Oh, I can't wait to show my wife this
episode. She'll finally respect you again. Can I
just say how stupid it is that it came down to the
fighting stat? Well, I mean, if they're going tit
for tat through all their thousand battles, at
some point things might turn physical because
they've exhausted everything else. And I don't
mean in that way. I mean, like a physical fight. And
if it comes down to that, yeah, Baron Mordo is going
to take it. But really, I don't see it coming down to
that very often. I guess in approximately like 37
matches or so out of the thousand. Wait, what were
the win percentages? Oh, yeah. Baron Mordo won 537
matches out of a thousand, whereas Felix Faust won
463. So it was 53.7 percent over 46.3 percent. OK,
so pretty close. Not surprised. Not close enough.
DC just can't hang with how awesome Marvel is. It's
embarrassing. You should be embarrassed for this
loss. I hope you are along with all DC fans. Marvel
fans, go ahead and pat yourselves on the back. You
did it. You did it this time. Yeah, this time this
time you got lucky. Yeah, Marvel fans getting
lucky. Unlike DC fans, fucking virgins. Not that
there's anything wrong with that. H &K, help close
us out. Spotify, Podchaser or on our website.
Don't forget to listen to the other shows in the
Dynamite podcast network, including Max
Destruction, Senjo World and Console Combat. In
our next episode, Continuing Spooktober, we will
be pitting the lords of the underworld against
each other, Nieran versus Hella. That'll be a good
one. I'm looking forward to that. And the episode
following that, which will be our Halloween duel,
which will keep a secret until our next episode.
But that does it for this one. We want to give a big
thanks to our executive producers, John
Staroski, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Belcom,
Mickey Muthin-Gian, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi
Yatyn, Austin Wieselowski, AJ Dunkerly, Nick
Obanto, Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Spees,
Dean Maleski, Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, Josh
Schleiner, Mike Williams and Paul Graves for
helping make this podcast possible. We'll talk to
you guys next week. Up up and away, true believers.
Honestly, I tried to bring that Uno draw four wild
card energy into daily life.