This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. I'm Marvelous
Joe. And I'm his twin brother Johnny DC. And if I
sound like ass, it's because I am sick. Yeah
Jonathan is sick, he's always sick, no one's
surprised. That's not fair, I feel like I haven't
been sick in a long time. You better get un-sick
because this is a big episode, in this matchup
we're going to find out who would win in a fight
between the teams of the Wildcats and the
Inhumans. Now I don't know much about the
Wildcats, but I know much about the Inhumans. And
they are one of the coolest, I think most
overlooked teams in all of Marvel and stupid
Wildcats are going down. Yeah, to be fair, I don't
know much about the Wildcats either. This is the
first time we're doing a dual episode in the
history of our 10 years where I have really no
reference for these characters because when I
first started reading comics, the Wildcats team
were published by Image until the whole Wildstorm
universe was acquired by DC Comics. Are they Image
or Wildstorm? Well, Wildstorm was an imprint of
Image. So they started out in Image, they went to
Wildstorm, and now they went to DC. No, they've
always been Wildstorm. I don't know what the hell
you're talking about then. Are they DC or not? This
is a DC vs Marvel podcast, clear this up for me. Yes,
they are now DC. Okay, thank you, that's all I
needed to know. But also, I don't fucking care
because I may as well have not even heard of this
team when they get their asses kicked later on this
episode. Before we get into that matchup, we're
going to break down the latest comic book movie
news that came out this past week, which there was
just one news item and that is it has been confirmed
by The Hollywood Reporter that Deadpool is going
to be in Avengers Doomsday. As always, we list our
segment times in our episode description, so feel
free to check out the show notes if you want to skip
ahead to a particular topic. Guys, our
artificially intelligent dual simulator, AJ9K,
has a quick message for our listeners, so listen
up. Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone who
supports the podcast. Be sure to tune in to the
other shows and the Dynamite Podcast Network this
week, including the console combat podcast,
where hosts John and Dean simulate battles
between popular video game characters. In
yesterday's episode, the two determined who
would win between Colonel Volgen from Metal Gear
and Kessler from Infamous. Over on the Max
Destruction podcast, hosts Scotty and Gilly pay
your favorite action heroes from film and
television against each other. They're taking a
hiatus during the month of August, so make sure to
get caught up on their latest episodes. And on the
Send Joe World podcast, host Zachary Hepburn
speculates on fights between fan favorite anime
and manga characters. In his next episode, Zach's
going to reveal who would win between a kudosai
from Demon King Daimo and Amos Voldigoad from
Misfit of Demon Academy. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our show
notes to listen to all of the shows in the Dynamite
Podcast Network. But with that out of the way,
quick to the no prize. A no prize is an award that
Marvel used to give out to fans. Our version, the
Dynamic Dual No Prize, is a digital award that we
post on Instagram for the person that we feel gave
the best answer to our question of the week. Last
week, we asked you guys, what is your favorite
supporting cast in a Marvel or DC ensemble
television series and why? And we got two answers
for this because it was a horrible question. I
blame Jonathan. He's the one that came up with the
question. What kind of question was this? Nobody
wants to answer about supporting cast in
superhero television series. I mean, I do. Well,
you and two others, apparently. Let's go to and get
into our honorable mention before revealing our
no prize winner. Our honorable mention goes to
Lorenzo Valdez, who said, my favorite supporting
cast from a Marvel or DC show is the cast of
Smallville. Now, that cast changed a lot over the
course of 10 seasons. But if we're going to
specify, I would say the season two and season
three cast. Now, I'd give this answer just because
of Lana, but also, of course, we've got Lex, Pete,
Chloe, Lionel, Martha and Jonathan. Clona,
forever and always. Bye bye. Now, Jonathan, I got
to ask you, Kristen Crook, as Lana Link, overrated
or underrated? I don't know. Maybe somewhere in
the middle. I would say that Erica Durant's as
lowest lane was better. And I think it's kind of
evident how she became the fan favorite as the
series progressed. But I will agree that the
ensemble that Smallville had as a series
throughout its entire run was really good. And
particularly the early seasons, I was absolutely
hooked on. Like I went through high school the same
time that Clark did during that series. And after
high school, I kind of fell off with the show. But
I'll always have fond memories of Smallville and
all of its cast members. I remember liking Chloe
more than Lana had a little bit of crush on Chloe
when I was a teen. And hopefully the actress Alison
Mack is out of prison now. That whole cult thing was
really awkward. I think for all Smallville fans.
But a great answer, Lorenzo. The winner of this
week's snow prize, though, is Alex Albro. Who
said? Hey, guys, I think the best supporting cast
is definitely Ms. Marvel. You have Nakia, who
walks through life with Kamala and just has a lot of
shared experience and Bruno is kind of the
respectful shy love interest and supports them
culturally in all that they're doing and in their
difficulties in school and you feel real stakes
when the convenience store blows up and you're
worried about them. Not to mention her family, her
parents and her brother. You know, they add so much
to the story and the culture and you get excited to
see them and other things like Daredevil just as
much as you do the main character. So yeah, it's Ms.
Marvel for me. Thanks, guys. Yeah, I agree. I
didn't really consider my own personal answer to
this question when we first asked it. But I have to
say that this would probably be my answer, too. In
the comic books, Kamala Khan's family is a huge
part of her story. And the show was no exception.
There was such a good cast of characters, they
showed up again in the Marvel's movie. And her dad,
Yusuf also appeared in the Daredevil born again
television series. There's a reason they keep
popping up. It's because they're such rich
characters. Honestly, her family kind of made
that show. So it made me really like the show
because I'm not sure I would have otherwise. The
family was fun, but it also felt real. Right.
Right. They were funny. They provided great
cultural insight. They really gave Kamala a hard
time as she's struggling to be this superhero.
Good times. If you guys haven't seen the Ms. Marvel
television show, I definitely recommend it. And
then go listen to our review of it. But congrats to
Alex for winning this week's No Prize. If you, the
listener, want a shot at winning Giro No Prize,
stay tuned to later on this episode when we'll be
asking another question of the week. And now that
that's done, on to the news. All right, this past
week, it was revealed by the Hollywood reporter.
They have like a sub newsbeat that focuses on
superhero stuff called heat vision. They
produced a newsletter that confirmed that
Deadpool will be appearing in Avengers Doomsday,
and this was partially supported by their
sources, as well as Ryan Reynolds own Instagram
post, where he posted an image of the Avengers logo
that has a red anarchy symbol pasted over it. So
this is exciting news. However, the sources don't
expect that Deadpool will be joining the
Avengers, more like he'll have a minor role within
that film, which makes you wonder, like Ryan
Reynolds is a big name. Why wasn't he included in
the initial cast reveal? With the chairs? That's a
great question. It's most likely because the
character is a late addition to the script. Does
that bother you? A little bit. I like these scripts
to be finalized before they even begin
production. Otherwise, I think they kind of film
themselves into a hole as it were. And then you have
to deal with reshoots and all that stuff. But the
Marvel machine is always chugging along. And
sometimes they have to make quick decisions on the
fly. I think adding Ryan Reynolds is kind of like an
insurance policy, ensuring that people who are
fans of the Deadpool franchise will come see
Avengers Doomsday because Deadpool and
Wolverine earned a billion dollars at the box
office. That franchise makes money. And in a
climate where movies are making that much money
anymore in theaters, you want to ensure that
people are getting their butts in those seats. I'm
really excited by this news. I think Ryan Reynolds
is a marketing genius and him combined with the
return of Robert Jenny, Jr., whose creative
instincts, I think, are largely responsible for
the success of the MCU. Those two combined, I
think, will do really well for Avengers Doomsday.
Yeah, hopefully. I don't know how involved Ryan
Reynolds will be in the marketing of Avengers
Doomsday. I think it will largely depend on the
size of his role within the film. But that brings us
to our question of the week. What do you think
Deadpool's involvement in the Avengers Doomsday
story will be? Do you think he'll have his own arc?
Do you think it'll be just a glorified cameo? Will
he show up and say, this isn't where I parked my car
and then exit frame? Let us know how you think it'll
go down. Record your answer at dynamicdool.com by
clicking on the red microphone button in the
bottom right hand corner of the screen, which will
prompt you to leave us a voicemail. Your message
could be up to 30 seconds long and don't forget to
leave your name in case we include you on the
podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer and award
that person a dynamic dual no prize that will post
to Instagram. Be sure to answer before August
30th. But that does it for all the news for this
episode. So let's go ahead and move into our main
event where we find out who would win in a fight
between the teams of the Wildcats and the
Inhumans. All right. Wildcats versus Inhumans.
Why did we put these teams against each other?
Well, because our executive producers wanted us
to. And also it's not a bad option. These are both
really powerful teams. Yeah, plus both teams have
ancient ties to an alien race that has been trying
to influence Earth. So there's some thematic
connections here as well. Right. The Inhumans
have ties to the Kree aliens who experimented on
ancient man in an attempt to turn them into
warriors for their interstellar conquests. The
Inhumans are descendants of those experiments.
And a majority of the Wildcats characters are
actually descendants or hybrids of an ancient
race known as the caribam. Caribam from the planet
Kara. Sounds like a pretty interesting story. Do
you know who created the Wildcats? Was it Jim Lee?
Yeah, I believe it was Jim Lee. He was one of the
founders of Image and was like the main guy who
oversaw Wildstorm. That's how he got the job as the
publisher of DC Comics. Yeah, I like the look of the
team. Jim Lee is a great artist. I like the power set
variety. Both of these teams have a good mix of
different kinds of powers. And I think our
speculation is going to be a lot of fun just seeing
how these different abilities clash against each
other. Yeah, the Wildcats definitely suffer from
sort of that 90s extremism where they're sort of
like overly violent and all trying to be like
Wolverine. But they are pretty damn cool. They
were really popular in the 90s, so much so that they
even had their own animated series, which will be
much more finely remembered than the Inhumans
show. You're not wrong. Where did the Wildcat
series air? CBS. Interesting. Was it a kids
cartoon? Yeah, it was like a kids Saturday morning
show. I had to know how that got past us as 90s kids.
Yeah, we didn't really watch it. We were more Fox
and WB kids. Yeah, yeah. And sometimes
Nickelodeon too. One of these days, the Inhumans
will get a television series worthy of their
stories in the comics. But to explain the
methodology behind our duels, let's go to our
sentient dual simulator, Alfred Jarvis, 9000,
H89K, tell our listeners how you go about
determining a winner in our dual matchups. Yes, of
course, sir. The way I determine a winner between
the two teams is by running 1000 Monte Carlo
simulations between every character on each team
using their statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation
is a probabilistic model used to determine
outcomes through random sampling. In this case, I
randomize the statistics along a normal
distribution as a way to simulate the many
variables that can occur during battle. The stat
parameters are based on the official Marvel power
grid from which the DC characters statistics are
extrapolated. Additional stat categories are
included such as range, damage potential,
versatility and perception in order to create a
more detailed and accurate simulation. The
results of the 49,000 simulations provide a
percentage of wins for each character on both
teams. The team with the higher average win rate is
declared the victor as they have a higher
probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither team should win 100%
of the matches. The comic book stories have shown
that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman. So the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks, AJ9K.
Before we run the simulations, though, we like to
break down each team's histories and rosters
before improvising a scenario on how we imagine
one of the thousands of simulations would play out
beat for beat. And it's my turn to go first on the DC
end. So let me tell you all about the Wildcats. No,
long ago, Earth became a hidden battleground in a
war between two alien races, the immortal noble
caribam and the parasitic malevolent
daemonites. After a disastrous space battle
brought both species crashing to Earth, many
caribam assimilated into human society while the
daemonites sought to dominate it from the
shadows. Millenia later, a caribam noble named
Jacob Marlowe, known in covert circles as Lord
Amp, recognized the reemerging daemonite threat
resurfacing and assembled a team of enhanced
individuals to oppose it. He named the group the
Wild Covert Action Teams, or Wildcats. The
original lineup included Spartan, a synthzoid
with enhanced strength and tactical prowess,
Zealot, a deadly coat of warrior and centuries old
caribam, Grifter, a gunslinger and former Black
Ops agent with psionic potential, Maul, a caribam
human hybrid titanthrope who could increase his
size at the cost of his intellect, warblade, a
martial artist whose hands could morph into
blades, and voodoo, a young woman able to perceive
and exercise daemonites from human hosts. The
team was empowered and guided by Void, a
mysterious woman who could teleport in sense
dimensional rifts. Operating out of a
nondescript skyscraper in New York, the Wildcats
conducted covert missions to stop daemonite
infiltration and protect humanity from the
larger caribam-daemonite conflict. Early
enemies included the daemonite warlord,
Hellspawn, who had aligned with corrupt elements
of the US government and his lieutenant,
Hightower. As the team exposed deeper
conspiracies, they stumbled upon an ancient
caribam starship buried on earth. While
investigating it, the ship launched them into
space and delivered them to Kara, the caribam
homeworld. On Kara, the team discovered that the
supposed utopia was built upon the enslavement of
the daemonites and a rigid caste system that
persecuted hybrids. Disillusioned, voodoo left
the team. Marlowe, likewise shaken, stepped away
from leadership. Spartan, grifter, maul, and
zealot returned to earth, where a new Wildcats
unit had been assembled in their absence under the
Halo Corporation. Marlowe's front company had
quartered in a secure Manhattan Tower. This new
team, led by Savant and the caribam warlord, Mr.
Majestic, whose powers rivaled those of
Superman, included Max Cash, Grifter's brother,
codenamed Condition Red, the psychic cyborg Lady
Tron, and the enigmatic tactician, Tao. With
Halo's resources, the Wildcats shifted to
targeting organized crime and rogue metahumans,
using a sophisticated virtual prison system to
contain their enemies. Tao's manipulations,
however, instigated a massive gang war. The
original Wildcats returned to assist, but Tao's
betrayal culminated in an explosion at Clark's
Bar, a neutral hub for superhumans, also known as
post-human. The event fractured alliances and
destabilized the post-human community. Tao
faked his death by substituting a shapeshifter in
his place, escaping capture. Meanwhile, Marlowe
underwent a transformation, merging Void's
essence into his synthesoid body, renaming
himself Jack Marlowe. He took control of Halo and
shifted its mission from defense to societal
reform. From Halo's high tech headquarters in Los
Angeles, the new Wildcats released
groundbreaking technologies like
self-recharging batteries, clean vehicles, and
anti-surveillance devices that destabilized
global power structures. Marlowe employed
Grifter as his personal enforcer, alongside
agent Wax of the National Park Service and a
reprogrammed Lady Tron. Halo accountant Edwin
Dolby joined the field team as Grifter's trainee,
learning combat and espionage in the field. The
Wildcats confronted cyber assassins, corrupt
government agencies, and rogue Cota operative.
Zellet, thought dead, was rescued by Grifter's
strike team from a hidden mountain monastery.
Internal conflicts simmered when war, one of
Marlowe's advisors, attempted to ease Halo's
extra-dimensional energy for himself. Marlowe
stopped him, ensuring Halo's continued
dominance as a force for change. During the World
Storm era, after DC acquired the Wildstorm
characters, the Wildcats regrouped to face a
reemergent Daemonite threat as Hellspawn's
allied with Kaizen Gamora. Marlowe gathered
Zellet, Grifter, Voodoo, Savant, Lady Tron, and
Mr. Majestic, and their headquarters became a
Halo-powered orbital station. Warblade
operated undercover, and Marlowe remained in
retirement. Shortly after a global catastrophe
struck, an event known as World's End. The moon
shattered, Earth's magnetic field
destabilized, and civilization collapsed. The
Halo building in Los Angeles survived, however,
as its batteries kept lights and hope alive. With
Void's power gone from Spartan, now called
Hadrian, the team focused on humanitarian
relief. They rescued survivors, fended off
scavengers, and turned Halo into a safe haven.
Majestic established a breakaway caribbean
enclave in Hawaii and began raiding Halo's
supplies. Tensions escalated, but eased after an
uneasy truce allowed survivors to migrate to
Majestic's colony. New tensions emerged when the
Wildcats learned Majestic was harvesting DNA
from cactives, including Savant, to create a
genetically superior caribbean race. Nemesis, a
sword-wielding caribbean warrior, sacrificed
herself to destroy the facility. At the same time,
Lord Defile, a daemonite warlord, broke the peace
and led in an assault on Halo. The team opened a
gateway to other space, sacrificing their
building and themselves to eliminate both Defile
and Majestic's threat. Surviving members
regrouped with John Lynch of Team 7 to oppose Tau
once more. Now wielding cosmic power stolen from
Void and Providence, Tau sought Godhood. Their
efforts failed until a final confrontation on a
remote island where Max Faraday, holder of the
Creation equation, had gone into hiding. Tau
reached the equation and altered reality, but
Lady Tron had memorized the formula and helped the
heroes regain control. In a surreal
psychological realm, Grifter confronted Tau's
inner Void, his inability to feel connection or
love. The confrontation weakened Tau, who was
then shot and killed by Grifter. Faraday
entrusted the heroes with new uniforms and tasked
them with rebuilding the world. In DC's
post-Flashpoint continuity, the Wildcats were
reimagined as a secret strike force operated by
the Halo Corporation to battle global
corruption. The team's new focus was to dismantle
clandestine organizations threatening Earth
stability, particularly the mysterious
Leviathan. Grifter, masquerading as his dead
brother Max Cash, infiltrated Leviathan to steal
classified intelligence. Operating once again
from the Halo building in Los Angeles, the team
composed of Grifter, Zella, Tavudu, and a newly
upgraded Lady Tron, targeted Leviathan's assets
and clashed with other global players, including
the Corps of Owls and secret divisions within
Wayne Enterprises. You can of course learn more
about the Corps of Owls in our Talon versus Niko
Minoru duel. Grifter's infiltration led to
confrontations with both Batman and Superman,
who viewed the Wildcats methods as reckless and
destabilizing. Despite opposition, the team
succeeded in extracting critical data and
neutralizing a Leviathan strike team sent to
eliminate them. After dismantling one of
Leviathan's black sites in Egypt, the Wildcats
traced a metahuman trafficking gang to Eastern
Europe, where they discovered Daemonite genetic
experiments being funded by remnants of Gamora's
elite. Halo launched a covert rescue operation
that liberated several hybrid children,
prompting Zella to re-establish her coda
contacts in the Balkans for sanctuary.
Meanwhile, Grifter continued posing as Max Cash
to infiltrate a rogue Leviathan cell embedded
within Spiral, clashing with agents loyal to both
checkmate and trust. During a raid in Gotham, Lady
Tron engaged a nanai augmented assassin
dispatched by the Corps of Owls, confirming
rumors of their expanded influence. Following
these developments, the Wildcats relocated
their operations to a fortified Halo facility
beneath the Pacific Ocean, where they began
investigating dimensional anomalies linked to
the return of Void's energy signatures,
suggesting a resurgence of the energy once
believed lost. Now for my seven person roster, I
went with the original team that was also featured
in the animated series, specifically Spartan,
Warblade, Void, Voodoo, Maul, Grifter, and
Zealot, which I also think presents a good balance
against the inhumans. To go into a bit of detail on
each character once again, Spartan, the caribam
android leader of the team and essentially the
Superman of the group, has enhanced strength,
durability and senses, as well as flight and
bioplasma energy emission, among other android
skills like technopathy and cloaking fields.
Zealot, a centuries old blade wielding Kota
warrior, has enhanced caribam physiology that
grants superhuman strength, durability, senses
and a healing factor. She's like Wolverine.
Voodoo is a caribam daemonite human hybrid with
enhanced physicals, particularly when she
shapeshifts into a demonic daemonite form,
though she also has psychic level perception
known as Sight. The ability to freeze time for
short periods and she's a practitioner of voodoo
magic who can raise zombies. Maul, a member of a
caribam subspecies known as a Titanthrope, is a
Nobel Prize winning biochemist who can grow
exponentially in size and strength, though at the
cost of his intelligence. Warblade, a caribam
subspecies hybrid known as a Shaper, can convert
his body into a metallic substance that he can
stretch and shape at will, often into bladed
weapons. A non-caribam related member of my team
is Void, a powerful manipulator of space time with
abilities like teleportation, precognition,
telekinesis, time travel and quantum energy
emission. And finally, Grifter, probably the
most popular member of the team, is a
sharpshooting tactician, martial artist and
demolitions expert whose exposure to modified
alien DNA known as Gen Factor grants him
telepathy, telekinesis and a healing factor. And
that's the Wildcats. As you're going through
their backstory, I thought of something I hadn't
thought before, is the name of Wildstorm, a
portmanteau of the Wildcats and Stormwatch?
Probably? Cool. Thank you for that insight.
That's a pretty interesting story, at least the
first arc, as with any long running team, the first
arc is usually the best. And then because writers
got to keep things going, they kind of lose their
original focus. But I like the idea of how they
started out very similarly to the Inhumans, where
you have warring alien races fighting and
involving humanity and having superpowered
beings stem from that. Great pairing. The
executive producers probably already knew of
this thematic tie-in. That's why it's great to
have multiple minds pulled together in the
formation of these duels. Absolutely. Never
would have thought of this match. But I'm really
glad that we're doing it. Well, let me get into the
Inhumans backstory. The Inhumans are
descendants of a group of ancient humans
genetically experimented on by the alien race
known as the Kree. Tens of thousands of years ago,
the Kree spliced their own DNA into primitive man,
hoping to create a superpowered race that could
serve as soldiers in their interstellar wars.
Eventually, the Kree abandoned the project where
it was lost to time. But the altered humans, now
Inhumans, remained. Carrying with them a dormant
potential through their Kree modified DNA.
Generations later, these early Inhumans
discovered a strange extraterrestrial
substance developed by the Kree called pterogen.
When refined into the pterogen mists, it would
activate their latent genetic enhancements and
grant them extraordinary powers, a process known
as pterogenesis. Isolating themselves from the
outside world and their more primitive human
counterparts, the Inhumans built a hidden city
called Adalan, where they formed a superpowered
society governed by a monarchy obsessed with
genetics. Their culture developed into a strict
caste system, where the most successful results
of pterogenesis rose in prominence and
culminated in the royal family. However,
pterogenesis was unpredictable and in rare cases
had catastrophic results. Those who emerged from
the mists as deformed, subhuman throwbacks were
called alpha primitives. They were condemned to a
lower caste forced to live underground. This
harsh system cemented the Inhumans genetic
hierarchy, elevating the most gifted to the royal
palace while relegating the most unfortunate
underground. A strict human genetics council, a
12 member body chaired by the king, regulated
pterogenesis, mapped family lines and even
approved marriages. In the 20th century, King
Aegon, regarded as one of Adalan's greatest
rulers, convinced his wife Rhinda to expose their
unborn child to pterogenesis while she was
pregnant, defying the genetic council. Their
son, Blackaggar Boltagon, aka Blackbolt, was
born with a voice so destructive that even a
whisper could level a city. He was raised in
isolation to master absolute control over his
ability. Young Blackbolt was betrothed to his
cousin Medusa, whose hair moved with strength and
precision and obeyed her will. King Aegon then
secretly urged relatives to expose their infants
early, producing a remarkable generation of
Inhumans, including Maximus, Blackbolt's
brother who was brilliant but unstable, Gorgon,
whose hooves could unleash earthquakes. Triton
drastically altered into an aquatic beast,
Crystal, who commanded the elements, and Karnak,
who never underwent any of the But heavily trained
to see the flaw in any object, tactic, or system.
Finally, there was Lockjaw, a massive canine who
was bonded to the royal family who could teleport
to nearly anywhere. You can learn more about
Blackbolt, Medusa, and Crystal in their
respective dual episodes against Shazam,
Long-Gated Man, and Tempest. As humanity spread
over the earth, the Inhuman's secret existence
came under threat. They at times clashed with
frightened humans and suppressed alpha
primitive revolts, but they also formed ties with
Earth's heroes such as the Fantastic Four and
sometimes even fought beside them. Inside
Adolan, Maximus schemed to take the throne using
devices, riots, and manipulation. Adolan
endured kidnappings, invasions, and cycles of
destruction and rebuilding. Eventually, the
world learned that this hidden race existed, and
Adolan was moved off of Earth to the blue area of the
moon. Blackbolt's reign faced a personal crisis
when he and Medusa conceived a child. The genetics
council, fearing his bloodline, seized the
infant and cut off parental contact. Medusa fled
to Earth with members of the family while Maximus
hounded them. When Blackbolt learned the council
planned to use his son in his scheme against him, he
turned on the council. He set aside the crown for a
time, and the royals lived away from Adolan,
returning when their people needed them.
Eventually, Adolan returned to Earth, isolated
in the Himalayan Mountains. The Kree later
returned to claim their rediscovered subjects.
Ronan the Accuser struck from orbit, enslaving
the Inhumans and forcing Blackbolt to lead
missions against their rival alien empires,
including the Shiar. He exiled Maximus and the
alpha primitives to the negative zone and
revealed that the Inhumans had been designed for
infiltration. Their traits meant to echo alien
forms for espionage and assassination. He used
them to sabotage ships and treaties and tried to
force Blackbolt to assassinate the Shiar
Empress. Blackbolt challenged Ronan to an honor
duel, won, and forced Ronan to withdraw. Later,
back on Earth, Crystal's husband, Quicksilver,
stole pterogen crystals in an attempt to regain
his lost powers and help other depowered mutants.
You can learn more about this in our Quicksilver
vs. Flash duel episode. The United States
government seized the pterogen crystals and
Blackbolt declared war, pending their return. A
strike to recover them caused many human deaths
and hardened the world's opinion against
Adaline. Though the crystals were finally
reclaimed, Maximus seized control and Adaline
suffered devastating ruin. Not long after,
Blackbolt was kidnapped and replaced by an
imposter from the Skrulls, a shapeshifting alien
race. The royal family, aided by the Kree, rescued
Blackbolt from Skrull captivity and returned
home. Seeking to escape the strife from the
outside world once and for all, the Inhumans
transformed Adaline into a starship powered by
Blackbolt's voice and ventured into space. They
fluted the Kree homeworld of Hala where they
overthrew the empire that once created them. A war
with the Shiar followed, during which a pterogen
device called the T-bomb apparently killed
Blackbolt and the rule fell to Queen Medusa. The
Alpha Primitives revolted, Maximus again sought
the crown, and the Kree nobles resisted, eroding
Inhuman control. It was discovered that the Kree
had also altered other species long ago, not just
humans. These universal Inhumans, as it were,
traveled to Earth's moon and united with the
returned Blackbolt, stopping an attempt by the
Supreme Intelligence to attack Earth and retake
control of the Kree. Abandoning Hala and
returning back to their home planet, the Inhuman
royal family rebuilt Adaline, this time in the
clouds above New York City. Soon, the mad Titan
Thanos demanded that Adaline's render all
Inhumans within certain ages as tribute to him.
Blackbolt realized that hidden within the demand
was a hunt for Thanos' secret son, who was an
Inhuman descendant. The royal family evacuated
Adaline, and rather than submit to Thanos,
Blackbolt destroyed the city with a shout. This
triggered a pterogen bomb built by Maximus that
spread pterogen across the globe and awakened
powers in many people across Earth with dormant
Inhuman genes. In the aftermath, Blackbolt went
into exile for his actions, and Medusa rebuilt New
Adaline, an independent nation open to all
Inhumans. Crystal led a team aboard the royal
Inhumans' transport to track the drifting
pterogen cloud and protect people about to
change. Unfortunately, the cloud proved lethal
to mutants. Fearing extinction, mutant leaders
launched a preemptive strike against New
Adaline, neutralizing most of the royal family
and trapping them in a hostile dimension. After
learning the full stakes of what was happening,
Medusa destroyed the remaining pterogen cloud
herself. She abdicated the throne and passed
leadership to the Inhuman people, installing a
new Inhuman democracy. She and Blackbolt then
reunited and journeyed into space, seeking the
origins of pterogen. Their search led to the
discovery of Primogen, a mutagenic substance on
which the Kree had based their creation of
pterogen. Traveling back to Earth, the family
then founded a new Inhuman city called Arctilan on
the moon. There they were attacked by the Kree, who
learned about the Inhumans' acquisition of
Primogen and gave them an ultimatum. Join the Kree
or die. The Kree massacred Inhumans across space.
Blackbolt summoned the leaders of the universal
Inhuman tribes to plan a response, but a Kree
executioner named Vox ambushed the gathering,
slaughtering the group. In the battle, Triton and
Maximus were seemingly killed, and Blackbolt's
throat was slit. After the remaining Inhuman
population was imprisoned, the royal family
escaped with help from Blackbolt's faint,
returning voice. They learned that Vox was not a
person, but a Kree program that converted
prisoners into living weapons. Given a directive
to acquire Primogen and weaponize the Inhumans,
Vox converted the Inhuman population and
embedded within them the code to restart the Vox
program should he be destroyed. With one paint
whisper, Blackbolt destroyed the engines that
transmitted the Vox program, ending the Kree's
plan, and ending the lives of most of the Inhumans.
The few survivors gathered, with Lockjaw
teleporting them home. The former royals learned
that they were just a few of the last remaining
Inhumans. And that's the Inhumans' history so
far. For this team duel, I'm obviously going with
the members of the Inhuman royal family, as
they're among some of the most prominent and
important members of the Inhuman race. This
includes Blackbolt, the former king of Adolan who
has the ability to absorb and convert electrons
into a devastating energy he can unleash through
his voice or channel into blasts, energy shields,
or used to enhance his own physiology. Queen
Medusa is next on my roster, who can scionically
control every strand of her tensile hair.
Crystal, her sister, is third on my team, able to
control the four elements of fire, earth, air, and
water. All three of them have their own duel
episodes we've done, but the rest are new. I'm
including Maximus, Blackbolt's brother, who is
mentally unstable, but also a powerful telepath
and genius strategist and inventor. Blackbolt's
cousins round out the rest of the team. There's
Karnak, the unparalleled fighter who can detect
the weak point of anything. Gorgon, the brute who
can create seismic shockwaves by stomping his
hooves. And finally Triton, the scaly
water-breathing scout with twin curved short
swords. And that's my team. I wanted to go with
Lockjaw, trust me, but we're going to be saving him
for a later team duel episode this year. If you're a
fan of Lockjaw, you probably already know what
that team is. Hey, spoiler warning! Just
listening to the Inhuman's backstory again, I'm
reminded of how good an Inhuman show should have
been. It should have been sci-fi Game of Thrones.
Yeah, we've said that multiple times on this
podcast, but it remains no less true. The
television show should have been so much better.
Now, if you've listened to our team duels before,
you know that we like to come up with comparable
rosters, finding some kind of analog between
characters of both sides. And this is just to make
sure that we're going into this matchup as
balanced as possible. Now, our matchups consist
of Spartan and Blackbolt, since they're both the
powerhouse leaders of each team, Warblade and
Medusa. Yes, since they could both shape shift
parts of their bodies into weapons. Void and
Crystal. One being able to control Space Time, the
other the elements. Boodoo versus Karnak, who
both have the ability of sight, essentially.
There's Maul and Gorgon, the brutes of each team.
Maximus and Grifter, the telepaths, and Zealot
and Triton, the weapon wielding warriors. Which I
thought lined up perfectly, considering we're
both going with like the base rosters for each of
these teams, I would say. For sure. But now that
we've got the team's histories and rosters out of
the way, let's speculate on how one of the
thousands of simulated matches will go. The
winner is determined by simulations, not the
speculation, but it's fun to imagine how a fight
could play out. AJ9K, what are the rules of our
speculation? Well, I should say there are no rules
other than the teams have no prior knowledge of the
other going into the fight. All they are aware of
starting out is that the other side is a threat that
needs to be eliminated. For the speculation, the
groups will begin approximately 50 meters apart
in a non-descript environment that will have no
bearing on the match itself, as no environmental
statistics are considered in my simulations. The
teams must earn victory on their own merit. All
right, then let's get into it. The Wildcats and the
Inhumans meet on the battlefield. Who goes first?
I'm going to say Warblade starts things off for the
Wildcats by extending his long metal fingers into
the ground, at which point these long metal spears
are going to shoot up beneath the Inhumans
impaling them through their torsos. Damn, that's
how we do. Well, Gorgon sees Warblade's hands go
into the ground and already suspecting
something's up, he's going to quickly stomp the
ground with one of his hooves and that creates a
seismic shock that like breaks each of Warblade's
fingers in like 17 different locations. He's
like, oh, shit, my fingers. And this tremor that
Gorgon creates also knocks each of the Wildcats
members on their asses. OK, well, while on the
ground, Grifter, he's just going to mag dump his
dual pistols while telekinetically curving the
bullets so that each of the Inhumans gets two in the
chest and one in the head. John Wick style. Except
that black bolt throws up an energy shield that's
going to protect his family from all sunsets and it
also weakens a dust storm that affects the entire
area of the battlefield around the Wildcats. And
it's a heavy storm that blocks their vision. They
can't see anything. But then suddenly they all
start getting slapped around by a bunch of whips
created by Medusa's hair, who extends her hair
into the storm. And she could feel through it and
just beat the shit out of them simultaneously
while the Wildcats are inside. I mean, Void has a
spatial sense on a planetary scale. So maybe a few
Wildcats get hair whipped before Void teleports
her entire team out of the dust storm behind the
Inhumans, at which point Spartan is going to blast
them all in the back with this sweeping plasma beam
blasting across the Inhumans and frying them.
That's a good move. Okay, I forgot that you guys can
teleport. Yeah, the Inhumans would probably be
taken by surprise by this. So they're all on the
ground and like singed on their backs with third
degree burns. Except for Maximus, because his
telepathy warned him of the attack because he
could detect the Wildcats' minds were behind
them. So they gave him enough time to react and duck
beneath the plasma beam. And while he's crouched
down, he pulls out a sonic rifle he has that he's
fueled with the same energy as Black Bolt's voice.
What? Like whispers of Black Bolt, right? And he
just lets Spartan have it. He fires the rifle and
punches a big basketball sized hole right through
Spartan's torso and he drops to the floor. He's an
android, right? Yeah, yeah, and actually that's
not going to take Spartan out. But while his
android body is on the ground repairing itself,
that's when Maul is going to Fastball Special
Zellet, hurling her right at Maximus, blades
first, and she straight up decapitates his ass.
No, no, no, no, no. She flies right into a force
field. He had set up this negative zone barrier
that was secretly activated in front of him. He set
up like negative zone barriers all the time in the
comic books, mostly around Adeline, but he has a
personal force field too, in this case. And she
crashes into it and slides down to the ground like a
bird who just crashed into a window. Dang. By this
point, the Inhumans have gotten up from the ground
after dealing with Spartan's attack and Crystal
is going to whip up and hurl a firestorm at the
Wildcats. It's just this big fiery tornado that's
shooting fireballs and it burns and just scatters
the Wildcats team. Okay, but Voodoo, she's going
to mindlock Crystal for an incident, causing her
mind to go blank and the fire tornado is going to
dissipate because of that. And with the fire gone,
Warblade is going to shift his hands and feet into
scissors, along with the ends of eight metallic
spider legs that he grows from his back. And he
leaps at Medusa, chopping up any hair that may get
in his way until he's able to get close enough to her
to deliver a fatal stabbing. Except I don't think
he can cut her hair because it's too durable. It has
like the tensile strength of iron wires. And his
blades could cut through anything. But like,
traditionally, Medusa's hair can't be cut unless
she wants it to be cut. But I also guess it stands to
reason that something sharp enough to cut it would
be able to do it. So say Warblade's cutting her hair
as she's defending herself, okay? Trying to fight
him off. What Warblade doesn't know is that Medusa
can still control any of her hair that's cut. What?
So as he's trying to get to Medusa, he gets all
tangled up in this mess of his own making. And so
he's now just busy slashing and fighting at these
hair strands, just flailing around. At that
point, Karnak flips in, he sees Warblade's weak
point, spots his opening, and then just karate
chops Warblade's spine with like the force of a
cannonball that just causes Warblade's liquid
metal form to explode into like liquid metal
droplets everywhere. Okay, well meanwhile,
thanks to Voodoo's gift of sight, she's able to see
how Black Bolt is restraining himself from making
vocalizations during the battle. So she uses her
psychic ability to separate Black Bolt from his
mental conditioning. And that's when Black Bolt
looks at Gorgon, just confused, and is like, what
just happened? Obliterating Gorgon. Geez. Well,
if he has forgotten his mental conditioning after
he sees Gorgon just get obliterated, he's gonna
turn his head and be like, holy shit! And that's
gonna obliterate Zellet, who happened to be in
front of him. What? So Zellet's out of the match as
well. And then Maximus, who's insane, but he's not
stupid, he knows he needs to silence his brother
for the sake of everybody, right? So he
telepathically reminds Black Bolt of his mental
conditioning to stay mute. Okay, but while
Maximus is distracted telepathically
communicating with his brother, Grifter, an
expert thief, is going to steal Maximus' sonic
rifle from him, and he's gonna use it to blow up
Maximus. Except that this gun, the sonic gun, is a
weapon designed for inhuman militia, so that
means it's programmed only to respond to the
genetic signature of an inhuman. So Grifter tries
to shoot Maximus, but instead the gun just
explodes in his hands. And now Grifter's arms are
gone. And before Grifter can even process what
just happened, Triton leaps by him and takes off
his head with one of his curved blades. What? Wait,
wait, wait. First of all, the pterodrine mist is
like a gas, right? Correct. Well, the gen factor
that Grifter inhaled was also a gas. What if it's
like the wildstorm pterodrine mist, making
Grifter an inhuman? No, I'm sorry. Not
genetically. Whatever. Grifter's gone, but he is
a demolition guy who's like armed to the teeth with
various explosive gadgets inside his trench
coat. So he may be dead, but the explosion from
Maximus' gun sparks an igniter on one of his
grenades. And when that goes off, all of his
explosives go off, killing Triton as well. And,
you know, Maximus is probably pretty injured,
too, I'm sure. All right. Okay. So Triton is out.
Grifter's out. While this is all happening,
Karnak is fighting Maul. And Karnak is dodging
Maul's attacks just with like super efficiency,
striking all of his pressure points. So Maul's not
even really able to land a hit on Karnak. And Karnak
is going to strike a nerve in Maul's legs, which is
going to drop Maul to his knees. And then Karnak
leaps up and finger strikes him right in between
the eyes, which is a weak spot that makes his brain
explode inside his head. So now Maul's out. Except
that the last second, though, Maul's going to
shrink his body down to the size of a thimble in
order to dodge Karnak's attack. And at that size,
he's a super genius because, you know, his size
correlates with his intellect. And he's going to
deduce Karnak's one weakness, which is his
insides. So Maul's going to shrink down, jump into
Karnak's booty. No! Before expanding to
skyscraper size and just obliterating Karnak.
Did you just thinus Karnak? You're damn right I
did. What are you, nine? Why did he go in through the
butthole? Because he could. Anyway, Maul is now
the size of a skyscraper, you say. But that means
he's dumb as a rock. Okay? Fair. So suddenly he
starts beating the shit out of his own teammates.
He smashes Spartan, you know, before he can finish
repairing his android body. He just smacks Void
across the horizon and he pummel's voodoo into the
ground with his fists. All of this because now he's
being mind controlled by Maximus. Oh. Well, I
mean, Maul is said to be fairly psychic resistant
because of his decreased intellect at giant size.
No, well, I mean, the reason I did this is because
actually the more mindless that a subject is, the
more susceptible they are to Maximus's mind
control. Like that's why Maximus is so good at
controlling the alpha primitives. Really? Okay.
Wait, so Spartan's finished. But we'll say that as
Void is sailing across the horizon, she's going to
teleport back to the battle and rescue voodoo for
Maul's attack, like just in time. And with voodoo
using her gift of sight to be able to recognize
who's controlling Maul, that's when she
transforms into her daemonite demonic form and
just tears into Maximus, ripping him to shreds
while he's distracted. And meanwhile, you
remember how Warblade was sort of scattered
everywhere by Karnax attack? Yeah. Well, that
would not kill him because eventually all of those
metallic droplets would find their way back to
each other, sort of like T1000. And so we'll say by
this point, enough of Warblade's scattered
droplets have coalesced to form a long hammer,
which Maul by this point back to 10 feet tall or so
picks up and proceeds to pummel crystal into the
ground. Okay. So Warblade is back from being
exploded and he's just a hammer now. Right. Is he
like a hammer with Warblade's face? Uh, yes,
actually, specifically that. I wasn't sure if he
was just like an inanimate object now. No. But
Crystal's going to handle this liquid metal guy
the same way you would handle any liquid metal guy.
She's going to freeze the hammer so that shatters
when Maul swings it. So Warblade's gone for good
now. Maul's confused because his hammer broke on
him. And at that point, Crystal fills Maul's lungs
with water and he drowns. Oh, okay. Well, Crystal,
she's just going to get lasered and half at the
torso at this time by one of Void's quantum beams.
So she's out. And as that happened, Voodoo brought
Maul back as a zombie using her Voodoo knowledge
and she's going to control Maul to choke out Black
Bolt. And that's going to prevent him from using
his voice as he suffocates and dies. No, because
before Black Bolt suffocates, Medusa is going to
take a page from Maul's playbook and destroy him
from the inside. Okay, but she's not like a pervert
like he is. She goes in through his ears. So her hair
infiltrates Maul's skull through his ears and she
just scrambles his zombie brain to mush. All
right. And with Black Bolt free, he's just going to
take out both Void and Voodoo by shouting, like,
you guys suck. And they're just obliterated from
his voice and the Inhumans win. Wait, he
obliterates both of them? Do you think they were
standing like right next to each other? Because
they weren't. Says who? Me, bro. We'll say that
Voodoo freezes time just before the sound waves
reach her. And that's going to allow Void to set up a
portal that catches all of those sonic waves and
redirects them through another portal lined up to
hit both Medusa and Black Bolt. So they're dead
instead and the Wildcats win. Now you can't just
dictate where people are on the battlefield. I'm
saying that Void and Voodoo were standing next to
each other and they didn't have enough time to
react to Black Bolt's shout. Wait, I can't. But you
can? Yes. I mean, Singly didn't have enough time to
react also, by the way. Void literally controls
space time. So she'll just go back in time if they
didn't. Void's a bum. Okay. We could go out and
leave the match there. Either one of two things
happens. Either Black Bolt shouts Void and Voodoo
out of existence or they're able to redirect his
blast and Black Bolt ends up taking himself and
Medusa out. Let's go ahead and input the team
stats, run the simulations and find out which of
the scenarios happens when we come back with a
winner. 8G9K, hit it. Alright, that was a crazy
matchup. Both of these teams have some really
powerful members. There's actually a good
variety among both teams. They had a lot in common.
They had a lot that was not in common, but breaking
it all down. The teams were actually even when it
came to intelligence and versatility. Right. The
biggest discrepancy they had actually came down
to durability, considering basically all of the
Wildcat's characters have healing factors.
Yeah, they're all Wolverine wannabes. Like, the
inhumans have an accelerated rate of healing
compared to normal humans, but it's not crazy fast
like Wolverines and it's not fully regenerative
either. My most durable guys were Black Bolt,
Gorgon and Triton. People like Medusa, Crystal,
Karnak and Maximus just didn't have the same level
of durability. But the inhumans did have the
advantage when it came to the category of range.
Black Bolt, Crystal and Maximus and even Gorgon
have tremendous range with their attacks. You
know, Maximus being a psychic, Black Bolt with his
shouts, Crystal with her elemental powers and
Gorgon with his seismic stomps. Yeah, when you're
going up against elemental powers with like
bullets and blades and stuff like that, it's not
quite as effective. My strongest character on my
side was Spartan, followed up by Void. And my
weakest character was actually Warblade. Yeah,
my strongest character obviously was Black Bolt
and the weakest member of the inhuman family is
actually Karnak, probably because he never
underwent terror genesis. And, you know, he's
really good at finding weak spots and striking to
defeat them. And he was smart, but he didn't have
those like superhuman stats that his cousins and
his brother have. Yeah, Karnak only won about a
quarter of his matches. He won 27.9 of the total
matches that he was in, which was not the lowest win
rate. Actually, Warblade had the lowest at 26%
even. Yeah, and Black Bolt had the highest win rate
individually, winning 81.3% of all of his
matches. And that was actually the highest win
rate overall, because my highest win rate was
79.9% held by Spartan. So taking all of these
figures and stats into account, Joseph, who do you
think came out on top in humans? They have the most
powerful member. Black Bolt had the highest win
rate. They're a pretty well rounded team. I'm
going to give it to the royal family. You would. And
Instagram agrees with me with 63% of our poll
respondents, citing with the inhumans saying
that they would defeat the Wildcats. Well, let's
see if you jerks are correct. AJ9K, the results,
please. Here you are, sir. The winner of the team
dual matchup between Wildcats and Inhumans is the
Wildcats, son of a bitch. No. The Wildcats won
52.5% of their matches compared to the Inhumans,
who only won 47.5. And honestly, I'm kind of as
surprised as you are. I thought the Inhumans were
going to take this. I mean, they have fucking Black
Bolt. You just start off the match by going, screw
you guys, and then it would be over. But yeah, Void
could, you know, just again, teleport all of the
energy back at them. The Inhumans had Black Bolt,
but the Wildcats had Spartan and Void and Grifter,
each of whom had over a 60% win rate. My guys overall
were just a little bit more powerful. Honestly, I
think it really came down to the defense of stats.
Having a healing factor really helps in battle, as
it turns out. I'm like horribly depressed now. I
was expecting to go into this with the Inhumans win
to give them some kind of victory and make up for all
the disappointments that fans have encountered
with them over the years. And here's just another
one to add to the fucking list. Honestly, I think
it's time to give up on the Inhumans. Like they have
nothing going for them. I think it's time for you to
give up. You know what? You piece of shit. Jeez. But
that is it for this duel, guys. AJ9K helped close
this out. Thanks for listening to Dynamic Jewel.
Visit the show's website at dynamicjewel.com and
follow us on Instagram at Dynamic Jewel podcast.
You can support the show on Patreon at patreon.com
slash dynamicjewel and joining a tier that works
for you or by rating and reviewing Dynamic Jewel on
Apple podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser or on our
website. Don't forget to listen to the other shows
in the Dynamite podcast network, including Max
Destruction, Senjo World and Console Combat. Our
next episode, we don't actually know what the next
episode is going to be yet because we have yet to
have our monthly meeting with our executive
producers who will determine what the next
episode is. So next week will be a surprise for you
guys. Hope you enjoy it. And if you want to help make
those decisions, be sure to become an executive
producer on Patreon. But that does it for this
episode. We want to give a big thanks to our
executive producers, John Staroski, Zachary
Hepburn, Dustin Belcom, Miki Matangin,
Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yatyn, Austin
Wieselowski, AJ Dunkerly, Nick Ibonto, Scott
Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Spees, Dean Moleski,
Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, Josh Liner, Mike
Williams, Oscar Galvez and Paul Graves for
helping to make this podcast possible. We'll talk
to you guys next week. Up, up and away. True
believers. The amalgam version of these two teams
would be the cat humans, and it would be about the
lives of humans and their own cats.