This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi and welcome
to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe and I'm his twin
brother Johnny DC. And in this episode we're going
to find out who would win in a fight between
Elongated Man versus Medusa. Now Elongated Man is
a stretchy DC character with the most perverted
name and existence against Medusa who has no
relation to the Greek mythological character
except for, you know, they both have interesting
things going on with their hair. Yeah, Elongated
Man is a fairly popular character in DC so I'm
surprised that it's taken us this long to get to a
dual episode with him and the same kind of goes for
Medusa I feel. Yeah, so far we've only done one
inhuman unless you count Miss Marvel Kamala Khan,
but yeah, that was Black Bolt in our Shazam vs.
Black Bolt episode and, you know, that's a mistake
because I love the inhumans and I'm really excited
to get back into those characters with this duel.
But before we find out who wins between these two
characters, we're going to break down the latest
comic book movie news this past week of which there
was none. So we're not going to do that. Yeah, we are
going to give you guys a special update on the
podcast though so stay tuned for that. As always,
we list our segment times in our episode
description so feel free to check out the show
notes if you want to skip ahead to a particular
topic. Our artificially intelligent dual
simulator AJ9K has a quick message for our
listeners so listen up. Want to know more about
this podcast? Then become a part of the dynamic
dual community on Patreon where you can choose
from three tiers. The dynamic 2.0 tier gives you
access to our Discord chat server. The Fantastic
Four tier gives you two bonus episodes each month
and the X-Force tier makes you an executive
producer of this show. Lastly, the DynaMic
podcast network tier lets you create your own
podcast using this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny
and Joe will help you develop your show, provide
graphic support and consultation, and get you
simulation results. Pitch the twins your ideas
via email at dynamicdualpodcast.com. Check it
out at patreon.com .pippip. Thanks AJ9K and
thanks to everyone who supports the podcast.
Guys, be sure to tune into the other shows and the
DynaMic podcast network this week including
the Konsole Kombat podcast where hosts Jon and
Dean simulate battles between popular video game
characters. In yesterday's episode, they
reviewed The Last of Us season 2. Over on the Max
Destruction podcast hosts Scotty and Gilly pit
your favorite action heroes from film and
television against each other. This week, the
brothers are returning to kick off a new season by
pitting Ben 10 against Aang from Avatar The Last
Airbender. On the Senjoh World podcast hosts
Zachary Hepburn speculates on fights between fan
favorite anime and manga characters. In his next
episode, Zach is going to reveal who would win
between Makka Al Barn from Soul Eater versus Ryuku
Matoi from Kill La Kill. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our show
notes to listen to all the shows in the DynaMic
podcast network. But with that out of the way,
quick to the no prize! A no prize is an award that
Marvel used to give out to fans. Our version, the
Dynamic Dual No Prize, is a digital award that we
post on Instagram for the person that we feel gave
the best answer to our question of the week. Last
week, we asked you guys, what's your favorite
theory as to why Victor Von Doom would look like
Tony Stark? Right, this is coming off the news that
Avengers Doomsday has been pushed back here.
We've all been eagerly anticipating the film, but
we're going to have to wait until December of 2026
to see it. In the meantime, we thought it would be
interesting to get your ideas on why, God, why
would they cast Robert Dunney Jr. as Dr. Doom and
how could that best be rationalized? We actually
got quite a number of answers, but quite a few of you
guys repeated your answers. So we still have only
three honorable mentions and one no prize winner.
Our first honorable mention goes to by Dear
Bangura and Jutson Batty. Who said? Hello Dynamic
Dual, I think that a good theory would be that
Victor Von Doom implanted his brain inside Tony
Stark's body. Very similar to Superius
Spider-Man with Doc Oub. I think he was trying to
make him a superior Iron Man. Maybe Marvel will
follow that storyline and kind of blend in with
this one and give us the best version of Tony Stark
possible. Thank you. Hi guys, Jutson Batty here. I
think that my favorite theory as to why Doom looks
like Stark in Avengers Doom is that in his reality,
it was a play on the superior Spider-Man story.
Instead of it being Doc Ock and Spider-Man, it was
Doom and Stark being that Doom gets some form of
cancer that would kill him somehow and capacitate
Iron Man. It takes his body and Iron Man dies
instead. Alright, so they both gave the same
answer, essentially theorizing that the Dr. Doom
Iron Man relationship is going to be similar to the
superior Spider-Man relationship between Dr.
Ock to Puss and Spider-Man in that comic book
storyline. Which is a theory that I haven't heard
before. I think it's a pretty interesting one.
Essentially, they're saying that an alternate
reality, Dr. Doom, is going to somehow
telepathically or otherwise implant his mind
into an alternate reality, Tony Stark's body, and
then come into the main 616 universe. Which is an
interesting idea, but it's not necessarily an
idea that I love because I can't come up with any
kind of justification for why Doom would take over
Tony Stark's body when he could easily just
probably create a clone of his former body. Like
there's no advantage to having Tony Stark's body
unless you don't want a functioning heart. Well,
one could say that the motivation would be
deception. Dr. Doom puts his mind in alternate
reality, Tony Stark's body, who comes to Earth
pretending to be Tony Stark. I'd rather have
Doom's face hidden the entire time behind a dope
metallic mask. I don't need that kind of level of
deception. Maybe Doom's plan does, we'll see.
Great answer by Deer and Judson, our next
honorable mention goes to Lorenzo Valdez. Who
said? This is Lorenzo Valdez calling in once
again. What I keep going back to with RDJ as Dr. Doom
is the Superboy TV show, where at the beginning of
season 2, Lex Luthor gets plastic surgery to look
like another character, Warren Eckworth. And I'm
wondering whether Dr. Doom has done something
similar, and whether he's perhaps trying to pose
as Tony Stark, or revive Tony Stark, to infiltrate
the Avengers. Clon of forever and always,
buh-bye. Yeah, this is a similar type of situation
as the previous answer, except instead of being an
alternate reality, Dr. Doom inserting his mind
into an alternate reality, Tony Stark's body, it
is Dr. Doom getting plastic surgery to look like
the deceased Tony Stark. So face off,
essentially. Yeah, yeah. The reason I find this
particular theory unsatisfying, and same thing
with the Superior Spider-Man theory, is that it
doesn't give enough space for the character of
Victor Von Doom to be his own character prior to
this deceptive plan. So in that case, we will never
really get a good sense of who this guy is, what he
looks like, before we dive in head first into, oh,
this appears to be Tony Stark, and like acts like
Tony Stark, and all this stuff. And it just bothers
me because Victor Von Doom is such an interesting
character in the comic books, and really truly has
not been done justice in the films, and deserves to
be. Right, at least even in the movie Face Off, in
the first act, you got a sense of who the characters
were before they switched faces. Exactly,
exactly. Great answer, Lorenzo. Our final
honorable mention goes to Alex Albro, who said,
Hey guys, I think it plays out similar to the MCU
with a few twists. Instead of getting stranded in
Afghanistan, he gets stranded in Laveria, uses
the Ten Rings to help him take over the country,
still feels the need for a suit of armor around the
world, builds Ultron, which turns into the
Doombots. And since he can't save his mother in
this universe, as the universe's collapsed, he
trails the Fantastic Four to the 616, back in time
to save his mother from the Winter Soldier, and
he's been here all along. So yeah, this is the type
of scenario that I'm really hoping that Marvel
does not actually go down. What he poses is that an
alternate reality, Tony Stark, named Victor Von
Doom, goes through the same essential arc of being
a weapons designer who gets captured and taken to
Laveria, instead of Afghanistan like Tony Stark
did in the first Iron Man movie. And then takes over
the country, proposes the Ultron program, which
turns into Doombots, and then comes into our
reality to stop his mom from dying by the hands of
the Winter Soldier. So that's what I don't want to
happen. I don't want the character of Victor Von
Doom to essentially be Tony Stark, because Victor
Von Doom's actual origin story from the comic
books is much more interesting than just being an
alternate reality rehash of the MCU's Tony Stark.
Yeah, it may sound petty, but I think Victor Von
Doom should be done more justice than just being a
Tony Stark variant. Right, exactly. Yeah. That's
what I don't want. I don't want him to be a Tony Stark
variant, necessarily. I mean, there's one theory
that was not called in as an answer that I'll
discuss in a minute here, but for the most part,
yeah, I would not like Dr. Doom to be a variant. That
said, if Victor Von Doom was going to be a variant of
Tony Stark, that was a very creative way of going
about that. So still, great answer, Alex. But the
winner, or should I say winners of this week's No
Prize are Travis Herndon and Cyrus Moore. Who
said? Well, so the name of the dude's Travis here,
shut up to my twin. So my theory is that what if RDJ is
a red herring? Like they actually hired someone
else to play Victor and they're keeping it hush
hush. So when at the end of Doomsday, we actually
get the true reveal of the actual actor who's
playing Doom, Marvel would then pretty much pull
the biggest, got y'all, fuck all of you guys that
were doubting us moment in MCU history if that was
the case. Hey guys, Cyrus Moore here. So my
ultimate theory is that Tony Stark is coming back
as Victor Von Doom is actually just an illusion.
It's just a mass effect. Marvel's actually going
to have Tony Stark come back and be Iron Man, and
they will cast somebody else as Von Doom. Because
you know the only character to stay dead is Uncle
Ben. So yeah, I think Iron Man's coming back.
Alright, this may be wishful thinking on my part
and probably most fans who don't like the idea of
Robert Downey Jr. being Iron Man, but it would be
pretty impressive if Marvel was playing this kind
of long con where they announced Robert Downey Jr.
as being cast as Victor Von Doom. And then it turns
out that it was all just a scam and that he's
actually coming back as Iron Man and the character
of Doctor Doom is played by a different actor. I
don't think that's likely. I think it would be far
more likely that maybe Robert Downey Jr. plays
Doctor Doom for like the first movie at which point
at the end he gets reverted to his true form and then
we see another actor like pull away the disguise as
a were and show us who the real Doctor Doom is. I
think that is still potentially a possibility,
but Marvel pulling off something like that I think
would be exciting and would be something that I
would actually love to see. Yeah, one thing about
the Marvel fandom is that they're always trying to
figure out all of the secrets that Marvel may or may
not have. Like when it came to, you know,
Spider-Man No Way Home. Like everyone knew what
the spoiler for that film was going to be before we
even saw it. It was still exciting when we learned
that Toby Maguire and Andrew Garfield would be in
the movie, but I think it would be cooler if
sometimes we didn't know all the secrets or
couldn't figure out all the secrets ahead of time.
If Marvel is really just punking all the fans, I
would actually love that. I'm so sick of all of the
Marvel speculation and rumors. I don't give a shit
about it because, well, one, I'm a DC guy, but also
two, like there's no way you're going to know until
you see the actual movie. So just stop. Right. I
mean, speculation is fun, but there's a limit to
what I can tolerate even as a Marvel fan. I think
essentially lying to fans is probably the best
means at this point of actually retaining some
sort of surprise, as they did with Spider-Man No
Way Home. They basically lied and said these guys
weren't in the movie, but then it turned out they
were. But the lie just has to be maintained and
believable. We'll end up seeing what happens. In
regards to my statement that there was another
theory out there that I liked. I think we talked
about it on this podcast before. But if Victor Von
Doom is going to be a Tony Stark variant in this
cinematic multiverse, then I also want Chris
Evans and Scarlett Johansson to come back as evil
variant versions of their characters. So like
Hydra Cap along with Superior Iron Man version of
Doctor Doom and maybe Scar Joe as like Madamask or
something like that. That's the only way I can see
this working if it's not just Robert Downey Jr.
coming back, but other original Avengers actors
coming back as variants of their former roles.
Something like that I think could be pretty cool.
And that's probably the only way I'll accept Doom
being a variant of Tony Stark. But thanks to
everyone who called in and congrats to Travis
Herndon and Cyrus Moore for winning this week's No
Prize. If you the listener want a shot at winning
your own No Prize, stay tuned to later on this
episode when we'll be asking another question of
the week. And now that that's done, on to the news.
Alright, in one of the biggest announcements for
this podcast, we want to let you guys know like
seven months in advance that in mid January on the
10th anniversary of this podcast, Jonathan and I
will be ending Dynamic Duel as we all know it. That
doesn't mean that we're going away forever. It
just means that Dynamic Duel will no longer be
putting out a weekly show. By the time that mid
January comes around, Jonathan and I will be
turning 40. And as many of you listeners may know,
we started this podcast on our 30th birthday. And
we feel that 10 years is a long time to exhaust any
single topic, especially one like Marvel vs DC.
Yeah, it was interesting. We started this podcast
because DC that year was releasing Batman v
Superman and essentially kicking off their very
own shared cinematic universe to compete with the
MCU. And that was a big ol' failure. Apparently.
But I thought it was kind of fitting that we would
kind of end the podcast once that journey was over
and as DC is kicking off a new universe. So we
started the show with the birth of one DC universe
and we're ending it with the birth of another. Now
the weekly format will be going away for the show,
but we will still be doing film reviews of the
upcoming Marvel and DC theatrical projects. And
maybe some television shows as well. I'm not quite
sure. Right. We're still going to be on Ron
Tomatoes. We're still going to be here just not
every week for you guys. Yeah. And to that end, the
executive producers have determined the
remaining dual episodes that we'll be doing
throughout the rest of this calendar year into
next January. So the main reason we're announcing
this now is because if there are any potential
executive producers out there, and I had to tell
Paul Graves this, who is our newest executive
producer, basically the role of the executive
producer was to determine the content calendar of
this show and pitch dual ideas and things like
that. All the duels are figured out for the rest of
the show. And so the main role of the executive
producer now is to determine in what order those
duels will be coming out. So I don't want to
discourage anyone from supporting this podcast,
but if you do become an executive producer from
here on out, just know that the responsibility of
that role has kind of shifted. Yeah. If you've been
a supporter of this podcast, you've known about
this news for a while and it's kind of bittersweet.
But we're all really looking forward to the
upcoming schedule we have for the remainder of
this year. And the final episodes in particular
are just going to be amazing. I almost can't wait
for them. Yeah. In some ways next year can't come
soon enough. And in other ways, it'll be hard to
stop doing a weekly show, you know, something that
we've done for literally a decade consistently.
We've never missed a drop date, even while sick.
Even while at the hospital having a kid. Yeah, I
guess I did miss that episode for sure. But I did
not. Hopefully this doesn't come as like a sad
announcement to a lot of our listeners out there.
Hopefully you guys understand that doing this for
10 years is a long time. And we still love doing the
show, though, and we can't wait to continue
putting out more episodes for you guys. Finally,
solving this Marvel vs DC debate and shutting my
twin brother up once and for all. Yes, those exact
words. But regarding this announcement, that
brings us to our question of the week. How did you
find Dynamic Duel and how long have you been
listening to the show? Yes, sometimes our
questions are more market research than looking
for editorials from you guys. But with the news
that the show will be ending as it currently
exists, we would just love to hear from some of our
listeners. Record your answer at
dynamicduel.com by clicking on the red
microphone button in the bottom right hand corner
of the screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long, and don't forget to leave your name in case we
include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a Dynamic
Duel No Prize that we'll post to Instagram. Be sure
to answer before June 7th. But I think that does it
for the news portion of this episode, so let's go
ahead and move into our main event. Where we find
out who would win in a fight between elongated man
and the inhuman Medusa. All right, elongated man
versus Medusa. The primary reason we are doing
this duel, not only because these characters can
stretch, but also they're going to lead into
future team duels that we have planned in the
coming months, including the Justice League
International versus the West Coast Avengers and
Wildcats versus the Inhumans. Of course,
elongated man was a member of the Justice League
and Medusa is a member of the Inhumans, and we
wanted to make sure to touch on these characters
specifically before their team duels because we
feel they're interesting and important enough
characters to delve deeper into. I don't know if
listeners have noticed yet, but Jonathan and I are
just plowing through the team duels in essence
trying to get through as many characters as
possible before this upcoming January. Yeah,
doing one team duel a month was going to be the only
way we could get through all of the team battles
that we were hoping to get through before moving on
from the current iteration of this show. Now, if
you're an avid fan of the Flash television series
on the CW, you are familiar with elongated man. He
was a member of the Flash's superhero team
essentially in the later seasons of the show, and
you may also remember Medusa from a really, really
shitty Inhumans live action series. It was so bad,
which is such a shame. I really wanted to like the
Inhumans series because it was being released in
IMAX and everything like that. And Jonathan and I
even went to our local IMAX theater to see the
Inhumans pilot episode essentially, and we were
severely disappointed. We actually did a review
of it on this podcast when it came out. And I thought
Serendis Swan, the actress who played Medusa, was
pretty well cast. A lot of the cast was actually
pretty good, but everything else in the show
really sucked. It's probably the worst thing
Marvel television has ever put out, and that's a
shame because the Inhumans deserve better. Yeah,
I've always thought that Inhumans were pretty
cool. I would agree with that. Before we get into
this dual matchup to explain the methodology
behind our duels, let's go to our sentient dual
simulator, Alfred Jarvis 9000. AJ and IK tell our
listeners how you go about determining a winner in
our dual matchups. Yes, of course, sir. The way I
determine a winner between the contestants is by
running 1,000 Monte Carlo simulations using the
characters statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation
is a probabilistic model used to determine
outcomes through random sampling. In this case, I
randomize the statistics along a normal
distribution as a way to simulate the many
variables that can occur during battle. The stat
parameters are based on the official Marvel power
grid from which the DC characters statistics are
extrapolated. Additional stat categories are
included such as range, damage potential,
versatility and perception in order to create a
more detailed and accurate simulation. The
results of the 1,000 simulations provide a
percentage of wins for each character. The
contestant with the higher percentage is
declared the victor as they have a higher
probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither character should win
100% of the matches. The comic book stories have
shown that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman, so the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks, AJ9K.
Before we run the simulations though, we like to
break down each character's histories and
abilities before improvising a scenario on how we
imagine one of the 1,000 simulations would play
out, beat for beat. It is my turn to go first with the
DC characters backstory, so let me tell you all
about Elongated Dan. Randolph Relf Dibney was
born in Waymore, Nebraska to a modest and
unassuming family. From a young age, Relf was
captivated by carnival side shows featuring
contortionists who seemingly impossible feats
of flexibility ignited his imagination.
Determined to uncover their secrets, Relf
discovered that many of these performers drank a
soda called Gin Gold, which was flavored with
extract from a rare fruit known as Jingo, which
only grew in the remote jungles of the Yucatan
Peninsula in Mexico. As it turned out, most people
were allergic to Jingo in its raw concentrated
form, as it possessed unusual biochemical
properties that interacted with the human
nervous system. Fascinated, Relf studied
chemistry and eventually traveled to the Yucatan
to collect Jingo fruit samples. He isolated and
refined the active compound into a highly
concentrated extract, which upon ingesting
radically transformed Relf's body, triggering
within it a latent metagene that granted him
superhuman elasticity. He found he could
stretch, twist, and reshape himself into almost
any form imaginable. Inspired by the flash in
Central City and determined to use his newfound
gifts for good, Relf adopted the heroic identity
of Elongated Man. You can learn more about Flash in
our Flash vs. Quicksilver duel episode. Unique
among superheroes, Relf never concealed his
identity and instead embraced fame as a celebrity
detective. Early in his heroic journey, he met
Su-Dirban, a spirited and wealthy socialite. The
two married and quickly became one of the most
beloved and enduring couples in the superhero
community. As a close ally of the Flash, Relf
became an honored member of the Justice League of
America. Known for his trademark nose twitch
whenever something seemed to miss, Relf relished
solving mysteries and earned a reputation as one
of the world's greatest detectives. His
lighthearted nature, keen intellect, and
unwavering devotion to Su made him a respected
figure among both heroes and civilians. While
joining the Justice League on countless missions
together, Relf and Su traveled the globe solving
bizarre, supernatural, and otherworldly
mysteries. Though not the most physically
imposing hero, Relf's flexibility and deductive
genius often made him the key to resolving crises
that others couldn't. The couple became
mainstays in the Justice League Europe and later
joined the offbeat Super Buddies team formed by
Maxwell Lord. In addition to his work with
superhero teams, Relf became a liaison between
the mystical and scientific community. He
consulted on arcane-related investigations and
developed a working knowledge of magical
phenomena, which aided in several cases
involving cursed artifacts and
extra-dimensional incursions. His ability to
combine scientific reasoning with open-minded
intuition set him apart for more rigid
detectives. He and Su also developed a rapport
with many of their fellow heroes, forging close
ties with members of the Justice Society and newer
heroes alike. They were frequently called upon
for both mystery-solving expertise and moral
support, becoming regarded as a stabilizing
presence in the heroic community. Relf's humor
and Su's charm made them a welcome addition to
nearly any gathering. Their joyful partnership
came to a tragic end, however, when Su was found
murdered in their home. Investigations revealed
that years earlier, Ralph was shattered by the
loss. His grief consumed him, and he turned to
mysticism in a desperate attempt to resurrect
Sue. After finding Sue's tombstone defaced with a
Kryptonian symbol for resurrection, Ralph
tracked down the vandals and learned of the Cult of
Connor, an organization attempting to bring the
recently deceased Superboy back to life. You can
learn more about Superboy in his duel against
Rogue. The Cult planned to test the resurrection
technique by first attempting to bring back Sue.
Ralph, lost without his wife, joined their cause
and brought four other heroes to the ceremony.
Midway through, however, Ralph deduced it was an
elaborate hoax and tried to stop the ritual. As the
ceremonial building burned, the straw effigy of
Sue, now a flame, crawled toward him and whispered
his name. Devastated, Ralph believed he had
destroyed his only chance at reunion. Ralph
relocated to Marseille under the alias Alvin
Bergson, where he was eventually found by
Detective Chimp, who sought his deductive
expertise. You can learn more about Detective
Chimp in his duel against Howard the Duck. Ralph
joined Detective Chimp and his magical Shadow
Pact team in Egypt, where the Helmet of Nubu began
to speak to Ralph. Eventually, Ralph performed a
resurrection ritual in the Tower of Fate using the
Helmet of Nubu. After donning the helmet and
firing an enchanted gun at it, the illusion
shattered, revealing that the supervillain
Felix Faust had posed as Nubu, manipulating Ralph
with the intention to trade his soul to the demon
lord, Nieron. Ralph revealed, however, that he
had known the truth all along and that the ritual he
had performed was actually a binding spell.
Nieron appeared and killed Ralph, unaware the
spell would imprison both him and Faust in the
Tower. Reunited with his wife in the afterlife,
Ralph and Sue remained on the mortal plane as ghost
detectives, solving paranormal cases from
beyond the grave. In post-Flashpoint
continuity, Ralph was alive once again,
portrayed as a private investigator
specializing in metahuman cases, and who had
withdrawn from the public eye after Sue's
apparent death in a metahuman-related accident.
Isolated and emotionally fractured, he was also
physically unstable. His body's elasticity
deteriorated from exposure to corrupted
synthetic gingold used in unauthorized
experiments. Ralph's condition worsened until
he was found by Batman and the Flash who brought him
to Star Labs. There, a Medigine Regeneration
Chamber stabilized his molecules and restored
his powers. Grateful for his second chance, Ralph
resumed his role as elongated man. Operating
under the alias Big Shot, he infiltrated the
Seeker Six under the direction of the Riddler who
was manipulating the team under the codename
Mockingbird. Sue, who supposed death had been
fabricated as part of Ralph's cover story, was
later revealed to be alive. Upon reuniting, the
couple reconciled and resumed their
crime-solving partnership, continuing their
adventures together. Powers-wise, elongated
man possesses an elastic body which allows him to
stretch and reshape his physical form,
contorting into nearly any shape with
extraordinary precision. His elasticity also
provides him with enhanced durability and
resistance to physical trauma. He can flatten
himself, elongate his limbs, slip through narrow
spaces, and rebound from impacts that would
incapacitate normal humans. His flexibility is
matched by his brilliant deductive mind. He is a
world-class detective whose keen instincts and
analytical skills rival the best investigators
on earth. And that's elongated man. Elongated man
is probably, I think, an underrated character,
but with the worst damn origin story in existence.
He basically drank fruit juice and became
stretchy. Hey man, it was the Silver Age! What are
you gonna do? Silver Age doesn't cut it. Like, that
sounds more like a Golden Age-type origin story.
So even saying it's the Silver Age is just sad. Out
of all the origin stories we've discussed on this
podcast, that's the worst one. And probably will
remain the worst one. At the very least, it's
unique, alright? Fruit juice? Come on! Inhuman
origins? Way better, you know? The whole
backstory with the Kree experimentation on early
humans, special genes that give them powers when
they're exposed to an alien element. That's how
you do a Silver Age origin story right there. But
you know what's more realistic? Fruit juice! Let
me get into Medusa's backstory. In the hidden city
of Adelene, Medusa-Litha-Melaquin was born into
the Inhuman Royal Family, the daughter of Quillen
and Ember, and sister to Crystal. When she was an
infant, her parents exposed her to the Tarogen
Mist, the mutagenic vapor that unlocks late
in-inhuman traits, which granted her prehensile
crimson hair able to lift great weights,
lash-like whips, and move with the dexterity of
added limbs. You can learn more about Tarogenesis
and the history of the Inhumans in our Shazam vs
Blackbolt dual episode. During adolescence,
Medusa regularly visited her distant cousin
Blackbolt, who was confined in an isolation
chamber because a whisper from his voice could
level mountains. They invented a private sign
language, shared secret conversations through
the glass, and fell in love. Soon after
Blackbolt's 18th birthday, his parents were
accidentally killed when his voice destroyed
their spacecraft. The tragedy placed the young
man on the throne, with Medusa publicly
acknowledged as his betrothed. Early in
Blackbolt's reign, the Alpha Primitives,
Adelene's genetically engineered labor cast,
rebelled. Maximus, Blackbolt's unstable
younger brother, exposed three Alpha Primitives
to experimental Tarogen energy, mutating them
into monstrous beings called the Tricon. Medusa
battled the trio from a sky sled, but the craft
crashed, and the impact left her an amnesiac
wanderer. She drifted through Europe, where she
was discovered by the villain, Wizard, who
recruited Medusa into his frightful four team.
Wizard's mind-altering devices kept her
obedient while she fought the Fantastic Four on
several occasions. Eventually, Medusa's
cousin, the Inhuman Warrior Gorgon, arrived on
Earth to retrieve her. Medusa was returned to
Adelene, where the shock of familiar
surroundings restored her memory. During her
absence, Maximus had seized the throne and
declared Medusa his future queen. He sealed the
city inside an energy dome generated from
negative zone particles. Blackbolt used his
devastating voice to shatter the barrier,
freeing the Inhumans but leveling large portions
of their capital. With Adelene's secrets now
exposed, the royal family undertook a diplomatic
mission among humans. In New York, Medusa was
manipulated into battling Spiderman, and the
Wizard briefly recaptured her before she escaped
again. Medusa soon forged friendlier ties with
humanity. When Susan Richards left the Fantastic
Four, Medusa filled her vacancy, fighting
threats on Earth and in deep space attending
Crystal's marriage to the speedster
Quicksilver. You can learn more about the
Fantastic Four in their duel against the Justice
Society and more about Quicksilver in his duel
against the Flash. After Susan Richards returned
to the Fantastic Four, Medusa rejoined Blackbolt
and guided Adelene through environmental
crises. Earth's pollution threatened in human
biology, so the city was relocated to the
oxygen-rich blue area on the moon. There,
Blackbolt and Medusa married, formalizing her
position as queen consort and royal interpreter.
A new conflict flared when Medusa became
pregnant. The genetics council ruled the fetus
too dangerous, fearing it might combine
Maximus's madness with Blackbolt's power and
ordered termination. Defying them, Medusa fled
to Earth's deserts and gave birth in secrecy to
Ahura. Returning under truce, she surrendered
the infant for study, unaware the council planned
to trade him to human scientists for Earth
technology. The transport crashed, Ahura
vanished and Medusa sank into depression. Years
later, the boy, aged rapidly by his genetics, was
recovered, declared unstable, and imprisoned in
solitary confinement, much as his father once had
been. Public outrage over the council's
duplicity forced both council and royal family to
advocate Adelene, but political chaos soon
demanded the royals resume their leadership,
still headquartered on the moon. When most of the
Earth's mutants were stripped of their powers by
the Scarlet Witch's magic, Crystal's ex-husband
Quicksilver, stripped of his mutant speed,
sought asylum in Adelene. Medusa granted refuge
before bait him from entering the Tarjan
Chambers. Quicksilver defied her, stole Tarjan
crystals, and fled. In the ensuing turmoil,
Blackbolt snapped at Medusa for misinterpreting
his silent orders before the council, and Maximus
exploited their marital strain by psychically
darkening Medusa's thoughts. Confused, she
visited Maximus in a cell, and under his
influence, they shared a single kiss that
Blackbolt witnessed in anguish. Not long after
the royal family learned Blackbolt had been
replaced by a scroll, a shapeshifting alien
infiltrator. Medusa led an assault into galactic
territory controlled by the Kree Empire,
bargaining her sister Crystal's hand in marriage
to the Kree leader Ronin in exchange for aid,
rescuing Blackbolt and Ahura. You can learn more
about Ronin in his dual episode against Big Barda.
Upon their return, Maximus had fortified Adelene
and converted the city into a starship. The
Inhumans launched a campaign that routed the
scrolls, and, after fierce clashes with the Shiar
Empire, left Blackbolt and the Shiar ruler
apparently dead in a doomsday blast. Medusa,
weeping yet resolute, declared victory against
the Shiar, and assumed sole rule of both Inhumans
and the newly conquered Kree. As queen, she
quelled riots incited by outside agitators and
secretly staged a faux rebellion engineered by
Maximus to prove the royal family's necessity,
defeating it publicly to consolidate authority.
During this period, she represented the Inhumans
on the Illuminati, a clandestine council of
Earth's foremost strategists. Despite those
successes, disaster struck when Blackbolt
detonated a pterogen device while repelling an
attack on Adelene by Thanos. The Inhuman City was
obliterated and a miscarrying pterogen
particles drifted across Earth, awakening
dormant Inhuman genes amongst some humans,
creating new humans. Medusa established new
Adelene at the mouth of the Hudson River, welcomed
the royal family's newly empowered subjects, and
defeated rogue new human factions. She assisted
Blackbolt in saving their son Ahura from the
time-manipulator Kang the Conqueror and guided
him home. You can learn more about Kang in his duel
against Professor Zoom. Elsewhere, scientists
discovered that lingering pterogen clouds were
poisonous to mutants, igniting global tension.
Medusa pursued diplomacy, but hostilities
escalated. Confronted with the looming
extinction of mutants, she chose to destroy the
last pterogen cloud. The decision sacrificed her
people's future ability to undergo
pterogenesis, but it averted worldwide
disaster. Medusa abdicated the throne and
appointed the engineer Iso to guide Adelene under
a more democratic charter. No longer monarchs,
Medusa and Blackbolt led an exploratory mission
to the ruined alien Kree world of Hala. Their outer
space expedition led them to an ancient substance
called Primogen, the source of all pterogen
guarded by the cosmic gardeners known as the
progenitors. During the voyage, Medusa and
Blackbolt reconciled emotionally, agreeing to
stand as partners, but not lovers. The pair
eventually returned to Adelene, their long
severed bond rekindled once more, as I said about
rebuilding their people's future yet again. And
that's Medusa's backstory powers-wise. Medusa
has the enhanced physiology of an inhuman granted
to her through pterogenesis. This includes
greater strength, speed, and durability than any
normal human. She also has trichokinesis, or the
ability to psionically control every strand of
her hair, each one having tensile strength and
durability of an iron wire. With her hair, she can
lift over one and a half tons and she can move it in
any manner imaginable from performing delicate
tasks like threading a needle, creating powerful
whips, or ensnaring opponents. She cannot detect
pain through her hair, but she can feel sensations
through her psionic connection to its strands.
Finally, Medusa is a skilled diplomat and an
experienced fighter. And that's Medusa. I have to
say, elongated man may have kind of a silly origin,
but at least the guy did not marry his cousin. Oh
dang, what is this, Game of Thrones? Kinda. I mean,
they're distant cousins, alright? I don't know
how far removed they are, but uh, yeah, that
thing's kind of common I guess within royalty.
That's a pretty good description though. At their
best, the inhumans kind of feel like a sci-fi Game
of Thrones. That inhuman show should have been so
much better. So much better, I know, right? But now
that we've got the characters' histories and
abilities out of the way, let's speculate on how
one of the 1000 simulated matches will go. The
winners determined by our simulations not our
speculation, but it's fun to imagine how the fight
could play out. AGA9K, what are the rules of our
speculation? Alright, then let's get into it.
Elongated man and Medusa meet on the battlefield?
Who goes first? I'm gonna say that elongated man
starts with his nose twitching, probably, as he
tries to make sense of this new foe before him.
Okay, while elongated man is busy twitching his
nose, Medusa extends her hair downward and uses
her hair like legs to race toward elongated man
moving across the floor, kind of like a Mustang or
something, and she uses some of her hair to wrap him
up and crush him in her hair grasp. She tries at
least because elongated man, he's gonna inflate
his body like a balloon to escape her grasp and he's
gonna quickly contract his body, then stretch his
legs to double kick her right in the gut. Well,
Medusa blocks the double kick because she's gonna
form some of her hair into a shield, right, and her
hair is super durable, so the hair blocks the
attack and then her hair grabs his legs and she also
grabs his arms with other strands of hair and she's
gonna stretch elongated man out just like Taffy
until he snaps. Alright, well as she continues to
stretch him and find out that his limit is really
long, that's when he's gonna shoot his head
forward, you know, stretching his neck to
headbutt her right in the face and just blinding
her from the pain. That was a pretty good move.
Okay, so that's probably gonna hurt her, she drops
his legs and arms, but she's durable, you know,
she's an inhuman, but she's also royally pissed,
okay, so she forms some of her hair into a sharp like
spearhead and kind of like a scorpion tail, she
strikes forward with it and stabs through
elongated man's chest. Damn, okay, well
elongated man, he's essentially immune to blunt
physical force, but he can be pierced or stabbed by
sharpen of objects, but not this time. I'm gonna
say as soon as he feels the initial poke, he's gonna
stretch his chest backward to compensate. And
while she's trying to stab essentially putty,
elongated man is gonna stretch himself really
wide covering Medusa and all of her hair in like a
giant tarp essentially made of his body. And
that's gonna suffocate her beneath him. Couldn't
she just stab him repeatedly with her hair from
under that tarp with like a thousand hair needles?
That's just acupuncture, you know. If anything,
you know, she blocks his chi or some shit. All
right, okay, well then she turns her hair into like
spinning fan blades, which I started doing the
comics once. So she fills this elongated man tarp
with air, which is gonna cause him to rise and lift
off of her like a sheet in the wind. And he doesn't
want to get blown away, so he shrinks back down to
normal size. And at that point, Medusa lashes him
with hundreds of hair whips, just like loud
cracking all over his body, like just like
firecrackers. And he gets whipped to death
basically. Oh, damn. Okay, well, he's going to
expand the size of one of his hands to act as a
barrier between his body and her whips. And sure,
that probably means he's whinsing by how much his
hand hurts, but he'll live. And it's going to give
him enough time to grow his other hand to giant size
and have it reach over his barrier to slam down on
top of Medusa, squashing her into the ground like
whack a mole. All right, okay, so she's like in a
hole in the ground, but she's going to come out of
the hole unscathed because at the very last
second, she used her hair to wrap around her entire
body and form like a hair armor, like a hair suit of
armor type thing. And as she comes out, she lassos
out a strand that wraps around elongated man's
neck and she tightens it just grotting him to
death, like either causing him to die from
strangulation, or like even if he can stretch his
neck and trachea thin enough to still breathe,
she's going to tighten it even more just to take his
head completely off. Match over. Dude, elongated
man, as he's being grotted, I'm going to say he
quickly stretches his fingers down and around
Medusa. So they approach her from behind out of her
line of sight, and the fingers are going to plunge
into her ears, making their way past her skull to
her brain, and it's just going to squeeze it to
death essentially. So she dies before he gets
strangled and now the match is really over. All
right, well, that seems like a good place to end the
match. So either elongated man gets garotted by
Medusa's hair, or he squeezes her brain by
entering her skull through the ear canal. Let's go
ahead and run the simulations and find out which of
these two scenarios ends up happening by coming
back with a winner. AG9K, hit it! Inputting data,
running calculations, processing results,
simulations complete. All right, I liked this
matchup. I wasn't quite sure how it would go. I was
hoping it wouldn't be too much like our Plastic Man
vs. Mr. Fantastic dual episode, but I thought this
would be neat because it's really a stretchy guy
versus a woman who makes her hair stretch, and I was
wondering how that would affect the stats, right?
Because in some ways, Medusa stretching her hair
gives her an advantage, because it's not really
her making herself vulnerable, it's just her
hair, right? So she has pretty damn good
evasiveness, although elongated man, of course,
is really damn evasive himself. Right, we did say
that elongated man is faster than Medusa, just
because of the nature of his powers, and he's an
ally of Flash who he's been able to keep up with.
Yeah, he can stretch his legs like hundreds of feet
and make huge strides, whereas Medusa can't
quite, it doesn't really do that to the same
effect. We also said that elongated man was more
durable considering how malleable his body is.
Yeah, Medusa is durable if she gets hit, but she
herself is not malleable, it's her hair. So in
terms of using her hair defensively, we put those
types of moves in the evasiveness category as
opposed to durability. And the only other stat
category where elongated man came out on top was
intellect, considering he's an incredibly
intelligent and deductive thinker, but Medusa
was not only more versatile, but also had a greater
damage potential, surprisingly. Oh yeah, her
hair is really strong, I've seen her knock around
characters like Thing and Iron Man with her hair.
We also interestingly said that Medusa had
greater perception because of her connection to
her hair. Yeah, she has psionic feelers with her
hair essentially. So taking all of these stats
into consideration, Joseph, who do you think came
out on top? I don't know, I'm gonna say Medusa, I
think it's gonna be close though. Big surprise,
biased. Is it though? Is it a surprise that I would
guess the Marvel character? Because I don't think
so. What is a surprise is how many of our Instagram
followers that voted in our poll that we put up
chose elongated man as the likely winner, because
he got 63% of the votes. Now both of these
characters, I would say are pretty obscure,
potentially, though Medusa is probably more
obscure than elongated man, and that's why I think
he got the edge in the poll. I wouldn't know how to
quantify that, but maybe we just did. Well, let's
find out who won. AJ9K, the results please.
Alright, the winner between elongated man and
Medusa is Medusa. Yes, but it was so close. Medusa
won 514 of the 1000 matches, or 51.4%, compared to
elongated man, who only won 486 of his matches.
It's a coin toss, pretty much. I wonder what put
Medusa over the edge, I bet you it was probably her
inhuman physiology. Well, actually it was her
damage. Okay, so her inhuman powers then. Which
makes sense, I mean like her hair can perform a lot
of the same feats that elongated man stretching
can, but I think her hair is a whole lot more durable
and strong than elongated man's body. Well,
considering it's like iron fibers, yeah, you
could probably make that argument. But that
particular stat being that much higher than
elongated man doesn't surprise me, considering
her ranking within the inhuman royal family. Like
the royal family tends to be amongst the most
powerful inhumans. That's true. So for her to be
queen means that she could basically take on
almost any other inhuman, right? Blackbolt is
just insanely powerful, so I don't know. I mean,
she's shut him up a few times with her hair, so it's
hard to say. It all depends on, you know, how the
story's being written. We could run the stats, who
knows. Wait, you're saying she's blocked his
speech with her hair? She kept his jaw closed so he
couldn't speak. Gotcha. Okay. Wow. Well, I gotta
say, I'm not surprised that this match was this
close. I assumed it was going to be this close. It's
always nice when the matches are close like this,
because it means it was just a good pairing. And
when I lose, I think it just means that Jonathan has
to respect the Marvel character even more when
it's close. That being said, I don't have to
respect any DC character, Marvel wins. So
elongated man could take his dumb nose twitching,
ginkgo biloba, take an ass, and get the hell out of
here. Well, you know what? At the end of the day,
elongated man gets to go home to a beautiful wife
who I'm sure is very satisfied by him in multiple
ways. And therefore he's the true winner. I was
wondering when you were going to go for the dick
joke. Elongated man is just, it's just the worst
name, the character with the worst name and the
worst origin. There's actually a panel in the
comics where elongated man is like, I love my wife
because she's been around guys like Superman, it
still loves me. And I'm like, we all know why. That
does it for this dual guys. AJ and IK help close this
out. Max Destruction, Senjoh World, and Console
Combat. In our next episode, we are doing another
dual this time between the insanely powerful
characters, Mr. Mxyz Spitalik, and Impossible
Man. But that does it for this episode. We want to
give a big thanks to our executive producers, John
Staroski, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Balcom,
Mickey Mathen-Gian, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi
Yatyn, Austin Wazalowski, AJ Dunkerly, Nick
Obanto, Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Speese,
Dean Moleski, Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, Josh
Leiner, Mike Williams, Oscar Galvez, and Paul
Graves for helping make this podcast possible.
And we'll talk to you guys next week. A popin' away,
true believers.