This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi, welcome to
the DynaMic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin
brother, Marvelous Joe. And there are only four
episodes left of the weekly show of DynaMic Duel
after this one, which will be a team duel, our final
Christmas duel in which we're going all out by
pitting the Legion of Super-Pets against the Pet
Avengers. It is the pet duel to end all pet duels.
Yeah, typically, for the most part, around
Christmas time, the show does a silly animal duel
and this is like the ultimate version of that.
Yeah, I think there were only two years where we
didn't do like pet heroes. That was Alfred versus
Jarvis and Keelix versus Herbie. But those are
like robot pets. Yeah, exactly. It still counts.
But we're going to tell you about each team's
backstories before running the stats and finding
out which team would win before that we're not
going to break down the comic book movie news
because we're recording this episode early and
there isn't any yet. Yeah, we're recording it
early due to the upcoming holiday break. This
episode will drop just a few days before
Christmas, so we just want to wish everyone a happy
holiday. As always, we list our segment times in
our episode description, so feel free to check out
the show notes if you want to skip ahead to a
particular topic. Our artificially intelligent
duel simulator, AJ9K, has a quick message for our
listeners, so listen up. Hello, these are the
final episodes of Dynamic Jules Weekly podcast,
leading up to our grand finale on January 20th. We
hope you've enjoyed the past 10 years of Marvel and
DC duels and reviews, and we'd love for you to stick
with us as we count down these last episodes. We're
inviting you, the listener, to help us close out
the show by visiting dynamicduel.com over the
next few weeks and clicking the red microphone
button in the bottom right corner to leave us a
voicemail that we'll play during the final
episode. Tell us what first got you into DC or
Marvel, how long you've been listening, a
favorite episode or moment, or anything else you
want to share about what the podcast has meant to
you. Your messages will be aired and responded to
on the January 20th finale. Again, head to
dynamicduel.com and leave your final message. We
would love to hear from you. Pip Pip Cheerio.
Thanks AJ9K, and thanks to everyone who takes the
time to call in and leave a parting voicemail. Be
sure to tune into the other shows on the Dynamite
Podcast Network this week, including the Konsole
Kombat podcast, where hosts John and Dean
simulate battles between popular video game
characters. In yesterday's episode, they found
out who'd win between Pac-Man and Yoshi. Over on
the Max Destruction podcast, hosts Scotty and
Gilly pet your favorite action heroes from film
and television against each other. On Wednesday,
the Macho Twins are learning who would win in a
fight between Santa Claus from Violence Night and
Krampus. That's going to be a really good one. I'm
looking forward to that one. On the Senjoh World
podcast, hosts Zachary Hepburn speculates on
fights between fan favorite anime and manga
characters. In his next episode, Zach's
revealing who'd win between Shigyo Kageyama, aka
Mob from Mob Psycho 100, and Tatsumaki the tornado
of terror from One Punch Man. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our show
notes to listen to all of the shows in the DynaMic
Podcast Network. And now that that's done, quick
to the main event! Alright, now let's find out who
is going to win in the ultimate pet team duel
matchup of the Legion of Super Pets against the pet
Avengers. Okay, the Legion of Super Pets versus
the pet Avengers. Of course, you may also know the
Legion of Super Pets as the League of Super Pets
because they had a film with that title a few years
ago. Oh yeah, that's right. Yeah, they weren't
called the Legion, they were called the League.
I'm assuming to tie them into the Justice League.
Why are they called the Legion of Super Pets in the
comics? Because the Legion of Super Heroes were
the ones that assembled the team initially. Oh,
oh, interesting. Okay. Yeah, the pet Avengers
have not had their own movie, nor is one slated, but
a few of the people on my roster have appeared in
films, including Throg. He was like an Easter egg
in the Loki show. Lockjaw, of course, was in the
God-awful in humans television series. Lockheed
played a really cool part in the New Mutants movie.
Oh, that's right. And of course, Cosmo was in the
Guardians of the Galaxy film, the third one. And I
guess Cosmo has been the most prominent pet
Avenger on your team in terms of like on-screen
media. Right. So not a bad showing for the pet
Avengers. I did really like the League of Super
Pets movie that they put out, though. I liked it
more than I wanted to. We reviewed that film a
couple of years ago. Well, the Super Pets have also
had a cartoon starring Krypto and Ace. So they're
just better, like all around, you know? Everyone
knows them. They're really popular, really cool.
It's so sad that most of them are going to be going
over the Rainbow Bridge in the course of this
upcoming fight. Throg is going to send them there
using the Bifrost. I should probably save that for
the speculation. Yeah, what are you doing? Now I
know your plan. But speaking of the speculation,
first to explain the methodology behind our
duels, let's go to our sentient dual simulator,
Alfred Jarvis, 9000. AJ9K tell our listeners how
you go about determining a winner in our dual
matchups. Yes, of course, sir. The way I determine
a winner between the two teams is by running 1,000
Monte Carlo simulations between every character
on each team using their statistics. A Monte Carlo
simulation is a probabilistic model used to
determine outcomes through random sampling. In
this case, I randomize the statistics along a
normal distribution as a way to simulate the many
variables that can occur during battle. The stat
parameters are based on the official Marvel power
grid, from which the DC characters statistics are
extrapolated. Additional stat categories are
included such as range, damage potential,
versatility and perception in order to create a
more detailed and accurate simulation. The
results of the 49,000 simulations provide a
percentage of wins for each character on both
teams. The team with the higher average win rate is
declared the victor as they have a higher
probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither team should win 100%
of the matches. The comic book stories have shown
that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman, so the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks, AJ9K.
Before we run the simulations, though, we like to
break down each team's histories and rosters
before improvising a scenario on how we imagine
one of the thousands of simulations would play
out, beat for beat. And it is my turn to go first with
the DC team's backstory. So let me tell you all
about the Legion of Superpets. During a temporal
crisis involving the alien brain globes, the
Legion of Super Heroes, who you can learn more
about in their team duel against the new mutants,
determined that the beings were attempting to
influence Earth's past through indirect
temporal interference using the pets of high
profile historical figures to counter the threat
without destabilizing the timeline. The Legion
selected super powered animals whose senses and
instincts could track and counter the threat with
minimal disruption. Under the coordination of
Brainiac five with Saturn girl providing
telepathic oversight and communication,
several animals were gathered from different
points in history and brought to the 30th century
operating together for the first time. Krypto the
super dog, Strixie the super cat, Beppo the super
monkey and Comet the super horse confronted the
brain globes, disrupting and neutralizing their
influence on the timeline. Following the
mission, Saturn girl formally designated the
animals as the Legion of Superpets with chameleon
boys, shape shifting pet, Prody the second
joining the team before the animals were
eventually returned to their respective eras.
Following the multiverses collapse after the
crisis on infinite Earth's, the Legion of
Superpets did not operate as an active team,
though various super pets continue to appear
alongside their individual allies pets such as
Krypto and Ace the bat hound operated as
supporting characters as did Wonder Romans pet
Jumper, one of the battle trained Kangas raised on
Themyscira. Kangas sometimes referred to as sky
Kangas were bred by the Amazon's for
extraordinary leaping ability and long distance
traversal capable of crossing oceans, hostile
terrain, planetary bodies and even mythic
boundaries in a single bound. Jumper formed a bond
with Wonder Roman and served as her mount during
multiple engagements, particularly in
conflicts involving mythological threats.
Jumper accompanied Wonder Roman both on and
beyond Themyscira and soil, participating in
confrontations with hostile forces and
assisting during expeditions that required
mobility and resilience beyond conventional
transport. Like the invisible jet, another
prominent pets amongst DC's most well known
champions was Toppo, an unusually intelligent
octopus native to the seas of Atlantis. After
entering the service of Aquaman, Toppo became
involved in numerous undersea operations,
particularly those requiring infiltration,
sabotage or interaction with Atlantean and
surface world technology. His dexterity and
problem solving ability allowed him to
manipulate machinery, disable control systems
and operate complex equipment despite lacking
humanoid form. For a time, he was depicted as a
colossal undersea monster known as a Kraken, but
was later reverted back to being an octopus in
continuity. A variation on the Superpet team
concept did appear in far future continuity
during the events of the 853rd century. In that
era, animal based teams such as the Justice Legion
of Super Zoomorphs and the Legion of Super
Familiars operated alongside the Justice Legion
A, a future incarnation of the Justice League.
After the Flashpoint event reset DC's continuity
past and future, Krypto was alerted to a situation
involving a rash of dog nappings across Gotham.
Enlisting Titus on his mission to rescue the dogs,
Krypto went to Detective Chimp for help who
recounted the Legion of Superpet's last mission
in which Clay faces pets. The shapeshifting Clay
Critter died during a battle at Gotham Zoo with
various villainous pets such as Dexter, the Red
Lantern and Harley Quinn's hyenas, Bud and Lou.
Streekey the Supercat evidently blamed Krypto
for Critter's death and initially refused to help
Krypto on the new mission to save the kidnapped
dogs. Joined by Flexi, Plastic Man's elastic
parrot, the trio tracked down the dogs and their
abductor, a green-skinned alien who was
attempting to free Earth's pets from their human
masters. When Streekey brought Batcow to the
fray, the team was able to trap the alien and
deliver the missing dogs to Wayne Manor, forcing
Robin and Superboy to find their owners. Later,
after Batman was captured during a mission, Ace
the Bathound was taken and imprisoned alongside
other animals for experimentation, including a
trained grizzly bear, a pickpocketing squirrel,
a cybernetically enhanced chicken and an
unusually fast tortoise. After escaping
confinement, the team tracked down and rescued
Batman from the Joker and his underground fight
club. Though the chicken was killed during the
mission, the other animals survived, living on
the Wayne Manor estate, though Batman gave the
tortoise to the flash. Recently, Ace and Krypto
attempted to recruit Nightwing's three-legged
dog Haley, aka Bitewing, into the Legion of
Superpets on a mission to rescue Streekey from an
orbital satellite owned by Menagerie Man, who had
been abducting animals to form a private army.
Alongside Jumper the Kanga, Badge the Squirrel,
Gleek the Wonder Monkey, and Batcow, the Cow,
Bitewing found Streekey in the Menagerie, while
also managing to help free other super pets such as
Flexi, Wonder Dog, Toppo, Dexter, Bud and Lou,
Beppo the Super Monkey, and some Staro drones,
among others. After Menagerie Man's defeat, the
Legion returned to Earth to help the abducted
animals find homes, though Haley declined to
become an official member of the team. And that's
the Legion of Superpets backstory. Now, for my
seven-member roster for the Legion of Superpets,
I'm going with Krypto, Superman's Dog, who
possesses all of his powers and is a
representative of the original team, which was
comprised entirely of Superman's pets. I'm also
including Ace the Bat Hound, Batman's highly
trained canine operative, Jumper, Wonder Romans
the Moskeren Kanga, with exceptional strength
and leaping power, Badge the Green Lantern, the
Squirrel-like alien protector of Sector 1014,
and successor to Chip, who we had to duel with
against Rocket Raccoon. I'm also including
Toppo, Aquaman's highly intelligent and
stealthy octopus friend, the terrific What's It,
a durable tortoise with super speed like the
Flash, and finally, Flexi, a parrot with Plastic
Man's shapeshifting powers, though it's unclear
as to whether he's an actual parrot or a piece of
Plastic Man that thinks it is. That's hilarious.
We forgot to mention earlier when we were talking
about the pets' cinematic appearances that Toppo
played a sizable role in the Aquaman The Lost
Kingdom movie. Right, that's correct. Although
in that movie, his name wasn't Toppo. Toppo was the
task force that he was a part of. OK, he was pretty
cool, though. I am surprised to learn that Robot
Chicken used to be a member of the Legion of
Superpets. Yeah, I think it was supposed to be a
cyborg analog. The superhero cyborg from the
time. Yes, yes. Yeah. OK, so his pet is Robot
Chicken. Interesting. It makes sense, though,
because Robot Chicken is owned by Cartoon
Network, which is owned by WB, which also owns DC.
DC has such a vast universe of pet characters, like
almost every hero in DC Comics has some kind of
animal analog that exists in their pet universe.
Yeah, almost. Yeah, it's much larger than
Marvel's. But that's a good thing. We don't want to
make DC's larger than Marvel in general, my guy. I
don't think so. I don't know about that. I'm pretty
sure they're about the same. I'm talking about
endowment wise. You're stupid. Let me go ahead and
get into the backstory of the pet Avengers. The
story of the pet Avengers begins with Lockjaw, who
is the genetically altered dog of the inhuman
royal family created through experimental
terror genesis and bonded to the ruling house of
Aegon, possessing the innate ability to teleport
himself and others across vast distances over
Earth and space. Lockjaw became indispensable to
the inhumans as both transportation and
protector. Over years spent moving the inhuman
royal family through political upheavals,
exiles and interstellar conflicts. Lockjaw
developed a reputation for intelligence and
judgment that went far beyond instinctive
obedience. You can learn more about the inhumans
and their duel against the Wildcats. The chain of
events that let the formation of the pet Avengers
begin when Mr. Fantastic of the Fantastic Four
arrived in Adalan, the inhuman city located in the
blue area of the moon. Mr. Fantastic sought Black
Bolt's cooperation in locating the Infinity
Gems, which were six ancient cosmic artifacts
tied to the fundamental aspects of existence that
had begun resurfacing throughout the universe.
Unknown to Mr. Fantastic and most of the inhuman
court, Lockjaw had already encountered one of the
gems. Hidden within Adalan itself, the Mind Gem
had come into Lockjaw's possession, enhancing
his intelligence and granting him telepathic
abilities. Through contact with the Mind Gem,
Lockjaw became aware not only of the existence of
the other gems, but of the catastrophic danger
posed if they were gathered by a single wielder. By
then reading Mr. Fantastic's Slots, Lockjaw
learned of Thanos and his past dominion over the
gems. Rather than alerting Earth's heroes or the
inhumans, Lockjaw acted on the belief that a
quieter, less visible approach stood a better
chance of success. Using his teleportation
abilities, he set out to locate the remaining gems
himself, choosing allies who would not draw
attention. Lockjaw's first recruits were
animals already connected to heroes and
accustomed to danger. His first recruit was
Throg, the Frog of Thunder, who wielded a fragment
of Thor's enchanted hammer, Mjolnir, that
granted him powers proportionate to the God of
Thunder. Throg was once Simon Walterson, a
grieving human cursed into Frog form after
failing to pay a fortune teller. Living as the Frog
Puttlegub in Central Park, he became a warrior in a
long-running war between frogs and rats. During
one of Loki's schemes, Thor himself was
transformed into a frog and crossed paths with
Puttlegub, helping end the war. When Thor returns
to Asgard, a shard of Mjolnir was left behind.
Puttlegub proved worthy enough to lift it,
transforming into Throg. Lockjaw's next recruit
was Lockheed, the small but formidable alien
dragon who brought a long history of interstellar
combat experience and loyalty forged through his
bond with the X-Man Kitty Pride. Lockheed
originated as a warrior from a dragon-like alien
species known as the Flock. Renowned for fighting
the parasitic Brood aliens, Lockheed left his
people behind after saving Kitty Pride and
followed her to Earth. You can learn more about
Kitty Pride in our Gypsy vs Shadowcat dual
episode. Next on the team was Niels, a cat who was
exposed to extra dimensional energy alongside
his owner, Speedball, of the new warriors. Niels
took on the codename Hairball after developing
the ability to form a kinetic field around himself
that redirects and amplifies all force and energy
exerted against him. You can learn more about
Speedball and the new warriors in their
respective duels against Wally West the Flash and
Infinity Inc. Redwing, who is Falcon's trained
bird and Ms. Lion and Maze Dog, completed
Lockjaw's initial group. Their search for the
gems led first to the Savageland, an isolated
prehistoric preserve hidden in Antarctica.
There the group encountered Zabu, the Sabertooth
Tiger companion of the Jungle Lord Khazar. Zabu
was born in the Savageland, orphaned when man apes
killed his family. Raised among wolves before
striking out alone, Zabu eventually saved the
life of a young man named Kevin Plunder, forming a
bond that would shape Kevin into the Jungle leader
Khazar. Exposure to the gases of the Place of Mists
slowed Zabu's aging and granted him near human
intelligence. You can learn more about the
Savageland in our Parasite vs Sauron dual
episode. Zabu aided the group in locating the Time
Gem and joined their journey. From the
Savageland, Lockjaw transported the animals to
prehistoric Earth, where they recovered the
Space Gem after an encounter with Devil Dinosaur,
whom you can learn more about in his duo alongside
Moongirl against Dorothy Spinner. Continuing
their pursuit, the group traveled beneath the
Atlantic Ocean, where they were swallowed by the
massive creature Giganto. Inside the beast, they
discovered both the Soul Gem and the Reality Gem
before escaping. The final Gem, the Power Gem, was
located at the White House, attached to the collar
of the President's dog. As the animals converged
on their last objective, Thanos arrived, having
tracked the same cosmic energies. When the
animals refused to surrender their gems, Thanos
attacked and killed Miss Lion. In a moment of panic
and grief, Hairball instinctively used the Soul
Gem to resurrect her. Acting together, the
animals combined the power of the Infinity Gems
and under Lockjaw's direction defeated Thanos
and trapped him in another dimension. With the
team victorious, Miss Lion named the group the Pet
Avengers. Before returning the Gems, Lockjaw
used the Mind Gem to establish a psychic link
between the animals, ensuring they could find one
another again if needed. Though the Pet Avengers
initially separated, the psychic bond
eventually drew them back together. When Throg
vanished while searching for meaning beyond
Central Park, the group reunited and traveled to
the Himalayas, becoming entangled in a conflict
within the dream realm. There, they confronted
creatures unleashed by the Fallen One and worked
to return displaced mythical beings to their
homes. Later, when Thor, Captain America, and
Iron Man were transformed into frogs by the dragon
Fin-Fink Fooom, Thor sent a telepathic distress
call that reached Throg. The Pet Avengers
responded, eventually aiding Fin-Fink Fooom,
when they learned his actions were meant to
protect endangered dragon eggs. Their
intervention briefly placed them at odds with the
Avengers, but the conflict ended peacefully. You
can learn more about Fin-Fink Fooom in his duel
against Star-O, the Conqueror. In recognition of
their actions, the Avengers constructed the Pet
Avengers Mansion to serve as the team's
headquarters. That's the Pet Avengers backstory
for the seven-member team duel. I'm including
some famous pet and animal characters from
outside the comic Pet Avengers roster, that
better pair up against your Legion of Super Pets.
So in addition to Lockjaw, Throg, Lockheed,
Hairball, and Zabu, I'm also including Cosmo the
Space Dog and Jeff the Land Shark. Now Cosmo the
Space Dog has already had a duel against Dexstar,
the Red Lantern. Cosmo began as an Earth dog
launched into orbit by the Soviet space program.
An exposure to cosmic radiation granted him
telepathy, telekinesis, heightened
intelligence, and extended life. Lost in space,
Cosmo eventually became Chief of Security on
Nowhere, which is a space station formed from the
severed head of a celestial, and Cosmo operated as
a cosmic defender and ally to the Guardians of the
Galaxy, whom you can learn more about in their duel
against the Doom Patrol. Jeff the Land Shark is a
fan favorite and a personal favorite. He's new to
this podcast. He's actually the pet of Gwenpool
and formerly the pet of Kate Bishop Hawkeye. He was
created by MODOK, the villainous leader of the AIM
organization, as part of a line of engineered land
sharks. Adopted rather than weaponized, Jeff
demonstrated heightened intelligence,
loyalty, and adaptability that placed him firmly
among Earth's heroic animals. You can learn more
about his creator MODOK in his duel against Hector
Hammond. So that's the pet Avengers lineup for
this duel. Again, it's Lockjaw, the Inhuman Dog,
Lockheed, the Purple Pet Dragon, Hairball, the
Bouncing Cat, Throg, the Frog of Thunder, Zabu,
the Saber Tooth Tiger, Cosmo, the Space Dog, and
Jeff the Land Shark. Initially, I was thinking
about going with Chewie, aka Goose, in the movies.
He is a flurkin who you may remember from the
Captain Marvel movies, but I ended up replacing
him with Hairball, not only because Hairball was a
prominent member of the pet Avengers, but also
because I feel like between Jeff the Land Shark and
like Zabu, I don't think Goose really brought too
much more to the table. Yeah, initially, I was
going to include Gleek, the Wonder Twins monkey,
who we've actually put in a duel against Hit
Monkey, but I decided to go with Flexi instead
because I thought he was a better representative
for Prody the Second, one of the early members of
the Legion since they're both shapeshifters.
Yeah, and Hairball was a better pairing with
what's it, the Flash Turtle. Right. So really, the
pairings are Krypto and Throg, Ace with Zabu,
Jumper with Lockjaw, What's It with Hairball,
Badge the Green Lantern with Cosmo the Space Dog,
Toppo with Jeff the Land Shark, and Flexi with
Lockheed. And we do these pairings in order to
ensure general fairness between the rosters and
the overall matchup. These collide in Heroes
Clash. One podcast network rises above the rest.
Prepare yourself for the ultimate showdowns in
comic books, video games, movies, and anime. The
Dynamite Podcast Network presents Console
Combat, where video game legends brawl every
Monday. Dynamic Duel, where comic book titans
smash every Tuesday. Max Destruction, where TV
and action heroes battle every Wednesday. And
Sendro World, where anime champions clash every
Thursday. Join us as we speculate on the matches
and armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge
victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com where we
settle the debate and settle the score. But now
that we've got their histories and the rosters out
of the way, let's speculate on how one of the
thousands of simulated matches will go. The
winning team is determined by simulations, not
the speculation, but it's fun to imagine how the
fight could play out. A.J. and N.K., what are the
rules of our speculations? Well, I should say
there are no rules, other than the teams have no
prior knowledge of the other going into the fight.
All they are aware of starting out is that the other
side is a threat that needs to be eliminated. For
the speculation, the groups will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the match
itself, as no environmental statistics are
considered in my simulations. The teams must earn
victory on their own merit. Alright, then let's
get into it. The Legion of Super Pets and the Pet
Avengers meet on the battlefield. Who goes first?
I'll say that what's it starts off since he's the
resident speedster. And he's going to begin by
running circles around the pet Avengers,
creating this whirlwind tornado that hampers the
pet Avengers vision and also even lifts some of the
lighter ones like hairball into the air. And with
the pet Avengers hampered by this tornado, Jumper
is going to spring into action, just pinballing
between each one, knocking them all to the ground
with their super hard kicks. You mean Jumper jumps
right into Frog Yulnir, which is the name of Frog's
enchanted hammer, and Jumper gets knocked the
fuck back because while the pet Avengers were
trapped in what's its tornado, Frog spun his
hammer in the opposite direction to create a
counter whirlwind. So with the wind dissipated,
Cosmo sees what's it just running around and Cosmo
telekinetically flips the turtle onto his shell.
So what's it's not going to be running anywhere for
a while on his back? Alright, that's a good one. I'm
going to say Badge is going to fly into the air and
he's going to create this huge bazooka that looks
like a hollowed out tree trunk. And he's like, suck
on these nuts! And he starts launching softball
sized acorns at the pet Avengers. Well, that's
going to cause the pet Avengers to scatter and
Lockjaw is going to teleport behind Badge and just
snatch him out of the air in his jaws. And he's going
to land onto the ground in the middle of the Legion
of Superpets with this massive thud, because
Lockjaw's a huge dog, and Lockjaw shakes Badge
like a chew toy, snapping Badge's neck. I mean,
Badge would be able to escape by constructing like
a giant branch that pries Lockjaw's mouth open.
And then Ace, from his utility collar, he's going
to toss a tear gas pellet down Lockjaw's throat
poisoning him. Except that Lockjaw would just
teleport out of the way, so the tear gas misses and
Ace just tear gassed his own teammate, Krypto.
Meanwhile, Lockheed is going to swoop over to
Flexi, the parrot, and Lockheed shoots a fireball
from his mouth that just melts Flexi into a puddle.
I'm going to say Flexi stretches out of the way to
dodge that fireball, because Toppo saw Lockheed
swooping in and blinded him with a squirt of ink
into his dragon eyes. So not only does the fireball
miss, it hits hairball instead, and Lockheed
crashes right into Zabu. Okay, Zabu would get
knocked over, yeah, but hairball would be fine,
like the fireball would just bounce off of his
kinetic field. And that's when hairball bounces
into action. He's going to jump over to Ace, he's
going to bounce off of him and crash into Badge, and
then bounce off of him. And now he has all this
kinetic energy stored up in the form of these neon
colored balls surrounding him, and hairball just
unloads that kinetic energy like a volley of
cherry bomb explosives over at Krypto, who just
gets bombarded from all sides. Hairball is a cool
character. I forgot that he existed. To me, he's
even probably more dangerous than Speedball
because he has claws. Right, he's terrifying.
Yeah. Okay, so Krypto gets bombarded. It would
knock him around for sure. But I mean, hairball
just pissed him off now. And so he's going to growl
at hairball and then just freeze him with his
freeze breath, putting him on ice. And then Flexi
flies over to Jeff the Land Shark, dive bombing him
and shape shifting into a cannonball that
straight up knocks Jeff out. Jeff would just open
his mouth and swallow the cannonball. You know,
like Jeff has eaten the Infinity Gauntlet before.
I'm pretty sure he can handle a cannonball and he's
just going to lick his lips and be like, yum. All
right. Shit. Flexi, you know, he's probably
freaking out in Jeff's stomach, but he's going to
transform into a spiked ball. Just damaging all of
Jeff's internal organs. Yeah, that would
definitely give Jeff indigestion. So what he's
going to do, he's going to puke up Flexi into like
this gross puddle, like a puddle with a parrot
head. And Flexi is like gasping for air now that
he's out of Jeff's stomach. But Jeff is going to
snatch him off the ground and he's going to
forcibly fashion Flexi into this red cape, kind of
like Krypto's cape. And then Jeff is going to
strike a pose kind of like Superman. He turns into
Super Jeff, we'll say. What? And yeah, he does
stuff like this. He puts on costumes and Super Jeff
then leaps over to Toppo, just chomping down onto
one of Toppo's tentacles. And, you know, Toppo's
going to flail around, but Jeff is not going to let
go. All right. Well, that's happening. Jumper is
going to spring toward Lockjaw and just punch the
dog right in the nose repeatedly. Like it's a speed
bag. And then she's going to finish off her combo by
leaning back on her tail and kicking Lockjaw so
hard that he literally leaves the planet's orbit.
What? Yeah, her legs are that strong. Okay. Well,
hopefully her neck is strong because Zabu pounces
on Jumper and he sinks his giant fangs that are like
10 inches long into her neck, taking her out. Wow.
It's the circle of life. It happens. And meanwhile
Lockheed is going to thaw out hairball from being
frozen using his flame breath. So hairball is
free. All right. Well, badge is going to trap Zabu
in a green cage construct and is going to pull out
his fangs on all of his teeth with a pair of pliers
that he created. So now Zabu is just all gums. And
what's it? You know, he's flipped back over on a
shell. He's back on his feet. He's going to slam
into Jeff, the Land Shark at full speed like a
missile, which he was able to do because both Topo
and Flexi were choking Jeff out because Jeff was
dumb enough to use Flexi as a cape. And you know,
Topo has other tentacles. Jeff's out. You can't,
you can't hurt Jeff the Land Shark, man. It's Jeff.
Jeff had it coming. Well, everyone's going to be
pissed about this. They're going to be shocked
that Jeff was hurt because Jeff is like the cutest
thing ever. Throg's not going to have it. So he
leaps into the air and brings his hammer down onto
What's It just straight up stomping a turdy to mush
like Super Mario. I mean, What's It has a really
durable shell, but it's probably not strong
enough to stop Frog Mjolnir or whatever you call
it. Frog Mjolnir. Whatever. Meanwhile, Ace and
Zabu are scoring off. And when this toothless Zabu
lunges, Ace is just going to front flip over him and
plant a small taser disk on the scruff of his neck,
which he then triggers. And it's going to fry
Zabu's nervous system. So he's out. A front flip.
You think Ace is like a badass or something? Hell
yeah, I do. He's not that cool. He's lucky that Zabu
didn't have fangs anymore, is what I'll say. Well,
that's happening. Cosmo is going to take control
of Flexi's mind using his telepathy and he's going
to make Flexi transform into the Kono shame, like
that Kono collar that dogs get after the vet. Yeah.
And Cosmo is going to telekinetically place that
over Ace. And then he's going to force Flexi to
tighten the collar, which just puts Ace to sleep.
The big sleep. Alright. Meanwhile, Badge has
trapped Hairball inside of a box with a knockout
gas capsule, which he then launches into space. So
Hairball's out. So you just turned Hairball into
Schrodinger's cat. That means he is neither alive
nor unalive. Yeah, good job. We don't know whether
he's alive or dead. We do know though he is
definitely out of the match. Alright. While
that's happening, Lakja, he teleports back to the
battlefield after getting kicked into space by
Jumper. And he is going to drop right down onto
Toppo and just squish him into Octopus soup. I
mean, Lakja is like such a fat sack of crap with so
many folds of skin on his body. I'm sure Toppo can
find a place to squeeze into at the last second,
which he does. And he's going to camouflage
himself so that no one notices him. He's going to
sneak away undetected. Well, I mean, Lockheed
would be able to sense Toppo with his empathic
senses. So Lockheed flies over to Toppo, despite
being camouflaged and just turns him into
Kalimari with his flame breath. Yeah, but I mean
Toppo's pretty agile. So sure, one of his
tentacles gets singed, but then Toppo's just
going to grab Lockheed's neck with his other
tentacles, choking off the flame before swinging
onto his face like a face hugger and biting
Lockheed's jugular with his octopus beak. So
Lockheed's out. That's horrifying. Throg sees
that and he shoots a blast of lightning at Toppo and
that fries Toppo, turning him into delicious
Kalimari. Are you hungry or something? I could go
for some takeout. You want some frog legs? Because
while Throg is distracted taking out Toppo,
Krypto Heat Visions Throg right in half at the
waist. So there you go. I do not love frog legs. So
no, thank you. Too bad you've been served. Okay,
then Lockjaw is going to teleport Krypto into
space to some planet that has a red sun. And then
Lockjaw is going to teleport back into the fight.
So Krypto's out. Wait, how would Lockjaw even know
to do that? Like, I say he teleported him to a planet
with a yellow sun. I mean, something like three
fourths of all suns in the universe are red, like
red dwarfs. So it was just an odds game. Lockjaw had
a three fourths chance to get Krypto in front of a
red sun. That sounds like made up bullshit. No,
that's true. It's true. They far outnumber the
amount of yellow suns in the universe. Well,
that's lame. I'm going to say that Badge is going to
then construct a muzzle over Lockjaw once he
returns and then inject him right away with a
syringe construct. And he's also going to create a
boombox that plays Sarah McLaughlin's song in the
arms of the angels as Lockjaw passes out. What the
fuck? See, this is why last year we went with a dog
show instead of a dog fight. It's just way too sad
for pets to be taking each other out like this.
Borderline Evil. Cosmo, who's still in control of
Flexi, the parrot, Cosmo's going to force him to
shape shift into a sword and he's going to swing it
at Badge. The Badge is going to block it with a
shield construct and then form a sword of his own.
Alright, so yeah, Cosmo and Badge are going to
sword fight with their sword constructs, but you
forget that Cosmo's sword construct is Flexi, so
when Badge cleaves through Cosmo's sword, he just
took out Flexi the parrot. Well, okay, so it's just
Badge and Cosmo now then. So, alright, suddenly
this tall green forest is going to appear around
Cosmo and from the trees he suddenly sees
thousands of green eyes appear before this
massive swarm of squirrel construct creatures
attack Cosmo simultaneously. Just overwhelming
his telekinesis and defeating Cosmo the same way
that Squirrel Girl defeated Dr. Doom, Galactus,
and many other Marvel characters more powerful
than Cosmo. First of all, Squirrel Girl did not
defeat Galactus, really, and it certainly wasn't
through an ambush of squirrels like how she
defeated Dr. Doom. Second of all, I don't know how
these squirrels are going to get past Cosmo's
force field, and third of all, Badge thinks that's
what happened, but in reality it was just a
telepathic illusion that Cosmo put into his
squirrel brain using her telepathy. In
actuality, Badge is just an entrant and then Cosmo
shuts his mind down. So, match over. Ooh, sorry,
you see Badge put on armor when he was sword
fighting and he was wearing a helmet and per Marvel
rules, you can't telepathically get through a
helmet. No, he just thought that he had a helmet on
his head because it was an illusion. So dumb. We can
go ahead and leave the match there. Either the
Legion of Superpets wins by ambushing Cosmo with a
Legion of Green Construct Squirrels, or the Pet
Avengers wins because all of that was an illusion
and Badge gets his mind shut down. Let's go ahead
and input all the characters and team stats, run
the simulations, and come back with a winner.
AG9K, hit it. Okay, this is a fun match. I'm really
glad we got a chance to do this as our last holiday
pet duel. I like to both of these lineups a lot.
Same, and they came out fairly comparable to each
other in terms of their stats. When you look at the
overall team stats, the greatest advantage that
DC had over Marvel was durability. A lot of the DC
characters like Krypto and Jumper and Green
Lantern and even Flexi the Parrot had a lot more
durability over the Pet Avengers and they were
also faster. Like Krypto, What's It, Green
Lantern, they all had really high speed stats
compared to the Pet Avengers. But the Pet Avengers
had the edge in intelligence because Throg has a
human mind and Cosmo the Space Dog is also hyper
intelligent and the Pet Avengers also had an
advantage in perception, largely because,
again, Cosmo is telepathic and no one on the Legion
of Superpets is telepathic. That's right. We said
they were fairly comparable when it came to
fighting skill and invasiveness. The most
powerful character overall was by far Badge the
Green Lantern. I'm so sick of these damn Green
Lanterns. Yeah, Badge totally stomped. He won
86.4% of his matches, which is really high. I mean,
your most powerful member Cosmo only won 77.1.
Yeah, Throg was right up there with Cosmo as well,
winning 74.5% of all his matches. The weakest pet
out of both sides was Jeff the Land Shark. Yeah, but
if we had a stat for a cute factor, he'd win that for
sure. Over Badge? I think not. Yes, over Badge. A
squirrel or a shark? No way a shark is cuter. This
shark is. Does Badge put on silly little cute
costumes all the time? Does Badge have dead shark
eyes? Eh, Jeff's eyes are anything but dead.
They're not like a doll's eyes. But overall,
considering all of these stats, Joseph, who do you
think came out on top in this team? The pet
Avengers. Don't even ask me. Just assume that I'm
going to go with the Marvel side because Marvel
side will always be better. Even though our
Instagram followers don't think so because in our
poll for this matchup, 66% of them sided with the
Legion of Super Pets. As they should, as they
should, if they were smart, which they are. Now
they're dumb as shit, man. Wow, okay. All of you
heard it. Not all of them, just the ones that voted
for DC, of course. I don't know if that makes it any
better, but let's find out who won. AJ9K, the
results, please. Here you are, sir. The winner in
the Team Duel matchup between the Legion of Super
Pets and the pet Avengers is... The Legion of Super
Pets. Whatever. And it was a horrible Christmas.
It was so close. So, so close. They won 50.2% of
their matches compared to the pet Avengers who won
49.8%. That's insanely close. That's the
difference of four matches out of a thousand.
Yeah, it seems like a majority of these Team Duel's
that we do are all really close. Like, I think a
majority of them are within five percentage
points of each other. And I think it's because we
take care to try and make sure that the rosters are
balanced. And when the stats average out in all of
the matches, it just ends up being really close.
This is the closest Team Duel results that we've
had in a long time. We haven't had one this close
since Guardians of the Galaxy vs Doom Patrol.
Interesting. I gotta say, I'm pretty sad this
Christmas season now that the pet Avengers lost.
I'm especially sad for Jeff. He deserved better. I
don't get Jeff. I know nothing about Jeff. I've
never seen Jeff in a comic except for the recent
crossover where he appeared with Krypto. Forget
Jeff. He's lame. Maybe go read a Jeff the Landshark
comic book and then come back and tell me that you
don't love him. Because that's impossible. I'm
good, bro. That sounds like kid shit for Marvel
fans. Or, you know, just people that don't have a
Grinch heart like you. Piece of shit. Why don't you
go read a Jeff the Landshark comic and have your
heart grow three sizes? I think that would be
fatal, honestly. But that does it for this Team
Duel. AJ9K help close this out. Thanks for
listening to Dynamic Duel. Visit the show's
website at dynamicduel.com and follow us on
Instagram at Dynamic Duel Podcast. Don't forget
to listen to the other shows in the Dynamite
Podcast Network, including Max Destruction,
Senjo World, and Console Combat. Our next episode
is going to be our 10th annual Brothers Awards
episode where we countdown the best that Marvel
and DC had to offer in the year 2025. Always look
forward to those episodes. We hope you guys enjoy
them too. Definitely tune in next week and give it a
listen. You can't believe it's already the end of
the year. That's wild. This was a fast year. Yeah.
But that does it for this episode, guys. We want to
give a big thanks to our executive producers, John
Straussky, Zachary Hepburn, Nathaniel Wagner,
Levi Aten, Austin Wieselowski, and Nathaniel
Wagner. AJ Dunkerly, Nick Obanto, Scott Camacho,
Gil Camacho, Adam Spees, Dean Molesky, Devin
Davis, Joseph Kirsting, and Paul Graves for
helping make this podcast possible. We'll talk to
you guys next week. Up, up and away, true
believers. I've breathed out some flames. I wish
you the best. These beasts and their bite. Merry
Christmas to all and to all a good fight.