This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi, welcome to
the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Johnny DC and I'm his twin
brother, Marvelous Joe. And in this episode, we
are doing a duel between the sword-wielding,
fantasy-esque characters of DC's Amethyst and
Marvel's Black Knight. Yeah, Black Knight is
actually one of my favorite characters. I don't
know why, but I've always just kind of gravitated
toward him. I was really excited when he was in the
Eternals movie played by Kit Harrington,
although it was just Dane Whitman. We didn't
actually get to see the Black Knight. Maybe
eventually we'll get to see the character in the
MCU at some point. But I know for a fact that we will
never see Amethyst in live action. That's all I
know. Well, that's not true at all. Actually,
James Gunn has hinted that they're looking into
doing an Amethyst movie. He's hinted at a lot of
things. Okay? Amethyst would actually be a
spectacular movie. It's like the ultimate girl
fantasy story. It's an Isakai where she's like a
forgotten lost princess. It's tailor-made for
that demographic. Cool. Yeah, it is. I have
daughters. It's really cool. I have a daughter
too, but there's no way I'd ever let her watch it.
Not because it wouldn't be good, but because it's
DC and it's forbidden in my house. Oh yeah, I get
that. To this day, like anytime we put in a new
movie, my girls ask me, wait, is this a Marvel
movie? Are you trying to trick us into watching a
Marvel movie? And I'm like, why would I do that? You
indoctrinating piece of shit. Well, I hope Black
Knight wins because of that and we'll get into that
matchup later on this episode. Before that, we're
going to break down the latest comic book,
actually video game news that came out this past
week. Yeah, there's not a lot of movie news, but we
did get the official gameplay trailer for
Marvel's Wolverine. That's going to be on the
PlayStation. As always, we list our segment times
in our episode description, so feel free to check
out the show notes if you want to skip ahead to a
particular topic. Our artificially intelligent
dual simulator, AJ9K, has a quick message for our
listeners. So listen up. Thanks AJ9K and thanks to
everyone who supports the podcast. Guys, be sure
to tune into the other shows and the Dynamite
Podcast Network this week, including the console
combat podcast, where hosts John and Dean
simulate battles between popular video game
characters. In yesterday's episode, they
determined who would win between Nightmare of
Soul Calibur and War from Darksiders. Over on the
Max Destruction podcast, hosts Scotty and Gilly
pay your favor action heroes from film and
television against each other. On Wednesday,
they're going to find out who would win between
Werewolf by Night and Van Helsing. Werewolf by
Night's obviously going to take that, obviously.
No, no. It's Van Helsing, dude. He could transform
into a Werewolf. That's true. The Hugh Jackman
version, right? Yeah, that's the version they're
going with. The Hugh Jackass version. What the
fuck did you just say? The Hugh Jackoff version.
Oh, okay. On the Central World podcast, hosts
Zachary Hepburn speculates on fights between fan
favorite anime and manga characters. In his next
episode, Zach is revealing who would win between
Whitebeard and Kampachi, both from One Piece.
Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in
our show notes to listen to all of the shows in the
Dynamite Podcast Network. But with that out of the
way, quick to the no prize. A no prize is an award
that Marvel used to give out to fans. Our version,
the Dynamic Dual No Prize, is a digital award we
post on Instagram for the person that We Feel gave
the best answer to our question of the week. Last
week, we asked you guys, what was your favorite
story within the Deadpool Batman crossover comic
book and why? And we got one answer. Yeah, I don't
know if a whole lot of listeners of this show
actually read the comic books because, yeah, only
a single person called in. So congrats to Noah
Terry, you win this week's no prize. And he said,
hey guys, within the Deadpool slash Batman
crossover comic, we all know the best story and
that's the dead of night where the dark night and
the merc with the mouth meet up. It's just the
perfect team up. I never knew I needed it. It's
hilarious. The art is amazing. The story is
fantastic. I'm not saying the other stories
weren't solved, but this was definitely a no
brainer first pick for me. So that's my answer.
Thanks. Bye guys. I think one of the best things
about the Deadpool Batman crossover comic book
was how clearly the writer seemed to nail Ryan
Reynolds voice. Just his comedic style that the
character has used in the films, which is mostly on
par with Deadpool's comedic style from the comic
books. It was just a joy to read when I read Deadpool
comic books. Now it's definitely in Ryan Reynolds
voice. When I read Batman, it's definitely in
Kevin Conroy's voice. The Joker showed up in that
issue. I definitely read it in Mark Hamill's voice
and it was all just so well written and clear and
hilarious on top of everything else. It was such a
blast. Like Noah said, it was the crossover event.
I didn't know I needed. Yeah, I was not really
looking forward to a Deadpool Batman crossover
because we've had so many Batman crossovers. I
never really wanted to see him go up against
Deadpool, not realizing that they are the perfect
foils for each other. And it just made for a really,
really fun story. And yeah, I totally read
Deadpool in Ryan Reynolds voice. And I think it's
because it was written by Zeb Wells, who was the
co-writer on the Deadpool and Wolverine movie.
Yeah, absolutely. So he definitely knew the tone
of the character and how to nail that. You're
right. They were the perfect foils for each other.
I love how Batman just could not tolerate Deadpool
shit and Deadpool could not help but love how cool
Batman was. It was great. It was great. But besides
that one, what was your favorite storyline? Well,
as much as I wanted to like the Daredevil green
arrow crossover, it was too cliche for me, which
was surprising. Given that it was written by Kevin
Smith, who was a solid comic book writer. I think
actually the one that surprised me the most was the
Wonder Woman and Captain America crossover. Oh,
man. Because the reveal that it was a conjoined
Marvel and DC universe out of the multiverse was a
pretty good twist. And it totally makes sense that
Wonder Woman and Steve Rogers would be into each
other because Steve Rogers is a lot like Steve
Trevor, you know, they would totally get it on.
Dude, I want more from the Infinityverse. I think
that's what they called it in that storyline.
Yeah. Because that was spectacular. I was
actually going to choose that one, too. But I guess
if I had to choose another one that I really liked,
it would have been the Rocket Raccoon and Green
Lantern crossover. Where it was like the
Guardians of the Universe and the Guardians of the
Galaxy. I thought that was pretty cool,
especially with that twist ending where Hal
Jordan gets the Infinity Gauntlet. Right. And
that was pretty good. Well, thanks, Noa Terry, for
reading the comic book and for calling in with your
answer. You win this week's No Prize. If you the
listener want a shot at winning your own No Prize,
stay tuned till later on this episode when we'll be
asking another. Question of the week. And now that
that's done, on to the news. All right, this past
week we got the first official gameplay trailer
for the upcoming Wolverine video game made by
Insomniac for the PlayStation 5. It's coming out
late in 2026. About a year from now. It looks really
damn good. As good as the Spider-Man game is for the
character of Spider-Man, this game looks like the
same level of quality for the character of
Wolverine. The movement of the character through
the environment, the camera motions and the fight
mechanics look just so well polished and true to
character. It just looks amazing. And hyper
violent as it should. Right. I mean, I would expect
no less from a Wolverine video game where you
straight up stab people in the face. I will say that
this trailer got more violent than I was
expecting. It's definitely rated to
infirmature. We're talking like Mortal Kombat
levels of violence as opposed to like Spider-Man
levels of violence from that video game. We see him
straight up rip dudes in half down the middle. And
what I thought was interesting too is that these
guys are also like part robots seemingly or
they're wearing like some high tech gear. I
thought we would have seen Wolverine turn to a
couple of robots, but they're like, no, all
humans. Yeah, these robots are going to have
blood, right? He's not just tearing through
circuitry here. We're going to make sure that
they're at least cyborgs. So there's some blood is
what the developers said. It looks like we get so
many different classic versions of Wolverine
because the character is just so versatile in the
world of Marvel. He fits right at home, you know, in
Westchester with Xavier school as a teacher, but
he can also feel very Western, you know, with his
cowboy hat and stuff. He could also feel very like
East Asian with stories set in Japan or Madropore
or like in the middle of a Canadian forest in the
Rockies in the mountains, being a wild animal in
the snow in the city. There's just so many
different directions you can take the character
and to that end, we're getting a whole lot more
level designs here than we do from like your
typical Insomniac Spider-Man game, which
largely takes place in Manhattan. Yeah, when you
compare this to something like Batman Arkham
Knight or Arkham City, which takes place entirely
in Gotham or like you mentioned, the Spider-Man
games, this doesn't feel open world to me, but
that's not a bad thing. No, not necessarily. It
looks very level based. I don't think you could
actually like walk from the Canadian Rockies to
Japan in this game. I don't think it is open world
like those other games, but I might be wrong. You
know, you may just have to go to the airport and then
there'll be a cutscene where he's traveling or
something. He does have his motorcycle in a few of
these levels, which looks super sick wearing the
yellow costume, the yellow costume, which looks
very influenced by the design that was in the MCU in
the Deadpool and Wolverine film. It looks really
cool. I guess the one nitpick I have and this
definitely is a nitpick because I brought it up
with our executive producers and Zach kind of set
me straight because I was talking about how the
fight system incorporates so many different
things. So many combos, kind of like with
Spider-Man, that it's kind of ridiculous because
it makes no sense for a guy to still be standing
after the first Adamantium Claw slash, right?
Like if you get slash with Adamantium Claw, you're
basically done. But some of these combos in this
Wolverine game fight system incorporate like 10
plus hits, which is just kind of ridiculous. It's
such overkill. But Zach, one of our executive
producers and the host of Central World was like,
yeah, but Wolverine's kind of about overkill when
he's in his berserker rage modes, to which, you
know, that's fair. Yeah, he'll keep slashing even
though you're dead. Yeah, I mean, like if you get
slashed in the face, do you really need to be
slashed in the chest and in the gut and in the arm and
in the neck and in the face again? I don't think so.
Yes, according to Wolverine. It's just not a very
efficient fighting style. I'll say that. It looks
like Omega Red is going to be one of the villains.
Yeah, we see Omega Red. We see Mystique in the video
game. There's a Sentinel, which looks like it is
going to be a really cool fight scene. I don't know
who the main bad guy is. If it's like, I don't know,
Saber Tooth or Romulus. I hope it's not Romulus. I
hate that character, but somebody else will have
to wait and see. So are you picking up PlayStation 5
for this? Maybe. I mean, I'm overdue on playing the
Insomniac Spider-Man games. If this game does
really well too, it sounds like Insomniac is going
to make a whole lot more Marvel video games. And I
just need to get back up on that horse, on that video
game horse, because I haven't been a big gamer in
about five or 10 years now. I bought an Xbox One just
to play Arkham Knight and Injustice 2. And once I
beat those games, I essentially just sold it
again. But I regret that because those are really
fun games and I wish I could still play them. Well,
what is a PS5 running for these days? Let's see.
Alright, so basically anywhere from $550 to $750.
I'll get back to you on when I will pick that up.
Maybe next year, when the price comes down. But
speaking of superhero video games, that brings us
to our question of the week. Besides Batman,
Spider-Man, and Wolverine, which Marvel or DC
character do you most want to play as in a
single-player adventure video game? Yeah, tell
us what character and what you want the game to play
to be like. Record your answer at dynamicduel.com
by clicking on the red microphone button in the
bottom right hand corner of the screen, which will
prompt you to leave us a voicemail. Your message
could be up to 30 seconds long, and don't forget to
leave your name in case we include you on the
podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer and award
that person at Dynamic Duel No Prize that we'll
post to Instagram. Be sure to answer before
October 4th. But that does it for all the news for
this episode, so let's go ahead and move into our
main event, a duel between the DC heroine of
Amethyst and Marvel's hero, Black Knight. Okay,
Amethyst versus Black Knight. As I mentioned
earlier, these are two fantasy characters with
Amethyst coming from Gemworld and Black Knight
being tied to Arthurian, Legend, and Avalon.
Yeah, they both wield magic swords, and that's
basically the full extent that I know of that ties
these two characters together. Because really, I
don't know much about Amethyst. Who does? She's a
pretty obscure character. She's kind of like one
of those characters that was like commandee or
warlord, just kind of offset in their own niche
fantasy world, largely separate from the other DC
characters. But she's cool. DC produced a series
of shorts with the character one time that I
thought was fantastic. I can't wait to see the
character in live action. I'm pretty confident
eventually we will. These shorts were animated?
Yes. Yeah, and it was very much based off of like a
Zelda type of video game. It was awesome. Are you
able to watch them on HBO Max or were they just on the
DC Universe app back when that was around? Yeah,
they were on the DC Universe app, but you can also
see them on YouTube now. Oh, cool. Interesting.
Okay. Well, the Black Knight never got his own
shorts, but he did show up in an episode of the
Avengers Earth's Mightiest Heroes cartoon, but
he didn't have a speaking appearance. Oh, he was
just like a background cameo? Yeah, basically.
Doesn't count. I really did like the casting of
Kate Harrington as Dane Whitman though. It's
going to go somewhere eventually and I can't wait
to see it. Yeah, seriously, get that guy his own
movie already. Seriously. What the fuck, Marvel?
What are you guys doing? I can get masses. Get your
shit together. Let's go to get into the dual
portion of this episode to explain the
methodology behind our duels. Let's go to our
sentient dual simulator Alfred Jarvis 9000. AJ9K
tell our listeners how you go about determining a
winner in our dual matchups. Yes, of course, sir.
The way I determine a winner between the
contestants is by running 1000 Monte Carlo
simulations using the characters statistics. A
Monte Carlo simulation is a probabilistic model
used to determine outcomes through random
sampling. In this case, I randomize the
statistics along a normal distribution as a way to
simulate the many variables that can occur during
battle. The stat parameters are based on the
official Marvel power grid from which the DC
characters statistics are extrapolated.
Additional stat categories are included such as
range, damage potential, versatility and
perception in order to create a more detailed and
accurate simulation. The results of the 1000
simulations provide a percentage of wins for each
character. The contestant with the higher
percentage is declared the victor as they have a
higher probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither character should win
100% of the matches. The comic book stories have
shown that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman, so the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks, AJ9K.
Before we run the simulations, though, we'd like
to break down each character's histories and
abilities before improvising a scenario on how we
imagine one of the 1000 simulations would play out
B for B. And it is my turn to go first with the Marvel
character, so let me tell you all about the Black
Knight. Dane Whitman was born in Gloucester,
Massachusetts, to a wealthy family and grew up
studying physics, eventually earning a master's
degree and pursuing doctoral work. His life
changed when his uncle Nathan Garrett, a
super-criminal scientist who had assumed the
mantle of the villainous Black Knight, was
mortally wounded in a battle with Iron Man. On his
deathbed, Garrett confessed his crimes to Dane
and implored him to redeem the family legacy by
restoring honor to the mantle of the Black Knight.
Inheriting Garrett Castle in England, Dane
discovered there the Ebony Blade, a mystical
sword forged by the sorcerer Merlin as a dark
counterpart to Excalibur. It was passed down
through generations by their ancestor Sir Percy
of Scandia, the original Black Knight of King
Arthur's Camelot, whose spirit appeared to Dane
in a vision. He explained that the Ebony Blade
carried a blood curse, that every time it drew
blood, it would drive its wielder closer to
madness. Dane accepted the burden and claimed the
weapon as his own. Initially, Dane sought to
infiltrate his uncle's former allies, the
Masters of Evil, in order to bring the team down
from within. During this time, he encountered the
Avengers, but was mistaken for his uncle Garrett
and was attacked. After proving his true
intentions, he aided the Avengers, becoming a
trusted ally and later a full member of the team.
You can learn more about the Masters of Evil and
Avengers in their respective duels against the
Legion of Doom and the Justice League. Using his
scientific knowledge and engineering skills,
Dane created a genetically engineered winged
horse named Aragorn and designed advanced
weaponry, including a power lance. Though he
wielded the Ebony Blade, he was always wary of its
corrupting influence. Dane soon became
entangled in mystical adventures. Fighting
alongside the defenders, his spirit was drawn
back to the 12th century, where he inhabited the
body of his ancestor, Sir Eobar Garrington,
during the Crusades. There, he fought in years of
bloody warfare under the Ebony Blade's
influence, battling the Fomor, a monstrous race
from Irish mythology. During this time, Dane
allied with the time-displaced Avengers and the
Eternal Cersei. Eventually, a druid returned his
spirit to his own restored body in the modern era
and Dane resumed his role as Black Knight. The
sorcerer Merlin soon summoned him, charging him
and Captain Britain to battle the villain Mordred
and the demonic knight Necromon. Their campaign
saw Dane briefly wield Excalibur when the Ebony
Blade was destroyed and fight beside the
resurrected King Arthur. Though Camelot was
ultimately destroyed, the Ebony Blade was
reforged and returned to him and he went home with
his new winged steed named Valinor. You can learn
more about Captain Britain and his duel against
Uncle Sam. Back in modern times, Dane resumed
active duty with the Avengers. His tactical mind
and scientific expertise proved invaluable,
particularly when geniuses like Iron Man or Hank
Pym were absent. His life grew more complicated
when the Submariner used the Ebony Blade to kill
his monstrous wife Marina, reigniting the
blade's blood curse. Dane's body slowly began
transforming and eventually succumbed to the
curse completely. He was held at Garrett Castle by
his friend Victoria Bentley, who attempted a
restoration spell but instead summoned the
spirit of Cer Percy from the court of King Arthur
into Dane's body. Cer Percy had ventured in the
modern world for a time with a man named Sean Dolan
as his squire until the curse was lifted and Dane's
own body was restored. To avoid the Ebony Blade's
curse again, Dane engineered a weapon called the
Photon Sword that was essentially a lightsaber.
His squire, Sean Dolan, was corrupted by the Ebony
Blade and transformed into the villain
Bloodraith. In battle, Bloodraith accidentally
killed Victoria Bentley, devastating Dane.
Despite this tragedy, Dane continued his service
with the Avengers and eventually rose to become
the team's field leader under Black Widow. In his
personal life, he found himself caught in a love
triangle between the Eternal Cersei and the
Inhuman Princess Crystal, both of whom you can
learn more about in their respective duels
against Firestorm and Tempest. Though bound to
Cersei through a mystical bond meant to stabilize
her fraying mind, Dane's feelings for Crystal
complicated matters. The situation grew dire
when Proctor, an alternate reality version of
Dane, embittered by rejection from his world
Cersei, attacked. After Proctor's defeat,
Cersei exiled herself to another universe and
Dane chose to accompany her, leaving Crystal
behind. Dane and Cersei's exile took them across
realities, including to the Ultraverse, where
Dane briefly became leader of the hero team Ultra
Force. Returning to Earth after splitting from
Cersei, he joined the heroes for Hire Team
alongside Luke Cage and Iron Fist. Dane was chosen
by the Lady of the Lake as the pen dragon of his age,
receiving new mystical equipment including the
Sword of Light, Shield of Night, and a new winged
steed named Strider, who could achieve
supersonic speeds and travel through
environments like outer space or underwater.
Dane trained the Knights of Wondegor, a group of
warriors created by the High Evolutionary, and
briefly served with the British team Excalibur,
later converting Garrett Castle into a museum
chronicling the Black Knights lineage. During
the Skrull Invasion of Earth, Dane fought across
London with what he believed was the Ebony Blade,
later revealed to be a vampiric counterfeit
created by Dracula, whom you can learn more about
in his duel with Andrew Bennett. Eventually
reclaiming the real Ebony Blade from Wakanda,
Dane fought vampires in Britain alongside MI-13,
the UK's Paranormal Intelligence Division. The
Ebony Blade's curse weighed heavily on Dane, and
after nearly killing an opponent in a Berserk
rage, his deteriorating mental state led him to
flee through a rift to a chaotic realm that he took
over and transformed into new Avalon, serving as
its protector. In time, Dane returned to Earth,
fighting the evil organization Hydra with a team
of heroes called Euroforce, and aiding the
Avengers against cosmic threats like the Kotari.
When Null invaded Earth with his symbioted
hordes, Dane fought valiantly. However, Null
revealed that the Ebony Blade did not corrupt its
wielders, but instead fed upon their existing
darkness, drawing strength from their flaws.
This revelation forced Dane to confront his own
inner demons and accept responsibility for his
violent impulses. You can learn more about Null in
his duel with White Lantern. Amidst this turmoil,
Dane discovered he had a teenage daughter named
Jax, secretly born years earlier to his college
girlfriend. Around this time, the villain
Mordred sought the Ebony Relics, which were a set
of mystical items all forged from the same
meteorite that formed the Ebony Blade, including
the Ebony Dagger, Ebony Shield, and Ebony
Chalice, the three of which could join together to
form the Ebony Crown, a weapon of ultimate mystic
control. Dane pursued Mordred through the mystic
realm of Lysinae's discovering Merlin's secret
betrayal, that the sorcerer, long ago, had pitted
Arthur and Mordred against each other, knowing
Camilla would fall. Mordred attempted to forge
the Ebony Crown, killing Dane in the process. His
daughter Jax then claimed the Ebony Blade and
attempted to slay Mordred in a rage. However, Dane
was resurrected by the Ebony Crown, defeating
Mordred and reforging the Relic into the Ebon
Siege, a dark throne that projected vision for the
Abyss. Which makes him highly resistant to both
physical and mystical attacks. He has wielded a
variety of weapons over the years including the
Power Lance, the Photon Sword, and the Sword of
Light and the Shield of Night. But I'm going with
his classic weapon of the Ebony Blade, which can
cleave through any substance, even Iron Man's
armor, and can deflect or absorb even the most
powerful magic directed at it. It can be
telekinetically summoned to its wielder, and its
wielder can be injured, but not killed, as the
blade will resurrect them. The Ebony Blade is
cursed in that it craves blood and corrupts its
user to kill. If fully corrupted, the wielder
becomes a bloodraith, a dark being who feeds on
souls. Outside of his relics, the Black Knight is a
gifted physicist, biologist, and engineer. He's
an expert trained swordsman, is an expert in
medieval history, and has a familiarity of the
world of magic. And that's the Black Knight. What
was the name of his Pegasus again? He's had three
Pegasi. The first one was called Aragorn, the
second one was called Valinor, and the third one
was called Strider. So there were all references
to the Lord of the Rings, Middle Earth. Is he going
to have one of these horses in this speculation? I
don't know, do you want him to? He can. If Amethyst,
I guess, is going to have a horse, is she? I don't
know, do you want her to? She can. First of all,
Strider would absolutely murder Amethyst's
horse, and I don't know if I want to speculate on
horse violence. I'm sorry, Amethyst's horse
isn't even a horse, it's a unicorn. It's a
Pegacorn. It would straight up impale Black
Knight's horse. Alright, we'll include him in the
duel, but you know, we'll be gentle. We'll be
gentle. Says you. Let me get into Amethyst's
backstory. Never suspecting her extraordinary
origins, but as her 13th birthday approached,
Citrina's spell began to weaken. On the night of
her birthday, Amy received a mysterious Amethyst
pendant, the key to her true destiny. Soon after a
creature from Gemworld breached the barrier
between worlds and abducted Amy, dragging her
through the portal to her birthplace. Crossing
into Gemworld caused her to age rapidly,
transforming from a young teenager into a grown
woman. Rescued by Citrina's agents and brought
before the witch mother herself, Amy finally
learned the truth of her lineage. She was Princess
Amethyst, heir to a fallen house and the only one
who could oppose Dark Opal's rule. With her
lineage revealed and Citrina's guidance, Amy
accepted her role as Princess Amethyst and began
to build a rebellion. She forged alliances with
her remaining houses that had resisted Dark
Opal's control, including Turquoise and Topaz.
Though new to her powers, Amethyst quickly
mastered the use of crystal-based magic and
martial combat, wielding enchanted weapons and
artifacts tied to her gemstone heritage. She led
an uprising against Dark Opal's forces,
culminating in a siege of his fortress, where she
faced him in battle and ultimately defeated and
killed him, restoring the freedom of Gemworld and
reclaiming her family's throne. Amy returned to
Earth after her victory, attempting to resume a
normal life, but her connection to Gemworld could
not be severed. Conflicts erupted once more among
the noble houses in her absence, and Amy returned
to Gemworld to stabilize the realm. As her
influence grew, she attracted the attention of
greater magical forces, including the Lords of
Chaos. Dr. Fate revealed to her that she was not
merely a noble but a lord of order, like her father,
a powerful being meant to preserve balance in the
multiverse. This made Amethyst unique among the
Lords of Order, as she had been born into a human
form and carried the dual identity of mortal and
cosmic being. You can learn more about Dr. Fate in
our Dr. Fate vs. Dr. Strange dual episode. She
continued to act as Gemworld's protector,
returning to Earth once again to help repel the
specter who had turned against magic. She stood
alongside Earth's mystics at the Rock of
Eternity, alongside the Lord of Order Naboo, who
was killed along with the wizard Shazam, making
Amy the only living Lord of Order to enter into the
10th Age of Magic that emerged following the
specter's defeat. Upon Amy's return to Gemworld,
she learned that Gemworld had fundamentally been
altered by the shift in magic. With Gemworld now
known as Xerox, the realm was engulfed in civil
war. Amethyst fought to preserve what remained of
her home, and when the magic wars devastated the
realm, she was seemingly destroyed along with it.
However she later emerged on Earth and served as
one of its protectors for a time. Following the
Flashpoint reset of continuity, Amy Winston's
history was reimagined. She lived on Earth with
her mother, Gracie Winston, a stern and reclusive
woman who trained Amy from a young age in martial
arts and swordsmanship without explanation. On
her 17th birthday, Gracie took Amy to a remote
hilltop and opened a magic portal, revealing the
truth. Amy was actually Amaya, Princess of House
Amethyst on Nila, the realm known to Earth as
Gemworld. She learned she was the daughter of Lady
Graciel of House Amethyst and Lord Virion of House
Turquoise, the latter of whom sacrificed himself
to get Amy and her mom to Earth and away from the
murderous ambition of Graciel's twin sister,
Lady Mordriel. The noble houses of Nila were
locked in an uneasy balance of power, with House
Amethyst ruled by Amaya's aunt, Lady Mordriel.
Graciel and Mordriel, twin sisters, shared the
power of their bloodline equally, but upon
Amaya's 17th birthday, the bloodline magic would
be split three ways unless one of them died. During
the ritual to awaken Amaya's bloodline power, she
was drawn into a mystical trial where her mother
Graciel and her aunt Mordriel confronted her with
a shared telepathic vision. The ceremony forced
her to choose between the path of blood and the path
of heart. On the path of blood, she could seize
greater power by killing her mother, and on the
path of heart, she would share the inheritance
equally. Mordriel whispered for Amaya to strike,
urging her to embrace bloodshed and ambition.
Amaya engaged Graciel in combat within the trial,
but when the moment came to deliver the killing
blow, she refused. Her choice aligned her with the
path of heart, and the magic of House Amethyst was
divided three ways, binding Amaya, Graciel, and
Mordriel together as co-heirs. Amaya's return to
Nila sparked fresh conflict. She allied with the
House of Citrine and began to master her magical
abilities. Ingvi, a noble from House Citrine,
became her political tutor and friend, helping
her navigate the intrigue of Gemworld. Amaya's
dual heritage, with blood from both House
Amethyst and House Turquoise, granted her unique
magical abilities. Amaya was also gifted a winged
horse named Epsilonus, a loyal companion that
carried her across Nila's skies and into battle.
Amaya's leadership expanded beyond Nila when a
dimensional breach connected Gemworld to Earth.
She joined Young Justice, helping the team
navigate her homeland and fight off magical
invaders. Her portal magic became essential in
transporting allies across realms, and later she
joined the Justice League Dark, standing
alongside Earth's most powerful mystics to repel
supernatural threats. You can learn more about
Young Justice and their team duel against Young
Avengers, and Justice League Dark in their duel
against the Midnight Suns. During her reign,
Amaya faced Eclipse, who sought to dominate
Gemworld through the corrupted power of the Black
Diamond. Using the prime catalyst, the core
magical artifact of House Amethyst, Amaya
disrupted Eclipse's hold and prevented an
Eclipse-powered cataclysm. You can learn more
about Eclipse in our Eclipse vs. Malekith duel
episode. With Amaya having proven herself to be
the savior of Gemworld, Graciel and Mortariel
abdicated their rule, making Amaya the
undisputed ruler of House Amethyst. Her control
over her house's full power allowed her to repel
even cosmic threats, and under her leadership,
the 12 houses entered a fragile peace. That's
Amethyst's story so far. Powers-wise, Amethyst
wields a vast and diverse magical arsenal rooted
in her bloodline's connection to crystalline and
gemstone-based magic. She can generate and
manipulate crystal constructs, hard-light
weapons, and enchanted armor. Her command of
lattice magic allows her to interact with
energies of other houses, using rubies for
healing, emeralds for plant growth, topaz for
illumination, and more. She can open dimensional
portals, project destructive energy bolts, move
objects telekinetically, and perform
reality-altering spells through crystal
energy. As a hybrid of House Amethyst and House
Turquoise, she is immune to illusion and can wield
mist silk, an enchanted, intangible fabric she
uses as a whip or lasso in combat. Her heritage also
grants resistance to magical corruption, and
enhances her agility, strength, and reflexes. A
trained warrior, as well as a sorceress, Amethyst
is skilled in swordsmanship, hand-to-hand
combat, and battlefield strategy. Now with full
command of her house's power, she stands among the
most formidable magic entities in DC's
multiverse. With a few other magical tricks.
Fantasy-based, and she can do a lot more. DC needs
to be more original. This is just fantasy Star
Sapphire where all the constructs look like
low-res polygons. I just said she could do so much
more. She has a few other tricks. We'll see how that
goes for her. Network rises above the rest.
Prepare yourself for the ultimate showdowns in
comic books, video games, movies, and anime. The
Dynamite Podcast Network presents Console
Combat, where video game legends brawl every
Monday. Dynamic Duel, where comic book titans
smash every Tuesday. Max Destruction, where TV
and action heroes battle every Wednesday. And
Sendro World, where anime champions clash every
Thursday. Join us as we speculate on the matches
and armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge
victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com where we
settle the debate and settle the score. Well, now
that we've got their histories and abilities out
of the way, let's speculate on how one of the 1,000
simulated matches will go. The winner is
determined by simulations, not the speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how this fight could play
out. AJ9K, what are the rules of our speculation?
Well, I should say there are no rules, other than
the characters have no prior knowledge of the
other going into the fight. All they are aware of
starting out is that the other character is a
threat that needs to be eliminated. For the
speculation, the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the match
itself, as no environmental statistics are
considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. Alright,
then let's get into it. Amethyst and Black Knight
meet on the battlefield. Who goes first? I say they
both actually start off atop their ringed steeds,
Strider, whatever the fuck his name is, and
Ipsilos. And so they'll take to the skies and
charge at each other, just like a midair joust
pointing their ebony blades and the sort of
amethyst at each other. But at the last second,
Amethyst is going to generate this long,
crystalline lance around her sword, extending
her reach and knocking Black Knight out of the air,
so he falls to the ground, probably dies. So she
turns her sword into a lance? Yes. I'm going to say
that he dodges it at the last second right before
they clash, because Black Knight's horse,
Strider, can go supersonic, right? So he just
rushes past her like a blur, and he slices her lance
right in half, and she and her horse, whatever the
fuck its name is, gets staggered from the sonic
boom that Black Knight and Strider just created.
Okay, well as Amethyst is regaining her bearings,
she sees Black Knight behind her as he's flown past
her, and she's just going to generate a portal in
front of Ipsilos that opens above Black Knight's
flight path. So she's going to fly through that,
crashing into him from above, and sending him and
Strider just spiraling to the ground. I mean, if
she crashes into him, like Black Knight's pretty
armored, Strider is a tough as nails horse, like
crashing into them is just as likely to send
Amethyst spiraling to the ground too. Like that
wasn't smart. And actually as they're both
falling to the ground in their horses, Black
Knight's going to leap off of Strider over to
Amethyst's horse and just cut off one of its wings
with his ebony blade, and then kick her off of her
horse, and then he's going to get caught mid-air
right before he hits the ground by Strider, who
lands safely. Well that was messed up. So Amethyst
and her horse fall to her death. Well, I mean
Amethyst doesn't actually need Ipsilos to fly,
she could fly under her own power. So as she's
landing on the ground, she's going to send her mist
silk toward Black Knight, because she can control
it. It's like a scarf, a magic scarf, and it's going
to wrap around Strider's neck, choking him out.
And since it's intangible to Black Knight,
there's really nothing he could do about it.
Except the ebony blade can cut intangible things,
like you can cut vision when he goes intangible. So
like a fucking surgeon, Black Knight slides the
blade underneath this magic silk and cuts his
horse free, and then sends Strider away back to
Avalon. Okay, well while he's busy saving his
horse though, Amethyst is already on the
offensive, and she's hurling magical crystal
shards at Black Knight, which pierces armor,
tagging him in the back. I mean, can her weapons
even pierce elf-forged Lady of the Lake enchanted
armor? Of course! Don't answer that, it doesn't
even matter, because Dane's going to swing his
sword and just slice all of these shards out of the
air, and then he's going to blitz Amethyst, just
rushing toward her. Well I mean, he's going to run
straight into a magic energy bolt, then several of
them actually. Yeah, sorry, except the ebony
blade can absorb a magic energy too. So like, I feel
bad for you man, honestly, like the ebony blade is
just too bad ass for you it seems, because like as
the Black Knight continues running at her, he's
going to fire the magic energy stored up in the
sword right back at her, and she gets hit by it, and
at this point he reaches her, and he straight up
stabs her through the shoulder, disarming her,
and making her drop the Amethyst sword. No,
because she's already generated a shield, a
crystalline Amethyst shield by this point, in
preparation for his approach. So that's going to
protect her from his energy blast, and by the time
he rages her with his sword, you know, she'll parry
his lunge attack, and she's going to transform her
shield into a second sword, the crystalline one,
so now she's dual wielding like a bad ass, and with
the extra blade, she's going to slice off his left
arm at the shoulder, and she's like, now stand
aside, we're the adversary. We're the adversary,
what? Oh! Black Knight's like, tis but a scratch.
Scratch his arms off! Notice that, like, he wears
enchanted pauldrons on his shoulders, that would
prevent his arm from getting cut off. So
literally, she just scratches his armor, tis but a
scratch, and he's going to respond to her attack by
slicing her purple gem sword into, and then he's
going to slash right across her forearm, which is
going to force her to drop her sword, and more
importantly than that, he draws blood. So now
Black Knight is bloodlusted due to the ebony
blade, and Amethyst is really fucked. Well if he's
bloodlusted, then he's not really in control, and
so he'll probably charge at her, at which point
both halves of her mist silk that was sliced into
are going to fly to him and wrap around his face and
neck, just blinding and choking him, and as he
struggles against that, Amethyst is going to
quickly conjure this giant purple crystal battle
axe that she's going to sword wielding arm, where
he's not armored. So she slices that arm right off
before spinning around and cleaving him in half at
the waist. So with him on the ground, she's able to
pick up her sort of Amethyst back up, and on one
knee, she's like, we thank thee, Lord, that in thy
mercy. Yeah, and then she gets booted right in the
head by the Black Knight who, surprise, is not
dead. He's resurrected because the wielder of the
ebony blade cannot be killed. So she gets knocked
over, and he's like, I'm invincible. And then he
impales her right through the torso into the
ground, and wins this match. But also he's like
super bloodlusted by this point, and probably
close to succumbing to darkness and becoming a
bloodwraith, because he just spilled so much of
her blood. There's no way that Black Knight
survives being sliced in half, because like he
wasn't even wielding the ebony blade at the end,
because she sliced that sword-wielding arm off,
remember? I don't have to tell you, man, it's
magic, okay? The sword was still in his severed
hand, so he still got resurrected. That's just how
it works. The Black Knight always triumphs.
Hopefully our audience has seen Monty Python and
the Holy Grail. Oh my gosh, if they haven't, what
are they doing with their lives? Stop listening to
this podcast, go watch that movie. But we'll go
ahead and leave our speculation there. Either
Amethyst kills the Black Knight by severing him in
half, and he doesn't get resurrected, or he does
get resurrected due to the ebony blade's magic and
then finishes her off by impaling. So let's go
ahead and find out which of these two scenarios
happens by inputting the stats, running the
simulations, and coming back with a winner. A.J
.9K? Hit it! All right, this was an interesting
matchup. Both of these characters have things
going for them over the other, kind of going back
and forth. Like, Black Knight is more durable,
largely due to his enchanted armor, but also
because he can be considered regenerative
through the resurrection enchantment that his
sword grants him. Yeah, he was more durable than
her. He was also much more intelligent than her.
Considering Amethyst is really just a teenager.
Yeah, Dain is considered like the Avengers
resident scientist, like I said in his bio, when
people like Iron Man or Ant Man are away. That's so
weird to me. Like, why would a character like Black
Knight need to be a scientist? Why would he need to
be able to engineer his own horse? Because he was a
scientist who was really introduced to the world
of magic through the death of his uncle, and
learned about this, like, whole legacy of the
Black Knight. I listened to your backstory. I just
think that's dumb. I don't know what to tell you,
man. You know, he made his own lightsaber, he makes
a lot of his own weapons. It's just part of the
character. Whatever. We did say that Amethyst was
obviously more versatile than him, considering
not only can she create constructs, but is also
just a sorceress in general. Yeah, her whole power
set is a little bit vague. Don't you think? Oh, I
mean, no more vague than any sorcerer. Yeah,
that's lame. We also said that Amethyst has a
greater range due to the fact that the Black Knight
can really only blast energy if he absorbs that
magic with his ebony blade, or if he's wielding a
different weapon such as the Sword of Light. But
everything else was pretty close, I would say.
Well, we said Amethyst was faster because she can
fly and generate portals. I mean, the Black Knight
does have Strider, who can go supersonic speeds,
but he's not always mounted on Strider. So we just
gave a slight edge and speed to Amethyst. We also
gave her a slight edge and damage level as well,
again, because of magic, which is also why she got a
slight edge in perception because of her noble
blood, she's able to perceive things that other
people can't, including magical illusions she
sees right through them. That all said, Jonathan,
who's taking the win on this one? I'm going to say
Amethyst. I know you really like Black Knight. I
just don't think he has enough going for him in this
match. Well, that was dumb. That was a dumb thing to
say. Maybe, I mean, Instagram probably agrees
with you because 54% of them sided with Black
Knight to be the winner. But I feel like that's
probably just because Amethyst is a fairly
obscure character. Or maybe it's just because you
don't want to admit it to yourself. Let's find out.
AJ9K, the results, please. Here you are, sir. All
right, the winner between Amethyst and Black
Knight is Amethyst. We'll call it a draw though,
right? We'll call it a draw. It depends on what the
percentage was. Out of 1000 simulated matches,
Amethyst won 674 of them compared to the Black
Knight's 326 wins. So it was 67.4% over 32.6%. I'm
sorry, that is definitely not a draw. Amethyst
wins this hands down as she should because she's a
pretty powerful sorceress. I guess Black Knight
is kind of like the Avengers equivalent to
Wolverine in a sense, in that his primary power is
that he can cut through anything and kind of goes
into these berserker rages on occasion. If you
think about it, it does make sense that it wouldn't
hold up to someone as versatile as Amethyst. Maybe
I should have gone into this match with his sort of
knight in shield of light. Joseph, no one cares.
He's a loser. He lost. I have one thing to say to
Black Knight, none shall pass. Okay, Gandalf. Oh,
that was you shall not pass, right? Yeah. Okay.
Congrats to Amethyst. That does it for this duel.
AJ9K, help close us out. Thanks for listening to
Dynamic Jewel. Visit the show's website at
dynamicjewel.com and follow us on Instagram at
dynamicjewelpodcast. You can support the show on
Patreon at patreon.com slash dynamicjewel and
joining a tier that works for you or by rating and
reviewing Dynamic Jewel on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, Podchaser, or on our website. Don't
forget to listen to the other shows in the Dynamite
podcast network, including Max Destruction,
Senjo World, and Console Combat. All right, the
next episode is where we're going to get them guys
because we're going to find out who would win in a
fight between Ocean Master, the Aquaman villain,
and Hellstorm, aka Damien Hellstrom, who is the
son of Satan. So it's Tritance versus Pitchforks,
Water versus Fire. It's going to be a good one. And
it's kicking off our spooky October season where
we're giving you all duels all the time. We're
actually pushing our peacemaker review to
November just so we can get in all of the spooky
duels this upcoming month. So look forward to
those guys. That does it for this episode. We want
to give a big thanks to our executive producers,
Jon Sturrosky, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Balcom,
Mickey Mathen-Geehan, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi
Aitin, Austin Wazalowski, AJ Duckerly, Nick
Obanto, Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Speese,
Dean Maleski, Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, Josh
Leiner, Mike Williams, and Paul Graves for
helping make this podcast possible. We'll talk to
you guys next week. Up and away, true believers.