This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi and welcome
to the Dynamic Dual Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe and I'm his twin
brother Johnny DC. And in this episode, we're
going to find out who would win in a fight between
DC's Freedom Fighters and Marvel's X-Factor.
It's a team duel, we're pitting seven characters
from the Freedom Fighters against seven
characters from X-Factor. For an all-out, no
holds barred brawl. We're going to input all the
character stats from simulations to find out who
the superior group is. Yeah, this matchup was
chosen by our executive producers in part because
both teams have been government-based agencies.
And with Independence Day coming up and July
already being packed full of reviews, we
definitely wanted to get this match in before
then. Yeah, we'll find out which team wins later on
this episode. Before that, we're going to break
down the latest comic book movie news to come out
this past week of which we finally got some news.
There was the new trailer for the Superman movie
announcing that tickets are on sale. There was the
second trailer for Iron Heart. And DC Studios
announced that they're making a Mr. Miracle
animated series. As always, we list our segment
times in our episode description, so feel free to
check out the show notes if you want to skip ahead to
a particular topic. Our artificially
intelligent duel simulator, AJ9K, has a quick
message for our listeners, so listen up. Why hello
there. Do you want even more from this podcast?
Then become a part of the Dynamic Duel Community on
Patreon, where you can choose from three tiers.
The Dynamic 2.0 tier gives you access to our
Discord chat server. The Fantastic Four tier
gives you two bonus episodes each month, and the
X-Force tier makes you an executive producer of
this show. Lastly, the Diner Mike podcast network
tier lets you create your own podcast using this
Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe will help
you develop your show, provide graphic support
and consultation, and get you simulation
results. Pitch the twins your ideas via email at
dynamicduelpodcastatgmail.com. Check it out at
patreon.com slash dynamicduel. Pip pip cheerio.
Thanks AJ9K, and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast. Guys, be sure to tune in to the other
shows in the Diner Mike podcast network this week,
including the console combat podcast, where
hosts John and Dean simulate battles between
popular video game characters. In yesterday's
episode, they pit the hero from Dragon Quest V
versus Ichiban Kasuga from Like a Dragon. Over on
the Max Destruction podcast, hosts Scotty and
Gilly pit your favorite action heroes from film
and television against each other. This week, the
brothers are pitting Danny Phantom against Space
Ghost. And on the Senjo World podcast, hosts
Zachary Hepburn speculates on fights between fan
favorite anime and manga characters. In his next
episode, Zach's going to reveal who'd win between
Power from Chainsaw Man versus Mariah Kuriyama
from Beyond the Boundary. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our show
notes to listen to all of the shows and the Diner
Mike podcast network. But with that out of the way,
quick to the no prize. A no prize is an award that
Marvel used to give out to fans. Our version, the
Dynamic Dual No Prize, is a digital award that we
post on Instagram for the person that we feel gave
the best answer to our question of the week. Last
week we asked you guys, what Marvel or DC character
that we haven't done a duel with yet, are you still
hoping we get to by January? And this is coming off
of the news that in January, Jonathan and I will
have hit the 10 year anniversary for this podcast.
We'll be turning 40 and we have decided that at that
point, this podcast will no longer be a weekly
show. We'll still do some review episodes when
films come out, but this will be the last year for
dual episodes. Yeah, we got quite a number of
answers, but we're going to break down three
honorable mentions before revealing this week's
no prize winner. Our first honorable mention goes
to Travis Bailey, who said, What's up, this Travis
Bailey, shout out to my good twin. All right, so I'm
not sure if y'all have done any, let me know. I'd
like to see Saber II versus Slade Wilson, for sure.
Let me get Gladiator versus Lobo. That could be the
main card. That could be the main event. Jamie
Madrox. Madrox and Gorilla Grodd, for sure. And
where's Mephisto? Y'all done Mephisto yet? Y'all
got to get Mephisto in there. All right. So there
were a whole lot of options in this one. We've
actually done a lot of these characters already.
We did Deathstroke versus Deadpool. Saber Tooth,
we put against Killer Croc. Lobo, we put against
Carnage. Gorilla Grodd, we put against Scylocke.
And Mephisto, we put against Sandman of the
Enthalas. Yeah, but there are a number of
characters he mentioned that we haven't done
duels with, namely, Multiple Man and Gladiator.
Yeah, Gladiator is the head of the Imperial Guard
for the Shiar Alien race. He's basically just like
Superman. With all the weeks planned out for the
rest of the year, by us and the executive producer
team, we won't be able to get to a Gladiator match,
but we've done a lot of duels with Superman-like
characters, such as Superman versus Dr. Doom,
Ultraman versus Hyperion, Sentry versus Zod,
things like that. And while we won't be getting to a
Multiple Man individual duel, luckily Travis, he
will feature in this duel episode, Freedom
Fighters versus X Factor. Right, so look forward
to that. Great answer, Travis. Our next honorable
mention comes from Matt from Texas, who said, Hey
guys, Matt from Texas here. I want to see the Crime
Syndicate versus the Squadron Supreme. Crime
Syndicate's Ultraman, Alman Superwoman, Johnny
Quick, Power Ring, Dead Eye, and White Martian.
Versus the Squadron Supreme's Hyperion, Night
Hawk, Power Princess, Blurred Doctor Spectrum,
Golden Archer, and Scrollion Skymaster. I think
it'd be awesome to see two alternate versions of
the Justice League fight each other. That would
have been a great matchup. Essentially, it's Evil
Justice League versus Marvel's version of the
Justice League. But since they're both basically
iterations of the Justice League, we can probably
assume that the match would be close to 50-50,
right? It's probably a coin toss. Although I'll
say I really liked Matt's picks for each team. We
have done individual duels with Ultraman versus
Hyperion. Yeah, I think that episode is probably
the closest we'll ever get to that match. Which
hurts to say because I really love Squadron
Supreme, but we have a lot of other great team duels
coming down the pike. You know, teams like West
Coast Avengers. The Inhumans, the Eternals,
Legion of Superheroes, the Authority. So you
still got a lot of great team duels coming your way.
So great answer, Matt. Our final honorable
mention goes to Alex Albro, who said, Hey guys, I
think you should do a duel between Lois Lane and
Mary Jane, our Superwoman versus Jackpot. They
could fight with their powers and compete to write
the best article for their respective dailies.
I'd also like to see Kevin Feige versus James Gunn,
if you have a chance, and then also the last duel
that I think we all want to see is Johnny DC versus
Marvelous Joe. Thanks guys. So actually the last
matchup that you mentioned, Johnny DC versus
Marvelous Joe, Johnny DC would totally win no
contest. What are you talking about? I would stomp
your goofy ass. Don't even try. Actually, we
already ran these simulations for one of our
patrons one time, and we did determine I would win
because frankly, I just have more weapons than
you. Yeah, I don't really own any weapons. So yeah,
I would get my ass kicked. If it got into close range
though, I'm like quicker than Jonathan, right? So
I just give them like a throat strike and he just
beat down for the count. What? No, you're not. I'm
way faster than you. What are you talking about?
You know it. I know it. As far as Lois Lane versus
Mary Jane Watson, that was actually a duel that was
pitched by Mickey Mathen-Gian, one of our
executive producers. Although I think we
determined that there were just more prominent
super powered characters that we wanted to get to
before them. Well, I mean, there are super powered
versions of Lois Lane and Mary Jane Watson. Mary
Jane Watson is jackpot in the comic books and she
gets a random power based on this like slot machine
gadget that she has. I don't know if a random power
would help you against the powers of superwoman,
but if she rolls three sevens on her device, she
gets like godlike power. It's a long shot though,
you know, could be interesting, but we're also
trying to get to characters like Abomination and
Ocean Master and Jubilee and Guy Gardner and you
know, some of these big time players that we just
haven't got to yet. But great answer, Alex. We want
to give a quick shout out to Coy and Liao, who also
gave the suggestion of Lois Lane versus jackpot.
Cyrus Moore, who said we should do a duel with
L'Arfles, which we won't get to, but we will be
doing other ring powered characters. Daniel
Alonso suggested Armadillo, or as I like to call
him, Armadildo, after the Modoc television show.
Jetson Batty also said L'Arfles, Kat Stevenson
said we should do a Hive versus Aime team duel,
that'd be pretty cool. Although we have some Aime
characters coming up in another team duel
episode. Lorenzo Valdez said Lana Lang, who at one
point was superwoman. Yeah, she was like an
electric version. Okay. I really like Sheldon
Moore's answer, who said we should do Superboy
Prime versus Franklin Richards, because that
would also tie into the upcoming reviews we're
doing next month with the Superman and Fantastic
Four films. I mean, Superboy Prime would just
punch Franklin Richards' reality alterations
really hard, just destroying them. You wish. And
then Travis Herndon suggested three matchups,
including Scandal Savage versus Daken, Scar
versus Calabac, and Kid Devil versus Robbie
Reyes. Great suggestions, but don't get greedy,
guys. Don't get greedy. Otherwise, I mean, we'd be
doing this forever, which may be what some people
want. Who knows. But the winner of this week's No
Prize is Brian Rochester, who said, Hi, I think you
should do a DC Universe versus Marvel Universe
universal war. Every character, every team. I
know that's very far fetched, but I think it would
be pretty awesome to see that. I love your show and
sorry to see it go. Bye. Well, funny you should
mention that, Brian, because we might have
something similar to that planned for one of our
final episodes. And I'll just leave it at that. All
I could say is I can't wait. It's going to be epic.
Great answer, Brian. Congrats for winning this
week's No Prize. If you, the listener, want to
shout out winning your own No Prize, stay tuned to
later on this episode when we will be asking
another question of the week. And now that that's
done, on to the news. OK, with less than a month to go
for the release of the Superman film in theaters,
DC last week unveiled what I imagine is its final
trailer for the film announcing that tickets are
now on sale. Now, when this film was first
announced by the head of DC Studios, James Gunn,
who is also writing and directing this film, he
said one of the inspirations for it was All Star
Superman, which was a comic book series written by
Grant Morrison that kind of showcased Superman's
last days on Earth. And it was very episodic. He
went up against various villains and various
adventures. And of all the trailers to come out for
this film, that very episodic nature of the All
Star Superman story feels the most apparent in
this trailer specifically. How so? I didn't get
that vibe at all. There's just so much going on with
all of the different characters that Superman is
fighting like Lex Luthor, like an army, giant
Kaiju monsters, portals opening up beneath
Metropolis, giant eyeballs in the sky. There's
just so much going on in this film. It seems like
it's going to be the most epic Superman movie ever
made. Now, there is a rumor that this film is not
going to have like a typical three act structure.
It's going to essentially be like a week in the life
of Superman as it were. In fact, they even had like
chapters for this film that would be like Sunday,
Monday, Tuesday. Now that was a rumor. I'm not
exactly sure if it was true, but again, this
trailer feels like it's kind of all over the place,
but in a really good and epic way. I didn't feel like
it was all over the place at all. There's a lot of
different types of villains that he's fighting,
but it doesn't seem like it's outside of an
elaborate plan by Lex Luthor, who really seems to
take the spotlight in this trailer. Yeah, I'm not
sure Lex Luthor is responsible for the portal
beneath Metropolis or even the Kaiju. I would be
surprised if that was the case. I'm pretty sure
that he will be the primary antagonist. But this is
a very, very action packed trailer. That's
probably one of the reasons I really like it
because I love seeing Superman in action. Not only
do we see him stop a series of toppling buildings,
but we also see him zipping around the skies,
battling Kaiju's and other flying super powered
beings. A few of which I actually think might be
Samson or Atlas from All Star Superman, just based
on their hairdos, which are a little bit blurry. I
think they're intentionally keeping some of the
villains secret in the trailers, which is fine by
me. I mean, there's one guy that he punches in the
face. I hope that's just not a normal human who's
wearing a suit of armor. I think if you get punched
in the face by Superman and you're not super human,
your head just explodes. This guy loses some
teeth, but it makes me wonder if Superman pulls his
punches in the same way that Spider-Man does when
he's going up against normal people. Yeah, I'd
like to think that these are some super powered
individuals, because yeah, I don't like the idea
of Superman just punching an ordinary human. But
it is cool to see crypto get in on the action as well.
As we see Superman fighting everyone, we also have
this voiceover from Lex Luthor, who's talking
about how he's essentially going to kill him and
everyone he loves. It's not the best voiceover,
but it does lend credence to the fact that he is the
primary antagonist for this movie and yeah,
probably has an elaborate plot to basically kill
everyone. There's this wild shot of Superman
holding a green baby while being wrapped up by this
other like alien octopus creature. I have no idea
what's going on in that scene, but it looks
incredible. It's very different from I think
anything we've seen before in a Superman film. Of
course, we also get to see the supporting cast,
everyone from Lois Lane, who pilots a high tech
ship alongside Jimmy Olsen and Perry White, as
well as the Justice League members Guy Gardner and
Mr. Terrific. They look awesome. I'm assuming
that ship belongs to Mr. Terrific. Maybe, you
know, it's kind of round almost like one of his
T-Spheres. That's a good guess, I would say. One of
the final shots of the trailer, we see Mr. Terrific
call down to Superman, who looks really beat up
like he has two black eyes and he's facing down this
portal beneath the city. Now, are those black eyes
or has he just been using his heat vision and that's
like heat scarring? I didn't get the impression. I
would hope that using his heat vision would not
give him scarring of any kind. I think it would
temporarily if he did a big enough heat vision
blast. I don't think I would like that personally.
Who knows? Again, the scale of this movie just
looks so massive. And I love the fact that James
Gunn seems to be giving Superman these challenges
that really only Superman can face. Because what
are characters like the X-Men or Spider-Man gonna
do when a massive black hole seems to open up
beneath the city? What is Superman gonna do? I
guess we'll find out. All I know is he's probably
gonna save the day and I can't wait to find out how.
Probably my favorite moment from this trailer is
also near the end where we see Superman surrounded
by these flying villains. And he's just blasting
all of them with heat vision while spinning around
super fast. It may be one of the coolest things I've
ever seen Superman do on screen. And I can't wait to
see it in theaters. This trailer totally sold me on
getting tickets for the film. I bought mine. I hope
you guys have too because it looks like it's gonna
be epic, especially on a really big screen like
IMAX. I'm gonna go see it on the smallest screen I
can. Sucks to suck, I guess. But considering all of
the cool stuff that we get to see Superman do in this
trailer, that brings us to our question of the
week. What has been your favorite Superman moment
from past films or television series? And why? And
this includes animated films and television
shows that Superman has been a part of, going all
the way back to the 1940s. Record your answer at
dynamicdool.com by clicking on the red
microphone button in the bottom right hand corner
of the screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long, and don't forget to leave your name in case we
include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a Dynamic
Duel No Prize that we'll post to Instagram. Be sure
to answer before June 21st. In way better news,
this past week we got the official trailer number
two for the upcoming Iron Heart television series
that's going to be released on Disney Plus,
starting on June 24th. Now Disney Plus is
releasing three episodes of the six episode
series all at once. So basically half the show
starting on June 24th, and then I think the
subsequent episodes will be released weekly. But
this particular trailer is probably the most
exciting look at the show that we've gotten yet, in
that it introduces the concept of
re-re-incorporating magic into her armor
system. Which is pretty damn cool visually,
because as we see her heads up display come up, we
see like sigils and runes and things like that.
It's a really cool concept that they briefly
touched upon in the comic books, where we've seen
her incorporate like the 10 rings into her armor.
And I remember one time she fought alongside Dr.
Strange, and she like accessed the Wellspring, I
think it was called, and she was shooting out like
magic repulsors. I'm pretty positive all this
magic occult stuff ties into the primary villain
of the show, who is the hood, who gets his powers via
the demon Mephisto. Oh I thought Mephisto was
going to be the primary villain. Do you think Riri
like sells her soul to get these powers? I think she
makes a deal with the hood, who is in turn powered by
Mephisto. So it's going to be something like that.
But it's interesting because this whole time we
thought that the show was going to be this set it off
style story where we see Riri steal in order to work
on her armor designs. But it looks like she
actually goes much further than simply stealing,
but she in fact taps into dark magic. So we're
definitely going to see her go down the rabbit hole
as it were, and redeem herself by the end
hopefully. Yeah I had no idea that she had a history
of tapping into magical sources in the comics.
That's interesting. Actually that's definitely
the most interesting thing I've seen come out of
all of these trailers. I would agree with you. Well
I mean it's not something that she regularly does
in the comic books, but there is precedent for
including magic in this type of story. One of the
other big reveals that we got in this trailer is
that the show will be including her AI assistant
named Natalie, and that she will be a 3D
holographic projection, not just a voice within
the armor, kind of like how Jarvis and Friday were
with Tony Stark's armor. I thought in the comics
that Tony Stark was her like AI assistant. No when
he was dead for a time in the comic books his digital
consciousness did serve as like a mentor figure
early on, but no he wasn't her AI assistant like
Natalie was. When Natalie was like who the hell
else would it be, Bish? I was like Tony Stark? Yeah
Tony Stark is the answer to that question. I didn't
love that line at all. That was just horrible
writing. You know who else I thought delivered
terrible lines? Alden Ehrenreich. I'm still
pretty confused as to what his role is going to be in
this show. Well as I mentioned before he's playing
Joe McGillicuddy who is an original character for
this series. I think he's kind of serving as a Tony
Stark stand-in taking on that mental role from the
comic books. I agree it's not great dialogue. The
whole taking things apart and putting it back
together really gives off watchman vibes. And
also I just don't like the idea of him being her
mentor. Like where is Shuri? Why isn't she
mentoring Riri? That's a great question. Yeah
considering that Shuri helped facilitate her
previous armor in Wakanda Forever you think she'd
be keeping tabs on her or something like that. In
the same way that the Dorya Milaje was keeping tabs
on Bucky. Right right right and maybe they'll show
up who knows. All I know is that I'm way more excited
for this show than Superman. And all I know is you
picked a hell of a week to stop sniffing glue. Going
back to DC news recently it was announced that DC
Studios is putting out its second animated series
after Kichir Commandos in Mr. Miracle which is
going to be based off of Tom King's Eisner
award-winning mini series. We got our first look
at the show in a single frame that looks like it was
ripped right from the comics. And we also got a
series description about how essentially Mr.
Miracle will be battling Darkseid who attains the
anti-life equation the result of which is
fracturing Mr. Miracle's mind. Now the comic book
series that this is based on dealt heavily with
themes of like PTSD and depression. I'm not sure
it's the best storyline to introduce the new gods.
I especially don't love the idea of our
introduction to Darkseid having him already
attain the anti-life equation like that's
something you should absolutely build up to. So
while I love the idea that Mr. Miracle is finally
getting his own show I don't love the storyline
that they will be basing it off of. Well they might
alter the storyline a little bit to accommodate
the greater DCU that they're establishing. It
could be more of like a personal story than
touching on the larger plot behind that arc. I
think the show has a lot of work cut out for it. Not
only does it need to introduce us to Jack Kirby's
fourth world and that whole cast of characters but
it also needs to be a personal story set within a
larger world that James Gunn is developing
essentially. Well he did a good job with that in
Creature Commanders. But that was a fairly
self-contained story. When you're involving
characters like Darkseid and things like the
anti-life equation if that doesn't affect other
DC projects I would feel like they would have made a
mistake because really Darkseid and the
anti-life equation should be a Justice League
level threat not just Mr. Miracle and Big Barda. I
guess it would be like saving Thanos and the
Infinity Gauntlet for an animated series as
opposed to a whole saga of films. Exactly. I doubt
they would do that and even if they do there's still
plenty of other large scale DC threats out there
for the films to touch on. Now there is a way in which
they could keep this self-contained that would
basically be to have Mr. Miracle contained within
an Omega Sanction which is a trap essentially set
by Darkseid in which Mr. Miracle would just relive
countless lives over and over. We'll see if they go
that route. They would almost need to. I think that
would be pretty cool actually. We'll have to keep
an eye on who they cast as the voice actors for these
different characters because as James Gunn has
said he wants there to be as much crossover between
the animation voice actors and live action actors
as possible. And here's hoping we get a live action
new gods movie one day. I think most fans know that
they try to get a live action new gods film off the
ground in the DCEU days with a film directed by Ava
DuVernay but that didn't come to fruition. It is
nice to see this fourth world stuff finally get off
the ground and hopefully it's done well. Yeah I
hope so. We don't know what network this is going to
be on. It may not be on HBO Max. I guess they're
shopping it around so we'll see where it ends up and
when it gets released. But that does it for all the
news for this episode so let's go ahead and move
into our main event where we find out who'd win in a
fight between the two teams of the Freedom
Fighters and X Factor. Alright Freedom Fighters
versus X Factor as we mentioned earlier these are
two teams that have been backed by the government
going up against each other. That's kind of their
thematic through line here although X Factor has
definitely spent time on its own not being
government sanctioned but I think the most
prominent version of the X Factor team was
spearheaded by government agent Valerie Cooper.
Who's that? Yeah I guess that means nothing to you
if you don't know the comic books but she had a lot of
dealings with like the X-Men books putting
together like Freedom Force. I go into it in our
Mystique versus Madame Rouge episode. Wait
Freedom Force why does that sound familiar?
Because that was Mystique's team of mutants like
the second iteration of the Brotherhood of
Mutants that were working for the government.
They were kind of like Marvel's version of the
Suicide Squad for a while. I'm sorry the correct
answer was because it's a ripoff of Freedom
Fighters. Now the Freedom Fighters actually had
their own animated movie of sorts I guess you could
say they featured heavily in the Rey animated
series which was set in the Arrowverse. Oh
interesting Yeah X Factor hasn't had their own
show or series or anything like that but a lot of the
characters have already played roles within the
live action X-Men films. Yeah characters like
Havoc were in the X-Men first class movies.
Polaris was in that one X-Men TV show I forget the
name. Yeah the Gifted but Ice Man of course was in
the movies. Multiple Man made an appearance in
X-Men 3. Beast of course was in the films. A whole
bunch of them. Maybe if things go well for the DCU
one day we'll get a Freedom Fighters movie who
knows. Oh that'd be cool. I'll say that there is an
impressive roster of characters on that team and
we'll discuss that soon but to explain the
methodology behind our duels let's go to our
sentient duel simulator Alfred Jarvis 9000. AJ9K
tell our listeners how you go about determining a
winner in our team duel matchups. Yes of course sir
the way I determine a winner between the two teams
is by running 1,000 Monte Carlo simulations
between every character on each team using their
statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation is a
probabilistic model used to determine outcomes
through random sampling. In this case I randomize
the statistics along a normal distribution as a
way to simulate the many variables that can occur
during battle. The stat parameters are based on
the official Marvel power grid from which the DC
characters statistics are extrapolated.
Additional stat categories are included such as
range, damage potential, versatility and
perception in order to create a more detailed and
accurate simulation. The results of the 49,000
simulations provide a percentage of wins for each
character on both teams. The team with the higher
average win rate is declared the victor as they
have a higher probability to win any given battle.
In an equitable pairing neither team should win
100% of the matches. The comic book stories have
shown that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman so the confidence rate of my method falls
in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks A.J .9K.
Before we run the simulations though we like to
break down each team's histories and rosters
before improvising a scenario on how we imagine
one of the thousands of simulations would play out
beat for beat. And it's my turn to go first with the
DC team's backstory so let me tell you about the
Freedom Fighters. Now the Freedom Fighters began
as a group of American superheroes brought
together during World War II by the mysterious
patriotic figure known as Uncle Sam. More than a
man Uncle Sam was the living embodiment of
American ideals, a spiritual force that had taken
form to protect the nation during times of crisis.
You can of course learn more about Uncle Sam in our
Uncle Sam vs Captain Burr in dual episode. As war
erupted across the globe Uncle Sam foresaw grave
danger ahead not just from the Nazis on earth but
from a parallel world where the Axis powers had
already won. That world was Earth X, a twisted
mirror of earth where the Nazis won the war and were
taking control of the entire planet. In an effort
to prevent the same fate from befalling his own
world, Uncle Sam assembled a team of heroes to
travel to Earth X and resist its oppressive
regime. His earliest group included lesser known
heroes like Neon the Unknown, Magno, Miss
America, and the Invisible Hood among others.
They attempted to prevent the attack on Pearl
Harbor but failed. Most of the team actually
perished in the mission with seemingly only Uncle
Sam surviving. Undeterred, Uncle Sam assembled a
second team consisting of Black Condor, Dollman,
the Human Bomb, the Ray, Phantom Lady, and the Red
Bee. They joined Uncle Sam on Earth X where they
continued to fight against the Nazi regime that
had overrun the planet. Tragically, the Red Bee
was killed during their first mission, rescuing
the hero Our Man from a Nazi villain known as Baron
Blitzkrieg. Eventually, the team liberated
Earth X with the help of the Justice League from
Earth One and the Justice Society from Earth Two.
You could learn more about both teams in their team
duels against the Avengers and Fantastic Four
respectively. After their success, the Freedom
Fighters became bored with peace and sought new
challenges. They migrated to Earth One where a
misunderstanding with authorities led them to be
wrongfully accused of terrorism. Framed by a
villain called the Silver Ghost, the team became
fugitives, struggling to clear their names while
fending off both supervillains and law
enforcement. They set up a base in New York City's
East Armory and continued operating as heroes
while being hunted by the authorities. While the
team faced many threats including alien war
makers and demons like Kamulus, they briefly
added new members like Firebrand and battled
alongside Superman, eventually preventing a
neo-Nazi plot to destroy American foundational
documents. After that, they returned to Earth X.
When the crisis on Infinite Earths destroyed
Earth X and folded its history into a single
continuity known as New Earth, the Freedom
Fighters were retroactively made a part of the
All-Star Squadron, a wartime superhero
collective that included other teams like the
Seven Soldiers of Victory and the Justice
Society. With Uncle Sam having mysteriously
vanished, the Freedom Fighters eventually faded
into obscurity. In modern times, Uncle Sam
re-emerged as the spirit of America, taking on a
new form as the Patriot during an intergalactic
conflict known as the Imperiax War. He gathered
together a new team of Freedom Fighters including
Damage, Iron Man Rowe, and new versions of Black
Condor, Phantom Lady, and the Wray. They later
worked with the Justice Society and operated as
federal agents. This team eventually met
disaster while investigating superhuman
activity during another crisis event. Black
Condor, Phantom Lady, and the Human Bomb were all
killed by members of the Seeker Society of
Supervillains. Damage was gravely injured and
Wray was captured while Uncle Sam vanished once
again. With their leader presumed dead and most of
the team destroyed, the Freedom Fighters
effectively ceased to exist. Uncle Sam returned
years later, resurrected in the Mississippi
River. With a new sense of purpose and warning of a
corrupt government on the rise, he recruited a new
generation of heroes. Among them were new
versions of Firebrand, Dullman, Human Bomb,
Phantom Lady, and the Wray. These new Freedom
Fighters had previously served as agents of the
shadowy government agency, Shade, led by the
immortal Father Time. Uncle Sam opposed their
brutal methods and convinced them to join his
fight against tyranny. Operating from a surreal
extra-dimensional base called the Heartland,
the new team continued to add members, including a
new Black Condor, Red Bee, and Invisible Hood.
Their main enemy became Father Time himself, who
was working to install a mechanical doppelganger
of a U.S. Senator, Gonzo, the mechanical bastard,
as President of the United States. Uncle Sam
discovered the plot and tried to expose Gonzo, but
was captured along with his team by a new Miss
America, secretly one of Father Time's agents.
The team was rescued by reinforcements that
included the resurrected original Miss America,
who defeated her imposter. With new allies like
the Second Wray, who you can learn more about in our
Wray vs. Havoc episode, the team regrouped and
fought back. They exposed Gonzo's identity in a
public press conference, just as he unleashed an
army of mind-controlled metahumans. Father
Time, betrayed by Gonzo, switched sides and
helped trap the robotic tyrant inside a special
containment device. Before vanishing into the
time stream with brainwashed metas, Father Time
revealed The president appointed the Freedom
Fighters as directors of Shade, though some
members, like the Rey, chose to return to civilian
life. Their next battles were no less strange.
They stopped a rogue nuclear launch orchestrated
by the calculator and later dealt with the bizarre
evolution of the Red Bee, who had been transformed
into a human insect hybrid. Shade tried turning
the team into media icons, but not everyone agreed
with this direction. Several members, including
Uncle Sam, Dullman, Human Bomb, and Firebrand,
returned to the heartland in protest. Others
remained and formed a new group called the
Crusaders. The Red Bee's condition worsened and
she eventually lost control to her insectoid
instincts, enslaving the Crusaders and the
Freedom Fighters through pheromones. A massive
battle erupted between the brainwashed heroes
culminating in the intervention of Linkford
Tarrell, who had inherited the power of Nyand
Yen-None. He cured Red Bee of the infestation and
the team stopped an insectoid invasion. Despite
the victory, however, the group dissolved again.
Though Uncle Sam vowed they would return when
needed. In post-Flashpoint continuity, the
Freedom Fighters appeared in alternate forms
across the multiverse. On Earth 10, they were
reimagined as a resistance force fighting
against a Nazi regime that had won World War II with
the help from Overman, a Superman-like figure
raised under fascism. The team's members were
genetically engineered by Dr. Savanna to
represent an inclusive, modern resistance
movement. It included alternate versions of Rey,
Black Condor, Phantom Lady, and Dullman, and the
destruction of a Justice League orbital station
over Metropolis. On the main Earth, a Chinese
version of the Freedom Fighters appeared, led by
the flying Dragon General. Members included
analogues of the original team, such as Sunbeam
for the Rey, Blue Condor, Ghost Woman, Folding
Paper Man, who was a version of Plastic Man, and
Human Firecracker. These characters embodied
nationalistic ideals tailored to China,
reflecting how the legacy of the Freedom Fighters
had spread beyond the United States. Recently,
the original Freedom Fighters surviving
members, including Uncle Sam and Phantom Lady,
reappeared during a discussion between Mr.
Trevick and Quiz Kid. There were shown mentoring,
the time-lost Sidekicks Cherry Bomb, and
Ladybug, young heroes who had once been
associated with the original human bomb and Red
Bee. And that's the Freedom Fighters history so
far. Now, for my 7-person roster for the Freedom
Fighters, I of course started with Uncle Sam, the
leader of the team, and the one responsible for
bringing various incarnations together. I'm
also going with the original team members of Black
Condor, capable of flight thanks to his wind
control, and the Rey, a being composed of pure
light energy, both of whom you can learn more about
in our Black Condor vs. Warpath and Rey vs. Havoc
episodes. Original members we haven't done duels
with yet that are on my team include Phantom Lady,
who can turn visible, intangible, and create
holographic illusions, the human bomb, who
possesses a powerful explosive touch, as well as
superhuman durability, and Dollman, the 6-inch
telekinetic. For the 7th and final member of my
team, I decided to go with Plastic Man, a
short-lived member of the team, yet hands down the
most popular character from Quality Comics,
where all of these characters originated prior to
DC's acquisition of that company. And you of
course can learn more about Plastic Man in his duel
against Mr. Fantastic. So to reiterate, my team
consists of Uncle Sam, Black Condor, Rey, Phantom
Lady, Human Bomb, Dollman, and Plastic Man. Yeah,
I really like that roster except for Dollman, who
is probably the worst DC character ever. You say
that about every DC character. That's true, but I
really mean it this time. Dollman's basically
just an action figure with telekinesis. And his
name is Dollman. You should be ashamed. Hey,
here's an acquisition, man. You came with the
whole package. What are you gonna do? Well, I can
guarantee you there's no one named Dollman on X
Factor, although some members did have some
pretty lame names like Strong Guy. Although
Guido's power was pretty cool. Let me tell you all
about X Factor. The five original X-Men, Cyclops,
Gene Gray, Angel, Beast, and Iceman, reunited
after Gene Gray was discovered alive after being
thought dead and was temporarily replaced by the
cosmic entity known as the Phoenix Force, an event
you can learn more about in our Raven vs. Phoenix
duel episode. The group, feeling out of place on a
team now led by their old enemy, Magneto, formed X
Factor Incorporated with Angel using his wealth
to fund the operation. To the public, X Factor was a
group of mutant hunters who captured dangerous
individuals for pay. In truth, the team found and
sheltered young mutants in an effort to help them
control and develop their newfound abilities.
While hunting the Alliance of Evil, they met
Apocalypse, an ancient mutant who preached
survival of the fittest. He vanished after
testing their strength in their first encounter,
promising to return. Soon, the villain Mr.
Sinister's mutant henchmen known as the
Marauders butchered a group of mutants called the
Morlocks who were living in the sewers under
Manhattan. Angel rushed in to help and the killers
severely damaged his wings. Broken and bitter, he
tried to attempt suicide but Apocalypse saved him
and experimented on him, giving him metal wings
and blue skin. Angel was transformed into Death,
one of Apocalypse's agents known as the Four
Horsemen. Angel later broke free of his mind to
control, yet his new form and the name Archangel
stayed with him. You can learn more about
Archangel and Apocalypse in their respective
duels against Zoriel and Black Adam.
Apocalypse's horseman attacked Central Park,
and X Factor saved thousands of civilians, many
belonging to the same crowd that had cursed
mutants in fear. With Apocalypse defeated, the
team moved into his captured living starship, a
base big enough for all their young students.
Later, demons warped the mind of Cyclops' wife and
Jean's clone named Madeleine Pryor, turning her
into a possessed villain known as the Goblin
Queen. She tried to sacrifice her and Cyclops' son
Nathan on the Empire State Building, but X Factor
and the X-Men teamed up to stop her. However,
Apocalypse soon kidnapped Nathan and infected
him with a techno-organic virus to kill him.
Rebels from 2000 years into the future traveled to
the present and took the baby forward in time to
save him. He would return later as the hero Cable,
whom you can learn more about in his dual episode
against Booster Gold. After a final fight on Muir
Island against the evil psychic entity Shadow
King, the founding five X Factor members rejoined
the X-Men and X Factor closed its first chapter.
You can learn more about the X-Men in their team
dual against the Titans. Federal agent Valerie
Cooper believed the United States needed a public
mutant team and asked Cyclops' brother Havoc to
lead a government-backed X Factor. Cooper also
brought aboard Lorna Dane, a magnetic-powered
mutant called Polaris. When Lorna was a young
teen, her parents argued mid-flight on a private
plane. The stress triggered her hidden magnetism
power, which tore the plane apart and turned her
hair green. The mutant magneto sensed the
magnetic pulse and rescued Lorna, later learning
that she was his daughter. He left her with
relatives to grow up safely and as an adult, she
joined the X-Men and later joined Havoc as the
second X Factor recruit. Valerie Cooper also
contacted Jamie Madrox, the mutant known as
Multiple Man. From the moment Jamie was born, when
the doctor slapped his baby behind, the child
split into a perfect duplicate. Born with the
mutant power of kinetic duplication, Jamie wore a
suit that absorbed his shocks so he would not keep
dividing. Years later, after leaving his Kansas
farm, the X-Men's leader Professor Xavier
discovered and taught Jamie how to reabsorb his
duplicates and keep their memories. As Multiple
Man, he became the team's instant backup. Wolf
Spain, a Scott's girl who could shift into a wolf,
signed on next. Strong Guy, who stored impact
energy as muscle and the speedster Quicksilver,
rounded out the new squad. Together, they stopped
Mr. Sinister, foiled extremists in the war-torn
Middle East, and guarded witnesses from mutant
killers like Cyber. On the island of Genosha, when
one of Multiple Man's duplicates caught the
lethal legacy virus and died, the team feared the
original Multiple Man was lost. Strong Guy
absorbed an alien bomb blast over Magipore and
suffered a heart attack that put him in a coma.
Havoc, quit in grief, and Forge, a mutant inventor
who could build any device he imagined, became the
team's new leader. Washington soon forced
Mystique and the Feral Sabertooth onto the
roster, but soon, funding dried up and the
government squad dissolved. The original
Multiple Man later resurfaced in New York's
mutant town and opened X-Factor Investigations,
a private detective agency. He hired Wolfsbane
and the recovered Strong Guy, also welcoming
Teresa Cassidy into the agency. Teresa, called
Siren, could shatter steel with her sonic scream.
Raised by her criminal uncle, Black Tom Cassidy,
she once aided him in robberies, unaware that her
real father was the heroic X-Men member Banshee,
from whom she acquired her powers. After being
caught stealing by Spider-Woman, Siren chose a
better path with X-Factor Investigations. The
mutants Monet, St. Croix, and Richter joined
next, followed by Leila Miller, a team with hidden
knowledge about the mass loss of mutant powers
around the world caused by the Scarlet Witch, an
event you can learn more about in her duel against
Zatana. When the X-Factor detectives outsmarted
the rival firm, Singularity Investigations, the
anti-mute agency retaliated by firing a
power-dampening dart into Siren's throat,
temporarily stripping her upper power.
Quicksilver later appeared with Tarogen
crystals stolen from the Inhumans that could
restore a mutant's lost powers, but also cripple
the user. X-Factor exposed the risk and drove him
off. You can learn more about this in our Flash vs.
Quicksilver episode. Leila Miller later
followed a multiple-man duplicate into a future
where mutants were jailed, while the present
multiple-man battled Cortex, who was a rogue
duplicate who had become an evil murderer. The
billionaire Cade bombed New York's mutant town,
forcing the agency to move to Detroit. After Siren
was impregnated by multiple-man, or perhaps one
of his duplicates, she gave birth to a boy named
Sean, named after her father. However, while
holding the infant, multiple-man involuntary
absorbed his child, who was born with the same
powers, an act that devastated both parents.
Later, when Polaris' mind unraveled after being
tortured by Apocalypse, Siren bargained with the
Celtic goddess Morrigan for power that healed
Lorna, yet bound Siren to the deity's service.
During these struggles, Jaime recruited
Longshot to the agency, a genetically engineered
rebel from the television ratings-obsessed
dimension of Mojo World. Longshot had enhanced
physiology, limited psychometry, throwing
knives, and a subconscious gift to bent
probability in his favor. After finding an
interdimensional portal to Earth, he helped the
X-Men repel an invasion by Mojo, his impossible
luck earning him the moniker Longshot. When the
agency dissolved, Polaris accepted an offer from
several industries to lead a short-lived,
corporate-backed X-Factor team with Gambit,
Quicksilver, Danger, Cipher, and Warlock on the
team. During this time, they rescued mutant
hostages from the evil science organization AIM,
retrieved stolen data from the Thieves Guild, and
prevented a potential threat by the tech-narci,
an artificially intelligent alien race. When
Professor Xavier founded the island nation of
Cracowa, the mutant North Star formed another
X-Factor team. He drafted Polaris, his twin
sister Aurora, Wolverine's son Daken, the
power-mimicking prodigy, illusion-spotting
i-boy, and the telepathic prestige. Their
assigned task for their new nation was to confirm a
mutant's death so that Cracowa's resurrection
protocols would not create accidental
duplicates. The team's first cases took them into
Mojo World's lethal live streams, and later to
Alberta, Canada, after Siren, who was still bound
to Morrigan, repeatedly caused her own death in
order to stall the Celtic Deity's mass sacrifice
of every mutant on Cracowa. The mutant
Shatterstar's dimension-cutting swords killed
the goddess, freeing Siren from her control.
X-Factor later investigated the mysterious
death of the Scarlet Witch on Cracowa, though it
was determined to be an elaborate ruse by her and
Magneto. Their plan used Chaos Magic to establish
on Cracowa a magic plane of existence called the
Waiting Group, which allowed Cerebro to scan
through time for mutants to use in Cracowa's
resurrection protocols, ensuring that every
mutant who had ever died, past or future, had a
chance at resurrection. This plane, however, was
destroyed during the fall of Cracowa. That's
X-Factor's history. For the seven-person
roster, I'm going with a mix of mutants from across
the various iterations of the team. This includes
the original members Beast and Iceman, who formed
the first X-Factor alongside their original
X-Men teammates, and both have their own
individual duels. Also on my team are Havoc,
Polaris, and multiple men who were founding
members of the X-Factor's government team. Out of
that group, only Havoc has his own duel. And for my
final two, I'm going with members of the X-Factor
Investigations Agency, Siren, and Longshot. So
to reiterate, that's Beast, Iceman, Havoc,
Polaris, multiple men, Siren, and Longshot.
Yeah, this is a solid roster, and I'm actually
surprised some of those members like Iceman and
Beast haven't been in previous team duel episodes
with other X-Men characters. I'm glad we finally
get around with them. Yeah, for sure. Some of my
favorite X-Men characters of all time are members
of X-Factor. I'm a huge Jamie Madrox fan, multiple
man, and while it's a shame we won't be doing an
individual duel with him, I'm glad to at least be
doing this team duel with the character. Yeah, he
has one of the coolest powers in comics, I think. If
I could have any super power, like my list of top
five would definitely be multiple man's powers.
Yeah, and his Madrox series and X-Factor written
by Peter David rest in peace, he did a phenomenal
job writing Jamie Madrox as a character. Now that
we've got the teams, histories, and rosters out of
the way, let's speculate on how one of the
thousands of simulated matches will go. The
winners determined by simulations, not our
speculation, but it's fun to imagine how the fight
could play out. AJ and IK, what are the rules of our
speculation? Well, I should say there are no
rules, other than the teams have no prior
knowledge of the other going into the fight. All
they are aware of starting out is that the other
side is a threat that needs to be eliminated. For
the speculation, the groups will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the match
itself, as no environmental statistics are
considered in my simulations. The teams must earn
victory on their own merit. All right, then let's
get into it. Freedom fighters and X-Factor meet on
the battlefield. Who goes first? I'm going to say
Uncle Sam goes first, and he's going to start by
growing about six stories tall right off the bat,
and he's going to point to the X-Factor and say, I
want you to die. And so he's going to leap towards
them and land right on top of the group, just
stopping them all into the ground with his giant
feet. No, but Siren is going to shout out a sonic
blast at Uncle Sam as he's trying to land on them.
And the sonic force waves are going to make him fall
short in his leap, and he's just going to fall on his
ass instead. And then Havoc unloads a giant plasma
blast in Freedom Fighters direction that for sure
incinerates Uncle Sam, but also just
disintegrates the rest of the team. For sure. No.
Uncle Sam is basically invulnerable. So he may get
burned, but he's not going to disintegrate. In
fact, actually his body is going to act as a barrier
between both teams, and he's going to protect his
side from Havoc's energy. And from behind Uncle
Sam, the ray is just going to zip right into the sky
and rain lasers down upon X-Factor, which is going
to provide cover for the rest of his team to emerge
into the battle. Well, Polaris throws up an
electromagnetic shield that'll protect
X-Factor from the ray's lasers and also provide
that team with cover to go out into the battle. And
right away, Iceman rides over to Black Condor, and
he's going to be like, let's clip those wings, and
he's just going to perforate Black Condor's wings
with the volley of icicles, just turning the wings
into Swiss cheese. So now the dude can't even fly.
No, I'm going to say Black Condor totally saw
Iceman sliding toward him, because how could he
not? And he's going to counter these icicles with a
generated gust of wind that's strong enough to
redirect them toward, let's say, beast. And it's
going to attack him in his chest and in each of his
limbs. Well, okay, so beast gets tagged with like
one or two of these icicles, but the damage is minor
at best. He also has quick enough reflexes to avoid
the rest of the ice spikes by flipping into the air.
And in fact, he catches one of the icicles, and he's
going to land on Uncle Sam's giant head and
probably make some quip about the sorry state of US
politics before just jamming the icicle right
into one of Uncle Sam's eyes. So now Uncle Sam has no
depth perception for the rest of this match. Well,
let's say Dull Man was on Uncle Sam when this
happened, just kind of hiding out. And he's
definitely too small for beast to notice. So
before beast can even land on Uncle Sam, Dull Man is
going to telekinetically stall beast in midair
and then hurl him really hard right into long
shots, sending both of them toppling across the
ground. Except that with long shots, good luck
power. He ducks out of the way just in time. So beast
misses hitting long shot and instead he rolls into
a ball that plows right into Phantom Lady, like a
furry 300 pound bowling ball. Okay. And he just
knocks her right the heck out. Except that Phantom
Lady was invisible and intangible at the time. So
no, actually he slams into multiple man. And
that's just going to send new versions of multiple
man scattered everywhere. Well, she's like an
impact of that magnitude would probably create
like 20 duplicates of multiple man
instantaneously. And I'm going to say that all 20
of these dupes are going to run over to the human
bomb and just start stomping his ass like they owe
him money. Human bomb. You clearly know nothing
about human bomb. You fucked up. I'm going to say as
these multiple men are attacking the human bomb,
he's going to pull off one of his gloves and just
punch one of them right in the shin, generating
this massive explosion that disrupts the entire
environment. Everyone just goes flying away from
the explosion and all of the multiple men
themselves, including the original, capture the
brunt of this explosion and get disintegrated.
You can't do that. No, that was way too quick for
multiple man. He didn't know what human bomb does.
How was multiple man supposed to know? He's going
to learn today. He just did. Okay, so multiple
man's out and the battlefield is a shallow crater.
Everyone's scattered. The dupes are dead and
everyone on X Factor is probably like, oh, shit, we
got to get rid of this human bomb guy. So I'm just
going to go out on a limb here and say that I think the
human bomb suit is made out of metal. Oh, no,
actually, it's a material called fibrowax. It's
like this non-metallic heat resistant material.
It's like the only thing he could touch that
doesn't explode because it's chemically inert.
Fucking course it is. Well, then Iceman freezes
human bomb. So now he's just frozen in this big ice
cube and Siren lets out a sonic cry that shatters
the ice cube and human bomb to pieces. So he's out of
this match now. No more threat from him.
Meanwhile, Havoc fires a plasma wave at Plastic
Man that just melts him into a plastic puddle.
Okay, well, Plastic Man, of course, is going to be
super extra about it. He's going to transform to
look like the Wicked Witch of the West. He's going
to be like, I'm melting. I'm melting. And that's
going to get the attention of Black Condor, who is
just going to dive bomb Havoc and knock him onto the
ground, which is going to give Plastic Man just
enough time to spring into the air and turn into
this small house that lands on Havoc crushing his
body with only his legs poking out from beneath the
foundation. So Havoc's dead. Why all the Wizard of
Oz references? I don't know. Plastic Man just
watched the movie. It was tough to mine. Okay,
well, Polaris would be upset by Havoc's death.
She's angry and she's so angry that she emits a
electromagnetic wave that fries all the tech on
the battlefield. So that would include Phantom
Lady's tech, right? And whoever else uses tech.
And at the very least, I think the EMP would make Ray
puke his guts or something. Oh, right. Because
he's sensitive to electromagnetic energy.
Maybe, maybe. But yeah, Phantom Lady really is the
only one on the team who uses tech. It would disrupt
her Black Light technology that gives her her
powers. So, you know, she's probably not
invisible or intangible anymore. Good. Because
that's when Beast leaps over to her and lands like
this 25 hit combo. Just like a cartwheel kick
followed by like a breakdance windmill move and
like a capoeira butterfly kick thing. Phantom
Lady is just getting hit like, uh, and then, you
know, she's dead. Wow. Okay. Meanwhile, Polaris,
she's suddenly going to get wrapped up in a giant
Plastic Man burrito. Like literally it's a giant
tortilla with goggles. And in her panic while
trying to get out, she's going to quickly use up all
of her air and suffocate. So, she's out. A burrito
is a weird way to go out. But I'm going to say this is a
frozen burrito because Iceman just froze Plastic
Man and Plastic Man's out of the match because Ice
is his weakness. But Iceman grows into a giant form
like an Ice Giant about the same size as Uncle Sam.
And he's going to grab this frozen Plastic Man
burrito and just slap it across the face of Uncle
Sam. So Plastic Man shatters and Uncle Sam just got
walloped in the face. Okay. So you literally awoke
a sleeping giant. Bad move because while Iceman is
distracted by treading blows with Uncle Sam, Rey
is going to just bombard Iceman from above with
heat waves. That's going to melt him and evaporate
him simultaneously so that Iceman becomes
non-existent, basically. Okay. But Beast, after
beating the crap out of Phantom Lady, he used his
ingenuity to get her Black Light technology
working again because he studied it and he's smart
like that. And he's going to use her Black Light
technology to emit a Black Light hologram that
he's going to shoot at the Rey, which is going to
encase the Rey in darkness and just erase him from
this match. Interesting. Okay. Science. That was
a good move, actually. But suddenly, Uncle Sam's
giant top hat is going to slam down over Beast and
when he lifts it back up, Beast is gone because he
was banished to the Heartland dimension by Uncle
Sam, who used his hat like a portal. What is he? Some
kind of stage magician? Sure. Instead of pulling a
rabbit out of a hat, he puts a beast into it. But then
all of a sudden, Uncle Sam's head explodes. What?
And Dollman crawls out of it. Why? Because Siren
used her hypnotizing Siren song to lure Dollman
into going into Uncle Sam's head and then blowing
it up with a mental blast. Dang. Well, with the
death of Uncle Sam, the leader of the team, Black
Condor is going to fly literal around Siren,
trapping her in a tornado that's also going to suck
the air away from her. And that's going to prevent
her from using her sound powers while also
simultaneously knocking her unconscious from
the lack of oxygen. So Siren's out. But then all of a
sudden, Black Condor falls out of the sky because
he got a throwing blade to the face. And yeah, he's
high up in the air, but Longshot threw the blade and
Longshot's aim is lucky like that, which means
that the battle is down to Longshot and Dollman.
Oh, shit. OK, Dollman, he's a master of stealth
operations. So he's just going to use the
environment and like all of the bodies strewn
about to hide from Longshot. And he's going to wait
until Longshot just stumbles right over him. And
that's when Dollman is going to do a leaping
uppercut right to Longshot's abdomen, just
knocking the wind out of him. And with Longshot on
his knees, trying to breathe, that's when Dollman
is going to deliver a knockout punch right to
Longshot's temple, knocking him out. So Dollman
is like leaping around doing all this punching.
Yeah. OK. Well, when Dollman first makes contact
when he knocks the wind out of Longshot, that's
when Longshot got a glimpse of Dollman's future
using his psychometry. So Longshot knows that the
second blow to his head is coming while he's
kneeling. So instead of landing that shot,
Dollman just jumps into a knife that Longshot
threw and the match is over. Nah, because Dollman,
he's really agile for his size. And so as the knife
is coming at him, Dollman's just going to freeze it
midair, jump onto the blade like he's surfing it,
and he's going to ride it as he telekinetically
hurls it right into Longshot's own neck. Yeah, he
meant to do that, but he mistimed everything and
then got cleaved into by the knife. Caused, of
course, by Longshot's probability
manipulation. That's dumb. That's also probably
a good place to leave the match. Either Dollman
uses Longshot's own blade against him or Dollman
just has bad luck and ends up getting cleaved into.
Let's go ahead and put the team members statistics
into our simulator, run the sims, and come back
with the winner. A.J .9K, hit it! Inputting data,
running calculations, processing results,
simulations complete. What'd you think of this
episode? I thought it was pretty fun. I liked the
rosters on both teams. They're definitely really
cool characters. Like I mentioned earlier that
Multiple Man had a cool power set, but so does like
the human bomb and Phantom Lady and Rey and really
all of the members of the Freedom Fighters. Yeah,
it was really fun to pair those characters against
X Factor. In order to maintain like, a semblance of
fairness between these rosters, we like to pair up
each of the characters. So in this instance, we
went with Rey and Iceman, Plastic Man and Multiple
Man, Dollman and Longshot, Black Condor and
Siren, Phantom Lady and Polaris, Human Bomb and
Havoc, and Uncle Sam and Beast. I thought those
were pretty damn good pairings. Yeah, a few of
those would have made fantastic individual dual
episodes. Inputting the team statistics, it
looks like the biggest differences between the
teams were in the categories of durability and
perception, with the Freedom Fighters being way
more durable, like shockingly more durable than X
Factor. As compared to some of DC's characters
like Plastic Man, Uncle Sam, Human Bomb, who all
have increased durability. Yeah, the Rey can
regenerate and stuff like that. My most durable
character was Iceman, who could also regenerate.
But we had decent evasiveness like Polaris has her
force fields, Longshot has his probability
manipulation, and Iceman also has shielding. We
did say that the X Factor team was much more
versatile. A lot of the Freedom Fighter members
are kind of one-trick ponies. I think another
category that sticks out is range. A lot of the X
Factor guys have some sort of ranged attack,
except for Beast. Now, I definitely had the most
powerful character on both teams in the Rey,
surprisingly. No, he wasn't the most powerful. He
actually tied with Polaris, who was also very
powerful and the most powerful on X Factor,
stat-wise. But X Factor had the weakest members
out of both teams in Siren and Havoc, which is
shocking to say because they're both pretty
powerful characters. So I think that just goes to
show that both teams have really solid rosters. So
with all of this said, Joseph, which team do you
think came out on top? I think it's going to be X
Factor. And Instagram agrees with me, because 61%
of our followers who took part in our poll said that
X Factor would win. And I think the win rate's going
to be right around there. I feel like anytime you
pit an X-Men team against any other team, people
are going to vote for the X-Men team. They're just,
yeah, more popular. As they should. But are they
right? Let's find out. AJ9K, the results please.
Hey, you are, sir. The winner in the team duel
matchup between Freedom Fighters and X Factor
is... Freedom Fighters! Bish! How the hell did
that happen? By how much? Freedom Fighters won
56.2% of the simulated matches compared to X
Factor's 43.8. So it was close, but not that close,
I guess. You thought X Factor was going to beat
Freedom Fighters by 61%. Yeah. What? Why not?
Because they're not that good, bro. I was
initially thinking about having Quicksilver on
this team duel, and I wonder if maybe I should have
replaced Longshot or Siren with Quicksilver, who
may have been more statistically impressive. I
was thinking about that when you were listing all
the different characters that were on the team,
and I was like, oh, Quicksilver, why was he not on
this roster? Not that it would have made a
difference. It probably wouldn't have made a
difference. I think I still would have lost,
because even Quicksilver is not that much
statistically better than Longshot or Siren or
Havoc. Freedom Fighters, I guess, is just a team
composed of cheater characters who are way too
powerful for their own good. Just vague and
powerful. That's all DC has. I mean, they didn't
even start on DC. They were quality comics
characters that DC acquired. Well, they acquired
them because the characters were vague and super
powerful. And winners, unlike your team, of
losers. Now, actually, the losers are a DC team as
well. Oh, yeah, that's fair. That's true. But that
does it for this duel. AJ9K help close us out.
Thanks for listening to Dynamic Joule. Visit the
show's website at dynamicjoule.com, and follow
us on Instagram at Dynamic Joule podcast. You can
support the show on Patreon at patreon.com slash
dynamicjoule and joining a tier that works for
you, or by rating and reviewing Dynamic Joule on
Apple Podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser, or on our
website. Don't forget to listen to the other shows
in the Dynamite podcast network, including Max
Destruction, Senjo World, and Console Combat. In
our next episode, in lead up to the Superman film,
we will be doing another duel episode this time
between the Green Lantern Guy Gardner against
Gord the God Butcher. That'll be a fun one. Can't
wait for Guy to get his ass kicked. But that does it
for this episode. We want to give a big thanks to our
executive producers, John Strausky, Zachary
Hepburn, Dustin Balcom, Maggie Mathen-Geehan,
Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yatn, Austin
Wieselowski, AJ Dunkerly, Nick Abanto, Scott
Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Spees, Dean Molesky,
Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, Josh Leiner, Mike
Williams, Oscar Galvez, and Paul Graves for
helping make this podcast possible. We'll talk to
you guys next week. I'm up and away, true
believers. But the real question is who would win
between X Factor and the Masked Singer. Am I right?