This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi, welcome to
the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Johnny DC and I'm his twin
brother Marvelous Joe and in this episode we are
doing a duel between the characters of Rey from DC
and Havok, Cyclops brother. Yeah, Havok has been
part of the X-Men and X-Factor. He's probably the
biggest X-Men character that we have yet to do a
duel with, although you know we haven't done a duel
with Kitty Pride yet so that needs to happen at some
point. Oh totally. This episode is actually in
lead-up to a future team duel we have planned
between the Freedom Fighters and X-Factor since
the Rey is a member of the Freedom Fighters. Yeah,
you can expect that team duel next month I believe.
It should be exciting to see who wins between these
two energy-blasting characters but before that
we're gonna break down the latest comic book movie
news that came out this past week. Of which there
was one news item and that was the release of the
peacemaker season 2 official teaser. As always we
list our second-hand times in our episode
description so feel free to check out the show
notes if you want to skip ahead to a particular
topic. Our artificially intelligent duel
simulator AJ9K has a quick message for our
listeners so listen up. The X-Forced Tier gives
you access to our Discord chat server, the
Fantastic Four Tier gives you two bonus episodes
each month and the X-Forced Tier makes you an
executive producer of this show. Lastly the Diner
Mike podcast network tier lets you create your own
podcast using this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny
and Joe will help you develop your show, provide
graphic support and consultation and get you
simulation results. Pitch the twins your ideas
via email at dynamicdualpodcast.com Thanks AJ9K
and thanks to everyone who supports the podcast.
Guys be sure to tune into the other shows in the
Diner Mike podcast network this week including
console combat where hosts John and Dean simulate
battles between popular video game characters
and yesterday's episode they speculated on who
would win in a fight between Ellie Williams from
The Last of Us versus Claire Redfield from
Resident Evil. Also make sure to check out the Max
Destruction podcast hosted by Scotty and Gilly
who paint your favorite action heroes from film
and television against each other. Their podcast
and Senjo World the anime and manga battle podcast
hosted by Zachary Hepburn are both on a brief
season hiatus. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or
click the link in our show notes to listen to all the
shows and the Diner Mike podcast network. But with
that out of the way, quick to the no prize! A no prize
is an award that Marvel used to give out to fans. Our
version, the Dynamic Dual No Prize, is a digital
award we post on Instagram for the person that we
feel gave the best answer to our question of the
week. Last week we asked you guys including
Deadpool who should be on the roster for the X-Men
Deadpool team-up film and this is coming off of the
news that was reported by the trades that Ryan
Reynolds has been tapped by Marvel Studios to
write a movie that features Deadpool teaming up
with three to four X-Men characters and this film
would be one of two X-Men films set in the MCU that
are currently being written. We got five answers
this past week so let's go ahead and run down our
three honorable mentions and the no prize winner.
Our first honorable mention goes to Lorenzo
Valdez who said, This is Lorenzo Valdez calling in
again. My pitch for the roster for the X-Men
Deadpool team-up film would be alongside
Deadpool of course, Wolverine, Jean Grey and
Cyclops and my idea would be that Deadpool would
help them work through their love triangle while
simultaneously providing fourth wall breaking
analysis of the love triangle itself. Clonifer
everyone always, bye bye. Yeah and I would
actually throw in Emma Frost into the mix and then
you could get Deadpool's commentary on this kind
of love quadrilateral as it were. This almost
seems like the premise for an adult film. Yeah it
sounds like a parody of an X-Men Deadpool team-up
but it made me laugh so you get an honorable
mention. Great answer Lorenzo our next honorable
mention goes to Travis Herndon who said, What's up
dynamic dudes Travis here, shout out to me able to
win so my choices would be Deadpool, Colossus,
X-23, Silo, Nightcrawler and Warhead. I think
that's a nice little mix with the old Fox X-Men and
then you can introduce the new three new actors to
play those three new X-Men characters. It could be
a nice little mix. They can easily play off each
other pretty good something similar to the
Thunderbolt so that's it. Yeah I'm not sure who
Travis is referring to the old X-Men and who would
be the new but we know that Colossus and Negasonic
Teenage Warhead have both been in the Deadpool
films and then you have X-23 who's played by Daphne
Keane, Silo who is portrayed by Olivia Munn in
X-Men Apocalypse and Nightcrawler who of course
was portrayed by Alan Cumming next to who will be
reprising the role in Avengers Doomsday. There
was also the other version of Nightcrawler that
was in the first class timeline who was played by
Cody Smith McPhee. I actually really like that
lineup it's a really cool cast of characters with
really cool power sets I would love it if that was
the roster. Yeah I mean you have your strong guy you
have your teleporter you have your psychic you
have your blasty girl and then you have your stabby
girl it works it works great answer Travis our next
honorable mention goes to Mike Williams who said
my roster for a new Deadpool movie would be
Deadpool themselves Wolverine Bishop Warpath
and Domino maybe revive the X-Force so that they
don't all die at the end and maybe start an X-Force
franchise that's my two cents as always make mine
Marvel. Yeah this would be essentially a new
X-Force movie with some of the characters that
were in the Deadpool 2 film like Domino actually
just Domino was part of X-Force in that movie but
Warpath is a long-standing member of X-Force in
the comic books and he was in X-Men Days of Future
Past he would be a good addition here Bishop was
briefly on the X-Force team in the comic books if I
remember correctly I think he was on Storm's
version of the team and then of course Wolverine
obviously was on the Strike Force version of the
X-Force team as well so yeah this is a pretty good
lineup too I like the inclusion of Domino
specifically. Yeah I felt like she was missing
from the third Deadpool film personally. Yeah
yeah same well I think the same thing with Cable too
I think they all had pretty good chemistry in
Deadpool 2. I just remembered that Bishop was also
in Days of Future Past. Great answer Mike we want to
give a special thanks to Kat Stevenson who took the
time to respond with their answer they mentioned
Cable, Professor X, Nightcrawler and Cyclops
which was a pretty very team with an interesting
mix of characters but the winner of this week's No
Prize goes to Gavin Troyer who said I think the
Deadpool team-up movie should be an X-Force movie
with Deadpool's supporting character, Silak,
Bishop, Forge and Wolverine played by a separate
actor than Hugh Jackman and Deadpool's mini arc in
the movie is to move on from Hugh Jackman's
Wolverine and accept that this new actor can
follow his footsteps. Also the actor who's
playing Wolverine now should be Tom Hardy but
anyways that's my thoughts. It's an interesting
cast for Wolverine I don't know if the fact that Tom
Hardy has played Venom would have any bearing on
him being cast as an MCU Wolverine but beyond the
Wolverine casting aspect the thing I liked most
about this answer was the inclusion of Forge.
Gavin's answer out of all the answers was the only
one that included a new character from the X-Men
comic books that we haven't seen yet adapted to
live action and I'm a big Forge fan so I think that'd
be really cool. Yeah if you're not familiar with
Forge we did a dual episode between him and Mr.
Terrific. His mutant power is essentially that he
can create anything he can imagine like
technology wise. Right exactly not as like a
technopath he's also like engineer the parts and
stuff like that but he makes like a great
quartermaster I think for an X-Force team which
was his role for both X-Force and X-Factor in the
comic books and also I like the variety in this team
I think it would make for a great X-Force film as
well. So great answer Gavin you win this week's No
Prize if you the listener want a shot at winning
your own No Prize stay tuned to later on in this
episode when we'll be asking another question of
the week. Another that's done? A lot to the news!
Okay last week we got the first official teaser for
Peacemaker season two written by James Gunn the
new head of DC Studios who previously wrote season
one of the show along with the Suicide Squad film
from which John Cena's Peacemaker character
comes from. I loved the Suicide Squad I loved
Peacemaker season one and I've really been
looking forward to Peacemaker season two even
though I've been kind of confused as to how it fits
in the new universe that James Gunn is
establishing considering John Cena's
Peacemaker character comes from the DCEU. Well
this trailer did not clear up any confusion
whatsoever in fact it probably made me more
confused but I'm also hoping that it clears things
up once we finally watch the show. Yeah not to skip
to the end of the trailer it does look like at some
point Peacemaker goes into his dad's miniature
universe of closets. Yeah his like pocket
dimension where he's able to access the
multiverse maybe. Yeah it kind of seems that way
but in the beginning we get to see the new Justice
League that's going to appear in the upcoming
Superman film although the Superman movie comes
out before this show debuts. Right Peacemaker
goes to an audition in a rundown toy store to meet
with Hawke Girl Green Lantern Guy Gardner and
Maxwell Lord played by the same actors who play
them in the Superman movie. During Peacemaker's
interview they failed to mute themselves so
they're just talking shit about him behind the
glass and it's very humiliating for him. It was a
somewhat humorous scene though I'm not sure all of
the actors pulled off the comedy specifically
Isabella Merced. We'll see how it goes. What's
interesting is that Maxwell Lord could be twins
with Calenderman as he was portrayed in the
Suicide Squad film and he moves a lot like Weasel
how weird is that. Now of course Maxwell Lord is
played by Sean Gunn who yes did play Calenderman in
the DCEU but he's moved beyond that. He's onto
bigger and better things like the benefactor of
the Justice League Maxwell Lord. After the
opening scene for the rest of the trailer we
essentially see the old cast from season one
coming to terms with the fact that even though they
saved the world they're getting no real
recognition for it and in fact it looks like
they're being hunted by Argus formerly run by
Amanda Waller now run by Rick Flagg Sr whose son was
killed by Peacemaker in the Suicide Squad film. It
was a very powerful moment in that film so I'm glad
they're still able to play up on that as they did in
Peacemaker season one. We get to see Adebayo,
Adrian Chase, AK, Vigilante, Harcourt,
Economist all return they're all being their
badass hilarious selves. And we get to see Tim
Meadows as one of the agents of Argus it looks like.
Yeah he's in the scene where he's giving nicknames
and directions to his Argus crew and they're all
fairly insulting. Yeah Mexicali, Ponyboy,
Titties and Ceno Man I thought that was pretty good
one. It was interesting to see Tim Meadows here
who's primarily known for his comedic work but it
seems like James Gunn has a pretty good
relationship with a lot of SNL actors because
we've seen him use like Pete Davidson as
Blackguard in the Suicide Squad and Beck Bennett
is going to be in his upcoming Superman movie. Yeah
I'm a big fan of Tim Meadows from his SNL days it's
great to see him on this cast surprisingly also we
get a glimpse of Michael Rooker as a character that
I have no idea who it is. Some people are saying
Snowflame I don't know if I believe that. I
definitely don't think it's Savant the character
that the actor played in the Suicide Squad
considering he's dead so who knows. Yeah James
Gunn likes to work with a lot of the same actors over
and over again Michael Rooker you know being the
actor who played Yondu in The Guardians of the
Galaxy movies but again we have this weirdness
where Michael Rooker played Savant in the DCEU and
he's playing this new character in this new
version of the DC Universe but they could be like
twins just like with this Shang-Gun situation
it's a little bit confusing how they're going to
pull this off although that's not to say that
Marvel hasn't reused actors in different roles
people like Alfred Woodard or something like
that. Yeah or Gemma Chan. Right like I said earlier
I'm hoping some of this confusion gets cleared up
once we watch the show I'm definitely fully
expecting to love this show and just find it
hilarious and if things get cleared up in the midst
of the fun of watching it that's just icing on the
cake. The show premieres on August 21st on Max and
we will absolutely be reviewing it once it wraps up
but going back to our discussion of Tim Meadows
that brings us to our question of the week. Cast any
Saturday Night Live actor as a Marvel or DC
superhero who would you cast and why? And
portrayed characters in Marvel and DC the most
popular of course was Robert Downey Jr who was a
member of the cast for I think like a year but you
know he's Iron Man so that doesn't count neither
does Kristen Wiig who played Cheetah in Wonder
Woman 1984 or Pete Davidson who again played
Blackguard in the Suicide Squad. There's also
Bill Murray who played Lord Krylar in Quantum and
recently Shazir Zamata played Jennifer Kale in
Agatha All Along. Would love to get your answers.
Record them at dynamicdool.com by clicking on the
red microphone button in the bottom right hand
corner of the screen which will prompt you to leave
us a voicemail. Your message could be up to 30
seconds long and don't forget to leave your name in
case we include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a dynamic
duel no prize that we'll post to Instagram. Be sure
to answer before May 17th. DC High Volume Batman.
The Dark Knight's definitive DC comic stories
adapted directly for audio for the very first
time. Fear. I have to make them afraid. He's got a
motorcycle. Get after him or have you shot? You
mean blow up the building. From this moment on,
none of you are safe. New episodes every Wednesday
wherever you get your podcasts. But that does it
for all of the news for this episode so now let's
move on to the main event where we find out who would
win between the Freedom Fighter Ray and the
X-Factor member Havoc. Ray vs. Havoc. These
characters were chosen by our executive
producers to battle against each other because
they're both energy emitters as it were. They're
both fairly popular characters within Marvel and
DC that for some reason we just haven't gotten to
yet. Back when I first started reading comics in
the 90s, Ray was all over the place. Not so much
lately in the comics, but you occasionally see him
from time to time. He has a cool look to him. So does
Havoc I think. They both have pretty cool
headgear. Ray has his like Spartan warrior style
helmet and then Havoc has his like tri-pronged
mask thing. Whatever the hell that is. That's
weird. I never really liked his look. It's an
interesting look but it's also a weird look. It's a
unique look for sure. He did not have this look in
X-Men 1st class when the character was played by
Lucas Till. Yeah, he also showed up in X-Men
Apocalypse where it was established that he and
Cyclops were brothers. The way they portrayed
Havoc's plasma blasting abilities in the movies
was a little unique. You know, they made his plasma
red probably so that it resembled Cyclops powers a
little bit more, but traditionally Havoc
emanates the plasma from his body like in all
directions and it emanates in waves. And he's also
not able to control that just like his brother
Cyclops. Sometimes he is, but most commonly he
wears a containment suit that helps him control
and direct his powers. In a similar way that
Cyclops wears his visor that helps him control and
direct his powers. Now you've never seen the Ray in
a live-action movie but he has been in the
Arrowverse on live-action television and also he
had his own animated series called Freedom
Fighters the Ray, which is pretty Yeah, I never saw
that but his power set is pretty cool so I bet you the
action in that series is pretty well done. Yeah,
both of these characters are pretty powerful so
I'm excited to see how this is going to turn out. To
explain the methodology behind our duels, let's
go to our sentient duel simulator, Alfred Jarvis
9000. AJ and NK tell our listeners how you go about
determining a winner in our duel matchups. Yes, of
course, sir. The way I determine a winner between
the contestants is by running 1000 Monte Carlo
simulations using the characters statistics. A
Monte Carlo simulation is a probabilistic model
used to determine outcomes through random
sampling. In this case, I randomize the
statistics along a normal distribution as a way to
simulate the many variables that can occur during
battle. The stat parameters are based on the
official Marvel power grid from which the DC
characters statistics are extrapolated.
Additional stat categories are included such as
range, damage potential, versatility and
perception in order to create a more detailed and
accurate simulation. The results of the 1000
simulations provide a percentage of wins for each
character. The contestant with the higher
percentage is declared the victor as they have a
higher probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither character should win
100% of the matches. The comic book stories have
shown that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman, so the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks, AJ and IK.
Before we run the simulations, though, we'd like
to break down each character's histories and
abilities before improvising a scenario on how we
imagine one of the 1000 simulations would play out
beat for beat. And I think it's my turn to go first
with the Marvel character, so let me tell you guys
all about Havoc. Alexander Summers was born in
Honolulu, Hawaii, one of the sons of Air Force
Major Christopher Summers and his wife,
Catherine. As a child living in Anchorage,
Alaska, Alex was aboard his father's private
plane with his parents and older brother Scott
when it was attacked by an alien spaceship
belonging to the Shi'ar Empire. To save their
sons, Christopher and Catherine strapped Alex
and Scott to the plane's only parachute and pushed
them out before the plane exploded. The fall left
Scott with a head injury and the boys were placed in
an orphanage in Omaha, Nebraska. Unbeknownst to
them, the facility was secretly run by the
geneticist, Mr. Sinister, who was obsessed with
the Summers bloodline. You can learn more about
Scott Summers, aka Cyclops, in his duel against
Negative Man, and more about Mr. Sinister in his
duel against the Ultra Humanite. Alex was soon
adopted by the Blandings, a couple who had lost
their own son, Todd. Traumatized in wanting a
replacement child, they raised Alex to behave
like Todd. When Todd's killer returned and
kidnapped Alex and his younger foster sister, the
stress triggered Alex's mutant powers. He
released a blast of plasma that incinerated the
kidnapper. Mr. Sinister erased Alex's memories
of the incident and suppressed his abilities,
causing Alex to grow up unaware of his mutant
nature or that he had a brother. After earning a
degree in geophysics in college, Alex was
kidnapped by Professor Ahmed Abdaal, also known
as the Living Pharaoh, who discovered that he and
Alex shared the same type of cosmic
energy-absorbing mutation. Alex's presence
prevented Abdaal from accessing his full power.
By abducting and shielding Alex from ambient
cosmic energy, Abdaal was able to transform into a
giant entity called the Living Monolith. The
X-Men arrived to stop him, and Alex's powers
reawakened under stress. Though he couldn't
control his abilities, he helped defeat the
monolith. And afterward, Professor X revealed
that Cyclops was Alex's older brother. Fearing
the damage his powers might cause, Alex initially
chose to stay behind in Egypt, but he was soon
captured by the mutant hunting sentinels led by
Larry Trask. Trask provided Alex with a
containment suit and dubbed him Havoc. The suit
helped regulate Alex's absorption and release of
cosmic radiation, which his body naturally
stored and expel in the form of powerful plasma
blasts. After being rescued by the X-Men, Alex
joined their ranks and trained to master his
abilities. You can learn more about the team in
their duel against the Titans. During this
period, Alex grew close to fellow mutant Lorna
Dane, also known as Polaris, who was the daughter
of Magneto. The two became romantically involved
and helped the X-Men repel numerous threats,
including alien invaders and anti-mutant
groups. Eventually, they left the X-Men to attend
graduate school in Nevada. However, they were
manipulated by the Shiar agent Eric the Red and
temporarily turned against the X-Men. After
being freed from their mind control, they
recovered at Muir Island, where they later fought
the reality-warping mutant Proteus. Alex
eventually learned that his and Scott's father
had survived their plane attack and escaped Shiar
slavery to become Corsair, the leader of a
spacefaring team called the Starjammers. During
their reunion, Scott met Madeline Pryor, a secret
clone of Jean Grey, at a time when he believed Jean
was dead. Alex served as the best man at Scott's
wedding to Madeline, and Alex later attempted to
leave behind the superhero life. He was drawn back
in, however, when Polaris was possessed by the
villain Malice. Alex was unable to free her from
that control and the experience left him
frustrated and helpless. He continued to serve
with the X-Men and eventually entered into a
relationship with Madeline, who had at the time
been abandoned by Scott when he learned that Jean
was still alive. Madeline was then corrupted by
demonic forces and transformed into the Goblin
Queen, triggering a demonic invasion of New York.
She manipulated Alex into becoming her Goblin
Prince, turning him against the X-Men, until the
conflict ended with her death, when Madeline
learned that she was a clone. You can learn more
about Jean Grey in our Raven vs Phoenix duel
episode. To escape an ambush with the cybernetic
villains known as the Reavers, Alex and the rest of
the X-Men passed through a mystical gateway
called the Siege Paralysis, which for a time left
the world thinking that the X-Men were dead. They
eventually reemerged on Earth, where Alex became
a magistrate for the new mutant nation of Genosha.
There, he helped build the Republic, led by
Magneto, into a sanctuary for mutants around the
world. Professor X later recruited Alex to lead a
government sponsored mutant team called X
Factor, where he was reunited with Polaris.
Though effective as a leader, Alex struggled with
team politics, romantic entanglements, and the
apparent death of his teammate multiple man from
the Legacy Virus. During a mission with X Factor,
Alex was presumed dead in a time machine
explosion. In reality, he was thrown into a
parallel universe known as the Mutant X Reality,
where he led a team called the Six, and was married
to Madeline Pryor with whom he had a son named
Scotty. Alex helped save the dimension from
another iteration of the Goblin Queen before
being cast into the void between dimensions,
where his consciousness remained suspended
until his eventual return to the main Marvel
timeline, Earth 616. He woke up in his home
reality, after which Polaris proposed marriage
to him. Though Alex initially agreed, unsure of
his feelings, he ultimately called off the
wedding. Angered, Polaris attacked Alex, but the
two eventually reconciled. Alex rejoined the
X-Men during a time when most of the Earth's
mutants had their powers taken away by the Scarlet
Witch. Though Alex kept his powers, Polaris did
not, and they left the team to be together.
However, Polaris was later abducted by the
ancient mutant Apocalypse, who re-granted her
powers as one of his horsemen, and Alex fought
alongside the X-Men to rescue her. You can learn
more about Scarlet Witch and Apocalypse in their
respective duels against Satana and Black Adam.
Professor X soon recruited Alex for a space
mission to stop Vulcan, the long-lost Third
Summer's brother who had become a powerful threat
that usurped the alien Xiar Empire. Vulcan killed
their father Corsair, and Alex vowed revenge,
taking command of the space-faring Starjammers
to resist Vulcan's tyrannical rule. In one of
their fights, Vulcan blasted Havok into a son,
seemingly killing him. However, Alex's ability
to absorb cosmic radiation supercharged his
cells with a massive influx of energy that enabled
him to survive the experience. Alex re-emerged
with enough power to damage Vulcan's weapons and
free his captured teammates. Returning to Earth,
Alex joined X-Factor Investigations, a mutant
private detective agency led by a multiple man who
had survived the Legacy Virus. During the
Avengers vs X-Men conflict, Alex sided with the
Avengers and was chosen by Captain America to lead
the Avengers Unity Division, an initiative meant
to promote human and mutant superhero
cooperation. During a battle with Red Onslaught,
Alex was among several heroes who were morally
inverted by a magical spell. Most were eventually
restored by a subsequent spell, but Alex remained
inverted. He resigned from the Avengers and
joined Emmafrost, Bastion, and Mr. Sinister in a
plan to spread a mutagenic virus called
Mothervine, which would cause mutations in
humans and result in mutant dominance on Earth.
However, when it was revealed that Mothervine
would also mind control all mutants, Emmafrost
betrayed the group and psychically restored
Alex's original personality. You can learn more
about Emmafrost in our Poison Ivy vs White Queen
duel episode. Alex died again while defending the
X-Men from Sentinels, but was resurrected on the
new Mutant Island nation of Krakowa through a
process they could bring mutants back to life via a
select combination of mutant powers. There, he
joined the Helians, a new team led by Silak, where a
variant of Madeline Pryor was killed on a mission.
Alex pleaded for her resurrection, but was denied
because she was a clone. Frustrated, he lashed out
and destroyed one of Mr. Sinister's hidden labs on
Krakowa, ending the villain's secret
experiments. Emmafrost eventually persuaded
the Krakowin Council to approve Madeline's
resurrection. Although she and Alex reunited,
she told him they needed space. When Alex
sacrificed himself to defend her in a later
adventure, Madeline used her magic to restore him
to life in gratitude. And that's his backstory.
Powers-wise, Havoc has the innate mutant ability
to absorb ambient cosmic energies, including
radiation, light, heat, x-rays, etc., which his
body can store and release by converting it into
plasma, which is a super hot ionized gas that
ranges from 11,000 to 14,500 degrees Fahrenheit.
Typically, the plasma emanates from Havoc in all
directions, but by focusing, he can direct the
blasts into directional beams, often while
wearing a special containment suit. He can focus
the amount of energy he projects from levels small
enough to increase the surrounding temperature
or powerful enough to disintegrate his immediate
vicinity. In addition to his mutant power, he
holds a degree in geophysical science and has
received some hand-to-hand combat training. And
that is Havoc. Wait, so he could absorb light?
Yeah, basically, in small quantities. Oh, small
quantities. Good. Cause he's gonna get so many
quantities. Well, don't forget that he was thrown
into a sun and managed to survive that, so you might
have your work cut out for you. Hmm, we'll see. Let
me get into the Rey's backstory. Langford, happy,
Tarrell, was a reporter in the early 1940s who
joined an upper-atmosphere balloon expedition
sponsored by the U.S. government under the guise
of scientific exploration. Unbeknownst to him,
the expedition was a covert experiment by a
government research group called RONAL, or
Research on the Nature of Light, led by Dr. Dazel.
Dazel believed that light originating from the
birth of the universe would eventually circle
back to Earth as a sentient destructive entity.
And that only being composed of both human and
light could communicate with it. During the
expedition, Hapi was exposed to a burst of
electrical energy and ambient sunlight from a
detonated light bomb designed to give him
energy-based powers. Surviving the
quote-unquote accident, Hapi discovered he
could manipulate light and energy, which he used
to become the hero known as the Rey. He fought in
World War II and joined the freedom fighters to
combat access forces. During his early
adventures, he battled threats ranging from
mystics to metahumans and developed his skills as
a light-wielding champion. He later fought
alongside other Golden Age heroes in the All-Star
Squadron. After the war, Hapi married his first
wife, Gale, and had a son named Joshua. Joshua
accompanied him briefly as his sidekick
Spitfire, until the boy's unstable nature led to a
violent episode in which he accidentally killed
his mother. Unable to cope with his son's
volatility, Hapi placed Joshua in suspended
animation. Disillusioned and burdened by the
consequences of his role in Dazel's plan, Hapi
retired as the Rey in 1950. In the 1970s, Hapi
briefly joined the freedom fighters before
marrying again. When his second wife Nadine gave
birth to a glowing infant, Hapi realized Dazel's
theories had been correct. Bearing the
implications of raising such a child, he told
Nadine the baby had died and entrusted his son to
his brother Thomas to raise as his own. The boy was
named Raymond Terrell. Years later, Hapi was
summoned by the freedom fighters leader Uncle Sam
to seek out the mystical being known as Neon the
Unknown, who Uncle Sam believed could help Hapi's
son Raymond. You can learn more about Uncle Sam and
his duel against Captain Britain. When Neon
refused to help, Hapi drank from the mystic waters
of Neon's oasis, an act that caused him to merge
with Neon. Though Hapi as the new Neon was largely
absent after that transformation, he continued
to watch over his son from a distance. As Rey was
raised by his Uncle Thomas, it was claimed that Rey
suffered from a lethal light allergy. Confined to
a darkened home and kept from the outside world,
Rey was known to the public as Night Boy. On the day
of Thomas's death, Rey learned the truth. He was
not allergic to light, and his real father was the
wartime hero known as the Rey. At Thomas's
funeral, Rey met his cousin Hank, who helped him
step into the sunlight for the first time,
awakening his powers. Though initially
reluctant to become a hero, Rey was soon
confronted by Hapi, who revealed the truth about
Ronal and Dazel's experiments. To prepare his son
for a potential confrontation with the returning
light entity, Hapi orchestrated a complex plan,
using agents to pressure Rey into heroism.
Ultimately, Rey ventured into the realm of the
light entity and convinced it to spare Earth.
Embracing his destiny, Rey adopted the mantle of
the Rey and began his career as a superhero. He
battled villains such as Dr. Polaris, Brimstone,
and Lobo, and briefly worked under Vandal
Savage's employ before breaking away. Following
the death of Superman, Rey was recruited into the
Justice League of America, where he served for
about a year. During this time, he had a
short-lived romance with Black Canary, who you
can learn more about in her duel episode against
Black Widow. He later joined the Justice League
task force under the Martian Manhunter, helping
to train younger heroes. Following the team's
dissolution, Rey remained a reserve Justice
League and joined the forgotten heroes to take
down Vandal Savage. He later joined Young
Justice, where he briefly ran for team leader.
Though older than most members, he bonded with the
group before later departing. You can learn more
about Young Justice in the team duel episode
between them and the Young Avengers. Rey was
captured during a battle against the Nowhere Men,
who sought to erase individuality. He was rescued
during the fight and returned to his hero duties,
joining a new incarnation of the Freedom
Fighters. During an ambush by the Secret Society,
most of the team was killed, and Rey was taken
hostage to power a device meant to recreate the
universe. He was freed, however, before its
destruction. He reemerged with a new costume and
defeated the rogue Stan Silver, who had stolen his
identity. Rey joined the Reformed Freedom
Fighters and helped counter various threats.
During the sun-eating crisis, Rey masqueraded as
a second son to deceive the threat and provide
hope. He continued aiding the superhero
community, including participating in
operations against the Anti-Life equation. In
post-Flashpoint continuity, Raymond Terrell
was raised in a windowless home by his mother
Nadine, who claimed he was deathly allergic to
light. In truth, Rey's powers were latent and
dangerous, passed down from his father, the
original Rey. After an accidental flare-up of his
abilities injured his childhood friend, Caden
Zipodi, Rey became completely isolated. On his
18th birthday, Rey left his home and was struck by
the lights of the city, triggering his
transformation into a being of living light. He
became invisible and remained in that state for
four years, drifting through the world. One day,
he saw Caden campaigning for mayor of Vanity,
Oregon, and watched an attempt on his life by a
member of the Sons of Liberty. Rey intervened
using his powers to stop the attack and was dubbed
the Rey by the press. He became the city's
protector and was later recruited into Batman's
new Justice League of America. With the league,
Rey participated in freeing the hero Bloodwind,
resisting reality-altering threats and serving
as a courier during dimensional crises. He helped
expose plots by the Secret Society, contributed
to relief efforts after global disasters, and
operated as a solo hero when not engaged with the
league. And that's the Rey's backstory so far.
Powers-wise, the Rey possesses the ability to
absorb and process light energy, which fuels his
superhuman abilities. He can project
concentrated rays of destructive light, emit
blinding flashes, and form solid light
constructs similar to those of a Green Lantern.
His powers allow him to create illusions, render
himself invisible, and heal from injuries
through photonic regeneration. Rey can also
convert his entire body into coherent light,
rendering himself intangible and immune to
physical damage, while also allowing him to
travel at light speed. And that's the Rey. That's a
bullshit power set. Any more so than Havoc's?
What? Yeah, he could turn into light and move at the
speed of light. What is he, the Flash? All I know is
that it's just like DC to name a character whose
superhero name is the Rey as Rey. His real name is
Rey. What the fuck? All right, it makes things
easy. Way to go, DC. It's not like anyone's going to
deduce his secret identity. When he goes into his
like power mode, he turns actually all black, kind
of similar to Sunspot. Oh, from absorbing all the
ambient light energy? Exactly. Yeah, actually,
his design was created by Joe Cassata, the former
editor-in-chief of Marvel Comics. Oh,
interesting. That is interesting. But now that
we've got their history as a whole, we're going to
have to go back to the way. Let's speculate on how
one of the 1000 simulated matches will go. The
winner is determined by simulations, not the
speculation, but it's fun to imagine how the fight
could play out. AG9K, what are the rules of our
speculation? Well, I should say there are no rules
other than the characters have no prior knowledge
of the other going into the fight. All they are
aware of starting out is that the other character
is a threat that needs to be eliminated. For the
speculation, the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the match
itself, as no environmental statistics are
considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. All right
then, let's get into it. Rey and Havoc meet on the
battlefield. Who goes first? Actually, I'm going
to say the Rey goes first because he can move at
light speed since he's literally light and he'll
start off by emitting these flashes of bright
light from his palms that are going to blind Havoc
and while Havoc is stumbling around, not sure
where to aim, that's when Rey's gonna just
straight up blast him right through his heart with
the laser beam. Boom. But who needs to aim when you
can blast in all directions at any given time?
Like, Havoc doesn't need to aim, so like, sure, he
may get temporarily blinded but as his eyes are
recovering and before the Rey could even laser
him, Havoc's just gonna release a plasma wave in
all directions and that wave is gonna plow into the
Rey and it's gonna throw off his laser beam while
also incinerating him with 12,000 degree heat.
No, because as the Rey gets blasted by the initial
front of the wave of plasma, he's going to turn his
body intangible and that's going to allow that
wave to pass right through him before the Rey traps
Havoc in a sphere of hard light and then just slam
him into the ground repeatedly, knocking him
silly and probably knocking Havoc out. Wait,
wait, wait, I don't think the Rey can phase through
plasma. Like, it's not some kind of like solid
physical attack that's just gonna go through him.
That's like saying Rey's gonna phase through the
air that's around him. Like, the Rey would somehow
have to physically remove himself from like their
plane of existence or something to not be affected
by the superheated matter around him. Well, yeah,
plasma is matter. Rey can phase through matter.
Yeah, but it's like highly energized matter.
Like, it's atoms that become ions, essentially.
So how can the Rey phase through something that's
affecting his surrounding physical location?
Like, if he were placed in a giant oven and the oven
was turned up to 12,000 degrees, do you think the
Rey could just phase through the heated air around
him in order to avoid being baked? Because I don't
think so. That's a good question. You know, he
could always phase through the oven wall, but if
it's too big for him to reach it in time, he probably
would be damaged because he is vulnerable to
energy attacks like heat. There you go. Exactly.
So going back, no, Rey isn't creating any sort of
hard light construct. He's fucking baking in his
helmet. Okay, well, all right, so the blast would
probably knock him out of his light mode, but once
he reentered it as a being composed of pure light,
he'd be fully healed once again. So that's when
he's going to trap Havok in that sphere and knock
him around. So he has like some kind of like light
based healing factor? Yeah, exactly. He's a being
of pure light. He doesn't have like a physical form
per se, sort of. Like he was once shot in the back of
the head and was told that he was going to be like
paralyzed for the rest of his life, but then he just
switched in and out of his light mode and he was
fully healed. That's stupid. So you say that he
traps Havok in a solid light construct? I don't
even know what solid light is, like even
conceptually, like what is it made out of? Like is
this like maybe a photon's head mass? Whatever.
I'm going to say that Havok is going to be able to
blast through it with a focused plasma beam from
his chest and it's going to go through the hard
light construct and slam into Rey again since
we've established that yeah, Rey is going to be
vulnerable to plasma and getting hit is going to
make him drop the construct. Okay. So the hard
light sphere disappears, Havok lands on his feet
under the ground and then he's going to blast a
plasma beam downward to propel himself up into the
air and just punch Rey right in his tangible face.
Oh, sorry. When Havok was knocked around, you
know, he lost his bearings and he didn't notice
that the Rey he now sees is actually a projected
illusion from the now invisible Rey who's
actually behind Havok and he's going to fly into
Havok at high speed and you just send him skidding
across the ground. Okay. Yeah, that would
probably hurt Havok, you know, getting hit at high
speed would definitely mean that he's going to get
up pretty slowly from the ground. But as the Rey
flies in and tries to land a finishing blow, all of a
sudden he just collapses out of the air like he's
sick or something because as it turns out this
entire match, Havok has been releasing like a low
level of plasma throughout the environment
that's been slowly burning and charring the Rey's
body from the inside out like a microwave. And
since we've established that intangibility
isn't going to help the Rey here, his insides are
basically charred like an overcooked steak and he
falls to the ground dead. Okay. The problem I have
is your use of the word slow. Like Havok stands up
slowly, he's slowly been burning the Rey. The Rey
is not slow. Okay. Even if he's damaged on the
inside and maybe even is dying in less than a
second, Rey could just slam into Havok, fly him
into outer space at light speed and just cause
Havok to freeze out there among the stars. No, no,
no. Havok isn't freezing at any point. He could
just keep himself warm with low level plasma and
but can he breathe? No, but he's displayed the
ability to survive for a short time in space like
when he absorbed the power of a star in his fight
with Vulcan. And this whole match he's been
absorbing basically the power of a star by the
energy that the Rey gives off. So, you know, Havok,
he's amped up. He's doing just fine. He's going to
direct a blast of plasma that sends him hurling
like a plasma comet that slams right into Rey and
sends them both creaning back into Earth, back
through the atmosphere, the heat upon reentry.
That's not going to matter, but they crash into the
ground and the Rey just flattens on impact. And
Havok, yeah, he's probably going to flatten too,
but the Rey is going to flatten first and therefore
Havok wins. Okay, well, I say the Rey is just going
to phase through Havok at the last second and let
Havok crash his own damn self into the planet's
surface, just kind of causing himself. So, Rey
survives, Havok doesn't match over. No, I think
the Rey's body is too charred on the inside by this
point to be able to do any sort of phasing. So, Havok
actually wins. But we'll go ahead and leave the
match there. It's kind of an interesting way to end
this fight, but that's where we ended up. Let's go
ahead and input the stats for the characters, run
the simulations, and find out which scenario
happens when we come back. A.J .9K, hit it!
Inputting data, running calculations,
processing results, simulations complete. All
right, these guys are two definite powerhouses
when it came to damage potential. They could both
basically explode and destroy entire city blocks
with their energy. Although we did say Havok was a
little bit more powerful in terms of damage
potential just because he can do things like melt
adamantium, whereas we didn't think the Rey would
be able to do that. No, yeah, Havok got the leg up
when it came to damage, but the Rey was pretty off
the charts in other stat categories, such as
movement speed, evasiveness because of his
intangibility, and even durability thanks to his
healing ability. Yeah, we also said that the Rey
was more versatile considering he can do all sorts
of things with his energy-based powers. However,
Havok is smarter having a degree in geophysical
science, so he's got that going for him. And I think
that his advantage and intellect and damage
potential are enough to give him the win here. What
do you think, Jonathan? I disagree. I think the Rey
is going to take this match handedly, although our
followers on Instagram disagree with me. In the
poll that we put up, 57% of people cited with Havok.
Damn straight. Various two group of Instagram
followers that we have, for sure. I doubt it.
They're going to learn today. Don't knock our
followers, but let's see who won. AJ and IK, the
results, please. Hey, you are, sir. All right, the
winner between the Rey and Havok is the Rey. Yes!
Now, did I say his superhero name or his real name?
Who knows? Because D.C.'s dumb. Yes, the answer is
yes. At a 1000 simulated matches, Rey won a
whopping 891 battles, whereas Havok only won 109.
So, Rey had a win rate of 89.1%, whereas Havok only
had 10.9%. So you're telling me Rey beats Havok 9
out of 10 times? Only because Rey is a cheater
character who can do way too much and, uh, sucks?
Yeah. I'll be honest, I did not think that the Rey
was going to defeat Havok so handedly. I actually
thought Havok was going to be a good opponent for
Rey, but clearly we were all wrong. Yeah, it's a
mismatch. It's a mismatch for sure. We never
should have put Havok up against Rey. We probably
should have put Havok up against, like, Robin or
somebody. I don't know. I think that would have
been a better matchup. So I'm going to say this one
doesn't even count, right? Oh no, I'm sorry. It
actually does count. Sucks to suck. I'm just going
to forget this one as soon as this episode ends,
which is right now. It's just going to be a bad
dream, basically. It's your living nightmare,
motherfucker. So that does it for this duel, guys.
A.J. and I.K. help close this out. Our next episode
is going to be another duel episode, where we find
out who would win in a fight between Mary Marble and
Hercules. But that does it for this episode. We
want to give a big thanks to our executive
producers, John Starroski, Zachary Hepburn,
Dustin Balcom, Maggie Methangian, Brandon
Esregard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yatyn, Austin
Wieselowski, A.J. Dunkerly, Nick Ibonto, Scott
Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Spees, Dean Maleski,
Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, Josh Schleiner,
Mike Williams, Oscar Galvez, and Paul Graves for
helping make this podcast possible. We'll talk to
you guys next week. Up, up, and away. True
believers.