This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi, welcome to
the DynaMic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin
brother, Marvelous Joe. And in lead up to our
review of the Marvel film Thunderbolts, we are
doing a team duel where we pit that team against
DC's Watchmen. Yeah, we're not pitting the
traditional Thunderbolts team against the
Watchmen, like the original classics. It's going
to be more in line with the film version of the
Thunderbolts, which is also in line with the most
recent roster in the comics. Basically the idea
here is that we have a bunch of street level heroes
and one super powerful character on the team to
back them up. Yeah, Dr. Manhattan in the century,
respectively. Exactly. We'll be raking down each
team's histories and the rosters we'll be using
later on in this episode. There's no comic book
movie news this week, but as always, we list our
segment times in our episode description, so feel
free to check out the show notes if you want to skip
ahead to a particular topic. Our artificially
intelligent duel simulator, AJ9K, has a quick
message for our listeners, so listen up. Why hello
there. Do you want even more from this podcast?
Then become a part of the dynamic duel community on
Patreon where you can choose from three tiers. The
Dynamic 2.0 tier gives you access to our Discord
chat server, the Fantastic Four tier gives you two
bonus episodes each month, and the X-Force tier
makes you an executive producer of this show.
Lastly, the Dynamite Podcast Network tier lets
you create your own podcast using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and
consultation, and get you simulation results.
Pitch the twins your ideas via email at
dynamicduelpodcast at gmail.com. Check it out at
patreon.com slash dynamicduel. Pip pip cheerio.
Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast, including executive producer Nick
Abonto who had a birthday recently. Happy
birthday man, if I could give you one gift from
Marvel, it would be the power of the century, but
without the void persona attached to it. Okay, and
I'll do you one better. I will give you the power of
Dr. Manhattan. Yeah, blue balls and all. Yeah,
have fun with those. Happy birthday. Guys, be sure
to tune into the other shows in the Dynamite
Podcast Network this week, including the console
Combat Podcast, where hosts John and Dean
simulate battles between popular video game
characters. In yesterday's episode, they
speculated on who would win in a fight between
She-Hulk from Ultimate Marvel versus Capcom 3
versus The Mask. Over on the Max Destruction
Podcast, hosts Scotty and Gilly pit their
favorite action heroes from film and television
against each other. They are on a brief season
break currently, so now is the perfect time to get
caught up with their past episodes. And on the
Senjoh World Podcast hosts Zachary Hepburn
speculates on fights between fan favorite anime
and manga characters. On Thursday, Zach is going
to reveal who would win between Sunraku from
Shangri-La Frontier versus Kirito from Sword Art
Online. We said that was going to be last week's
episode, but Zach had to undergo surgery last
week, so he was able to release the episode and
we're wishing him a speedy recovery. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our show
notes to listen to all the shows in the Dynamite
Podcast Network. But with that out of the way,
quick to the No Prize! A No Prize is an award that
Marvel used to give out to fans. Our version, the
Dynamic duel No Prize, is a digital award we post on
Instagram for the person that we feel gave the best
answer to our question of the week. Last week we
asked you guys, what did you think of the Shalabal
Silver Surfer from the Fantastic Four First Steps
official trailer? And we got three answers, so
let's go over our two honorable mentions and the No
Prize winner. Our first honorable mention goes to
Kat Stevenson, who said, Hi guys, this is Kat
Stevenson. I think that the Shalabal in the
Fantastic Four First Steps trailer, while it was a
bold choice, I think will ultimately be positive.
I think it'll keep the same people who have been
consistently shitting on James Gunn's Superman
away from the film and will help maintain positive
audience reactions to the film. Thanks guys.
Yeah, I'm not quite sure what he was saying here in
regards to the Superman film thing, but basically
his answer was it's a bold choice cotton. Let's see
how the strategy pays off for them. What I took this
to mean was that so many people are going to be
distracted by the Silver Surfer that's going to be
a positive for DC because they're not going to care
if anything's wrong with that film because
they're just going to be so negatively focused on
Fantastic Four and Silver Surfer. No he said it's
going to be a positive outcome. Yeah, for DC. Oh.
Yeah, I don't think that's what he meant. Well,
that's what I heard. Good answer Kat, our next
honorable mention goes to Gavin Troyer, who said,
I don't care if Silver Surfer has boobs or a penis. I
don't even care about bad CGI anymore.
Truthfully, I don't really care about the
Fantastic Four or Silver Surfer that much, but as
long as the movie is good, it's good. And it doesn't
really matter what the gender or how good the CGI
is. Hopefully the movie is fantastic and that's
all it really needs. All the criteria it needs is to
be fantastic. OK, but what if the Silver Surfer had
boobs and a penis? Well, like Gavin said, I don't
think it would matter if the movie was good. If the
movie is good, then, you know, the sex of the Silver
Surfer is probably going to be the last thing on
anyone's minds. At the end of the day, I think
people care more about the overall quality than
any specific, you know, genitalia detail. I don't
know about that. I think I would notice silver
genitalia. Great answer, Gavin. But the winner of
this week's No Prize is Travis Herndon, who said.
What's up, dynamic do's Travis here. So I'm fine
with a female Silver Surfer. I mean, they've
already established that this is an alternate
universe compared to the main MCU universe. And
usually when it comes to multiverses types,
situations is always the whole like, oh, hey, this
character might be gender-banned or this
character might be race-wild. I mean, we
introduced the multiverse into your story is kind
of expected. That's a great point made by Travis.
And I think why this answer got the No Prize win for
this being the multiversal saga as an audience,
we've gotten very little actual multiversal
content. And to quote the vision, what is the
multiverse, if not interesting and bold casting
choices, persevering? But what? I don't remember
him saying that. I'm paraphrasing. Oh, OK. Well, I
mean, Marvel does have a precedence for
gender-bending characters and the multiverse.
If you take a look at Captain Carter or Loki or even
Lady Deadpool, we've seen gender-bent versions
of heroes we know and love. And since this is a
multiversal character, I could see how people
could be a little bit more forgiving. That being
said, I still stand by what I said last week in that
sense. Shalabal is really the only seeming
multiversal component of the Fantastic Four
first steps film other than the time period. It
would have been nice if Marvel chose to go with the
Frankie Ray Nova Herald of Galactus instead.
Yeah, 100 percent. I agree with that. Well,
congrats to Travis Herndon for winning this
week's No Prize. If you, the listener, want a shot
at winning your own No Prize, stay tuned until
later on this episode when we will be asking
another question of the week. And now that that's
done onto the question of the week. Since this
episode is a team duel between Watchmen and
Thunderbolts and since Thunderbolts is coming
out this week, here's our question. For those of
you who have seen both films, which was better?
2009's Watchmen or Thunderbolts and why? Record
your answer at dynamicduel.com by clicking on the
red microphone button in the bottom right hand
corner of the screen, which will prompt you to
leave us a voicemail. Your message could be up to 30
seconds long. And don't forget to leave your name
in case we include you on the podcast. We'll pick
our favorite answer and award that person a
dynamic duel No Prize that will post to Instagram.
Be sure to answer before May 3rd. DC High Volume,
Batman. The Dark Knight's definitive DC comic
stories adapted directly for audio for the very
first time. Fear. I have to make them afraid. He's
got a motorcycle. Get after him or have you shot?
You mean blow up the building? From this moment on,
none of you are safe. New episodes every
Wednesday, wherever you get your podcasts. But
now let's go ahead and move on to the main event of
this episode, a team duel where we find out who will
win between DC's Watchmen and Marvel's
Thunderbolts. OK, Watchmen versus
Thunderbolts, as we mentioned earlier on in this
episode, this is really going to be a team of street
level heroes and one really superpowered
character backing them up. As you may know, with
the characters of Watchmen, none of them have
superpowers except for Dr. Manhattan, since this
is a world where people are essentially dressing
up to play superhero rather than actually being a
superhero. Yeah. And with Thunderbolts, if you
watch the marketing for the upcoming film, Yelena
Belova describes the team as a bunch of people who
punch and shoot stuff. But then there's also the
Sentry, who is on par with Superman, if not
stronger. I'm really excited for this matchup. I
never actually thought I would get to do Watchmen
as a team duel. Watchmen is one of my favorite DC
stories and highly praised as the greatest
graphic novel of all time. So I'm super pumped for
this matchup. Well, I think the original arc of the
Thunderbolts has also been called the greatest
graphic novel of all time. Shut the hell up by
somebody. Me, I mean, like at least I just said it
right now. So technically, yeah, it has been
called that. All right, one person. But to explain
the methodology behind our duels, let's go to our
sentient duel simulator, Alfred Jarvis, 9000.
Agent 9K tell our listeners how you go about
determining a winner in our team duel matchups.
Yes, of course, sir. The way I determine a winner
between the two teams is by running 1000 Monte
Carlo simulations between every character on
each team using their statistics. A Monte Carlo
simulation is a probabilistic model used to
determine outcomes through random sampling. In
this case, I randomize the statistics along a
normal distribution as a way to simulate the many
variables that can occur during battle. The stat
parameters are based on the official Marvel power
grid from which the DC characters statistics are
extrapolated. Additional stat categories are
included such as range, damage potential,
versatility and perception in order to create a
more detailed and accurate simulation. The
results of the 49000 simulations provide a
percentage of wins for each character on both
teams. The team with the higher average win rate is
declared the victor as they have a higher
probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither team should win 100
percent of the matches. The comic book stories
have shown that there's even a way for Batman to
defeat Superman, so the confidence rate of my
method falls in line with the precedents that have
been established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks, AJ9K.
Before we run the simulations, though, we like to
break down each team's histories and rosters
before improvising a scenario on how we imagine
one of the thousands of simulations would play out
beat for beat. And it's my turn to go first with the
DC team's backstory. So let me tell you all about
Watchmen. Now, the alternate universe of
Watchmen, the costumed adventurers first
emerged during the late 1930s and early 1940s,
beginning with the masked vigilante known as
Hooded Justice. His brutal and mysterious
activities against criminals inspired the
formation of The Minutemen, a team of eight masked
crime fighters, including Silk Spectre, Captain
Metropolis, Duller Bill, Mothman, the
Silhouette, Night Owl, the comedian and Hooded
Justice himself. Though publicly celebrated,
internal tensions plagued the group after an
attempted sexual assault by the comedian on Silk
Spectre was violently stopped by Hooded Justice,
the comedian was expelled from The Minutemen.
Despite their colorful appearances, the members
of The Minutemen harbored dark secrets and
personal flaws, and the team eventually
dissolved under the weight of scandal, tragedy
and infighting. Hooded Justice vanished without
a trace in the 1950s. His ultimate fate never
publicly confirmed. In the years that followed,
new costumed adventurers emerged. Daniel
Dryberg, inspired by the original Night Owl,
adopted the same moniker and operated with high
tech gadgetry. Laurie Yospeczyk, the daughter of
the original Silk Spectre, reluctantly took up
her mother's mantle as the second Silk Spectre.
Edward Blake, the comedian, continued operating
through government sanction, becoming a
hardened and cynical figure who participated in
the Vietnam War alongside Dr. Manhattan, who was
formerly John Osterman. He emerged as the first
being with true superhuman powers after a
scientific accident disintegrated and
reconstituted him as a blue-skinned being who
perceived all of times simultaneously. Adrian
Veit, known as Ozzy Mendeus and renowned as the
smartest man alive, rose to prominence with an
image of altruism and efficiency, only to retire
and channel his genius into business ventures. In
the early 1960s, Captain Metropolis attempted to
reunite the new generation of adventurers under a
team called the Crime Busters. The group gathered
for a meeting, but the effort collapsed when the
comedian mocked their idealism and exposed the
futility of costumed heroics in the shadow of
nuclear Armageddon. Following this, the
independent operations of the crime fighters
continued until in 1977, when the United States
passed the Keen Act, outlawing un-sanctioned
vigilanteism. Most heroes retired. Ozzy Mendeus
left the public eye to pursue corporate power.
Dryberg reluctantly stepped down. Dr. Manhattan
and the comedian continued their work as
sanctioned government operatives and only
Rorschach refused to comply. Continuing his
crusade illegally. In October 1985, Edward Blake
was thrown from the window of his apartment in New
York City. His death initially believed to be an
isolated homicide. Through the attention of
Rorschach, who uncovered Blake's secret
identity as the comedian, convinced that someone
was targeting masked heroes. Rorschach visited
his former colleagues, Daniel Dryberg, Laurie
Yospechik, Dr. Manhattan and Adrian Weitz.
Though most of them dismissed his warnings, the
seeds of suspicion were planted. Blake's funeral
brought the surviving former heroes together.
Dryberg, Weitz and Manhattan attended, each
reflecting under complicated relationships
with Blake. Shortly after the funeral, Dr.
Manhattan was publicly accused of causing cancer
among his former associates. Shocked by the
allegations and humanity's sudden rejection,
Manhattan exiled himself to Mars. With the
departure of their superhuman deterrent, the
Soviet Union seized the opportunity to invade
Afghanistan, escalating global tensions
towards nuclear war. Weitz narrowly survived an
assassination attempt for their convincing
Rorschach that a conspiracy was afoot.
Meanwhile, Laurie, disillusioned with her life
alongside the increasingly detached Dr.
Manhattan, grew closer to Dryberg. The two
eventually donned their costumes once more,
rekindling their sense of purpose as vigilantes
and rescuing residents from a burning apartment
building. Their renewed partnership deepened
into romance. Rorschach, continuing his
investigation, was framed for the murder of the
former villain, Mollick, and was captured by
police after a violent struggle. In prison, he was
subjugated to attacks from fellow inmates, but he
defended himself with ruthless efficiency,
culminating in a cafeteria scalding and the
brutal murder of a crime boss. Meanwhile, Dryberg
and Yospechek, believing Rorschach's
conspiracy theory had merit, executed a daring
plan to break him out of prison during a massive
riot. While Dryberg and Rorschach investigated
further, Dr. Manhattan transported Laurie to
Mars. There, Laurie pleaded with him to save
humanity from impending doom. Initially
unmoved, Manhattan reconsidered after Laurie's
revelation that she was the daughter of the
comedian, the product of a complex and painful
relationship between her mother and Blake.
Seeing the improbability and beauty of human
existence, Manhattan agreed to return to Earth.
During investigation, led Dryberg and Rorschach
to suspect Adrian Veit as the masked killer,
following a trail of evidence they traveled to
Antarctica to confront him in his private base,
where Veit revealed his plan to save humanity from
nuclear annihilation by staging an alien
invasion that would decimate New York City. By
uniting the United States and the Soviet Union
against a perceived extraterrestrial threat,
you believed he could avert global war. Veit
admitted to orchestrating the cancer scare to
drive Dr. Manhattan away, staging the attempt on
his own life to eliminate suspicion, murdering
Blake when he uncovered the plot and framing
Rorschach to impede his investigation. As
Dryberg and Rorschach reeled from the
revelation, Veit disclosed that his plan had
already been enacted. In New York, millions lay
dead amid the wreckage caused by the appearance of
the genetically engineered psychic creature, a
colossal sized squid that was teleported into the
city. News reports confirmed that the United
States and Soviet Union had entered talks to unite
against the supposed alien menace. Manhattan and
Lorry arrived on Earth and traveled to
Antarctica, confronting Veit. Although
appalled by the slaughter, the heroes realized
that exposing the truth would only reignite the
threat of nuclear war. All except Rorschach
agreed to keep silence. Rorschach refused to
compromise. As he departed into the frozen
wasteland to reveal the truth, he encountered Dr.
Manhattan and he demanded to be killed rather than
be silenced by any other means. Without a word,
Manhattan complied, disintegrating Rorschach.
Following the confrontation, Dryberg and Lorry
adopted new identities, leaving behind their
former lives. Meanwhile, back in New York, the
right wing newspaper New Frontiersman received
Rorschach's journal detailing his
investigation and suspicions into Adrian, its
contents poised to expose the entire truth,
depending on the editor's decision. Dr.
Manhattan, disillusioned by humanities and less
cycles, left Earth to explore new galaxies.
Adrian Veit, victorious, yet uncertain, was left
to wonder about the consequences of his actions.
Years after the devastation in New York City, the
world uncovered the truth behind Adrian Veit's
deception when Rorschach's journal was finally
published. Rather than uniting humanity
indefinitely, the revelation reignited
distrust and chaos among the nations. In
desperation, Veit sought to locate Dr.
Manhattan, believing only he could repair the
world he had broken. Tracking residuel quantum
traces across dimensions, Veit crossed into a
parallel Earth where superheroes had long shaped
history differently. There, he manipulated a
successor to Rorschach, Reginald Long,
convincing him to assist in the search. Edward
Blake, the comedian whose death Veit had once
orchestrated, was pulled from the moment of his
murder and brought into this new world by Dr.
Manhattan's intervention. Now alive again,
Blake hunted Veit for revenge, while also
becoming entangled in violent conflicts between
metahuman factions. Dr. Manhattan, observing
this world, had been subtly reshaping its
history. Intrigued by the resilience of its
greatest hero, Superman, Manhattan had
experimented with removing key figures and
altering pivotal moments, shifting the
emergence of heroes and the world's timeline.
Yet, despite his manipulations, Manhattan found
himself unable to see beyond a looming
confrontation with Superman, uncertain whether
he would destroy this reality or be destroyed by
it. Adrian Veit, recognizing the instability Dr.
Manhattan's presence created, attempted once
more to engineer peace by igniting a global
metahuman arms race and framing Superman as a
threat. His plans ultimately unraveled as the
truth surfaced aided by heroes from this new earth
who resisted further deception. In the final
confrontation, Superman's unwavering hope
inspired Dr. Manhattan to abandon his cold
detachment. Rather than destroy or dominate the
world, Manhattan restored what he had broken,
returning lost heroes to existence and ensuring
the survival of those he had once endangered. Veit
was returned to his own world, exposed for his
crimes and imprisoned, accepting that he had no
place in this world. Manhattan entrusted his
power to a child he had raised, a boy he named Clark,
whom he gave to Daniel Dryberg and Laura Yospechik
to raise before Manhattan vanished from
existence. Clark grew up to become the superhero
known as the Watchman. And that's the full history
of the Watchman characters. Now, for my seven
member Watchman roster, I am, of course, going
with the six main characters of the Watchman
story, including Rorschach, Silk Spectre and the
Comedian, none of whom who have superhuman
powers, but are skilled fighters and possess
various crime fighting tools and weapons. Ozzy
Mandius, also included on this team, possesses
near superhuman abilities, as he is the most
intelligent and most physically capable human
man in existence. Dr. Manhattan, as my sixth
member, is the powerhouse of the team, possessing
nine missions and omnipotence, whom you've
learned more about in our Dr. Manhattan versus
Molecule Man episode. For my seventh and final
member, I decided to go with Hooded Justice, as he
was the very first superhero in Watchman Comics
and is an accomplished fighter and stealth
expert. But who watches the Watchman? Your mom?
Yeah, I think she's seen that movie. You're right.
You're right. I got to say that the subsequent
rebirth DC universe aspects of these characters
history didn't really hold a candle to the
original Watchman story. No, and I don't think it
really holds a candle to what they did with the
Watchman television series. In my opinion, that
is the superior sequel to the Watchman story,
particularly when it comes to also the history of
certain characters like Hooded Justice. But
that's not comics canon. Yeah, if DC was smart,
they would actually serialize the Watchman
television show from HBO, put it into a comic book
format and then make it an official sequel. I might
be too late for that, but it's fine. Well, at least
Marvel has the synergy going with this new team
that's going to be in the Thunderbolts movie. But
let me take you back to the beginning of the comic
book history. The Thunderbolts were founded
after a battle with Onslaught left the world
without the Avengers or Fantastic Four. Seizing
the opportunity, Baron Zemo assembled a new team
of villains from the Masters of Evil group now
posing as heroes. Vidal, Fixer, Goliath,
Moonstone and Screaming Mimi, who adopted the new
identities of Mach 1, Techno, Atlas, Moonstone
and Songbird. You can learn more about the Masters
of Evil in their team duel against the Legion of
Doom. The Thunderbolts debuted to public
acclaim, even inspiring young heroine Jolt, who
joined the team unaware of their deception. After
the Avengers and the Fantastic Four returned,
Zemo accelerated his plans, publicly exposing
the Thunderbolts true identities to destroy
their chances at redemption and solidify their
loyalty to him. Zemo attempted to enslave the
global population with a mind control device, but
the team, having genuinely embraced heroism,
turned against him, freeing the mind controlled
populace. Zemo fled while the remaining
Thunderbolts, now fugitives, struggled to earn
back the trust they had betrayed. Better an
Avenger Hawkeye than joined and led the team,
boosting their credibility. He convinced Mach 1
to serve jail time for past crimes, solidifying
the team's commitment to change. Under Hawkeye,
the Thunderbolts defeated the new Masters of
Evil, gained the headquarters, and earned
government support. After exposing Henry
Guyridge's anti-superhuman conspiracy, they
were officially pardoned. Later, during a battle
with Graviton, several Thunderbolts, including
Fixer, Jolt and Songbird, were hurled to counter
Earth, which was a parallel world created by
Franklin Richards, the son of Mr. Fantastic and
Invisible Woman. There, they worked with Baron
Zemo to stabilize the devastated planet.
Meanwhile, Hawkeye formed a second Thunderbolts
team to combat Crimson Cowell's forces.
team to combat Crimson Cowell's forces. After
various battles in the return of the original team
from counter Earth, the Thunderbolts merged into
one group. Zemo seized control, convincing some
members to follow his vision of saving the world
through domination. His Thunderbolts clashed
with the Avengers and were ultimately defeated,
fracturing the team. Original members Mock Four,
Songbird and Atlas later revived the
Thunderbolts with new recruits like Joystick,
Rizzard, Speed Demon and Radioactive Man. This
era saw them battle against Hydra and the Purple
Man, who tried to enslave New York. Zemo secretly
manipulated a Formerly the Green Goblin, soon
assumed leadership of the new Thunderbolts
lineup. You can learn more about him in his duel
against the Joker. Characters like Songbird,
Moonstone, Bullseye, Venom, Penance, and
Swordsman operated as a sanctioned strike team
capturing unregistered heroes. Despite public
success, internal betrayal and corruption
riddled the team. Osborn manipulated events
during the Skrull invasion positioning himself
as the national hero known as Iron Patriot. Under
Osborn, the Thunderbolts became a covert
assassination squad known as the Dark Avengers.
New members included White Widow, Yelena Baloba,
who was actually Natasha Romanoff in disguise,
Ant-Man, and Ghost. Missions ranged from
targeting Deadpool to seizing weapons for Masked
Guard during Osborn's campaign against the realm
after it manifested on Earth. After Osborn's
fall, Luke Cage took over the Thunderbolts
program. The team included Songbird, Mach 5,
Ghost, Moonstone, Juggernaut, Crossbones,
Hyperion, and Manthing. Operating from the Raft
prison, this version aimed at rehabilitating
villains, though tensions and betrayals
remained. Crossbones and Hyperion were expelled
after betraying the team, and Satan had joined to
defend against magical threats. The team was
later lost in time, battling through World War II,
Camelot, and a dystopian future before returning
to the present and then disbanding. Later,
General Thaddeus, Thunderbolt Ross, now Red
Hulk, formed his own Thunderbolt strike team with
Deadpool, Electra, Agent Venom, Punisher, and
eventually Ghost Rider. Operating outside
government control, they confronted threats
like Madman, Gamma-irradiated Crimson Dynamos,
and even travel to Hell. The team fractured after a
brutal internal conflict between Punisher and
Red Hulk, which was partly orchestrated by the
villain known as the Leader. James Bucky Barnes,
aka the Winter Soldier, assembled a new
Thunderbolt squad, including original members
Fixer, Atlas, Moonstone, and Mach 10. The mission
was to prevent Shield from abusing the sentient
cosmic cube, Cobyc. During this time, they
battled alien invaders, the squadron Supreme,
and a secretly fascist Captain America. Songbird
briefly reunited with the team before it
disbanded, following attacks by Baron Zemo and
the Masters of Evil. Subsequently, Zemo
organized a Thunderbolt's team during his
vendetta against the Punisher. His roster
included Ghost, Moonstone, Radioactive Man,
Fixer, and Jigsaw. Their efforts to trap and kill
Frank Castle failed after Ghost turned against
Zemo. The Kingpin, as Mayor of New York later
formed his own Thunderbolt's task force led by
Taskmaster to fight the evil deity Null's
invasion of the city. After being hunted by Null's
shadowy forces, the team made their way to the
Ravencroft Institute, where they teamed with
Norman Osborn to use the Sentry against Null's
symbiote base. After Null's eventual defeat,
which you can learn more about in his duel against
DC's White Lantern, Kingpin continued using the
Thunderbolts, now led by a US agent to crack down on
Vigilantism. Following Fisk's downfall as
Mayor, the newly elected Luke Cage restructured
the Thunderbolts and placed Hawkeye in charge
with a new lineup featuring Photon, Miss America,
and Power Man. This team successfully defended
New York from several threats, but was
short-lived. Meanwhile, the Winter Soldier and
former Shield agent Contessa Valentina Allegra
de Fontaine assembled a separate Thunderbolts
team to dismantle Red Skull's global operations.
Red Guardian, White Widow, Black Widow, Sharon
Carter, Shang Chi, and US agent joined the cause.
They succeeded in defeating the Red Skull after a
battle in Laferia, involving Dr. Doom. And that's
the Thunderbolts backstory. For this team duel's
7-person roster, I'm going with mostly members
from the most recent iteration of the comic book
team, which largely coincides with the roster in
the Thunderbolts movie, which comes out this
week. Yes, it did destroy me that we're not
including any members of the original
Thunderbolts team here, including people like
Baron Zemo, Mach 1, Songbird, Atlas, Moonstone,
and Techno. No one is more upset by this than me,
because I think the original Thunderbolts
storyline up through Hawkeye's leadership of the
group is just classic Marvel storytelling that no
other iteration of the team has been able to match.
But as we said earlier, when we realized that the
film's Thunderbolts roster could potentially
make for a good duel against the Watchmen, we just
saw an opportunity that we couldn't pass up. So
representing the Thunderbolts are the Winter
Soldier, who has led two separate versions of the
team, Taskmaster, who served on three iterations
and even led the team once, Ghost, a three-time
Thunderbolts member, US Agent, who has served on
the Thunderbolts twice and led once, White Widow,
who was involved in two incarnations of the team,
Red Guardian, who was a more recent recruit, and
finally, the Sentry, who was never actually a
Thunderbolts member but who was a part of Norman
Osborn's Dark Avengers, which was a team that spun
out of the Thunderbolts. Each of these characters
has had their own duel episode for listeners to
learn more about them, except for Ghost and Red
Guardian. Ghost was a brilliant data engineer who
developed quantum computing chips that could
phase out of existence to bypass the physical
limitations of the real world, such as
overheating. When he was betrayed by the company
he worked for, he integrated the technology into a
suit that could render him both invisible and
intangible. After killing his company's
executives, he became a corporate saboteur for
hire. He clashed with Iron Man on multiple
occasions before being drafted into the
Thunderbolts. Ghost's suit also renders him
completely silent, able to zap others or disrupt
electronics with an electric touch, able to
interface with technology, and able to float. Of
course, the comic version is very different than
the MCU's version, who is Ava Star, the daughter of
the Ant-Man villain Egghead. Now Red Guardian's
real name is Alexi Shostakov, whom I discussed
briefly in our Black Canary vs Black Widow Duel
episode. In the comics, he is a former Soviet pilot
and husband of Black Widow. His death was faked by
the KGB in order to turn him into a special
operative. Russia is answered to Captain
America, called Red Guardian. He was often pit
against his American rival and later against his
ex-wife, when she defected from Russia and joined
the Avengers. Red Guardian later defected
himself, and often teamed up with White Widow
against the Red Room. He wields a circular shield
and carries smaller discs on his belt that he can
use as throwing projectiles. That's the team. To
reiterate, my Thunderbolts roster is Winter
Soldier, Taskmaster, Ghost, US Agent, White
Widow, Red Guardian, and Sentry. Right, and when
we're formulating rosters with our executive
producers, we like to pair up these characters
just to make sure that they are evenly matched, or
as evenly matched as we can get. In this case, Red
Guardian is pairing up with Hooded Justice, White
Widow with Comedian, Ghost with Silk Spectre,
Taskmaster with Ozzy Mandias, Winter Soldier
with Night Owl, US Agent with Rorschach, and of
course, Sentry with Dr. Manhattan. Yeah, one of
the main differences between the two teams is that
the watchmen are going to get served justice like
lightning. Okay. And if you didn't know, that is
the Thunderbolts tagline. So, yeah. But now that
we've got the team's histories and rosters out of
the way, we're going to speculate on how one of the
thousands of simulated matches will go. The
winner is determined by simulations, not the
speculation, but it's fun to imagine how the fight
could play out. Agent I.K., what are the rules over
speculation? Well, I should say there are no
rules, other than the teams have no prior
knowledge of the other going into the fight. All
they are aware of starting out is that the other
side is a threat that needs to be eliminated. For
the speculation, the groups will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the match
itself, as no environmental statistics are
considered in my simulations. The teams must earn
victory on their own merit. All right, then, let's
get into it. The watchmen and the Thunderbolts
meet on the battlefield, which team goes first?
Actually, I'm going to say that because Dr.
Manhattan already knows how this match is going to
play out and end, he's going to start by causing
this colossal labyrinth of reflective glass and
clockwork gears to rise up from the ground around
them. And so now the teams have to fight through
this MC Escher-esque hall of mirrors. That's
pretty cool, but the Thunderbolts are going to be
like, what the hell is this? How is this fair? And
why is that blue guy's dick out? And Red Guardian is
going to be like, should I pull my dick out? And
everybody's going to be like, that's gross. Don't
do that. But I'm going to say the century starts off
by he's just going to tear through the clockwork
tower, like shattering some parts of it, melting
parts of it down. So everything is basically
falling apart around them. And as this glass
structure gets torn down, Winter Soldier
suddenly gets a clear shot with his sniper rifle
through a hole in the glass, and he just shoots
Comedian right in his side. Actually, though,
that was just a reflection of the Comedian. So
Winter Soldier really just shoots through glass
and now he's given away his location to the real
Comedian to return to the favor by launching a
grenade from his rifle at the Winter Soldier. And
that's going to cause his good arm to get blown
right off. No, no, no, no, because as the grenade
comes in, it's just going to bounce off of US
agents' shield and blow up another part of the
glass tower. I think by this point, like at least
half of the structure is already gone. So White
Widow grapples up to the highest point that's
still around. And she's going to shoot down a gas
pellet that covers Rorschach and Hooded Justice
in tear gas smoke, and they're not able to breathe
and they're incapacitated. You literally chose
the two characters who both have mouth coverings
to filter their air. No, it would affect them more.
I don't think it would. Oh, shit, did I fuck up?
Rorschach, you know, he's going to see where the
tear gas came from and he's going to use his
grappling gun to zip up to where White Widow is, at
which point he's going to attack her with a broken
shot of glass that he collected down below and he's
just going to slice right into her neck. There's no
way. Like White Widow is going to block this slash
attack and then she's going to punch Rorschach
right in the face and then she's going to look at his
mask and she's going to be like, I think I see a bitch
and she's going to rent house, kick him right off
the glass tower where he lands on some spiky glass
debris down below and dies. What? Damn. OK, he's
probably going to call her a whore as he falls to his
death. Right in front of Night Owl, who's like, no.
And so he's going to grapple up to his Archie Owl
ship and use its sonic emitters to shatter the
glass tower that White Widow is in. So she also
falls to her death. I said that you couldn't use
Archie in the course of this battle. I'm sorry.
Why? For the same reason I said you couldn't use the
bug ship in the Blue Beetle duel episode. And yet I
did. And it's not fair to do one and not the other. So
suck it. Meanwhile, back in the match, Hooded
Justice has Red Guardian panties to the ground in a
wrestling chokehold. OK. And Red Guardian is
going to be like, why is the guy fighting me have an
erection? What is with this team? And he's going to
be rescued by USA agent who curls his shield at
Hooded Justice's head, which is going to cause him
to lose his grip on Red Guardian. And Red Guardian,
he's going to get up and he throws his shield at
Hooded Justice to in retaliation for the
chokehold. And then, you know what? Just to get it
on the action, Taskmaster also throws his shield
at Hooded Justice. So that's three different
shields being thrown at him. Hooded Justice is
looking like a pinball here and he's knocked out of
this match. No one's taken three shields to the
face and living to tell about it. OK, that seemed
unnecessary. Let's say Silk Spectre and Ghost are
battling get out elsewhere in this match. But, you
know, even with ghosts, phasing abilities, Silk
Spectre is one of the best trained fighters in the
watchmen world. So she's able to time her attacks
perfectly and land several debilitating blows
against a ghost that would never happen. If
anything, Ghost is probably just going to have
some fun, like frustrating Silk Spectre as she
tries to land hit after hit after hit and just
getting air each time. And then Ghost is just going
to turn invisible. And Silk Spectre is wondering
where the hell he's gone. When all of a sudden Ghost
appears behind her and straight up tases her in the
neck and she drops to the floor like a wet sack. So
Silk Spectre is out of this match now. For my
tasing? Yeah, she's incapacitated. OK, well,
this whole time, Ozymandias has been hiding in
the labyrinth, just observing the thunder bolts.
And through his powers of deduction, he's noticed
that the Russian technology of the winter
soldier's bionic arm doesn't match his accent. So
he assumes he is a kidnapped, brainwashed
assassin. And having read about Russian
brainwashing techniques, Ozymandias quickly
speaks Bucky's code words to take control of him.
And he has Bucky's snap red guardians neck killing
him. Well, you're thinking of the movies here,
like in the books, there were no code words. If I
remember correctly, it was just he was controlled
by the Russians through mind implants. But we'll
say that, yeah, sure. Somehow Ozymandias knew
something about Russia manipulation
techniques, at least enough to take advantage of
them. All right, cool. Yeah. So the winter soldier
is his agent now, and he killed Red Guardian. But
whatever Ozymandias can do, Taskmaster can
copy. So as the US agent and ghost are like
defending themselves from Bucky's gunfire,
Taskmaster is going to just run his sword through
Ozymandias and pailing him and killing him and
then using the same Russian techniques to bring
the winter soldier back onto the Thunderbolt
side. No, no, no, because Ozymandias had
observed Taskmaster as well and also deduced his
ability to mimic physical abilities. So as
Taskmaster attacks him, Ozymandias just
sidesteps and catches the blade of Taskmaster's
sword between his palms. And with one fluid
motion, Ozymandias disarms and impales
Taskmaster on his own sword. OK, so you're telling
me that Ozymandias not only still has winter
soldier under his control, but he also just took
out Taskmaster. That's right. Well, it's pretty
dang strong. I'm going to say by this point, Ghost
has floated up to Archie, Night Owl's ship, and he
uses his ghost tech to shut down all of Archie's
electrical systems and Night Owl has no idea
what's going on because Ghost is invisible and
inaudible. So Night Owl ejects from the ship as it
falls from the sky. But Ghost manages to steer it
right into Ozymandias, who's like, oh, shit, I
didn't see this coming. And then he gets fined into
the world's smartest pancake. OK, sure. Night
Owl, he's going to glide down from the sky
silently. And he aims right for US agent doing a
gliding double kick right into his spine, causing
US agent to topple forward. And Night Owl is
quickly going to follow up by hurling a crescent
blade right into US agent's neck. No, not only does
US agent block this crescent blade with his
shield, he's going to rush over and then straight
up shield uppercut Night Owl's head. Right off his
body, because, you know, he has like 10 ton level
strength. What the heck? All right. Well, this is
when US agent suddenly gets hosed down by the
comedian's flamethrower, just setting him
ablaze. And while US agent is dying, comedian
turns his attention to Winter Soldier, who's
coming out of Ozymandias's brainwashing, all
confused. And the comedian snipes him right in the
head. No, I think Winter Soldier is less confused
than you think. Like he snaps out of Ozymandias's
brainwashing and straight up catches comedian's
bullet with his metal arm. And then without
missing a beat with his other arm, he just flings a
throwing knife that flacks right into comedian's
forehead. Dude, I said comedian snaped him. He was
far away. Winter Soldier could throw a knife that
hard, that fast, that far. Yeah. OK. So what? All I
have left is Dr. Manhattan. Oh, no. Whatever.
Psych. Dr. Manhattan is going to split himself
into three duplicates and one's going to teleport
over to ghost and turn him into steam. And another
one's going to go to US agent. Just turn him to
Mercury. And the third one, he's going to teleport
over to Winter Soldier and turn him into
snowflakes. Wow. Easy peasy. And then he's going
to re merge into one giant being that's going to
snatch the century right out of the air. And, you
know, maybe taking a second to study his
photosynthetic physiology. He's just going to
straight up turn him into a black hole. Match over.
I win. OK. I'm going to say that Dr. Manhattan meant
to turn century into a black hole. But what he
actually accidentally did was bring out the
centuries void persona. So this like black hole
that Dr. Manhattan created, it actually develops
like this dark smile and shoots at a bunch of dark
tendrils that embed themselves into Dr.
Manhattan and they just explode him like a nuclear
bomb. No, Dr. Manhattan would have seen this
coming, though. No, no, no, because there were
tachyons. Right. Created by the mini black hole
that was actually the void. And then when Dr.
Manhattan exploded like a nuclear bomb, like,
yeah, there were tachyons. And, you know, all the
science stuff. So he couldn't see it. Sorry.
You're just saying words. OK. Actually, you know
what? There was a nuclear bomb explosion. So as the
voids embedding itself in Dr. Manhattan, let's
say suddenly this bright light crackles between
them just as a massive alien squid suddenly
explodes onto the scene, not only blowing up the
void and Manhattan, but also invading their minds
with like disturbing psychic energy that
literally shatters their minds. And how how did
this happen when Ghost crashed Archie into
Ozymandias at the last second? He leaped through
one of Archie's giant eye windows and then he
rewired and rebooted the ship's technology to
send a signal back to bite industries and putting
coordinates for where his squid alien should
appear and detonate. He probably knew he wouldn't
survive the explosion, but he knew that Dr.
Manhattan could by reconstituting himself
afterward, giving his side the wind. Except, you
know, that the century would also regenerate from
this, not just Dr. Manhattan. So that would work.
Yeah. OK, well, you know, Dr. Manhattan would
regenerate first, so we still win. I don't think
so, but we can go ahead and leave the match there.
Either Dr. Manhattan regenerates from
Ozymandias's giant squid explosion first or the
century regenerates first. Let's go ahead and
find out which scenario happens by inputting the
stats on these teams, running the simulations and
coming back with the winning team. AJ9K, hit it.
Inputting data, running calculations,
processing results, simulations complete. All
right, this is quite the fun pairing, mostly
because putting in the stats for the more street
level characters was funny compared to the more
god level power characters. Yeah, it was not even
close. Dr. Manhattan won a whopping 97.8 percent
of his matches against the entire Thunderbolts
team. It was funny because it's rare that we ever
get a zero win rate percentage, but it happened for
the first time in the course of this match. There
were several Thunderbolts characters who
literally stood a zero percent chance of
defeating Dr. Manhattan. Yeah, he was by far the
most powerful character on either of our teams.
Now, the century, obviously, was your most
powerful character. Yeah, and there were some
watchmen characters that the century beat, like,
99.9 percent of the time. So his overall win rate
ended up being 84.3 percent. It would have been
damn near close to 100 if it wasn't for Dr.
Manhattan. It was interesting seeing how the
overall stat categories compared across each
team, especially with things like evasiveness.
Like the Thunderbolts were way more evasive than
the watchmen, largely because US agent has a
shield, taskmaster has a shield, red guardian has
a shield, ghost is fucking intangible and
invisible. So the Thunderbolts just dominated in
that category. Yeah, the only stat where the
street level watchmen characters really shined
in was fighting skill. They're all pretty good
fighters. And next to Dr. Manhattan, my most
impressive character was actually Night Owl. I
thought it was going to be Ozzy Madius, but with the
Archie Owl ship that really leveled up Night Owl in
terms of his stats. I mean, yeah, the watchmen were
good fighters, but the Thunderbolts were also
really good fighters. That's fair. And you guys
were also much more versatile than the watchmen as
well. I had the most powerful character, but I also
had the two weakest characters in Silk Spectre and
Hooded Justice. Yeah, my weakest character was
actually Ghost, who does great in terms of
evasiveness, but wasn't really impressive in any
other stat category, except for intelligence and
versatility. Yeah, Ghost as your weakest
character had a win rate of thirty six point five
percent, whereas my lowest win rate of fourteen
point six percent belonged to Silk Spectre. So we
got a nice little trade off here going basically,
Jonathan, you have the character with the highest
win rate, but you also have the characters with the
lowest win rate. My best win rate doesn't match Dr.
Manhattan's, but also I don't go as low as fourteen
point six percent like you did. So that all said,
which team do you think came out on top? Well, it's
kind of hard to say. I think it's going to be the
Thunderbolts, because even though Dr. Manhattan
is statistically better than the Sentry, I think
that the rest of the team is far superior to the
Watchmen. Although Instagram does not agree with
me in the poll that we put up prior to recording this
episode, 69 percent of the poll takers sided with
the Watchmen. And I'm not surprised because
Watchmen is way cooler than Thunderbolts and
everybody knows it. But did Watchmen get the win? A
JNNK, the results, please. Here you are, sir. The
winning team in our matchup between the Watchmen
and Thunderbolts is. Thunderbolts, that's
right. What did I say? Justice like lightning.
They won an even 57 percent of their matches
compared to Watchmen who only won 43, which is
actually a pretty decent showing for the
Watchmen. Right. Now, I guarantee you that Dr.
Manhattan got all their wins for them almost
literally. Yeah. But still decent showing. I
don't understand this considering the fact that
at the start of each match, Dr. Manhattan could
literally teleport the entire Thunderbolts team
to Mars and they would all just die. Well, the
century wouldn't and he would bring him right back
to Earth and then kick Dr. Manhattan right in his
blue wiener. Whatever. Also, we don't consider
battlefield removal as a viable strategy in these
duels. Says you. Yeah, says the winner. Are you
sad, Jonathan? I'm not going to lie. I am pretty
sad. Like, I just want to go to bed now. Do you think
we could get you crying on air before we sign off?
Well, let me try. Let me try. No, I can't do it.
Sorry. Well, that's too bad. But that doesn't for
this duel, guys. Agent 9K, help close this out.
Thanks for listening to Dynamic Jewel. Visit the
show's website at dynamicjewel.com and follow us
on Instagram at Dynamic Jewel podcast. You can
support the show on Patreon at patreon.com slash
Dynamic Jewel and joining a tier that works for you
or by rating and reviewing Dynamic Jewel on Apple
podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser or on our website.
Don't forget to listen to the other shows in the
Dynamite podcast network, including Max
Destruction, Senjo World and Console Combat. As
we mentioned earlier, our next episode is going to
be a review of Marvel Studios Thunderbolts'
asterisk film. We'll find out what the asterisk is
apparently when we see the film. Yeah, I'm excited
to see it. Basically staying off the Internet for
the whole rest of the week because I'm not seeing it
until Friday evening. And I know there's going to
be spoilers galore out there. So I can't wait to get
spoilers. And I could just forward them to you
because I'm petty for losing this match. But thank
you for the warning. It helps me know that I should
block you now. I mean, I'm not going to do that.
Fuck. That does it for this episode, guys. We want
to give a big thanks to our executive producers,
John Staroski, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Balcom,
Mickey Mathen-Geehan, Brandon Estregard,
Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yatten, Austin
Wuzelowski, A.J. Dunkerley, Nick Ibonto, Scott
Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Speese, Dean Moleski,
Devin Davis, Joseph Kirchsting, Josh Schleiner,
Mike Williams and Oscar Galvez for helping make
this podcast possible. We'll talk to you guys next
week. Up up and away, true believers. Who watches
the Watchman when the justice like lightning is or
shit. I lost it.