This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi, welcome to
the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters and stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin
brother, Marvelous Joe. And in this episode, we
are taking a break from the reviews to do a team
duel, this time a rematch between the Justice
League and Avengers, but more specifically, the
Justice League International against the West
Coast Avengers. Yeah, there are different
spin-off branches of the traditional Justice
League and Avengers teams. I got to say, Jonathan,
this is my chance for sweet ass revenge against the
Justice League for what happened in our first
initial team duel all those years ago. Yeah, that
was episode 100. That seems like forever ago. It
was back in 2018, back when we were just kids. Oh,
what I wouldn't give to be seven years younger.
Well, it's gonna be a fun match this episode. Look
forward to that later on. Before that, we're not
going to break down the comic book movie news
because as per the norm for the past several weeks,
there really isn't any like James Gunn has been
talking a lot about various DC projects, but
nothing really concrete. Penguin did get
nominated for 24 Emmys, but that's not really news
until I actually win something. We're all just
kind of waiting for Fantastic Four to come out and
just lose horribly box office wise and critically
to Superman. Yeah, when Fantastic Four beats
Superman's opening weekend, we could definitely
talk about that in the new section. That'll be fun.
Yeah, or vice versa. Superman beats Fantastic
Four. It's not going to happen. You sack of shit.
Roll up. Roll up, bro. I guess we'll find out later
on this week what happens. But as always, we list
our segment times in our episode description, so
feel free to check out the show notes if you want to
skip ahead to a particular topic. Guys are
artificially intelligent. Dual simulator, AJ9K
has a quick message for our listeners. So listen
up. Why hello there. Do you want even more from this
podcast? Then become a part of the dynamic dual
community on Patreon, where you can choose from
three tiers. The dynamic to a tier gives you access
to our discord chat server. The Fantastic Four
tier gives you two bonus episodes each month. And
the X Force tier makes you an executive producer of
this show. Lastly, the Diner Mike podcast network
tier lets you create your own podcast using this
Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe will help
you develop your show, provide graphic support
and consultation and get you simulation results.
Pitch the twins, your ideas via email at dynamic
dual podcast at gmail.com. Check it out at
patreon.com slash dynamic dual. Pip pip cheerio.
Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast. Be sure to tune into the other shows
and the Diner Mike podcast network this week,
including the console combat podcast where hosts
John and Dean simulate battles between popular
video game characters. In yesterday's episode,
they determined who would win between Rayman and
Jake the dog from Adventure Time. Over on the Max
Destruction podcast hosts Scotty and Gilly, Pay
Your Favor Action Heroes from film and television
against each other. This week, they'll be finding
out who would win between Aaron Cross from The Born
Legacy and Jack Reacher. And on the San Joe World
podcast hosts Zachary Hepburn speculates on
fights between fan favorite anime and manga
characters. In his next episode, Zach's going to
reveal who would win between Injun from Gaichi
Akura and Naito Mudano from Togon Anki. There's no
way I'm pronouncing any of that right. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our show
notes to listen to all of the shows in the Diner Mike
podcast network. But with that out of the way,
quick to the no prize. A no prize is an award that
Marvel used to give out to fans. Our version, the
Dynamic Dual No Prize, is a digital award we post on
Instagram for the person that we feel gave the best
answer to our question of the week. Last week, we
asked you guys, what do you want the sequel to the
Superman movie to be about? And this is coming off
of the phenomenal box office opening weekend for
the Superman movie, which will more than likely
warrant a sequel for the character. We got quite a
few answers. We're going to break down this week's
honorable mentions before revealing the no prize
winner. Our first honorable mention goes to
Travis Herndon, who said, What's up, dead, I'm a
dude. Travis here. Shout out to my evil twin. So my
answer would be, be like, what if Superman is for
the sequel actually meets Mongol? I think Mongol
would be a pretty cool villain to introduce in the
sequel. He's a tank. This dude is powerful. And
this guy also be a nice little wedding of the
appetite for DC fans for like whenever dark side
shows up, like, hey, this guy with rock and swoop
man, shit, magic dark side rocking them. Yeah, I
love the idea of Superman going up against a
formidable physical threat like Mongol, who
literally owns an entire planet that's
essentially like a Death Star, but way cooler.
Yeah, war world. Yeah, we haven't seen Mongol on
the silver screen yet. I'd love to see someone new
for Superman to fight. And Mongol is a great
choice. And we know that he exists within this DC
universe because we saw his sister Mongal in the
Suicide Squad movie that James Gunn also
directed. That is correct. But hopefully Mongol
wouldn't go out like a punk ass like she did with the
helicopter. Right, right, right, right. Great
answer. Travis, our next honorable mention goes
to Alex Albro, who said, Hey guys, given the
message from Superman's parents, I think there's
still a lot left on the table for the media to begin
Superman, especially if the antagonist of the
second movie is some sort of Kryptonian invader. I
think you can get Kara involved there, depending
on how they handle it. You could even cause a rift
between Superman and Lois based on his actions. I
think the second movie should end darker just
since this first one was pretty upbeat and
positive. And I think we still benefit from seeing
Superman in a vulnerable position. I think Lex
should stay in jail till the third movie or till
maybe a Justice League team up where he comes back
with an injustice gang. Now, of course, we've seen
Kryptonian threats go up against Superman in
films like Superman to Antiban of Steel,
specifically with Zod and his crew. I think if you
weren't going to go that direction just to do
something new, though, other Kryptonian threats
could include like Doomsday or maybe like an evil
version of the eradicator. We've seen Doomsday as
well, but I think this would be an opportunity to do
him even better than BVS did. That's right. Yeah,
we haven't seen him done right, at least. You know,
you could do actually, there is a recent villain
called Rogel Zarr that was created by Jim Lee, who I
think was a creation of Jor-El, and he was revealed
to actually be the one responsible for Krypton's
destruction. That might be interesting. That
would be interesting. Great answer, Alex. Our
final honorable mention goes to Brayden
Schaffer, who said. Brayden here, I think the
perfect equal would have Zod being the villain. We
could see Superman fight an actual Kryptonian and
not a clone. We could see Zod not get killed on
screen this time. And we could see how the public
thinks of the rest of Krypton after, you know, the
whole news article. And I think it'd be great at the
end of that to have a post-credits scene teasing
Doomsday for that final kind of tease of
Superman's big fight. I mean, it is really hard to
do better than Zod. He's one of Superman's
ultimate foes. I wouldn't hate a reimagining of
him. And like Brayden and Alex said, it would be a
nice continuation of the story established in the
first Superman movie. Right. Continuing the
whole Kryptonian angle where they're more
conquerors, almost like Viltramites or
something like that. Great answer, Brayden. We
want to give a quick shout out to Lorenzo Valdez for
taking the time to visit our website and record an
answer. But the winner of this week's No Price is
Cornelius Robinson. Who said? Hey, guys, it's
Cornelius Robinson. And my idea for the next
Superman sequel, we introduced the villain,
Brainiac, you know, it would be too soon, but who
knows, it is new DC universe. A new character that
can also introduce as John Henry Irons, aka Steel,
and a possible return for Supergirl to help combat
this unknown thread and expanding Superman's
responsibility to Earth as well. I've been
waiting to see Brainiac on the silver screen for so
long. He is sort of the ultimate Superman villain.
And I don't understand why we haven't seen him on
screen yet. I think with Supergirl being
introduced in this universe, it also makes
perfect sense that Brainiac would come,
considering he's the one who shrunk the city of
Kandor, where Supergirl's parents lived. Yeah.
And since he's kind of a tech based villain, it'd be
cool for Superman to team up with another tech
based hero in Steel and introduce him in that movie
and actually get the whole Superman family going
up against Brainiac. I think that'd be cool. I
don't know if I'm quite ready for Steel. I do like
the idea of him coming around with the other reign
of the Superman Superman characters like
Superboy and the eradicator. But I could be wrong.
Steel is a really cool character. So great answer,
Cornelius. You win this week's No Prize. If you're
the listener want to shot at winning your own No
Prize. Stay tuned to later on in this episode, when
we'll be asking another question of the week,
which is right now. So onto the question of the
week. For those who have seen the Fantastic Four
first steps in its opening weekend, what did you
think? And why was it inferior to Superman? If you
want to include that in your answer, you mean
superior. Record your answer at dynamicduel.com
by clicking on the red microphone button in the
bottom right hand corner of the screen, which will
prompt you to leave us a voicemail. Your message
could be up to 30 seconds long. And don't forget to
leave your name in case we include you on the
podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer and award
that person a Dynamic Duel No Prize that we'll post
to Instagram. Be sure to answer before July 27th.
But now let's go ahead and move on to the main events
of this episode, where we pits against each other,
the teams of the Justice League International and
the West Coast Avengers. OK, Justice League
International versus the West Coast Avengers. As
we mentioned earlier, this is something of a
rematch for these two teams. Since the very first
team duel that we did in episode 100 of this podcast
was the Justice League versus the Avengers. But
those two teams have such broad rosters. We knew
eventually we would be able to get the best of the
best and we'd have to circle back with some of these
extra characters in the aftershoots that these
teams have had in the comics. Yeah, plus I just
really want to rematch. Yeah, I bet you do. And the
West Coast Avengers are just the perfect team to do
it. I don't know much about Justice League
International, but I know that they're not as good
as the West Coast Avengers, which is primarily
composed of your standard Avengers. They just
moved over to the West Coast for a while, operating
out of LA. Oh, they operate out of LA. Oh, yeah, the
Justice League International operates out of the
world, the whole world. It's international, not
regulated to a single coast. Where is their
headquarters? Actually, they have headquarters
all around the world as well. Oh, really? OK. Yeah.
Why be based around the world when you could be
based in LA? Right? Right. No. No. Well, since
these teams don't need too much setting up, let's
go ahead and get right into it. To explain the
methodology behind our duels, let's go to our
sentient dual simulator, Alfred Jarvis 9000.
AJ9K, tell our listeners how you go about
determining a winner in our team dual matchups.
Yes, of course, sir. The way I determine a winner
between the two teams is by running 1000 Monte
Carlo simulations between every character on
each team using their statistics. A Monte Carlo
simulation is a probabilistic model used to
determine outcomes through random sampling. In
this case, I randomize the statistics along a
normal distribution as a way to simulate the many
variables that can occur during battle. The stat
parameters are based on the official Marvel power
grid from which the DC characters' statistics are
extrapolated. Additional stat categories are
included such as range, damage potential,
versatility and perception in order to create a
more detailed and accurate simulation. The
results of the 49000 simulations provide a
percentage of wins for each character on both
teams. The team with the higher average win rate is
declared the victor as they have a higher
probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither team should win 100%
of the matches. The comic book stories have shown
that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman, so the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks, AJ9K.
Before we run the simulations, though, we'd like
to break down each team's histories and rosters
before improvising a scenario on how we imagine
one of the thousands of simulations would play out
beat for beat. And I believe it's my turn to go
first. So let me break down the West Coast Avengers
history. Most of the New York City based Avengers
vanished when a cosmic being called the beyonder
whisked heroes and villains to a distant world to
watch them fight in a secret war. In their absence,
acting Avengers Chairman Vision, fearing Earth
was underprotected, convinced the US National
Security Council to approve a second Avengers
team roster on the Pacific Coast and chose Clint
Barton, Hawkeye, to command it. You can learn more
about the primary Avengers team in the episode
where we put them against the Justice League.
Hawkeye and his new wife, former shield agent
Bobby Mockingbird Morris, bought a neglected
seaside estate near Los Angeles and recruited to
the initial team the super strong Simon Williams,
AKA Wonder Man and Iron Man, who was actually Jim
Rhodes wearing Tony Stark's armor at the time,
while Stark worked on recovering from his
alcoholism. The giant sized scientist Bill
Foster, AKA Goliath, oversaw renovations that
turned the coastal property into a new base called
the Avengers compound. Rounding out the debut
roster was the feline heroine Greer Nelson, AKA
Tigra, a Chicago native who worked in a lab
undergoing secret conditioning experiments
that boosted her strength, speed and senses. She
was later transformed by a member of the Mystic Cat
people into the half human, half feline Tigra.
After establishing a career as a vigilante, she
auditioned for the Avengers, accepting
Hawkeye's call to help found the Pacific
Division. The West Coast Avengers first crime
fighting mission came when the thief called the
blank, fled a robbery with tech that accidentally
recalled the villain Graviton from exile.
Graviton tried to rip Los Angeles off its
foundations until the team brought him down. The
West Coasters then flew east in a Quinn jet to help
the original team stop the cosmic schemer
Maelstrom, proving the two branches could
operate side by side. Hank Pym, the original
Ant-Man, moved into the Avengers compound as its
resident scientist, while Wonder Man's brother,
the Grim Reaper, formed a new lethal legion with
Ultron and other villains. The legion ambushed
the compound and took the hero's captive, but
Mockingbird's surprise ambush distracted the
villains long enough for her teammates to break
free. The Reaper seemingly died in the fight and
Ultron retreated. James Rhodes soon revealed his
true identity in the Iron Man suit, after which the
recovered Tony Stark reclaimed to the armor and
roadie became War Machine. Tigra's increasingly
feral behavior attracted Craven the Hunter, who
stalked her across Hollywood backlots until the
Avengers drove him off. Soon afterward, the
team's newest member, a devout New Mexican hero,
Firebird, was hunted by the demon called Master
Pandemonium, intent on reclaiming shards of his
broken soul hidden within her. The Avengers
tracked the villain to the hidden realm of the cat
people, where Tigra bargained to merge her split
human and feline selves in return for
Pandemonium's death, a deal she later regretted.
The villain Dominus next lured the team to New
Mexico and used Dr. Doom's time platform to hurl
them backward through history. Mockingbird was
stranded in the 1800s, drugged by Phantom Rider,
into believing she loved him. The rest of the team
landed in ancient Egypt and clashed with Pharaoh
Rama Tut. The moon god Kahnchoo guided his modern
champion Moon Knight, Hank Pym and Firebird to
mount a rescue. After months of jumping through
time, the Avengers reunited, and Mockingbird let
her abuser fall to his death. Upon returning to the
present, the heroes defeated Dominus. A period of
governmental tension followed. The mystique's
federal squad, the Freedom Force, arrested both
Avengers branches on false trees and charges
devised by the Zodiac cartel. You can learn more
about mystique in her duel against Madame Rouge.
Soon after, Washington forced the unstable super
soldier, John Walker, aka US agent, onto the West
Coast roster as Field Leader. Hawkeye resigned in
protests, Mockingbird followed, and the pair
mentored the quirky Great Lakes Avengers.
Meanwhile, in the International Coalition
dismantled Vision for his past attempt to seize
global computer networks. Hank Pym rebuilt him,
now chalk white and emotionless, because Wonder
Man refused to lend his brain patterns a second
time. You can learn more about Vision in his duel
against Marsha Manhunter. Vision's blank slate
worsened Scarlet Witch's grief after her twin
sons, created by her magic, were reabsorbed into
the demon Mephisto. Manipulated by Magneto and
Time Master Amortus, she attacked her teammates
until Agatha Harkness restored her mind. Roster
Turnover continued as Spider Woman and the
electricity-powered Living Lightning joined
the team. Stark, battling health issues, faked
his death and ceded the team lead to War Machine.
Interstellar Conflict soon pulled the West Coast
roster back into space. When Kree soldiers used a
Stargate near Earth to attack the rival Shiar
Empire, both Avengers teams split into three
squads to keep the fight away from the sun. The West
Coast unit failed to stop Shiar Commandos from
stealing the Kree Negabands and a bomb made from
that energy killed billions in Kree's space. Some
members, led by Iron Man, executed the Kree
Supreme Intelligence for that genocide, a choice
that offended others and left deep scars between
teammates. Back on Earth, the Avengers roster
shifted again. Tigra, Hank Pym and the Wasp moved
to reserve status, letting US agent Spider Woman
and Living Lightning step into full membership.
Hawkeye and War Machine rejoined and the teenager
Darkhawk joined as a part-time player. Ultron
returned in adamantium form, infected Hawkeye,
Tigra and Quicksilver with techno-organic
implants and unveiled Alkama, a murderous bride
cloned from Mockingbird's mind. The Avengers
purged the implants and turned Ultron's own
missile against him and Alkama, apparently
destroying them both. Hank Mann, backed by demons
Satanish and Mephisto, formed another lethal
legion and struck the depleted West Coast
Avengers. In the Infernal fight, Mockingbird
sacrificed herself to save Scarlet Witch and she
died in Clint's arms. The Avengers compound lay in
ruins, membership had fallen and disputes were
constant. Captain America convened an all-hands
vote and led by Stark, the majority closed the West
Coast branch. Stark then formed a new team called
Forceworks with several West Coast alumni, but
that group collapsed within a year and most
members drifted back to the main Avengers. The
deserted Avengers compound later reopened as the
training campus for teenage heroes of Avengers
Academy. California still lacked frontline
defenders, however, so Kate Bishop, the second
Hawkeye, started a detective agency in Santa
Monica. When giant Landsharks rampaged along the
pier, she called Clint for backup and assembled a
fresh West Coast Avengers lineup, including the
dimension-hopping Miss America, the
energy-absorbing Fuse, the sarcastic telepath
Kid Omega, and the reality-warping Gwen Pool, who
adopted a baby Landshark named Jeff. Mademask
soon captured the rookies with her West Coast
Masters of Evil, but Kate's ex-boyfriend, Novar,
aka Marvel Boy, helped them escape. The team then
received new headquarters in Venice Beach.
During the dark Elf Lord Malekith's invasion of
Earth, Kate joined a babysitting squad guarding
Thor's infant sister, Lhasa, while her teammates
fought Frost Giants in San Francisco. Afterward,
Tony Stark and Rody organized a
rehabilitation-focused West Coast roster that
included longtime ally Spider Woman and veteran
hero Firestar. Their opening mission dismantled
a machine-based religious cult called the Gospel
of Ultrons, which was formed from the fragments of
Ultron. And that's the West Coast Avengers
history. For the seven-person roster going into
the team duel, I'll admit I was a little loose with
the official members. For starters, I did include
several of the founding West Coast Avengers
members, including War Machine, Wonder Man, and
Tigra. The Wasp was an early recruit to the team, so
I'm including her. Quicksilver was a later
recruit, but I've been dying to squeeze him in a
team duel and passed over our last X-Factor duel
just to have him here. For the final two spots, I'll
admit I'm going a little rogue and blurring the
lines between what constitutes a West Coast
Avenger and a regular Avenger. Black Panther has
never officially been part of the West Coast
roster, but he has fought alongside them. And
given that he's been a major player for the
Avengers over the years, I thought it best that I
include him in one of these team duels. The same
goes for Hercules, who again has never been an
official West Coast member, but is an Avenger
nevertheless, through and through. And frankly,
a lot of the other prominent West Coast Avengers
members have already been in team duels like
Hawkeye, Ant-Man, Scarlet Witch, and Vision were
with the main Avengers in their duel. Mockingbird
was with the A-Force, Moon Knight was with the
Defenders, US Agent was just with the
Thunderbolts. I could have gotten some reserve
members in here like Darkhawk or Firebird or
Living Lightning, but I thought it was better to go
with Black Panther and Hercules. Because now I
think you can say that most of the classic comic
Avengers have been in a team duel. So to reiterate,
my West Coast Avengers team is War Machine, Wonder
Man, TIGRA, The Wasp, Quicksilver, Black Panther
and Hercules. That may be most bored I've ever been
listening to one of your backstories. They don't
have a great backstory. It's not very thematic and
it's burdened by a lot of roster changes,
enclosures and things like that. At least the
roster is cool. I actually really like this
roster, even though it's not entirely faithful.
It is a good cast of Avengers characters, I would
say. Thank you. Thank you. Yeah, largely you went
with these characters also because of the
pairings with the JLI roster that you have in that
we like to keep things even between the teams by
pairing each individual character with a
counterpart from the other side, but I'll let you
get into the Justice League International roster
as you get into their history, which I'll do now.
Now, after the disbanding of the original Justice
League of America, a new United Nations backed
initiative formed a global peacekeeping
superhero team under the banner of the Justice
League. The league was reorganized with the
intention of operating internationally with
multiple embassies and government oversight.
Spearheaded by UN liaison Maxwell Lord, the new
team operated out of the embassies in New York
City, Moscow, Paris, London and Tokyo with their
primary headquarters in the secret sanctuary, a
former hidden headquarters of the Justice League
of America just outside of Happy Harbor, Rhode
Island. The initial roster consisted of a mix of
veteran heroes and newer recruits. Blue Beetle,
Booster Gold, Guy Gardner, the Green Lantern,
Martian Manhunter, Black Canary, Shazam, Dr.
Fate and Mr. Miracle, with Batman serving as a
guiding presence. Over time, the team added more
international members, such as Fire from Brazil,
Ice from Norway, Rocket Red from the Soviet Union
and the Crimson Fox from France. The group
developed a reputation for balancing world
threatening commissions with interpersonal
dysfunction and comedic tension, particularly
between characters like Guy Gardner and Booster
Gold. The team battled numerous global threats,
including a new royal flush gang and the
time-manipulating overmaster. They also
defended Earth from alien invasions and
collaborated with other superhero groups around
the world. As the organization grew, it fractured
into multiple branches. The main team continued
as Justice League International, while a
European branch was founded later under the name
Justice League Europe, operating out of a Chateau
in the Loré Valley of France. Justice League
Europe's roster eventually included elongated
men, metamorpho, power girl and Captain Adam.
Though the league enjoyed official recognition,
tensions arose with traditional US authorities
and internal conflicts began to weaken its unity.
Maxwell Lord increasingly manipulated the
team's direction behind the scenes, using his
influence and technology to control outcomes.
The team's operations took them across the globe,
from Japan to Bialia, a fictional Middle Eastern
country where they were often entangled in
political intrigue. In one mission, they stopped
the Queen Bee's attempt to create a mid-human
army. Another one took them to Apocalypse, where
Mr. Despite their successes, the team was often
mocked by the media as being more of a circus than a
serious force, a reputation not helped by the
personalities of its more flamboyant members.
Booster Gold and Blue Beetle, in particular,
developed a close friendship that became central
to the team's dynamic, often spearheading
care-brained business ventures and stunts that
caused both trouble and amusement for the group.
Over time, leadership changed hands. Batman
eventually left due to ideological differences
with Maxwell Lord. Captain Adam took a leadership
role for a time, while Martian Manhunter served as
a stabilizing presence. The league continued
operating internationally, but fractures
deepened when internal corruption was revealed.
Maxwell Lord was exposed for secretly
manipulating events using a computer system
called Kilgore. After being shot, Lord was
temporarily replaced by Oberon and later by other
UN appointees. The Justice League International
eventually disbanded. Some of its members
continued on with a newly reformed Justice League
of America, while others retired or pursued solo
missions. Years later, Maxwell Lord attempted to
rebrand his public image and reassemble a
smaller, more relatable superhero team. He
contacted several former members of the Justice
League International and convinced them to join a
new low-profile operation known as the Super
Buddies. Operating out of a strip mall office in
Queens, New York, the team included Blue Beetle,
Booster Gold, Fire, Elongated Man, his wife Sue
Dibney, and Captain Adam, along with Maxwell Lord
and Oberon as support staff. Later additions
included Mary Marvel and the magical chimpanzee
Detective Chimp. The Super Buddies focused on
local threats and public engagement. Their
operations were less about world saving and more
about improving their public image and
self-esteem. They tackled issues like hostage
situations and metahuman disputes, but often
found themselves overwhelmed or outmatched.
Despite the comedy and dysfunction that
surrounded the group, they genuinely tried to
help their community. At one point, the team was
kidnapped to hell by demons posing as
superheroes, forcing them to work together to
escape. In another incident, they were trapped
inside of a magical sitcom reality. The Super
Buddies eventually disbanded after realizing
they were not suited for full-time heroics. The
experience, however, deepened the bonds between
many of the original Justice League
International members and offered closure to
long-standing tensions within the group. After
the Super Buddies disbanded, several of its
members returned to mainstream superhero
activity. Maxwell Lord, who had remained
publicly dormant for years, resurfaced with
telepathic powers and a hidden agenda. Secretly
working to eliminate superhumans, he considered
dangerous. Lord reactivated a Brother Eye
satellite system and manipulated events to
incite distrust in metahuman. He covertly used
his powers to control minds, including that of
Superman, who he turned against the League in a
test of loyalty. Blue Beetle uncovered Maxwell's
plot, but was unable to stop him. When Blue Beetle
refused to join Lord's cause, he executed him with
a gunshot to the head. This act set off the events of
Infinite Crisis, during which Wonder Woman was
forced to kill Maxwell Lord to free Superman from
his control. The Justice League International
era was definitively closed with Blue Beetle's
death, and many of its surviving members were left
shaken and disillusioned. That is, until
post-Flashpoint continuity, when the United
Nations again sanctioned a global superhero team
after the public debut of the original Justice
League. This time the team was formed explicitly
as a counterbalance to the independent nature of
the main League, with government oversight as a
prerequisite. Maxwell Lord was replaced by UN
director Andre Briggs, who selected Booster Gold
as the team's leader due to his public appeal and
historical record. Their new base of operations
was the United Nations Hall of Justice, designed
as a diplomatic and operational headquarters
rather than a superhero hideout. The new lineup
included Booster Gold, Guy Gardner, Fire Ice,
Vixen, Gdiva, Red Rocket, and August General &
Iron. Batman joined the team as a representative
of the original Justice League, assigned to
ensure that the new team would not jeopardize
global security. While Booster was nominally in
charge, Batman frequently stepped in as a de facto
leader during crises. Their first major mission
involved stopping the signalmen, giant alien
constructs awakened by unknown forces. The
League worked to neutralize the signalmen's
threat and discovered their connection to an
ancient interdimensional force. Their success
led to an increase in public support, and the
United Nations promoted their visibility as a
deterrent against metahuman threats. The League
soon faced internal strain as Gdiva and Booster
clashed over leadership and media handling. The
Rocket Red's armor, erratic behavior, and the
August General's authoritarian tactics caused
tension. Despite this, the team held together and
responded to global emergencies including alien
incursions, terrorism, and environmental
disasters. During a mission in the country,
Derain, the team was ambushed by a group of
cybernetically enhanced assassins under the
employee of the villain Breakdown. Rocket Red was
mortally wounded and several team members were
critically injured. Booster Gold was briefly
presumed dead after sacrificing himself to stop a
bomb. This marked the effective end of the Justice
League International. The UN officially
disbanded the group, setting its high casualty
rate and public relations issues. Booster Gold
later appeared, displaced in time. This future
self-involved an ecober effort to prevent
catastrophic events tied to the multiverse.
While the Justice League International did not
officially reform, its surviving members
continued to collaborate during global crises
and crossover events, often setting their shared
past as a source of camaraderie and tactical
coordination. Now for the Justice League
International's seven-member roster, I decided
to start with the iconic members of Booster Gold,
the Blue Beetle Ted Cord, and the Green Lantern Guy
Gardner, as all three of them embody the often
comedic vibe of this Justice League iteration.
I've also included Elogated Man, as he was a
prominent member of both the Justice League
Europe and Super Buddies, and to include some true
international flavor, I'm including the duo of
Fire and Ice, from Brazil and Norway, with Fire and
Ice powers respectively. For my seventh and final
member, I decided to go with Shazam, who was not
only an original member, but his sister
Mary-Marvel also had a presence on the Super
Buddies team. So again, my roster is Booster Gold,
Blue Beetle, Green Lantern, Elogated Man, Fire,
Ice, and Shazam. I gotta say your team's history
didn't seem that much better, with multiple
iterations and closures and things like that.
Wow, rude. I will say that the Justice League
International does seem to have a more distinct
personality that separates it from the primary
Justice League. Yeah, it was definitely a much
more comedic tone than the primary Justice League
team, which was much more serious. Well, I don't
think the JLI is going to have much to laugh at as
they're getting their asses beat as we get into the
speculation here. I do want to state that the
pairings that we've decided for this matchup are
Blue Beetle and Black Panther, Booster Gold and
Wonder Man, Green Lantern and War Machine, Fire
and Tigra, Ice and Wasp, Elogated Man and
Quicksilver and Shazam and Hercules, which are
pretty damn good pairings, I think. Yeah, I think
this should be good. In a world where fantasies
collide and heroes clash, one podcast network
rises above the rest. Prepare yourself for the
ultimate showdowns in comic books, video games,
movies and anime. The Dynamite Podcast Network
presents Console Combat, where video game
legends brawl every Monday. Dynamic Duel, where
comic book titans smash every Tuesday. Max
Destruction, where TV and action heroes battle
every Wednesday. And Cendro World, where anime
champions clash every Thursday. Join us as we
speculate on the matches and armed with the power
of mathematical simulations, discover who will
emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
Now that we got the team's histories and rosters
out of the way, let's speculate on how one of the
thousands of simulated matches will go. The
winners determined by simulations, not our
speculation, but it's fun to imagine how this
fight could play out. AJ and I.K., what are the
rules of our speculation? Environmental
statistics are considered in my simulations. The
teams must earn victory on their own merit.
Alright then, let's get into it. The Justice
League International and the West Coast
Avengers, me on the battlefield, who goes first?
I'm gonna say I go first. I finally get to kick
things off with this Speedster character with
Quicksilver. And Quicksilver starts off by just
running circles around the Justice League and he
creates this vortex that sucks all the year away
from all of the Justice League members. And he
extinguishes fires, flames, and the Justice
League just passes out. No, I'm gonna say that
before everyone passes out, ice is going to freeze
the ground around them. Quicksilver to slip right
into a giant green hand raising the middle finger
that was generated by Guy Gardner. And actually, a
bunch of giant green hands and fists are going to
erupt beneath the Avengers, swatting and
slapping and punching them all across the
environment. Somebody saw Superman. Yeah, I did.
Okay, so the Avengers are getting knocked around
by these giant green hands, but suddenly I'm gonna
say Green Lantern gets a glowing green dagger
blade right through his chest. Because Black
Panther used his agility to avoid the hand
constructs, and then he chucked a green Vibranium
energy dagger at Green Lantern, and green means
it's set to stun. So Guy Gardner's stunned, he
falls forward, lands right on his face, and he's
passed out for the time being. And then War Machine
just starts unleashing his shoulder-mounted
minigun at Blue Beetle and Booster Gold, just
targeting between the two of them and turning them
into human Swiss cheese. Well, Booster Gold, you
know, he'll fire up his force field to protect
himself. And Blue Beetle, he's just gonna start
doing backflips to dodge the gunfire. And he's
gonna backflip onto a trapeze wire hanging below
his bug ship, which is gonna quickly retract up and
pull him into the ship before it fires this
electrified net onto War Machine, and that's
gonna pin him to the ground and just short-circuit
his suit. So while War Machine is busy dealing with
that, Booster Gold is gonna turn his attention to
Wonder Man, and he's gonna blast him with an energy
beam from his gauntlet. Who said you get the bug
ship during this fight? Me! I did! It's Blue
Beetle! I got it in the proler match! No, that's
right, that's right. Okay, so Booster Gold shoots
Wonder Man with an energy beam? Yes. I'm gonna say
before he gets that shot off, all of a sudden his arm
gets knocked away, and he misses. And he's like,
what, what just happened? So he tries again with
his other hand, and that gets knocked away too by
this small beam. Booster has no idea what's
happening, but then all of a sudden he gets fucking
rocked in the jaw with an uppercut, and it's the
wasp. And he didn't see her because she had shrunk
down, and she used her stink blasts to knock
Booster's arms off his aim, and then she gave him a
miniature sized uppercut, but still packed with
full-sized power. Oh, dank. Okay. Well,
meanwhile, Shuzam and Hercules, they're
probably wrestling, and Shuzam is like, you're
Hercules? I have all of your powers! And then some.
So with Hercules in a headlock, Shuzam's gonna
yell out his name, and he's gonna electrocute
Hercules with Azusa's lightning. Except at the
last second, Hercules maneuvers out of the
headlock, and he lifts Shuzam above his head just
as the lightning strike hits, which is gonna turn
Shuzam back into Billy Batson. And like, he didn't
know this was gonna happen, he just thought he'd
use Shuzam as a shield, but with Shuzam turned back
into a kid, Hercules is gonna spin the kid around,
swinging him by his ankles, and then just let go.
Billy like a discus over the horizon. Well, after
he threw Billy, I'm gonna say he didn't notice a
lightning strike in the distance where Billy was
thrown, and as Shuzam is racing back toward the
battle, fire and ice, meanwhile, are going to be
tag-teaming Tigra, just blasting her with both
waves of fire and freezing hail. Well, wouldn't
the fire melt the hail, and then the melted hail
would put out the fire? No. So like, fire and ice are
just cancelling their attack out, like a couple of
dumbasses, and Tigra is gonna leap high up into the
air, like way out of their blasts, and she's gonna
land with a pounce right on top of fire, just
slashing her face right off, and taking her out of
the match. Okay, here's the thing though, once
Tigra landed on fire, fire's whole body flamed up
like the human torch, so Tigra essentially just
sacrificed her body to eliminate fire, and with
her badly burned, it's gonna leave her wide open
for ice to just freeze her solid for killing her
best friend. So Tigra's out now too. All right, but
Wonder Man saw that, and he's pissed off by that, so
he just flicks ice in the head, and now ice is out of
the match too. Wait, what? A flick? Yeah, Wonder
Man's like insanely strong, so like a flick from
Wonder Man is like getting hit with a sledgehammer
to the dome, so yeah, ice is out. Okay, well while
that happened, Elongated Man noticed
Quicksilver has, you know, recovered from the
start of the match, and so he's going to flatten
himself out along the ground of the battlefield,
and as Quicksilver is zipping around, once he runs
over Elongated Man, that's when his trap is going
to spring, and he's folding his body around
Quicksilver just suffocating him. Elongated
Man's not gonna be able to easily restrain
Quicksilver, because Quicksilver, he's gonna
shake and vibrate to give himself some space
within Elongated Man's trap, kind of like a rubber
ball in a balloon type situation, and when he has
enough space, Quicksilver's gonna spin like a
cyclone with his arms out, and that's just like
putting Elongated Man in a blender. So Elongated
Man gets knocked around and twisted, and
eventually he's gonna get flung away like a limp
noodle, and just be on the ground reeling from
getting punched like a thousand times in like 10
seconds. And while he's recovering, War Machine,
he reboots his armor from getting short circuited
by Blue Beetle's net, and he's gonna cut his way out
of the net using a plasma cutter on his wrist, which
kind of looks like a welding tool. But at that
point, War Machine's gonna shoot Blue Beetle's
bug ship just right out of the air with a bunch of
missiles fired from his arm-mounted rocket
launcher. So the bug ship gets hit, and it's gonna
crash to the ground and explode, which kills Blue
Beetle who's inside. Oh no, because like the bug
ship would be alerting Blue Beetle that the
missiles are coming, so Blue Beetle he'll eject
from the bug ship right before it gets hit by the
missiles, and as he's parachuting back to the
battlefield, he's actually going to control and
steer the crashing bug ship using controls and his
gloves into Black Panther, and that's gonna
obliterate him. Okay, okay. But as Blue Beetle is
parachuting to the ground, all of a sudden this
sword comes flying out of nowhere through the air
right at him, and it's the sword of Pellius, which
is Hercules Sword, Hercules threw it, and it
severs Blue Beetle's parachute cords, and he
falls to his death. Jeez. Okay, meanwhile Booster
Gold, he's too distracted to notice his friend
Blue Beetle's death just now, because he's been
using his future tech goggles to try and find and
track what hit him earlier, the wasp, and when he
finally pinpoints her buzzing around the
battlefield, he's gonna trap her in a tractor
beam, pull her right into his fist, and that's
where he's gonna crush her literally like a bug.
Well she could just grow to get out of his fist. No,
no, because he uses his force field energy to
create tractor beams, so she can't grow out of
that. Can't grow out of a force field? Right, it's
like a hard light energy bubble. Okay, uh, well War
Machine, he's using his armor's flamethrowers to
just ignite elongated man, and now elongated
man's out of this match. But no, it's not like
elongated man would just sit still long enough for
flamethrowers to take him out. As War Machine is
trying to burn him to death, elongated man is
dodging and flipping and that's when Shazam is
gonna zip over to War Machine and in a blur, he's
gonna yank off all of his weapons and armor before
War Machine can really do anything about it. And
with Rody standing there armorless, that's when
Shazam's gonna grab him and just eat him right into
outer space. Jesus. Well, elongated man may be
able to dodge flamethrowers, sure, but he's not
gonna dodge this sudden beam of ionic energy from
Wonder Man who shoots it out of his eyes. So
elongated man gets two holes just punched through
his head and now he's out of the match for real this
time. Okay, well you know who else is out of the
match? Quicksilver, because green lantern is
gonna generate glue all over the environment
floor around Quicksilver and that's gonna slow
him down long enough for green lantern to just
snatch him with a giant pair of chopper cable
pliers and those are gonna be connected to a giant
green battery which just fries Quicksilver.
Okay, but then, hey look Black Panther slashes his
way out of the rubble of the bug ship that crashed on
him. What? I mean he has vibranium mesh suit, you
know, that would just absorb the impact and it's
gonna like super charge him. So he slashes his way
out of the rubble and he has a reed on green
lantern's energy signature from his first attack
against him. So he knows Green Lantern's
weakness, he knows to target the ring from his
Kimoyo bead readout and while Guy is distracted,
frying Quicksilver, Black Panther leaps over and
slashes off Green Lantern's ring with his claws
and before Guy can even react, Black Panther
straight up unalives the guy with a kinetic
powered explosive kick right to his ribs just
shattering them. Wait, Black Panther cut off
Guy's finger? Yeah, that was actually a good move.
Sucky but good. Thanks. But Guy's ring is going to
seek out a new ring bearer and it's gonna choose the
closest most worthy hero and I'm gonna say that's
gonna be, who do I have left? Booster Gold and
Shazam? I'm gonna say it's Booster Gold. So I guess
he's Booster Green now with the ring and so he's
gonna trap Wonder Man in this futuristic battery
with cables attached to his suit and Booster Gold
is going to absorb Wonder Man's ionic energy form
into his suit, powering it up so Wonder Man himself
is just dissipated and now charging up Booster
Green. That's crazy. So I have Black Panther and
Hercules left and Black Panther's going up
against Shazam which sounds kind of one-sided but
little does Shazam know that Black Panther has
been recording this entire fight with his Kimoyo
beads. So Black Panther slides under Shazam and
one of his beads acts like a speaker and it shouts
out in Billy's voice Shazam which is gonna call
down the lightning and it transforms Shazam back
into Billy again and just when Billy is like aw man
again that's when Black Panther nerve strikes the
kid to put him down. It's child abuse man. So you
have Black Panther and Hercules left? Well my last
guy, Booster Green, he's now super charged with
ionic energy and he's gonna have literally no
problem power boosting and converting his suit's
internal time travel technology to easily snap
the two Marvel guys right out of the time stream.
What? Boom two birds with one stone and the end of
this match. Can he do that? He can't transform his
technology with his power ring. He literally just
did but that's lame. I'm gonna say instead all of a
sudden Booster Green's ring turns purple. It
glows purple and cackles with this ionic energy
and it shoots out a Wonder Man construct except
Booster can't control it because Wonder Man's
immortal you know he can't be contained so he's
back like he usually comes back in the comics and in
his ionic form he grabs Booster in this bear hug
just crushing his suit's batteries and Booster's
spine. So Wonder Man's the only one left standing
and he also has this like cool purple lantern ring
to boot. I'm sorry what the fuck just happened? I'm
saying that Wonder Man can't be trapped within
this green lantern ring. Whatever apparently
Wonder Man is now a violet lantern of love weird.
You know I think he'd go with that he's kind of a
pacifist anyway. I'm gonna say fuck that and he
actually could be contained in Booster's suit
because it's from the future. You don't know what
kind of technology it is. It could contain ionic
energy. Then why didn't it? I'm saying it did
though. I guess we'll leave it there. Yeah let's
leave it there. We'll see a scenario happens
either Booster Gold is able to contain Wonder
Man's ionic energy form within his power battery
or Wonder Man can't be contained and snaps Booster
Gold into. Let's go ahead and input the team stats,
run the simulations, and come back with a winner.
A.J .9K hit it. Inputting data, running
calculations, processing results, simulations
complete. Oh this was a close one. This is pretty
good. This is actually closer than the Justice
League versus Avengers duel that we did way back
when. That one was a little bit lopsided in favor of
the Justice League but these guys were actually
paired up pretty damn well. Yeah I mean I had the
highest win rate of around 85% but I also had the
weakest character surprisingly who turned out to
be Ice. She won less than 20%. Yeah my guys weren't
too far off of that like War Machine won about three
fourths of all of his matches and Tigro won just
under one fourth of all her matches. But regarding
the teams as a whole I gotta say the Justice League
International trounced the West Coast Avengers
when it came to the category of range. Like you have
a lot of Blasty guys on your side with Booster Gold
and Green Lantern of course Fire and Ice, Shazam
shoots lightning, Blue Beetle has his own
blaster, Long-Aided Mannequin stretch but like
guys on my side like Hercules and Tigra, Wonder
Man, and Quicksilver they barely had any range.
Yeah Wonder Man can shoot Ionic energy but it's
rare. It's super rare super rare. The best thing
your team had going for it was actually strength.
Yeah I mean we have heavy hitters like Hercules,
Wonder Man, War Machine, even Tigra can lift about
10 tons. She's like Spider-Man level strength
whereas on your side you know elongated man's not
that strong neither are Fire and Ice neither is
Blue Beetle so the West Coast Avengers were able to
lay the smack down in that regard. But were they
able to lay the smack down overall or were they the
ones who in fact got the smacking? Who do you think
came out on top? It's gonna be close but I'm rooting
for the Avengers because of course I am. Well I have
to say Instagram disagrees with you by a lot. 75% of
our poll takers voted in favor of the Justice
League International. Well that's
disappointing. That's life get used to it. It's
full of disappointment for Marvel fans. Let's see
if they're right. AG9K the results please. Here
you are sir. All right the winner in the team duel
between the Justice League International and the
West Coast Avengers is the West Coast Avengers.
West side? That's right. West side is the best
side. Out of all the simulated matches between the
teams the West Coast Avengers won 506 matches over
the JLI's 494. They only won 12 more than the
Justice League? This is a coin toss then. If by coin
toss you mean the Justice League got that shit
kicked out of them by the Avengers then yeah coin
toss. If this was any other day you guys would have
lost. But not this day. Not this day. This is sweet
justice for the Avengers. The West Coast branch
was able to redeem the Avengers brand. They're
reclaiming the trophy from the Justice League and
we're just running victory laps all around the
fucking Justice League. I cannot even fathom
these results. Like there's no way the Avengers
would ever beat the Justice League. This is. I'm
sorry they just did by 12 whole matches. Like I feel
like I'm in an alternate reality right now. It's
like what's going on? Well let's be frank you
needed to be taken down off of your high horse
Jonathan after watching the Superman movie. Well
it's fine I'll just get back up on it after I'm
gloating at the Fantastic Forest failure. Marvel
all day every day Justice League sucks. You suck
personally and I want you to remember this
feeling. Already forgotten. But that does it for
this team dual AJ9K help close us out. Thanks for
listening to Dynamic Jewel. Visit the show's
website at dynamicjewel.com and follow us on
Instagram at dynamicjewel podcast. You can
support the show on Patreon at patreon.com slash
dynamicjewel and joining a tier that works for you
or by rating and reviewing dynamic dual on Apple
podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser or on our website.
Don't send Joe world and console combat. In our
next episode of course we will be reviewing the
latest MCU film to hit theaters the Fantastic Four
first steps. Not looking forward to it. Not hyped
at all. I hope it bombs and it's already projected
to open less than Superman which is freaking
awesome. No one can predict the future but that
does it for this episode. We want to give a big
thanks to our team. Josh Liner, Mike Williams,
Oscar Galvez and Paul Graves for helping make this
podcast possible. And we'll talk to you guys next
week. Up up and away true believers.