This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Alright guys,
the clock is ticking, the holidays are just weeks
away and if you still haven't finished your
shopping, now's the time to act. So head to
OldGlory.com where you'll find officially
licensed Marvel and DC shirts, hoodies and gear,
perfect for every fan on your list. They ship fast
but time's running out to get your gifts before the
holidays hit. So go now and use the promo code Duel
at checkout to save 15% off your entire order.
That's D-U-E-L at OldGlory.com because even
superheroes can't stop the holiday countdown.
Hi, welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by
comparing their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin
brother, Marvelous Joe. And there are only six
episodes of this podcast left. We're counting
down to our 10th anniversary and final episode and
in this one we are doing a duel between the
characters of Gypsy and Shadowcat. One was a
member of the Justice League during the Detroit
era and one is a mainstay of the X-Men. Yeah, it's
probably a crime that we've waited this long to get
to a kitty pride duel. But here we are and I cannot
wait for Shadowcat to beat the shit out of this DC
character that I've never even heard of. You've
never heard of Gypsy before? I have never heard of
Gypsy and I don't care to either. Well, I hate to
tell you this, but you're gonna hear about her in
this episode. Yeah, be grudgingly so though. I'm
gonna laugh when not only she beats Shadowcat,
kitty pride, but also becomes like your new
favorite DC character. That's asking for a lot.
We're gonna find out who's gonna win later on in
this episode. Before that, we're gonna break down
the comic book movie news from the past week of
which there is a doozy, probably one of the biggest
news items to come out in the 10 years of this
podcast and that is Netflix is set to buy Warner
Brothers and an $87 billion deal. Shut up. Shut up.
I don't want to hear it. As always, guys, we list our
segment times in our episode description, so feel
free to check out the show notes if you want to skip
ahead to a particular topic. Guys, our
artificially intelligent duel simulator, AJ9K
has a quick message for our listeners, so listen
up. Hello. These are the final episodes of Dynamic
Jules Weekly podcast, leading up to our grand
finale on January 20th. We hope you've enjoyed the
past 10 years of Marvel and DC Jules and reviews,
and we'd love for you to stick with us as we count
down these last episodes. We're inviting you, the
listener, to help us close out the show by visiting
dynamicjule.com over the next few weeks and
clicking the red microphone button in the bottom
right corner to leave us a voicemail that will play
during the final episode. Tell us what first got
you into DC or Marvel, how long you've been
listening, a favorite episode or moment or
anything else you want to share about what the
podcast has meant to you. Your messages will be
aired and responded to on the January 20th finale.
Again, head to dynamicjules.com and leave your
final message. We would love to hear from you. Pip
pip cheerio. Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone
who takes the time to call in and leave a voicemail.
Guys, be sure to tune into the other shows and the
Dynamite Podcast Network this week, including
the console combat podcast, where hosts John and
Dean simulate battles between popular video game
characters. In yesterday's episode, they found
out who'd win between the Arbiter, Thelva Dom from
Halo and Commander Shepard from Mass Effect. Over
on the Max Destruction podcast, hosts Scotty and
Gilly pay your favorite action heroes from film
and television against each other. On Thursday,
the Macho Twins are learning who would win in a
fight between major chip hazard from small
soldiers and Buzz Lightyear from Toy Story. And on
the Central World podcast, host Zachary Hepburn
speculates on fights between fan favorite anime
and manga characters. In his next episode, Zac is
revealing who would win between Shigio Kageyama,
aka Mob from Mob Psycho 100 and Tatsumaki, the
tornado of terror from One Punch Man. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our show
notes to listen to all of the shows in the Dynamite
podcast network. But with that out of the way,
quick to the No Prize. A No Prize is an award that
Marvel used to give out to fans. Our version, the
Dynamic Dual No Prize, is a digital award we post on
Instagram for the person that we feel gave the best
answer to our question of the week. Last week, we
asked you guys, what review episode of Dynamic
Dual did you get the most out of? And that was coming
off of the announcement that we had gotten through
all the reviews that we were going to before the
show's finale, at which point we're changing from
a weekly podcast. We got three answers. So let's go
ahead and run down our two honorable mentions as
well as the No Prize winner. Our first honorable
mention goes to CJ Kraft, who said, Hey guys, it's
CJ Kraft. And I think my favorite review you guys
have done has been Werewolf by Night. I remember
watching it and thinking I can't wait to see what
the Dynamic Dual guys have to say about this. And
you guys for the most part felt the same way I did
about it. Plus, it was just overall a good episode.
So it's going to suck to see you guys go, but I'll be
appreciative for any episodes we do again. Yeah,
Werewolf by Night was interesting to review
largely because it's one of the more unique pieces
of media that Marvel Studios have put out. You
know, it was a special presentation around
Halloween a couple years ago. And it's always, I
think, just more fun to review things that are
unique and special. Yeah, honestly, I'm
surprised Marvel hasn't done more with not only
those characters, but that format, the short film
format. I feel like they should be releasing a new
special presentation at least twice a year, at
least once a year. I would settle for that. I think
you're right, though. They seem easier to
produce. They're a great way to explore
unexplored areas of the Marvel universe. And it's
a great way to get creative and interesting with
the continuity. I can't wait to see Werewolf by
Night and Man Things show up again and Elsa
Bloodstone and another piece of media. Hopefully
they like show up in a midnight sun's movie or
something like that. But who knows when that'll
happen. Overall, I really loved that special
presentation and I'm glad CJ Kraft that you
enjoyed what we said about it. And I'm glad that you
felt the same way. Thanks CJ Kraft. Our next
honorable mention goes to Alex Albro, who said,
OK, hear me out. The Batman and Robin review. For
one, this is when the audio no prize answers were
first announced. So all of us calling in get
something out of this one. But I love this movie as a
kid and had no idea it had any issues. I'd watch it
multiple times a week and probably burned out the
VHS. Robin's costume was sick. The black and
silver costumes were sick. George Clooney is
Batman for me. I guess my mid 20s, I can see your
points on what's bad, but nostalgia hits hard.
This is the best Batman movie in the first DC movie
I've seen. All right, it looks like you got cut off
there and I'm not going to lie. This was the last
review I thought anyone would say was their
favorite. We just trashed the film. Basically, I
hadn't seen it in maybe decades prior, I think,
before reviewing it. And well, it may have some
nostalgic appeal. There's just way too many cod
pieces. Yeah, Jonathan has a threshold for how
many cod pieces he'll allow in a movie. I do. Yeah, I
remember actually getting flack from a few
listeners that we even reviewed Batman and Robin
because they're like, we all know this movie
sucks. Why are you wasting your time? And that was
the first time I think I mentioned to listeners
that the reason that Dynamic Duel started, its
primary purpose was to review all the Marvel and DC
films that had come out. And the whole dual
speculation thing kind of came across as an
afterthought of that, because we would always
argue about the battles. And then we were like, oh,
we could actually use math to kind of figure this
out. But yeah, the goal was to review these films,
whether they were good or bad. We were going to talk
about them. And I'm surprised that considering
when the movie came out and how old we were that we
don't actually have nostalgic value for Batman
and Robin, it was kind of like we just recognized it
as pretty damn bad, even as children. Well, it
wasn't the first Batman movie we saw. We grew up
with the 89 Batman film on VHS. So comparing it to
not only that, but also Batman Returns and Batman
Forever. It was easy to see that this was just so
different and just weird that. Yeah, it was it was
easy to not appreciate it. I think for people our
age. Yeah, it was when the critic version of
Jonathan first manifested at 11 years old.
Another cod piece, one star. Thanks for the
answer, Alex. But the winner of this week's No
Prize is Kev, who I think might be Kevin Odleon, a
longtime listener, but I'm not quite sure. I could
be wrong. But he said, hey, what's up, guys? This is
Kev. The review that I enjoyed the most from you all
was the Infinity War review. That's actually how I
found you guys. I was looking for a review on a movie
and I found you out. And that led me to listen to more
of your backlog. And yeah. Yeah, I think Infinity
War and Endgame really expanded the fan base a lot.
It was just such a great period of excitement to be a
Marvel Studios fan around that time that people
were just craving that content. I think we saw
pretty good growth in our listenership when those
two films came out because they were fucking
fantastic movies. We gave both of them five stars
and it was a lot of fun to just basically just gush
all over the movie in our review of it. Ew, you liked
the movies, too. I distinctly remember walking
out of the theater and like going up to Jonathan and
being like, I think that's our first five star
review. And he was like, damn it, you're right. I
don't think it was our first five star review, but I
do remember being like, yeah, this is like the
Empire Strikes Back of superhero films. We have to
give it five stars. Was the Dark Knight our first
five star review? Yeah, I think so. That sounds
about right. I'm not surprised that Infinity War
or Endgame was an answer for this week's question
of the week. I am surprised that no one called in
with the Joker review, though, because if I'm not
mistaken, that is our most listened to episode of
all time. Surprisingly, I think it's a toss up
between our Joker review and our Avengers Endgame
review, but that's only for Apple podcasts.
Honestly, I think your Joker review just confused
a lot of people because everybody was like, oh,
this movie is amazing. And you came out like, oh,
this movie made me uncomfortable. It did. It did.
How could it not? That was a fun one, though. That
was a fun episode for sure. So congrats to Kev for
winning this week's snow prize. In fact, that was
the very last snow prize that we'll be handing out
because for our last few episodes, we're really
hoping that you guys call in and give us a farewell
message that will air on our final episode. Just
let us know how long you've been listening. You
know, if you have a favorite episode or moment from
the show or anything else that you want to share
about dynamic duel and what it meant to you. And
unlike the question of the week answers, we're not
giving you 30 seconds to do it. We're giving you two
whole minutes. And don't forget to leave your name
when you call in by clicking on the red microphone
button in the bottom right hand corner of the
screen at dynamic duel.com. That'll prompt you to
leave us a voicemail. Again, your message could be
up to two minutes long, and we will play your
voicemail on our final episode. But now that
that's done on to the news. OK, last week, Netflix
announced its intention to acquire Warner
Brothers in a deal that was valued at
approximately eighty seven billion dollars,
making it the largest studio acquisition of all
time. Like Disney didn't pay that much for Fox. So
that's kind of cool in a way. Netflix, of course,
bid out Comcast and Paramount, who had also
expressed interest in acquiring Warner
Brothers, but they just couldn't match the number
that Netflix did. The deal, of course, is not
finalized, and it's going to require at least a
year of not only regulatory review, but also the
division of Warner Brothers Studios from
discoveries, televised content. But basically,
what Netflix wants to do is absorb Warner Brothers
film and television library, their major
franchises and production capabilities into its
streaming ecosystem. Early reporting is
indicating that Netflix is primarily
interested, of course, in Warner Brothers IP
assets and content pipeline, rather than its
physical operations, including DC Comics and its
publishing divisions or ancillary business
units. I don't think there's any doubt as to how
that would radically reshape Hollywood's and the
comic industry's landscape, because Netflix
will be consolidating one of the oldest studios
under what is currently the world's dominant
streaming platform, which, of course, will raise
significant questions about the future of
theatrical releases, legacy media operations
and divisions like DC Comics and Warner Brothers
Games. Now, I think it's been reported recently
that Netflix is, in fact, interested in including
Warner Brothers Games as part of its
acquisitions. But there's been little to no word
about DC Comics. And I'm not going to lie, it has me
really freaked out and pretty depressed. It's a
fortunate timing that we're ending this podcast
in a matter of weeks, because it seems like this is
the end of DC Comics in general. Like Marvel just
won, right, Jonathan? I mean, it kind of feels that
way. I'm not going to lie, because Netflix only
wants the DC intellectual property. It's
characters and its stories, not the comics
themselves, not the creators and not the legacy.
Because Netflix is a industry disruptor, who's
openly signaled that they don't want the whole
Warner Brothers machine, including the loss
making divisions that don't fit their business
model and would be left on the transactional
floor. Like Paramount was the only company that
was actually interested in acquiring all of
Warner Brothers assets. Can you explain what
Netflix's business model is as you understand it
and why that would not include DC Comics? So
Netflix is a content algorithm, not a creative
studio. And print comics wouldn't really survive
in that business model. You know where Hollywood
has artistic gatekeeping? Netflix just dumps
content to keep subscribers engaged. Things like
quality, tradition and legacy don't matter when
the only metric is subscriber retention. So
monthly comics, a niche, expensive medium would
have no place in that system. Right. There's no way
to put physical print comic books onto the Netflix
digital platform. I guess there is in the form of
digital comic books, but it's not clear at this
time as to whether or not Netflix would be
interested in actually putting digital comics on
their streamer. They might. And that's the only
way I think DC Comics survives in the medium of
comics, whether that's digital or print. I could
totally see Netflix wanting to put new kinds of
digital content on their platform just to keep
people subscribed or maybe even acquire
subscribers at a higher rate if they're offering
things like books or podcasts, maybe. But comic
books are such a small industry like DC Comics is
only a tiny fraction of Warner Brothers revenue.
It may even be a money loser if you look at the
purchasing transfer comics within the past 20, 30
years. And Netflix is not going to subsidize a
dying medium. Warner Brothers kept comics alive
to cultivate IP, but Netflix doesn't really need
that. They have cheaper R &D through algorithmic
data. And now AI comics have shrinking
readership, shrinking orders, high costs. And
I'm pretty sure Netflix's lawyers and
accountants when they're finalizing this deal
are just going to elect that and be like,
absolutely not. That's my theory. In what
scenarios do you see DC Comic Book surviving as a
print medium if this deal goes through? I think
superheroes like Batman and Superman will thrive
in streaming and animation. But like paper
comics, they're probably gone. Netflix, I
imagine, would have no motive to maintain
physical publishing. And digital only AI
assisted comics are going to be far cheaper and
easier to produce. So I think the DC stories will
continue, but printed DC Comics likely won't.
Unless, of course, Netflix does what they
currently do with Miller World Comics, which they
currently own, and that's license those
characters to currently Dark Horse Comics.
Previously, it was Image. That's right. Netflix
licenses the Miller World Comic Books to Dark
Horse, who then produces and then publishes those
comic books. Right. But it's not exactly like
Miller World is thriving under Netflix. Like Mark
Miller still has to go to Kickstarter to get his
comics funded. And the projects that actually
turned into shows for Netflix, like Jupiter's
Legacy, like Super Crooks, they only lasted one
season. So that's terrifying. What do you think is
the likelihood that Netflix will actually
license the DC characters to Marvel publishing?
Oh, fuck off. Fuck you. Who knows? That may be what
they end up doing, which would freaking kill me.
And I think all DC fans, who knows, maybe this means
that these crossover comics that we've been
getting between both publishers would be a more
regular occurrence. But there's no denying at
that point that Marvel will have, indeed, won the
comic book wars. And you have to admit that I will
admit nothing until the steal goes through and we
see what happens. Because right now this is still a
long way off and it may not even go through. There is
a lot of politicians, a lot of industry people who
are disparaging this acquisition. So that's
good. I hope it doesn't go through. I was much more
hoping that Comcast or Paramount would get Warner
Brothers because legacy means nothing to
Netflix. They don't care about fans. They care
about subscribers. And I think even if you are a fan
of DC Comics with high hopes for printed comics to
continue, that sentiment is not going to save DC
Comics. We've seen beloved institutions
collapse like Wizard Magazine, newspapers.
Marvel Comics almost died before being acquired
by Disney. And believing DC Comics will survive
forever ignores business reality. Netflix is
ruthless and unsentimental and laser focused on
what drives subscriptions. Print Comics are not a
part of that future. I hope I'm wrong, but I'm
afraid I'm not. Print Comics notwithstanding, I
guess there still is potential for Netflix to
produce some amazing television and film based
off of the DC intellectual property. Like we've
seen them produce Sandman, which you've rated
five stars. Very true. Very true. It may just be
that the primary medium for these characters is no
longer comics, but their stories are told through
television series or films, which would be pretty
cool. I will always miss the comics if, in fact,
they do go away. But what's interesting to me,
though, is that Netflix really doesn't have
experience with a cinematic universe. You know,
they have seasons of television. Like I'm not
familiar with any spinoff shows from Netflix. I
could be wrong. Do you think James Gunn will want to
work for Netflix? He may get a few projects funded
through them. But ultimately, I know a lot of
creators have come out against Netflix because
they don't get paid residuals, because
ultimately that content ends up on a streaming
platform forever with little to no viewership
data, or at least a data that's only proprietary to
Netflix. A lot of people don't get to see that. So I
know a lot of guilds will probably be upset by that,
and they'll probably fight against this. If this
deal does not go through, I'm really hoping that
either Paramount or Universal follow up with
another bid. But that may not happen because the
rumors are currently that Paramount is
interested in now acquiring Universal, so
they'll have no need for Warner Brothers. How did
we get here, man? How did DC Comics get here? Like,
what has it been like to be a DC fan throughout the
course of these past 10 years? Man, so when this
podcast first started, Time owned Warner
Brothers, like Time Magazine, the publishing
division. So they actually cared about creating
print published works like DC Comics. When AT &T
bought them in order to promote their internet
service, they really didn't know what they were
getting into. And that showed with all of the
mistakes that they made in handling the Hollywood
studio. They sort of offloaded it onto David
Zaslaw, who promised that he could flip the
studio. And I was hoping it was going to be to
Universal because he used to work for them. And now
that it's going to be Netflix, it just feels like so
many things are going to change. And I hate change.
This sucks. Ultimately, I blame the tech industry
because that's what I see Netflix ultimately as.
It's a tech giant in the same way that Amazon and
Apple are. And they're also getting into the
Hollywood game. It's just a weird time for movies,
for sure. And since Warner Brothers owns DC Comics
in the same way that Disney owns Marvel Comics,
it's affecting that industry as well, which damn
it. Jonathan, what do you say to people that think
you're being doom and gloom about this? Are they
right? Are you a little bit biased here? Or are you
being a realist? I've always been biased for DC. I
mean, it's not like I want this to happen. It's just
somewhat predictable, knowing Netflix. Now, it
could be surprised. Netflix's acquisition of
Warner Brothers may not be the death knell of DC
Comics. I actually hope it isn't, but only time
will tell. And I don't think Netflix has really
given us any reason to not be skeptical about what
this acquisition means for the publisher. Well,
we'll see how your conjecture pans out in, you
know, a couple of years time. We'll report back at
that time. No, we won't. This podcast will be over,
but we'll see how it goes. I wish this happened
after the podcast was over. So you wouldn't have to
talk about it at all. Yeah, this sucks. This sucks
big time. It literally keeps me up at night. Like we
said earlier, there's no question of the week for
this news item. Thank goodness. So let's go ahead
and move on to the main event. We'll find out who is
going to win between the Justice League, Detroit
member Gypsy and the X-Men member Shadowcat. All
right, Gypsy versus Shadowcats. These are two
young female characters that are a part of larger
teams. Gypsy being a part of the Justice League,
Detroit era and Shadowcat Kitty Pryde being a part
of the X-Men. The characters have similar power
sets in that they're all about evasion, I guess you
could say. Yeah, Shadowcat can render herself
intangible in order to phase through solid
matter, making her extremely difficult to hit.
And Gypsy creates mental illusions or something
like that. Well, specifically to turn herself
invisible. She creates illusions that surround
her so that she can't be seen by human senses, by
electronics, by telepaths, anybody. What kind of
offensive ability is that? Does she create these
mental illusions in the same way that like
Mastermind does in the X-Men books? Well, I would
say they're as large scale as Masterminds because
Masterminds could immerse someone completely in
an illusion. Whereas Gypsy really just covers
herself, though later on in the comics she was able
to envelop like a vehicle that she was in as well or
people surrounding her. So how is being really
good at hide and seek a superpower? I feel like I
could not fight crime with that ability. Well,
you're going to learn later on what I break down the
character just exactly how she uses this ability
offensively. Yeah, I'm curious. I think a lot more
people are familiar with Kitty Pryde, Shadowcat.
She was in the first three X-Men films as well as
X-Men Days of Future Past. She was played by Elliot
Page for X-Men 3 and also in Days of Future Past. And
Gypsy has been in nothing. I don't even think she's
been in any of the cartoons. No, she's been in the
cartoons and she was also a love interest of sorts
for Cisco Ramon vibe in the Flash television
series. You don't know shit. Apparently I don't.
Well, at least you admit it. Now, to explain the
methodology behind our duels, let's go to our
sentient dual simulator, Alfred Jarvis 9000.
AJ9K tell our listeners how you go about
determining a winner in our dual matchups. Yes, of
course, sir. The way I determine a winner between
the contestants is by running one thousand Monte
Carlo simulations using the characters
statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation is a
probabilistic model used to determine outcomes
through random sampling. In this case, I
randomize the statistics along a normal
distribution as a way to simulate the many
variables that can occur during battle. The stat
parameters are based on the official Marvel power
grid from which the DC characters statistics are
extrapolated. Additional stat categories are
included such as range, damage potential,
versatility and perception in order to create a
more detailed and accurate simulation. The
results of the one thousand simulations provide a
percentage of wins for each character. The
contestant with the higher percentage is
declared the victor as they have a higher
probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither character should win
100 percent of the matches. The comic book stories
have shown that there's even a way for Batman to
defeat Superman. So the confidence rate of my
method falls in line with the precedents that have
been established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor a fan vote is tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks, AJ9K.
Before we run the simulations, though, we like to
break down each character's histories and
abilities before improvising a scenario on how we
imagine one of the one thousand simulations would
play out beat for beat. And it's my turn to go first
with the DC characters backstory. So let me tell
you all about Gypsy. Cynthia Cindy Reynolds was
born to Edward and June Reynolds in a quiet
Midwestern suburb. For several years, her family
life was stable, though after her younger brother
was born, arguments arose between her parents
escalating into a pattern of shouting,
resentment, neglect, and eventually physical
abuse against Cindy. During this period of
stress, her metahuman abilities surfaced,
telepathically rooted illusions that bent
perception, allowing her to blend perfectly into
her surroundings, shift her appearance or
obscure her presence entirely. By age 14, Cindy
decided to run away, buying a one-way ticket to
Detroit. Alone in the inner city, Cindy used her
powers for basic survival, slipping unseen
through alleyways and storefronts, hiding from
threats and stealing food when necessary. Word
spread of a barefoot Bohemian girl who could
vanish into the walls, and Cindy gradually
adopted the street identity of Gypsy. Cameron
Street became her informal territory, where she
learned to refine her abilities through constant
exposure to danger and remained hidden from both
criminals and authorities. When the Justice
League relocated to Detroit following the
dissolution of the prior team, Gypsy infiltrated
their new headquarters repeatedly, testing its
defenses and slipping past visual detection,
electronic systems, and even Martian
Manhunter's telepathy. Her existence became
undeniable only when she intervened during the
league's confrontation with the Obermaster and
his cadre. With her help, Obermaster was
defeated, prompting the league to offer her
official membership. You can learn more about the
Justice League in our Justice League vs. Avengers
Team Duel episode. Gypsy trained alongside
Steel, Vibe, Vixen, Zatanna, and Martian
Manhunter as part of the Detroit League's roster.
She refined her agility, acrobatics, and combat
skills, and grew more confident in using her
illusion casting offensively. During a
wilderness retreat intended to build teamwork,
the royal flesh gang ambushed the league. While
hiding, Gypsy was able to use her telepathy to
project an astral form to track down the league.
Before disappearing, emotionally devastated,
Gypsy attempted reconciliation with her family.
Eventually, the telepathed Disparo, who was
hunting Justice League members, located Gypsy
and murdered her parents. He would have killed her
as well, if not for the intervention of Martian
Manhunter, who arrived in time to drive Disparo
off. You can learn more about Disparo and Martian
Manhunter in their duels against the high
evolutionary and vision, respectively. With her
family gone, Gypsy accepted Boostergold's
recruitment into the conglomerate, a corporate
sponsored hero team. Though she contributed
significantly to their missions, the emotional
aftermath of her parents' deaths eventually
pushed her to leave the group. Gypsy later joined
the Justice League Task Force, where she
developed a close partnership with Martian
Manhunter. They worked together on missions
requiring infiltration, psychological
disruption, or precision stealth. Early in her
Task Force career, Gypsy was nearly forced into
combat with Lady Shiva during a tense operation,
but avoided the confrontation. On another
mission, she suffered catastrophic injuries and
was believed dead, though Martian Manhunter
invoked Khran Mir. The Martian got a fire and a
transformation, successfully restoring Gypsy
to life. As the Task Force restructured, Gypsy
remained a central member, undertaking covert
operations across multiple countries, until the
team eventually disbanded. Gypsy continued
working intermittently with Martian Manhunter
and assisted the Justice League during major
supernatural or large-scale threats, even
participating in operations supporting Wonder
Woman in battles against Cersei and her forces.
After being recruited by Barbara Gordon, Gypsy
next joined the Birds of Prey, which you can learn
more about in their duel against A-Force. Oracle
relied on her as an invisible operative capable of
infiltrating spaces unseen by cameras, guards,
or enhanced senses. Gypsy's powers had grown to
allow her to extend illusions across wide areas,
cloaking entire rooms, vehicles, or strike
teams. During this period, she partnered with
Vixen to resolve a long-running case involving
Amos Fortune and helped rescue Stargirl when
Fortune targeted Justice Society members. Gypsy
was later abducted by the Clock King and forced to
fight in the Dark Side Club's Gladiator Arena,
where she was defeated early in the tournament, be
freed once the arena was later dismantled. In
post-Flashpoint continuity, a new Gypsy
emerged, named Cynthia Mordeth, the daughter of
Quell Mordeth, who ruled an extra-dimensional
realm inhabited by nomadic travelers who moved
between dimensions and absorbed multiversal
energy. As Quell Mordeth's heir, Cynthia
possessed innate illusion-casting powers,
augmented by her ability to store and channel
dimensional energy. Rejecting her father's
oppressive role, Cynthia attempted to flee her
native dimension, but became separated from her
traveling family during a transit jump. She
emerged alone on Earth, where Argus agents
intercepted her. Mistaking her arrival for a
precursor to invasion, they imprisoned her in a
secure vault. She remained confined until
rupture. Another traveler from her dimension and
the brother of Cisco Ramone arrived on Earth. His
incursion broke her containment, drawing
Cynthia into conflict with her father's forces,
operating covertly across dimensions. You can
learn more about Cisco in our Vibe vs Miss America
dual episode. Because this new Gypsy's powers
incorporated both magical and
extra-dimensional aspects, she could absorb and
redirect dimensional energy to enhance her
abilities or shield herself. She participated in
several encounters involving Argus, rupture,
and breaches between dimensions tied to her
father's influence. When the defeat of the
multiversal threat from the Batman who laughs led
to the restructuring of the multiverse, the
original Gypsy, Cindy Reynolds, was restored to
continuity. And that's her history so far.
Powers-wise, Gypsy casts illusions that bend
perception, allowing her to render herself
invisible against shifting backgrounds or
project fear-based hallucinations into
opponents' minds. She can disguise herself as
individuals of similar size and can extend her
cloaking to nearby allies, objects, or even
moving vehicles. She possesses limited
precognition and can project an astral form to
observe from afar, and is a trained combatant,
acrobat, and stealth operative. That's Gypsy.
Okay, so she's less offensive and more of like a
spy. She's like the ultimate spy. Yeah, you could
say that. There was a time when she was a member of
Justice League Task Force, where she wore like
Romani armor and carried a scimitar, but it was
very short-lived. Actually, there was a time when
Shadowcat carried a Katana sword because she's
trained in Kenjutsu. Or I guess it's not a Katana
because that was a samurai weapon. It was like a
Ninjado or something. Interesting. Okay.
Depending on how offensive Gypsy was, I was
thinking about bringing Lockheed into this match
largely because he almost always accompanies
Kitty Pride. I'm sorry, did you let me have Skeets
in the booster gold duel? I mean, there's nothing
that Skeets could do that booster gold couldn't.
Okay, if you're including Lockheed, how are we
going to account for him in the stats though? By
giving Kitty Pride an extra range boost. Okay.
Yeah. Fuck off. You don't get him. Fine. All right,
all right. But if I lose, I'm blaming you. I'm
totally okay with that. Blame me for all of your
losses. You know, Kitty Pride's gonna be able to
hold her own though. Let me go ahead and get into her
backstory. Catherine Kitty Pride was born in
Deerfield, Illinois, where at age 13, her
emerging mutant power caused intense headaches.
However, she developed the ability to become
intangible and pass through solid matter called
phasing. Both Professor Charles Xavier and Emma
Frost sought to recruit her to their respective
schools. Though their meeting was cut short when
Frost's armored mercenaries attacked, forcing
Kitty to evade capture and contact the X-Men.
Phoenix then altered Kitty's parents' memories
so they would allow her to enroll at Xavier school.
Kitty became the youngest X-Men and took the code
name Sprite, forming close ties with Storm,
Wolverine, Nightcrawler, and Colossus, while
also befriending Magic. You can learn more about
the X-Men in their duel against the Titans. Early
in Kitty's time with the X-Men, her older self from
an alternate future briefly possessed her body to
prevent the assassination of an anti-muteant
politician named Senator Robert Kelly, whose
death would have led to a post-apocalyptic
timeline called the Days of Future Past. Kitty
went on to defeat Ingari demons, get abducted by
the mutant Caliban, and narrowly survive a
confrontation with Magneto that forced him to
reconsider his increasingly violent methods.
Kitty's parents later transferred her to Emma
Frost's Massachusetts Academy, where she became
embroiled in Emma's attempt to infiltrate the
X-Men before ultimately returning to Xavier
school. You can learn more about Emma Frost in our
Poison Ivy vs White Queen duel episode. During the
X-Men's imprisonment by the parasitic alien race
known as the Brood, Kitty encountered the small
alien dragon Lockheed who followed her to Earth
and became her loyal companion. Xavier attempted
to place Kitty with the new mutants team, but after
she fought off an alien threat with Lockheed's
help, he reinstated her as an X-Man. You can learn
more about the new mutants in their duel against
the Legion of Superheroes. Kitty and Colossus
developed a tentative romance, but their
relationship ended when Colossus admitted he had
fallen in love with another woman. Kitty then
found comfort in her friendship with Cypher,
though they never pursued a relationship.
Visiting her father in Japan led to Kitty's
capture by Ogan, who is Wolverine's former
martial arts master and whose psychic
conditioning forced her to believe she was his
ninja apprentice. After Wolverine helped her
break Ogan's influence through harsh training,
Kitty defeated Ogan alongside Wolverine and
returned to the X-Men, adopting the new code name
Shadowcat. During the Marauder's massacre of a
group of underground mutants known as Morlocks,
Kitty was struck by an energy weapon that left her
unable to regain full solidity. A joint effort by
the Fantastic Four and Dr. Doom restored Kitty to
stability, though she needed concentration to
remain tangible. While recovering, she and
Nightcrawler saw televised footage of the X-Men
apparently sacrificing themselves in a battle
with the demon known as the adversary, prompting
Kitty and Nightcrawler to help form the team
Excalibur in London alongside Captain Britain.
You can learn more about Captain Britain in his
duel against Uncle Sam. With Excalibur, Kitty
fought Mojo's war wolves, helped rescue Rachel
Summers, and entered a relationship with her
teammate Pete Wisdom. Kitty was later recruited
by the International Intelligence
Organization's Shield to repair the
Helicarrier's malfunctioning computers.
There, she discovered that Ogan's spirit had
infiltrated the system, which she purged with
Wolverine's help. Tensions eventually ended her
relationship with Pete Wisdom, and after
Excalibur disbanded, Kitty returned to the
X-Men, who had returned. A visit to the mutant
nation of Genotian profoundly affected Kitty,
and after Colossus seemingly died curing the
Legacy Virus, she saw a normal life studying at the
University of Chicago. She became involved in
conflicts with anti-mutant groups such as
Purity, and helped repel a new wave of sentinels
led by Nimrod, whom you can learn more about in our
Amazo vs. Bastion duel. Kitty later joined
Storm's Extreme X-Men squad, and confronted
threats including William Striker and Lord
Imperial, before accepting Cyclops's
invitation to rejoin the main X-Men team at the
Xavier Institute despite her uneasiness toward
Emerfrost. On one of her first missions back,
Kitty discovered that Colossus was alive, having
been experimented on after his apparent death by
an alien from Breakworld. The two reconciled and
resumed their relationship. Later, Professor
X's twin Cassandra Nova manipulated Kitty's
mind, making her believe she had a child who had
been taken captive, causing Kitty to free
Cassandra Nova's consciousness from
imprisonment. Afterward, the X-Men were
abducted by the extraterrestrial intelligence
agency, Sword, and they were taken to Breakworld.
There, Kitty phased into a massive bullet that was
fired at Earth, and unable to escape it, she phased
the whole bullet through the planet, saving
Earth, but remained stuck inside it as it hurtled
through space. Magneto later tracked and
redirected the bullet, pulling Kitty safely back
to Earth, though she remained stuck in an
intangible, speechless state. She was later
fully restored after a Breakworld alien ritual
revived her and stabilized her powers. Kitty then
accompanied Colossus and Magic to the Crimson
Cosmos, where Colossus became Sidorok's new
juggernaut, prompting Kitty to end their
rekindled relationship. You can learn more about
this in our Metal Man vs Colossus Duel. When
Wolverine founded a new mutant school in
opposition to Cyclops's militarization of the
X-Men, Kitty joined him as Headmistress. There,
she endured a brood infestation that masqueraded
as a sudden pregnancy, but she was able to remove
the alien parasite. She later mentored the
time-displaced original X-Men brought to the
present by Beast, but disagreements over how the
teenagers should be handled led Kitty to leave
Wolverine school and join Cyclops's Renegade
team, where she worked closely with the young Jean
Grey. During Jean's kidnapping by the Shiar Alien
race, Kitty collaborated with the Guardians of
the Galaxy, beginning a romance with Peter Quill,
aka Star-Lord. Kitty traveled to space and
rescued Quill from the Slaughter Lords, helping
steal a cosmic artifact known as the Black Vortex.
After the artifact changed hands repeatedly,
Kitty submitted to its power so she could phase the
entire planet's Spartax and its population from
captivity. Star-Lord proposed to Kitty
afterward, and she accepted. As Quill became the
King of Spartax, Kitty struggled with his growing
responsibilities and eventually took on the
mantle of Star-Lord herself. Their relationship
deteriorated until both were captured by the
Collector and forced to confront their
unresolved conflict, reconciling before
returning to the Guardians. Kitty later fought
the Kree accuser Hala, liberated prisoners on a
Pudun world, and assisted Earth's heroes during a
conflict between Iron Man and Captain Marvel,
before choosing to separate from Quill and leave
the Guardians of the Galaxy. You can learn more
about that team in their duel against Doom Patrol.
Back on Earth, Kitty settled briefly in Chicago
before Storm convinced her to rejoin the X-Men as
their leader. She moved the mansion to Central
Park, oversaw a restructured team, and rekindled
her relationship with Colossus, ultimately
proposing to him. However, Kitty left Colossus at
the altar, recognizing their volatile history
was not a foundation for marriage. When the mutant
nation of Kakao formed, Kitty discovered she
alone could not use its organic gateways.
Displaced from mutant society, she adopted the
name Kate and accepted Emma Frost's offer to serve
as the Red Queen of the Hellfire Trading Company,
taking to the high seas and leading the Marauders
to liberate mutants worldwide. Sebastian Shaw,
former leader of the Hellfire Club, was
threatened by Kate's influence and arranged to
have her drowned. Resurrection through Kakao
proved unusually difficult in Kate's case, but
with Emma's intervention, she returned, helped
defeat and politically neutralize Shaw, and
continued defending mutants. You can learn more
about Sebastian Shaw in his duel against Vandal
Savage. During a catastrophic attack on Kakao,
the anti-muent organization Orgis sabotaged the
island's systems and forced Professor Xavier to
evacuate mutants through the Kakao gateways,
only for the population to vanish to a pocket
reality due to Orgis' interference. Kate managed
to avoid capture and rebranded herself as
Shadowcat, Cat with a K. She conducted lethal
covert operations against Orgis, later joining a
small strike team that continued resisting until
Orgis' eventual defeat. With the conflict over,
she returned to Chicago, where a young mutant
inspired her to re-embrace her cheerful nature
and go back to her nickname Kitty instead of Kate.
Powers-wise, Shadowcat, with a K, has the ability
to phase through matter by rendering herself or
any part of herself intangible. She can extend
this intangibility to anyone or anything in her
immediate proximity, allowing whatever she
touches to phase as well. While phased inside
solid matter, she is decoupled from gravity and
inertia, allowing her to sink or rise through the
matter freely. A limitation on her intangibility
is that it is harder for her to phase through
extremely dense matter, for example, phasing
through adamantium makes her sick. She is also
unable to phase through mystical energies or
electromagnetic energy such as radiation,
electricity, or microwaves. However, this
allows her to disrupt electronic devices while
phasing through them, as well as a person's
nervous system, causing anything from shock to
unconsciousness in her enemies. She can also
partially phase, becoming just dense enough to
affect a person's internal states. She can also
phase out of sync with Earth's rotation, allowing
her to travel due west at a rate of approximately
1000 miles per hour at the equator, down to around
500 miles per hour in the mainland United States.
While tangible, her mind is immune to telepathy.
She is also an expert in computer science and a
Wait, she is immune to telepathy? When
intangible, yes. I don't know how that is going to
affect this particular battle, but I guess we will
play it out and see how that goes. Well, Gypsy is a
telepath, but her power affects all senses, not
just telepathic ones. I mean, she simulates
senses through the person's brain through
telepathy, how I figure it works. I don't know how
it works. I don't think it's that though. Okay,
okay. Let's find out. All right, guys, the clock is
ticking. The holidays are just weeks away, and if
you still haven't finished your shopping, now's
the time to act. So head to oldglory.com, where
you'll find officially licensed Marvel and DC
shirts, hoodies and gear. Perfect for every fan on
your list. They ship fast, but time's running out
to get your gifts before the holidays hit. So go now
and use the promo code dual at checkout to save 15%
off your entire order. That's D U E L at
oldglory.com, because even superheroes can't
stop the holiday countdown. Well, now that we've
got their histories and abilities out of the way,
let's speculate on how one of the 1000 simulated
matches will go. The winner is determined by
simulations, not this speculation, but it's fun
to imagine how this fight could play out. AJ9K,
what are the rules of speculation? Well, I should
say there are no rules other than the characters
have no prior knowledge of the other going into the
fight. All they are aware of starting out is that
the other character is a threat that needs to be
eliminated. For the speculation, the
contestants will begin approximately 50 meters
apart in a nondescript environment that will have
no bearing on the match itself, as no
environmental statistics are considered in my
simulations. The contestants must earn victory
on their own merit. Alright, then let's get into
it. Gypsy and Shadowcat meet on the battlefield.
Who goes first? I say Shadowcat is gonna start
first by phasing into the ground beneath her, so
she's intangible. That means Gypsy can't see her
and she can't also psychically influence her, so
Gypsy can't do jack shit. Okay, well, what are
Shadowcat's senses like underground? Uh, well,
her vision is obscured and her hearing would be
dulled, and her smell would also be dulled, and
like she has to hold her breath while phased
through solid matter because there's no oxygen
there, and that limits the time that she can spend
within solid matter. So not great. We'll say not
great. Alright, I guess I'll just fucking wait for
her to come back up to the surface then, because
when she does, she's not gonna see Gypsy anywhere,
because Gypsy goes invisible. Well, uh, like
assuming Gypsy didn't move after Shadowcat went
underground, Shadowcat leaps from out of the
ground with a ninja kick that busts Gypsy right in
the nose, blurring her vision. Ah, damn, sorry.
Gypsy did in fact move because she's not an idiot,
so Shadowcat literally kicks air and, you know,
she awkwardly lands. That's when her legs are
gonna get swept out from under her by Gypsy, still
invisible, and Shadowcat is gonna land on her
head, knocking her out. Sorry to tell you, only the
soles of Shadowcat's feet were tangible as she
landed. The rest of her was intangible, so when
Gypsy tries to sweep the leg, she just gets nothing
but air. And after that big ol' whiff, Shadowcat's
able to detect Gypsy's invisible leg going
through her, and therefore she's able to
determine her location. So using that, Shadowcat
leaps through Gypsy's body, disrupting the
electrical signals in her nervous system, and
causing her to become visible, and also barf her
brains out. And like when Gypsy's bent over,
puking, Shadowcat just punts her right in the
throat. Dang. Okay, well that will cause puke to
spray all over Shadowcat as Gypsy gets knocked
away by the kick. No, no, no, the puke just goes
right through Shadowcat, okay? And since Gypsy's
still visible, Shadowcat's gonna follow up with
this front flip drop heel kick. It's called a
rolling thunder kick, and that's just gonna knock
Gypsy the fuck out. Like, she's gonna be
unconscious after a kick like that. Except that
the Gypsy that Shadowcat attacked was an
illusion. The real Gypsy, you know, got her
bearings and rolled away to recover while leaving
a decoy projection of herself, so Shadowcat just
lands on the ground really hard. And since her body
was fully tangible to lend weight to her attack,
Shadowcat receives the full brunt of Gypsy's own
running drop kick right as she lands. No, that foot
would just go right through Shadowcat. Fuck you.
No, it doesn't. Okay, let's say Gypsy does land a
kick on Shadowcat. Big deal, it's not gonna happen
again. Like, Gypsy would probably try to follow up
with another hit, and that one would go right
through Shadowcat. So Gypsy would be thrown off
balance, and that would leave her open for
Shadowcat to again, except this time she takes one
of Gypsy's eyeballs with her, just phases it right
out of her skull. Actually, before she could do
that, Shadowcat is gonna stop short when she sees
that Gypsy suddenly is like a fucking vampire
zombie swamp monster, which is an illusion, of
course, but Shadowcat's gonna get so freaked out
by this, so shocked that she's gonna fault her and
become tangible, giving Gypsy just enough time to
do like a palm strike right to Shadowcat's solar
plexus. Except the palm goes right through
Shadowcat. You bitch. Okay, fine. Gypsy knocks
the wind out of Shadowcat, so Shadowcat's gonna
fall over, but she's just gonna fall into the
ground again to recover. And then she's gonna
launch out of the ground again with an uppercut
that phases Gypsy's heart right out of her chest.
Fatality. Match over, Shadowcat wins. No, no, no,
because Gypsy has limited precognition. That
actually helps her perfect her illusion casting
ability in like chaotic environments. So Gypsy
saw this coming, and she's just gonna step out of
the way, grab Shadowcat's tangible fist, and just
flip her back onto the ground in this really
powerful slam, when strong enough that it
straight up knocks Shadowcat out, giving Gypsy
the win. Now, Shadowcat just phases into the
ground again. I will cut you. This, this is exactly
why we waited so long to do a kitty pride duel. Well,
maybe instead of phasing into the ground, all of a
sudden Shadowcat phases out of sync with the
earth, so that all of a sudden Gypsy gets flung at
like 500 miles per hour due west alongside kitty
pride, and like just gets fucking thrown that way.
Did you not hear me say she has precognition? I'm
pretty sure I said that. That's fair. We could go
ahead and leave the duel there. Either Shadowcat
takes Gypsy out by phasing her heart out of her
chest, or Gypsy sees this coming and slams her to
the ground, knocking Shadowcat unconscious. Not
gonna lie, one of those endings is a lot cooler than
the other. We'll go ahead and input their stats,
run the simulations, and come back with a winner. A
G9K? Hit it! Alright, this was a very tricky
speculation to do, largely because both of these
characters are so defensive within their power
set that we quickly, I feel like, ran out of ideas on
how they could attack each other. This is one of the
reasons why you should let me include Lockheed in
this duel No, sorry, Lockheed is not Shadowcat.
Shadowcat is Shadowcat. So she was the only one you
got in this duel. I do think it would have spiced
things up a little bit because Gypsy and Shadowcat
weren't too impressive statistically when it
came to things like damage level, or strength, or
durability. They were hella evasive. Shadowcat
is faster than Gypsy, but only when going due west.
We said when they came to fighting skill, they were
even, and also versatility, which is not
surprising because they're both kind of
one-trick ponies. I was surprised that Gypsy was
as good of a fighter as Shadowcat. Dude, yeah, she
trained under Bronze Tiger. Is that more
impressive than training under Wolverine? Hell
yeah, bro. Hell yeah. Now, in addition to speed,
Shadowcat also got the edge when it came to
intellect and evasiveness, but only because it's
harder to hit someone who's intangible than
someone who's invisible. But Gypsy got the edge
when it came to perception, considering she's a
telepath. And she also has limited precognition.
And could observe things from afar with her astral
projection, which is why she also got a slight
range advantage, also considering that she could
project her illusions to encompass like a room. So
taking all of this into consideration, Joseph,
who do you think came out on top in this match?
Shadowcat, because I don't care how invisible
Gypsy goes, she's not going to be able to touch
Shadowcat. You think so, huh? Yeah. And Instagram
agrees with me. 67%, literally two-thirds of our
poll takers have cited with Shadowcat. And I got to
say, it's about damn time that they sided with the
Marvel character. And yet we all know this is
because Shadowcat has been in the movies. And the
Instagram poll is much more of a popularity
contest, rather than an evaluation of the
character's stats. Yeah, Shadowcat's been
better represented in the media, and is just
generally a better character overall, is what
you're saying? Yes. The Instagram poll takers
know this. But will that result in a win? Let's find
out. AJ9K, the results, please. Here you are, sir.
The winner of the matchup between Gypsy and
Shadowcat is Shadowcat. Of course, I feel like I
barely have to celebrate this. It was obvious from
the start. It was not obvious. What are you talking
about? I totally thought Gypsy was going to come
ahead in this. Shadowcat won an even 560 out of the
1000 matches, or 56% of the time, compared to
Gypsy, who only won 44%. Jonathan, Netflix bought
DC and Gypsy lost this dual matchup. What are you
doing next? I'm going to beat your ass is what I'm
going to do. Drive over to your house right now,
kicking your door. Thanks for the warning. I will
set my alarm. Or I guess it would just make more
sense just to call the cops. They'll be on my side
for all the shit talking you do. Well, congrats to
the Marvel fans. You guys did it again. Showed DC
what's up. We all know that Marvel's better,
especially nowadays. Cheers to you guys. Well,
that does it for this shitty episode. AJ9K help
close us out. Thanks for listening to Dynamic
Dual. Visit the show's website at
dynamicdual.com and follow us on Instagram at
Dynamic Dual podcast. Don't forget to listen to
the other shows in the Dynamite podcast network,
including Max Destruction, Senjo World, and
Console Combat. In our next episode, which
hopefully will be better, I think it will be, it's
going to be another duel this time between the
Superman villain Parasite against Sauron of the
Savage Land. Yeah, he's an X-Men villain
primarily. He looks like a big green pterodactyl.
So look forward to that next week. We want to give a
big thanks to our executive producers, John
Sturrosky, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Belcombe,
Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Aitin, Austin
Wazalowski, AJ Dunkerly, Nick Cabanto, Scott
Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Speese, Dean Molesky,
Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, and Paul Graves for
helping make this podcast possible. And we'll
talk to you guys next week. Up up and away, true
believers.