This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi, welcome to
the DynaMic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin
brother, Marvelous Joe. And in this episode, we
are reviewing Netflix's Season 2 of The Sandman
series. It's a fantastic series based off of one of
the best graphic novels ever made, definitely one
of my favorites, so I can't wait to talk about
Season 2. Yeah, not just one of your favorites. I'm
going to say probably the best adapted graphic
novel to television ever put out there. And
there's not many direct adaptations of graphic
novels out there, but this definitely sets a high
bar for future ones. We're going to talk about the
show later on in this episode. Before that, we're
going to break down the comic book movie news from
the past week, of which we just got a rinky dink look
at the new Spider suit for Spider-Man Brand New
Day. Yeah, rinky dink is the operative term right
there, for sure. As always, we list our segment
times in our episode description, so feel free to
check out the show notes if you want to skip ahead to
a particular topic. Our artificially
intelligent dual simulator, AJ9K, has a quick
message for our listeners, so listen up. Why hello
there. Do you want even more from this podcast?
Then become a part of the dynamic dual community on
Patreon where you can choose from three tiers. The
Dynamic 2.0 tier gives you access to our Discord
chat server, the Fantastic 4 tier gives you two
bonus episodes each month, and the X-Force tier
makes you an executive producer of this show.
Lastly, the Dynamite Podcast Network tier lets
you create your own podcast using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and
consultation, and get you simulation results.
Pitch the twins your ideas via email at
dynamicdualpodcast at gmail.com. Check it out at
patreon.com slash dynamicdual. Pip pip cheerio.
Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast. Be sure to tune in to the other shows on
the Dynamite Podcast Network this week,
including the console combat podcast where hosts
John and Dean simulate battles between popular
video game characters. In yesterday's episode,
they reviewed Season 1 of Twisted Metal. Over on
the Max Destruction podcast, hosts Scotty and
Gilly pit your favorite action heroes from film
and television against each other. They're
taking a brief hiatus during the month of August,
so make sure to get caught up on all of their latest
episodes. On the Sendro World podcast hosts
Zachary Hepburn speculates on fights between fan
favorite anime and manga characters. In his next
episode, Zach is going to reveal who'd win between
Akuto Sai from Demon King Daimo versus Amos
Voldigoed from Misfit of Demon Academy. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our show
notes to listen to all of the shows in the Dynamite
Podcast Network. But with that out of the way,
quick to the no prize! A no prize is an award that
Marvel used to give out to fans. Our version, the
Dynamic Dual No Prize, is a digital award we post on
Instagram for the person that we feel gave the best
answer to our question of the week. Last week we
asked you guys, if you could reimagine a Marvel or
DC superhero in an ancient culture, what
superhero and culture would you choose? This is
coming off of the trailer we got for Aztec Batman,
which reimagines the origins of Batman in the
ancient Aztec culture. We got quite a few answers,
we're going to break down this week's 3 honorable
mentions before revealing the no prize winner.
Our first honorable mention goes to... By Dear
Bangura. Who said? The character I would choose to
change arrows would be Punisher. I would put him in
pre-colonial West Africa. He would most likely
have a story where his family was killed by the
French or another superpower at the time. And he
would be there to free slaves to avenge those that
were taking and to make sure the freedom had spread
out throughout the continent. He would be a power
for a lot of other characters, he would be the
strength of Africa and he would make sure that his
story changes. And right out of the gate with a
pretty hardcore answer, By Dear suggested a West
African Punisher set during the early days of the
slave trade. And that would be crazy to watch. I
could imagine a West African soldier donning the
emblem of the skull and they don't have guns at the
time, right? So he'd probably use a sword or a spear
and he's just avenging the murder of his family.
Now the Punisher in the comic book isn't really
altruistic and fight for a larger goal of freeing
slaves or anything like that. He just kills
because he hates criminals. And this version of
the Punisher I don't think would be fighting
necessarily just to prevent slavery but largely
out of his anger for the people capturing slaves.
Right, he doesn't kill out of vengeance, he kills
out of punishment. Great answer by Dear, our next
honorable mention goes to Scott Camacho who said,
Ancient cultures. Hmm, let's see. My characters
would be the Justice League and I want to see them
portrayed in ancient Egypt. Superman is raw,
Wonder Woman as segment, the Flash as shoe and
Aquaman as sabok. The aesthetic of it would look
amazing. I love that idea. I think that's a really
cool idea. The Egyptian pantheon could very much
be like a superhero team. So to translate those
characters so well into their Justice League
counterparts, like right when he said Egyptian, I
already knew like what deities he was going to
connect to the Justice League characters. I love
that choice. I think that would be a really cool
aesthetic as well. And then you could say that
Superman was behind the pyramids or something
like the Egyptian pyramids were the remains of the
ships that were sent from Krypton or something
like that. It writes itself. Great answer Scotty,
our next honorable mention goes to Lorenzo Valdez
who said, This is Lorenzo Valdez calling in once
again. My idea is basically going off of what
Smallville did with Native American culture with
the Kowachi Caves, but taking it a step further and
setting the story before America was colonized
and having a Native American version of Lana Lang
and Kal-El arrives and having the story go from
there and explore Native American culture even
further. Kalana forever and always. Bye-bye.
Yeah, I'm not sure if the Kowachi tribe was real. I
think Kansas was actually populated by like the
Osage. Yeah, them and the Wichita and the Pani and
the Kansa according to Google. Either way, I think
the Kryptonian ship landing in pre-colonial
America would make for an awesome story. I'm not
sure how it would affect his upbringing and how he
would turn out as a character. It would be really
interesting to explore. Yeah, it'd be kind of
dangerous because I imagine he would be revered as
a God during that time. And how would he not let that
go to his head? That's the tricky part. He'd have to
have astute parents and maybe he would. Maybe they
would teach him about humility. It could be
awesome. Kind of like Superman Red Sun,
reimagined him landing in Soviet Russia. Landing
in pre-colonial America can make for a damn good
story too. Great answer, Lorenzo. We want to give a
quick shout out to Alex Albro and Cade Lehmann for
taking the time to visit our website and record an
answer. Yeah, Alex was not able to record an
answer, but he did write in suggesting an ancient
Greek Steve Rogers who fights against the
mythical Hydra. I thought that was pretty cool.
And Cade Lehmann suggested an ice man who was born
in Antarctica. But the winner of this week's No
Prize is Travis Herndon, who said... What's up,
the name of the dude is Travis here. Shout out to my
evil twin. So my answer will be Ghost Rider in
Nordic culture. Magi is seeing a badass Viking
Ghost Rider going around hacking dudes up with
dual axes and other Viking style weapons. And
that's for his vehicle, a Viking ship. And before
you say it, when it comes to land, it's being
carried by the souls of the damned while he's on
land. So I'm mad at seeing that charging at you. Oh,
shit. That's hardcore. That is so hardcore. You
know, Ghost Rider has always been pretty metal,
but I think this would just take that to the next
level with a Viking Ghost Rider who wields twin
battle axes. And I mentioned there will still be
chains on those and everything like that. He'd
probably have a fiery skull underneath his Viking
helmet. But what really sold me on this was
Travis's idea for his vehicle to be a Viking ship
that rides on the souls of the damned. And I don't
know if that would look like it was sailing on fire
or if it was sailing off of skeletons carrying it or
whatever, but either way, that's fucking badass.
That actually needs to be a thing. Like, I don't
care if it's a toy or a comic arc. That should be
real. Yeah, they've explored multiple Ghost
Riders throughout history in the comic books, but
I don't remember there being a Viking one. So yeah,
they could totally kind of tack that on there.
Great answer, Travis. You win this week's No
Price. If you the listener want to shut in winning
your own No Price, stay tuned to later on in this
episode when we'll be asking another question of
the week. But now that that's done, on to the news.
All right, this past week we got our first look at
Tom Holland's new Spider-Man suit that he's going
to wear in Spider-Man brand new day, which is being
directed by Daniel Destin Cretan and being filmed
right now. I believe they're currently filming in
Scotland, actually. And the way that Sony went
about revealing it wasn't the most exciting. They
kind of like showed this animatic of what the suit
could look like, but it was mostly in shadow and it
was only like a 9 second video. That wasn't really
worth talking about. And then there was also this
other video of Tom Holland coming out from behind a
door and, you know, he's like pumped to start
filming and he's wearing the suit. I was largely
unimpressed by the suit. But since those videos
have come out, better high res versions of the suit
were taken during the production of the movie and
they give us a much clearer look of what the new suit
is going to look like. And I will say it's not the
same suit that we saw at the end of Spider-Man No Way
Home, where that one was like kind of shiny. It had
more of a cyan blue color. It was pretty basic. This
new suit is also pretty basic, but it kind of feels a
lot more similar to the suits that he's had in the
past. If anything, actually the suit that it
reminds me most of is Andrew Garfield's from the
amazing Spider-Man 2, although the blue on this
suit is not quite as dark as that one was. And that
was a great suit. That was a fantastic suit. That
one had more like a navy color and this new
Spider-Man suit is more like a cobalt blue is what
I'll say. I gotta say it's more spandexy feeling
than I would have thought. Like I know he made his
costume at the very end of the last movie, but this
one definitely has that more homemade feel I would
say. And I don't know if it's just because of the
harnesses that he was wearing on set. Maybe
they'll just smooth out all the wrinkles in post,
but that was my first impression. Yeah, same here.
The material seems a lot thinner than the suits
that he's worn in the past, especially the ones
that were created by Tony Stark. Those seemed a lot
more heavy duty. But that's why I compared this
suit to the amazing Spider-Man 2 suit because when
Spider-Man was swinging through the city in that
movie, like the wind was like ruffling the spandex
of his outfit because the material was so thin,
right? Here you could also tell that the material
is similarly thin. The emblem is not quite as large
as Andrew Garfield's was. The mask is very similar
to his very first mask in Homecoming. But what's
interesting with this new suit is that his web
shooters look a whole lot different than they did
in previous films. They almost look like steel
drinking flasks attached to his wrists. They are
very prominent in this new suit. I don't know how I
feel about that because they seem like they would
make for easy targets for bad guys, right? To just
take out his web shooters. But they're there and
it'll be interesting to see how they look in
battle. I'm sad that we're going to lose a lot of the
cool features that Spider-Man had throughout his
initial trilogy. Where he had the web gliders and
the Spidey signal, Spider Tracers, things like
that. Things that he kind of developed over time in
the comic books and incorporated into his suit.
That I thought kind of added to his appeal as
somewhat of a tech hero and that he has a lot of
homemade tech that he incorporates. I hope he has
something going for him just beyond the web
shooters. Just because I don't know, I just really
like the web gliders I always have on his suit. I do
think that in modern Spider-Man movies there does
need to be at least two or three different
iterations of the suits. I mean, look at the last
film, how many he had. They'll come up with some
excuse to make some kind of toy wearing some kind of
different suit. So I'd be surprised if this was the
only one in the film. I think you're right. Yeah, I
think you're absolutely right. Although, you
know, this is rumored to be more of a street level
style Spider-Man movie, so we'll see. That being
said, if this is a street level Spider-Man outfit,
I'm totally for it. It looks very classic in that
regard. You'll just have bullet riddled
Spider-Man suit full of holes. Battle damaged
Spidey. That'll be the new action figure they
sell. But there's not really too much else to
comment on the suits. I'm sure we'll have a whole
lot more to say when they start releasing
marketing for the film, which won't be for a while
because they just started filming. So we probably
won't see like a trailer or anything until the end
of this year. Or maybe even after that because
really the Spider-Man movie doesn't come out
until July 31st, almost a whole year from now in
2026. I'm not sure how this particular suit will
rank among all of the Spider-Man suits throughout
all of his films. But on that topic, we have our
question of the week. What was the best live action
Spider-Man suits? And just for funsies, what was
the best Batman suits? And why? Yeah, we want an
answer for the best Spider-Man outfit and the best
Batman outfit. Just a tight DC in there. Jonathan
is going on vacation this next week, so we're going
to let this question of the week run for a couple of
weeks. Please record your answer at
dynamicdool.com by clicking on the red
microphone button in the bottom right hand corner
of the screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long and don't forget to leave your name in case we
include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a Dynamic
Duel No Prize that we'll post to Instagram. Be sure
to answer before August 16th. But that does it for
all of the news for this episode. Now let's go ahead
and move on to the main event where we review
Netflix's The Sandman Season 2. The Sandman
Season 2 Alright, The Sandman Season 2 is the
bittersweet conclusion of a dark fantasy epic
adapted from the award-winning DC Comics and
Vertigo Comics series, written by Neil Gaiman.
It's easily one of my favorite comic series of all
time and I truly loved Season 1. I actually
rewatched all of the first season in lead-up to
Season 2, which is something I've actually never
done before, but I knew I wanted to get the full
Sandman experience leading up to the saga's
bittersweet end. In my review of Season 1, I said
that while it was a faithful and worthwhile
adaptation, the books were better, only because
the story of Sandman has so many individual
threads and yarns to borrow an analogy from the
kindly ones that are seemingly separate until, as
the series progresses, you realize are part of a
much broader and beautiful tapestry. Season 2 is
missing a lot of those threads because while
Season 1 adapted volumes 1 and 2, Season 2 only
adapts 4 of the remaining 8 volumes of story. And
while you'd think missing half the story would
result in only half a tapestry, somehow the
showrunner Alan Heindberg and director Jamie
Childs, as well as the cast, were able to weave
something together that's a little bit smaller,
but still beautiful and still profound. If you
haven't seen this season or this series, I highly
recommend it. Please don't listen any further
because this story, unlike a lot of projects we
review, has a definitive, somewhat
unconventional end that you don't want spoiled
for yourself. No, definitely watch the series.
Don't listen to us just talk about the series. Go
watch Sandman, people. It's so good. There were so
many times when I was watching this show, because
my wife wasn't able to watch it with me this time,
that I just hoped that someone would walk in on me
watching it and just be transfixed by everything
going on. Because there's so much beauty in this
show. It is by far the best made comic book
adaptation on television and maybe even the best
looking adaptation on film, too. It's
incredible. And if you like dark fantasy, the
story is right up your alley as well. Just go watch
it. Go watch the Sandman. Go watch it! What are you
still doing here? No, yeah, it does not really get
better than the Sandman on multiple levels, from
production to writing to acting, just
everything. It was so good. Now, as we mentioned in
our review of the first season, Sandman for the
longest time was considered unadaptable because
of how dense the source material is. I was pretty
nervous going into season one, but even more so
going into season two, because I knew how much
ground the writers were going to have to cover in
such a short time span, considering they
announced that season two was going to be the final
season. And as I was watching the show, I was
legitimately amazed at how well they were able to
work in nearly all of my favorite moments from the
comics in a way that felt much more organic than I
expected it to. Like, Amidst Summer Night's
Dream, for example, that was something of a
standalone issue in the comic, but they worked it
into a flashback for the show. There were a lot of
smart choices on display here that came across as
very well thought out and planned at length, and I
appreciated that as I was watching this season.
Yeah, it's kind of a master craft in story weaving
on behalf of the screenwriters here. And, you
know, we have some veterans like Allen Heinberg,
David Goyer. Neil Gaiman himself was involved.
Yeah, we don't want to talk about him, though. No.
But, yeah, they did a really good job. I mean, you
got to think about just how much story they had to
condense. Well, again, there's a lot left out
because they only adapted four of the remaining
eight, but they did a fantastic job adapting
those. It's like you said, a masterwork. I'm
assuming the remaining volumes focused on the new
Sandman. No, the remaining volumes were
essentially anthological stories, though one of
them was Amidst Summer Night's Dream. So they
still were able to sneak some of those in their
different ways. Now, one of the great things about
the story of Sandman and what drew me to the comics
back when I read them in high school is that because
it's essentially a story about stories, it's not
necessarily bound to any particular setting or
time, genre, or even cast of characters. There are
seemingly entire volumes of the Sandman comic
series that are simply a collection of
anthological short stories. That is, until you
get closer to the end of the entire series and you
begin to realize that it's all connected, that
really every story was part of a much bigger
picture. You're kind of just along for the ride for
most of the series under the impression that this
is a story that could be endless. It's kind of the
promise made at the very start that dream stories
can and will go on forever. That is, until you
realize that this whole thing was really a setup
for how and why an endless being, a God
essentially, would come to accept death. And not
in any kind of macabre way, but in a way that makes
you feel like you truly lived an entire life with a
character and understand his decisions. Yes, the
story of a selfish God growing and changing and in a
sense becoming more human. Right, exactly. Yeah,
that's a great description of it. It's a very
existential work. And while I wouldn't exactly
say season two concluded with the same level of
existentialism as the books where you finish the
last page of the book and look up and you're like,
wait, I'm in a bookstore. I'm not in the dreaming. I
will say that because this television adaptation
is so hyper focused on dream story, which is a story
about life. It still manages to transcend and be
almost unbound by theme. It's not only a story
about life, but about death and mortality and
grief and responsibility, love and
relationships, personal growth, destiny and
free will. It's literally and literally about
everything. Yeah, I think I mentioned in our
review of season one that the whole Sandman series
kind of seemed to be a grand experiment by the
author Neil Gaiman. Every time I say his name, I do
want to make sure I clarify that the dude is a
fucking dickhole. But yeah, the Sandman series
was, I think, his grand experiment regarding the
topics of life and death and love. Yeah, there's a
lot of aspects about it that feel experimental and
indie in that way. Very creative in a way that is
unconventional, I think, for the medium. Now,
while I'm sincerely impressed with how well they
were able to wrap up dream story in a single season,
I'd be lying if I said I didn't wish this show could
have gone on for another four or five seasons. It
would have been better, but also pretty damn
expensive. Each episode of this season cost about
$15 million to make, making it one of the most
expensive shows ever produced. But it shows even
more so this season compared to last, in my
opinion. I agree. Like, I thought the
cinematography and costuming were noticeably
better this round, having watched both seasons
back to back. And the visual effects, for sure.
Merv Pumpkinhead, he felt so real. For me, I think
the best visual effect throughout the entire
course of this season was actually the
underworld. The Greek underworld ruled by Hades
and Persephone. There were so many moments
throughout the course of this show where I felt
truly transported, and the whole adaptation of
the Orpheus and Eurydice story was such a perfect
translation of the Greek myth that I think someone
even like Christopher Nolan, who's currently
shooting the Odyssey, is going to have a run for his
money in how well these Greek tragedies appear on
screen. There's just something so transportive
about the Sandman. Yeah, there's very few people
who could do mythology as well as Neil Gaiman. Even
with his other books, like American Gods and stuff
like that, a lot of that spills over into his
Sandman universe. And yeah, it's captivating. We
see multiple pantheons here. We see a lot of
different characters. There's so many
characters in the Sandman saga, but let's dive
into a few in our character breakdown. Starting
with Dream, played by Tom Sturridge. Now, I think
Tom was born to play this role. I know you mentioned
in our last review that his voice was too
theatrical, but like I also mentioned, I think the
choice to make his voice consistent while leaving
the subtle emotions to play out on his face worked
really well. I saw an interview where Tom said he
asked Neil Gaiman how Dream should sound, and his
response was that Dream should sound like the
voice in your head when you're thinking. Quiet,
but also with an authoritative tinge as well as one
of seduction and terror. I think that's a lot to ask
of an actor, but I think Tom did a great job. That's
not what the voice in my head sounds like. The voice
in my head sounds like this. I wonder what's in the
pantry for dinner. What does your voice sound
like? My inner voice, just like my regular voice,
but I wouldn't describe my regular voice as any of
those things. I feel bad for you. My voice is hella
seductive. Regarding Sturridge's performance,
I think I did criticize it saying that it was too
operatic, I think. And so it kind of came across as
forced and maybe even a little bit corny at times
for season one. But I think having seen season one,
I totally understand what he's doing. These are
larger than life characters. He's the fucking
embodiment of an abstract concept. He shouldn't
really humanize his performance. Maybe it should
be larger than life, and so I definitely had less
issue with it. I agree. I think maybe the guy was
born to play Dream of the Endless. He had the look
down better in this season than I think even last
season, which I didn't think was possible. And
plus, it was really easy to see his growth in his
performance going from someone who is so
emotional, yet so completely lacking empathy.
He's basically a sociopath who really comes to
humble himself and better himself throughout the
entire season. You see that. Right, exactly.
Dream's arc is ultimately about accepting
responsibility. He was this godlike being who was
incredibly humbled in the first season in which we
saw him work to regain his power and restore his
realm. But in season two, now that he and his realm
are back to full power, we see how the events of the
first season have changed him and caused him to
recognize that he doesn't just have a
responsibility to the dreaming, but for his past
hurtful actions that he would have otherwise
overlooked as a prideful and all-powerful deity.
Humility fosters empathy, and with his newfound
empathy comes newfound emotions like regret, but
also love. Yeah, I think early on he largely
confused desire with love, which may have been in
part due to the machinations of his sibling
desire. But through the course of the story, he
really comes to understand what actual love is.
And that is something worth dying for.
Absolutely. You know, not a told him 10,000 years
ago that she doesn't believe his kind is capable of
love, and he punished her for it because I feel like
he was afraid that was true. In the same way that his
parents didn't love him because when you're that
powerful and that important relationships and
love get in the way of duty and responsibility. But
dream realizes the season that he does love and has
hurt the ones he loves and in an effort to make
things right, willingly puts himself in the
position of undergoing the ultimate act of love,
which is to sacrifice yourself to protect your
loved ones. I believe that's what love really is.
Attention and sacrifice. And dream found himself
incapable of ignoring those that truly matter to
him, whether it was Nada in Hell, Delirium,
sulking in her realm, Orpheus on that Greek
island, or his staff in his palace being
destroyed. Dream chooses death not only out of
love, but because dream is bound by his identity by
function rules and ritual in a way that he sees
others of equal station are not Lucifer gives up on
her domain and so does destruction. But dream
cannot do that. He's seen what happens when his
realm is abandoned and he refuses to have that
happen again, taking steps to ensure the dreaming
will survive and be cared for after he's gone. And
yet, he also refuses to bear the burden of killing
another innocent in Light of Hall. His death is
both destiny and free will, both bound to happen,
yet also a conscious choice made by dream, because
he refuses to change back to the kind of being he
once was. And now has the courage to let go of
selfishness and pride, which is not easy and
something I think we'll all have to face one day on
our own deathbeds. It's such a profound arc, like
we talk about the themes in these superhero movies
and shows a lot in our reviews, but none of them
quite come as close to the profundity of what dream
goes through. His arc literally is the end all be
all arc, I feel like. And it shows what really
matters. That being said, I think I still have the
same criticisms of the story that I did from season
one in that Neil Gaiman's rules that he has set up
for this Santa Man universe do still seem
arbitrary. Like, oh, the spilling of familial
blood by the antelists will result in their
destruction by the kindly ones. It's all very
convenient to his story. You know, to me, like, why
couldn't dream just bring his son to live with him
in the dreaming and like give him a new body and even
recreate a facsimile of Eurydice and just support
him in that way and decline the boon of killing his
only son. It seemed like there were other options
for an all powerful entity like dream. I can answer
a few of those questions. I mean, dream is not all
powerful. He has most control in his realm and to be
in his realm, one has to be sleeping. Orpheus is
still alive in the waking world and it wouldn't
matter if dream created him a new body in the
dreaming because once Orpheus woke up, he would
still be headless in his world. Well, he could put
him into an eternal sleep and then it wouldn't
matter. That's fair, but that's still him not
fully taking responsibility for his actions. His
son asked to die specifically, not live with him
eternally in the dreaming. I think his son asked to
die because his love had died, but if you remove
like his loneliness, I think maybe that desire to
die goes away partly. I don't know, man. After
thousands of years as a decapitated head, I think I
would want to be done. I think after thousands of
years living as a decapitated head that couldn't
move if you gave me the illusion of a body and an
entire realm to explore, I suddenly feel less
shitty. Well, that's not what Orpheus asked of his
father, is it? It doesn't matter because that was
dream's workaround that he could have done. I
think it would have satisfied his arc. I think it
would have satisfied his soul and I think it would
have satisfied his son as well. Again, it comes
down to responsibility. He didn't want to have to
leave his son in the care of priests only to be
risked, stolen again like he was during the French
Revolution. Who cares if he's stolen? He's an
eternal sleep. He's of no use to anybody while he's
in an eternal sleep. You just don't want to accept
the fact that I thought of a better solution for a
dream situation than dream could think of
himself. Well, here's the problem with your
solution. It fails to recognize the fact that
dream wanted to die. Well, I guess that was one of
the things that Joanna Constantine posited to
him, right? I'm not entirely convinced that was
true though. I mean, he seemed rather reluctant to
die by the very end. I mean, he's the one who had
Matthew retrieve his sister's death to begin
with. He was willing to make that sacrifice. Yeah,
but he also asked the kindly ones if there was
nothing else that would satisfy them besides his
life. Those were some of his last words. Yeah, and
this was already after he had killed his son. Which
I'm saying he didn't have to do, okay? Anyway, we
could go on and on about this. Just know that I'm
right and that this is likely a plot hole in the
whole damn story of the Sandman. It is not. You
don't know what you're talking about. You don't
understand the characters at all, apparently.
Okay, okay. Read a book! Moving on to Delirium. She
was played by Esme Creed Miles. I looked at her
filmography. I have not seen a single thing she's
been in, but Delirium was one of my favorite
characters from the Sandman comic series. And her
personality is really all over the place, but
always in this haze. So I was curious to see how Esme
would approach the character. And while I
expected something a little more absurdist, I
guess, I thought she'd perfectly capture
Delirium's innocence and vulnerability while
still adding a level of quirkiness that helps
capture the dichotomy of both sanity and insanity
that Delirium should have, and I noticed in this
performance that she did. One thing they never
addressed in the course of the show is why she
became Delirium after being delighted for so
long. She brings it up, but can you answer that
question? No, because it's actually never been
answered in the comics. Oh. Lame, I know they
filmed this scene where it happened, but they cut
it from the show. Okay. I think because it's better
off being a mystery. Well, she says she knows
things about the endless that no one else knows,
not even Destiny. And it's a really vague line that
is left intentionally vague just for the sake of
it. I feel like if they're going to bring it up, they
may as well discuss it. It's a Chekhov's gun
situation that never goes off. Well, potentially
Delirium is the most powerful of the endless. So
that line was not surprising to me. But again,
she's all about mystery. She's insane. So she
probably doesn't even know what she knows or
doesn't know. Sure. We do know that Delirium is the
youngest of the endless who used to be delight, but
was something of a cosmic afterthought and wasn't
as stable as her siblings. At some point in the
past, she had a breakdown and became Delirium.
She's a tragic figure who's dismissed by her
siblings, who see her as naive, unstable, and even
annoying. But behind her erratic speech and
fractured behavior is this deep, unwavering
drive. She wants to find her brother destruction
and not out of duty or curiosity. But because she
misses him, she remembers what it meant to be whole
when she was delight and she wants her family to be
whole again. Dream realizes during the journey
that they share that Delirium is not the fool he
thought she was. She's just different. And she
feels everything because she's kind of
everything else. All the cosmic aspects and
emotions that her siblings aren't. And Dream
comes to recognize, respect, and even love that
about her. He loves her because she's so sincere in
her love in a way that none of the other endless are.
Moving on to destruction, he was played by Barry
Sloan. Now, like Esme Creed Miles, I was not
familiar with Barry Sloan's work prior to this,
but I thought he brought something really
grounded and unexpectedly warm to destruction.
Which matches the comic, actually, where
destruction, surprisingly, comes across as much
more chipper and less edgier than his siblings.
There's still this quiet sadness beneath Sloan's
performance, though, like a man who carries a
heavy truth but tries his hardest not to let it
harden him. I would say he's the most human of the
endless, and I thought that was easy to see in
Barry's performance. Yeah, it's interesting how
the members of the endless that you would assume
would be the darkest and edgiest, like death and
destruction, end up being some of the more
human-like characters, whereas some of the more
whimsical aspects like Dream and Desire end up
being the more edgy and closed off ones. Yeah, I
guess that is true. It kind of circumvents your
expectations in a way. Yeah, I did like the
character of destruction. I guess I don't quite
understand how a member of the endless can kind of
give up their responsibilities without
everything just turning to shit, but the
characterization of destruction as he was
portrayed here was like very grounded, very
level, very understanding. Maybe, yeah, but that
came with the cost as well. Now, Destruction's arc
is about the burden of inevitability and the moral
weight of choice. He's the only member of the
endless to walk away from his function, which has
changed specifically, though he didn't do it out
of neglect, but explicitly out of love. In a
flashback scene to 1675, during a conversation
with Dream, he reveals his growing fear of
mankind's increasing mastery of science and
rationality being used not for understanding,
but power and control. He sees the dissected apes,
the splitting of light and the probing of nature's
most sacred mysteries with the knowledge of what
it inevitably has always led to, the destruction
of the planet, of those he cares about, and
eventually the destruction of everything,
including himself and his family. Rather than
bearing responsibility of guiding change in the
universe to that fateful conclusion,
Destruction abdicates his cosmic role to let
change happen naturally. But I mean, he's not an
arbiter of unnatural change either, so I guess the
fact that everything kind of continues going on
without him makes it seem like the function of all
the endless characters is largely unnecessary.
Well, no, I think the implication is that he is the
guide of change, and when he abdicated his role,
that's essentially when we got the
Enlightenment, the Age of Reason, the Industrial
Revolution, like it's kind of speeding up and kind
of going out of control because he's not there to
foster it. Well, that's a dick move then. It's like
by leaving his responsibilities, he's just
turning his fears into a self-fulfilling
prophecy that much faster. Well, it's going to
happen anyway, and he didn't want to be
responsible for that, which is why he just kind of
gave up on everything and found his own kind of
peace in that way. He's not bound to this world and
its people. He could literally traverse the
universe. Now, when Dream and Delirium find
destruction, he challenges the very idea of duty
and identity, reminding Dream that just because
someone has a role doesn't mean that it has to be a
prison. Where Dream clings to form and function,
Destruction chooses freedom, even if it means
stepping away from the people and realms he loves.
Though Dream ultimately doesn't follow
Destruction's advice because he's not willing to
sacrifice the ones he loves like Destruction is,
both of them find their own path to peace. And
that's the cost I mentioned earlier, the
destruction of the ones you love. I mean, is it
going to happen anyway so that Kostas is going to be
buried regardless? So I'm not sure that's
something that he actually has to pay. He feels
responsibility for it is the whole point. He
doesn't want to see his loved ones like his family
be destroyed. He'd rather just ignore all of it and
ignore it's his bliss essentially with
Destruction. So the cost is lessened. Right,
exactly. He's a good guy, but he's not exactly a
good guy. I guess that's a good way to put it. I did
like his wisdom regarding the advice he gave
Daniel at the end when he said that there's no such
thing as a one sided coin. Oh yeah. And that each of
the aspects of the endless somewhat define their
opposites in that death in her role has come to
define life and despair has come to define hope,
desire, hatred and dream, I guess, reality. That
was just an interesting aspect because I've
always wondered why those other aspects never
existed as members of the endless. Why was it
limited to these D words? I was just about to say, I
was because they don't start with D. But yeah, I
guess in a way those opposite entities are
represented through the existing endless, which
I thought was pretty neat. Yeah, he also said
destiny defined freedom. Well, he didn't see what
he defined or delirium defined, but if I had to
guess, destruction defines meaning and delirium
defines reason. Sounds about right to me. Makes me
wonder what I represent. Taco Bell? But what's the
opposite of Taco Bell? Not shitting your pants.
Yeah, you define those two things. Nice. Now, I
wanted to touch on these three characters
specifically because they're my favorite of the
endless. And I really think the endless are one of
the most interesting aspects of the Sandman
series. But there are a lot more characters here,
as I've mentioned, many of whom are static
archetypes who don't really grow or have their own
arcs. You could say Dream really is the only one
except for maybe Lucifer and I guess Johanna
Constantine and maybe Daniel. But they're really
not in the show long enough to touch too much on. So
we'll do that in the story highlights. In a world
where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies and anime. The
Dynamite Podcast Network presents Console
Combat, where video game legends brawl every
Monday. Dynamic duel, where comic book titans
smash every Tuesday. Max destruction, where TV
and action heroes battle every Wednesday. And
Sendra World, where anime champions clash every
Thursday. Join us as we speculate on the matches
and armed with the power of mathematical
simulations. Discover who will emerge
victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com where we
settle the debate and settle the score. Episode
one was titled Season of Mists. As Dream rebuilds
the dreaming, he is summoned by his brother
Destiny to attend a family gathering of the
Endless in Destiny's realm, where a dream meets
his other siblings, death, desire, despair and
delirium. As they mentioned their absent brother
who broke off contact with them centuries ago,
Destiny explains that the fates have revealed a
cryptic prophecy to him that would start to unwind
with their meeting. Desire aggravates Dream,
reminding him of Nada, a human queen whom he fell in
love with millennia ago, but condemned to hell
after she ended the relationship, claiming the
Endless and mortals cannot live together after
their affair led to the destruction of her
kingdom. After a discussion with death, Dream
resolves to save Nada from hell, making sure to
secure the dreaming and meeting with Lightahall
and Hobgadling in case he would not return. As
Dream enters hell, Lucifer Morningstar calls on
the demonic legions intent to execute revenge on
Dream for the humiliation suffered during their
last confrontation. Now, if the Kindly Ones never
visited Destiny, it's likely Dream never would
have died. That is correct. What did the Kindly
Ones have against Dream? They're the ones that put
this whole thing into motion. They knew what would
happen. Well, so does Destiny. Now, he only knows
what happens. He doesn't see the future. But the
Kindly Ones do. And they knew what was going to
happen. So they set in motion what was already
going to happen. You have to think about it fifth
dimensionally. But if they don't set it into
motion, then it likely wouldn't happen. So why
would they have set it into motion unless they
wanted Dream to die? Because they're all about
telling stories and they wanted Dream to complete
his story. Fucking assholes. I agree. Not a fan of
the Kindly Ones, though I thought they did a
fantastic job adapting them in this show. Episode
two was titled The Ruler of Hell. Finding hell
eerily empty upon his arrival, Dream is
confronted by Lucifer, who, weary of her duty, has
abdicated the throne and released all souls and
demons to roam other worlds. After Lucifer
persuades Dream to ceremoniously cut off her
wings, she gives Dream the key to hell, making him
its custodian in revenge. Returning to the
Dreaming, Dream soon finds a flooded by
delegations of supernatural beings seeking
dominion over hell, among them being the gods
Susano, Odin, Thor and Loki, a pair from Fairy
named Chloracan and Nala, representatives of
both order and chaos, and the demons Azizal,
Corinzon and Merkin, who demand to return to hell.
Two angels, Remiel and Yuma, descend from heaven
as observers for God. Dream welcomes everyone in
his palace as guests and throws a banquet to watch
all decide who to give the key to hell to. Aside from
the Knights entertainment provided by Kanan
Abel, several guests approach Dream with bribes,
among them Azizal, who reveals he has captured not
a soul and is willing to exchange it for the key to
hell. Now, as I mentioned earlier, one of the
themes of this season is free will, and the
abdication of hell by Lucifer, played very well by
Gwendolyn Christie, is sort of the ultimate act of
rebellion. She, like death or any of the other
cosmic entities, don't really have free will
unless they choose to abandon their role
altogether. She's a great foil for Dream, in that
sense, because he struggles to separate his duty
from his identity. It is interesting thinking
about all the different ways Neil Gaiman's
version of Lucifer has been adapted throughout
various shows and movies over the years. Like this
is the same version of Lucifer that was in the
Constantine movie with Keanu Reeves. Yes. And the
one that had his own show on Fox or was it CW? I can't
remember. Maybe it was both the Lucifer show. I
think it even went to Netflix for a time. And I think
even in like Good Omens, it's the same character.
And thinking about how this is how it all ends for
the character with Lucifer's wings being cut off
by Dream. And then, you know, them going to a beach
just to live out the rest of eternity is kind of
fascinating. Well, Lucifer doesn't spend the
rest of eternity on the beach. It was just
something she wanted to do at that moment. Gotcha.
I did think it was hilarious how inferior the
show's versions of the Nordic gods were compared
to the Marvel Cinematic Universe. What? You heard
me. This Thor was a fucking joke compared to Chris
Hemsworth. And Chris Hemsworth would kick his
ass. No, this Thor is way more Thor than Marvel's
Thor could ever hope to be. Same with Loki. I don't
know what that means, but you're wrong. He's more
true to the mythical character that is Thor. His
hammer was tiny compared to Chris Hemsworth's.
Hey, man, it's not about the size of the hammer.
It's how you use it. And he used it well. I did think
Odin was cool, though. I thought Loki was cool
throughout this whole series. Was awesome. Yeah,
I really like the kind of Billy Idol David Bowie
approach they took to Loki. As much as I love Tom
Hiddleston, I think this version of Loki comes
pretty close to his performance. Fuck yeah. When
he set that chick on fire with his cigarette, I was
like, damn. Yeah. Moving on to Episode Three, it
was titled More Devils Than Vast Hell Can Hold. In
The Dreaming, Nala runs into Dream and they
recount their first meeting. In a flashback to
England in 1593, Dream inspires William
Shakespeare to write A Midsummer Night's Dream
and makes him play it for King Oberon, Queen
Titania and their court in an attempt to heal a rift
between the Dreaming and Fairy by making mankind
forever remember the Fae through the play. Oberon
and Titania like the play and make a bends with
Dream. In the present, Dream discusses his
dilemma with Hell's key to Nala. And the next
morning, everyone assembles to hear his
decision. Dream ultimately decides to return the
Lordship of Hell to God, provoking Azizal into
attacking him. However, being in the Dreaming,
Dream easily overpowers Azizal and saves Nala.
Before his departure, Clericun reveals that Nala
is a gift to Dream from Titania, and Dream
reluctantly accepts after Nala herself agrees to
stay. Dream finds out that Loki, trying to escape
imprisonment by Odin, swapped appearances with
Susano against Susano's will. Dream, in exchange
for a promise of future service, agrees to keep
Loki's escape a secret. After meeting with
Lucifer on a beach, Dream and she peacefully part
ways and later, Dream apologizes to Dada. She does
not accept his apology, however, and leaves for
the waking world instead. So this episode had the
adaptation of the Midsummer Night's Dream issue
in the comic book, which ended up winning a World
Fantasy Award. So I was really expecting a lot from
this episode. And I guess the whole play within a
play aspect was surprising to me because I thought
it would go deeper into that story of Shakespeare.
But you know, that whole thing really isn't
relevant to the story of Dream. So I guess that's
why it was left out. Well, the play within a story
played out just like it did in the comics. It was
actually a pretty faithful adaptation. Like
where you had Robin Goodfellow take on the role of
Puck within the play. Yes, I got to say that King
Joffrey, I don't know the actor's name. Jack
Gleason, he fucking nailed it in the role of Puck.
Oh, dude. Yeah. The combo of Freddy Fox as Loki and
Jack Gleason as Puck was so perfect. So perfect.
Yeah, they could get a whole series on their own. It
wouldn't be a really fucked up series. But yeah,
they're a good duo. Absolutely. Episode four was
titled Brief Lives. Delirium unexpectedly pays a
visit to Dream, seeking his help in finding their
absent brother, Destruction. Reluctant at
first, Dream agrees, secretly hoping to
encounter Nada on Earth instead of his brother.
Destruction is seen engaging in painting and
poetry accompanied by Barnabas, a talking dog on a
remote island. Dream and Delirium enlist Wanda, a
chauffeur of Dream's old friend, to help them
track down Destruction's contacts. The first of
them, however, dies just before they find him. And
Dream grows suspicious that an unknown force is
preventing them from finding Destruction. Next,
they seek Ishtar, an old Babylonian deity and
Destruction's former lover who, depowered
without worship, works as a club dancer. After a
heated discussion with Dream, Ishtar performs a
mesmerizing dance for her audience, causing an
explosion that kills everyone in the club,
including Ishtar and Wanda. Desire appears
revealing to the naive Delirium that Dream has
been lying to her, causing Delirium to leave her
siblings in anger. Dude, Madonna was in this
episode. Yeah, from the Punisher. I noticed that.
That's crazy. I was like, hey, what are you doing up
on the stage? Get down there and go solve a crime or
something. She was such a good detective in the
Punisher series. It's just, I guess, surprising
to see sometimes actors and other roles. She was
also a fantastic Ishtar, though. I can believe
that. Was the whole like Wanda trans issue in this
episode also in the comic book? It was, but not in
this volume. Wanda is actually a character that
was borrowed from Volume 5, which was not adapted.
It's titled A Game of You. I don't know if you
remember Barbie from season one, where she has
these dreams that she's like in this fantasy
world. She was one of Rose's and Light's roommates
in Florida when she was searching for Jed. Oh,
yeah, yeah, yeah. OK, I do remember. Yes. So in A
Game of You, Barbie is actually the main
character. Dream hardly ever shows up in that
volume. And Wanda is Barbie's friend. I think
she's a really popular character from that
volume. So they adapted her into this episode. Oh,
interesting. OK, that's like surprisingly
progressive for a series that came out in the 80s. I
think I was just surprised by that wondering if it
was something they just threw in to address
current trans issues or if it had always been
there. It was played a little differently here. I
wouldn't say that in the comic in the 80s, they were
addressing trans issues. It was just a trans
character that happened to be in the story.
Gotcha. OK. Moving on to episode five, the song of
Orpheus. After recalling when destruction tried
to tell him why he's abandoning his duty, Dream
attends Wanda's funeral, where death persuades
him to make amends with delirium. Dream enters
delirium's realm and eventually reconnects with
her, resuming their quest to locate destruction.
They seek advice from destiny. He tells Dream that
only his son, an oracle of endless blood, can help
them. In a flashback to Greece, 1700 BC, the
endless attend the wedding of Orpheus, son of
Dream and Calliope. That night, however,
Orpheus's wife, Eurydice, dies from a snake bite.
Orpheus begs Dream to help him retrieve Eurydice
from the underworld, but he refuses. With
destruction's help, Orpheus then approaches
death and she reluctantly makes him immortal,
allowing him to travel to the underworld. Once
there, Orpheus persuades Hades and Persephone
via song to revive Eurydice. But then he fails the
test of faith presented to him, leaving Eurydice
to stay dead. Against the caution of Calliope, the
desperate Orpheus lets himself be torn apart by
the Menads, murderous worshipers of Dionysus.
Left to live as a decapitated head, Orpheus begs
Dream to kill him to no avail. In the present, a
distraught Dream and delirium depart to see
Orpheus. This is my favorite episode of this
season. I thought it was a tremendous visual
telling of the story of Orpheus and Eurydice. Oh,
yeah, that's a classic Greek myth. And I agree, it
was very cool to see played out in live action. They
never addressed the fact that Desire was behind
Eurydice's death, though. Right. I'm glad you
mentioned that. I thought they would as well,
maybe during the wake or maybe even during this
episode. But yes, in the comics and I think in the
myth as well, Desire influences a Sader to chase
Eurydice, just lust filled. And in that chase is
when she is bitten by the snake. They didn't have
the Sader in this. They just went with the snake.
But I almost feel like that's doing a disservice to
the story because Desire really is the ultimate
villain, I feel, of the story. So I'm not sure why
they decided to downplay that. Yeah, they kind of
gave Desire a pass by the end. But yeah, they're
definitely the main villain. It was cool to see the
same actress playing Calliope as the first
season. Oh, yeah, for the bonus episode that was in
season one. Yeah, she's a great Calliope. The
entire cast is so damn good. Minus Rose, but we
didn't get much of her this season. And even what we
did get, she was much better. Yeah, I would agree.
Moving on to episode six, which was titled Family
Blood in a flashback to 1794. Dream approaches
Lady Johanna Constantine with a task to retrieve
Orpheus's head from France during the Revolution
and return it to a temple in Greece, where it would
be safeguarded by priests hunted down by a
Maximilian Robespierre. And as men Constantine
succeeds with the help of Orpheus himself, whose
song incites the end to Robespierre's tyranny.
After returning Orpheus's head to his temple,
Constantine asks Dream for a chance to visit
Orpheus and the present dream in Delirium past her
grave near Orpheus's temple. Their dream
reunites with Orpheus and he discloses the
location of destruction. Dream and Delirium
approach destruction who reluctantly welcomes
them. The three discussed destruction's
departure from his duties and his wards against
being found to be the cause of the deaths of Wanda,
Ishtar and others. He alludes that mortals are
capable of great destruction on their own without
the need of him being complicit. Despite
Delirium's plea, destruction bids them farewell
and parts advice to Dream and gives Barnabas to
Delirium to keep her company. With that, he
disappears into the sky. Dream and Orpheus
reconcile and upon Orpheus's request, Dream ends
his son's life. Elsewhere, the kindly ones
condemn Dream for spilling family blood. I really
like the way that the story incorporates actual
history, in this case, the French Revolution and
how you had Robespierre who during the French
Revolution tried to bring out an age of reason to do
away with religion, basically, and just
acknowledge like a supreme being that everyone in
the country would accept. And that kind of plays
out in his statement to Constantine when he's
like, there are no gods. There's just France and
the state. And she had that badass line where she's
holding the head and she's like, there's so much
more than that when the head starts sinking, you
know, given her knowledge of all of the endless and
all the supernatural and mysticism that
surrounds the world within the story. I thought
that was a really cool moment. Yeah. And some of the
volumes that were not adapted, like they also go
into the history of ancient Greece and history of
ancient Greece and Baghdad and stuff like that.
Again, the story of Sandman is not bound by any
location or time, which not only makes it great,
but again, very unique amongst literature.
Moving on to Episode Seven, which was titled Time
and Night. Dream asks Destiny's help to protect
him, but Destiny reveals there is nothing he can
do. Dream visits the kindly ones to give them an
explanation, but they too are bound by law and
cannot help him. Dream then visits Loki and Puck,
now a couple, who are pretending to be the Pope and
Cardinal. Dream calls in his favor for saving
Loki, though Puck later suggests privately to
Loki to do what Dream wants, but not when Dream
wants it to be done, thereby causing more chaos.
After returning to the Dreaming, Dream reveals
that Lightahall's son, Daniel, will be his
successor. Dream visits his father, Time, but
Time reveals he is powerless to help Dream, though
Dream tells him he loves him. He next visits his
mother, Knight, who asks Dream to live with her,
but he rejects her offer. Back in the Dreaming,
Clarke returns to bring back Nala at Titania's
orders, since she has heard that Dream could die
and doesn't want Nala hurt. Though Nala resists,
Dream persuades her to go back to fairy for safety
before leaving. He gives her a necklace as a
parting gift, which will summon him any time she
calls out to him, at which time he will offer her a
boon. Meanwhile, Lightah and Rose visit Unity's
home in London, where a disguised Puck works as the
chauffeur. That night when Rose and Lightah go to
dinner, Puck puts everyone at their home to sleep
before kidnapping Daniel and taking him to Loki.
Now, I thought it was really cool that they showed
Time and Knight in this episode because we don't
actually see Time, if I remember, in the comic
series. He's in one of the over-itchers, but not
this volume. So this whole journey he takes to meet
his parents is original to the story. Well, we get
to see Knight in the original 10 volumes, but not
Time. So, yeah, that was original and that was
great, I thought. It was fantastic. And it spoke a
lot to Dream's arc as well in terms of maybe how he
came to be the way he was and how he was really
growing emotionally as this abstract deity. The
actor who played his father, Rufus Sule, just did a
fantastic job with that performance. Honestly, I
think this whole scene is just a master class in
acting. Now, he's the most recognizable actor, I
think, out of the entire series. It was really an
interesting piece of casting to have like the head
honcho, all-powerful father of the endless being
actor of note. Episode eight was titled Fuel for
the Fire. Nala and Clericon return to the fairy
realm where Queen Titania jealously takes notice
of Nala's necklace. While contemplating his fate
in his throne room, Dream inadvertently ends up in
the realm of a sister despair where he sees through
one of her mirrors the light it also despairs over
her missing baby, Daniel. And Dream learns that
Loki and Puck have framed him for Daniel's
disappearance while posing as police
detectives. Despite Lucian discovering that the
kindly ones cannot harm Dream in his own realm,
Dream enters the waking world to enlist the
present day, Johanna Constantine, to find
Daniel. When the two of them visit Lighta, Dream
encounters Alex Burgess, the son of the man who
imprisoned him for over 100 years and whom Dream
cursed with a lifelong sleep. After seeing
Dream's antagonism toward Lighta and Alex,
Johanna begins to suspect Dream of wanting to die
and suggests he return to the dreaming.
Meanwhile, Puck flees from Loki with the baby
Daniel, having grown fond of the child and fearing
Loki's plans for him. Dream shares a final drink
with Hobgadling. And after speaking of regrets,
Dream awakens Alex from his sleep. Posing his
dream, Loki tricks Puck into returning to him with
Daniel, whom Loki then sets on fire in a fireplace
before showing photos to Lighta of her burned dead
son. Dream recreates the Corinthian, a nightmare
who once tried to kill him to aid Johanna. What did
you think of the actress who played Johanna
Constantine's performance this season compared
to last? Jenna Coleman? I thought she crushed it.
100 percent. Johanna has a really interesting arc
this season. It's a romantic one. You know, she
starts out traumatized by the deaths of those she
loved as we saw happen in season one. And she's even
like subconsciously killing lovers in her dreams
as an expression for how averse she is to the notion
of love. But the Corinthian proves to be too
charming, which is not necessarily in contrast to
his depiction in season one. But it is still kind of
weird and terrifying how she seems to fall for him,
I think. Yeah, considering that Johanna is a
gender bent version of John Constantine in this
show, I'm assuming that this arc is largely
original to her character. No, she shouldn't have
even been in the season. But Jenna Coleman, again,
just crushed the role in the first one. So I'm sure
they figured they had to bring her back. And I'm
glad they did. Got you. Another thing they rewrote
for this season was having dream end up in the realm
of despair, which was a brief little scene. But I
thought worked really well. Oh, yeah, that was a
brilliant moment. It was terrifying when Loki put
the baby on the fire. I was like, damn, is that how it
happened in the books? Yeah, that's another
fucked up moment. Yeah, it definitely was. Makes
me sad because, like, you know, the kids essence
didn't die, but his mortal form did die. Yeah,
really sad. Moving on to episode nine, the kindly
ones. When Johanna protests working with the
Corinthian, Dream gives her a necklace capable of
uncreating him if she wishes. When Daniel's nanny
suspects Loki is lying about the baby, he kills her
in a secluded alley. Well, Delirium meets with
Destiny seeking aid to find the lost Bernard and
realizing there are currently multiple
destinies. Dream meets with Fiddler's Green and
discusses how Dream has changed. Loki,
meanwhile, reveals to Puck how he changed Daniel
from a mere mortal into a deity by burning away his
human body, allowing him to take on Dream's powers
should the need arise. While also framing Dream so
that Lighta will invoke the kindly ones
vengeance. Matt Heddy, an agent of the kindly
ones, helps Lighta to do so. While the Corinthian
and Johanna track down Loki to his hotel, where
Puck gives them the key to their room before
returning to Ferry. The two rescue Daniel, while
Odin and Thor, who followed Johanna, capture
Loki. After Dream gives Delirium Goldie to help
find Bernard, the kindly ones convince Lighta to
become their avatar of fury and vengeance in
response to Dream killing Orpheus and, as she
believes, her son. When Nala learns that Queen
Titania stole her necklace, she's unable to
retrieve it before Titania summons Dream,
removing him from his realm just as Lighta and the
kindly ones appear there and kill Fiddler's
Green. I wonder what the point of showing multiple
destinies was. It kind of gave the illusion that
another outcome was possible, even though there
was no alternate outcome. I think it was to give the
viewers hope as well as Dream hope. And I think
there were other outcomes possible if Loki had not
done what he did. Interesting. It was actually a
brilliant plan on Loki's behalf. He really
couldn't have screwed Dream over better. There's
a few things that I think the show does better than
the comic. But one of the things they really kind of
messed up on was ruining the surprise that Daniel
was going to be the new Dream, because we didn't
know that was going to happen in the comic until it
actually happened. Really? Yeah. So what was
Dream's preoccupation with the child in the books
then? Well, in the books, it's not revealed until
later what favor he asked of Loki. So at the time you
didn't know that he asked Loki to kidnap Daniel.
You just assumed that Loki kidnapped Daniel just
to do it. Gotcha. That actually would have been a
cool reveal, I think. Yeah, and I don't really
understand why they spoiled it, other than maybe
it would have left audiences questioning what was
going on and why we were watching this kind of
tangential thing going on with Daniel. I do think
it's really cool. And I thought this in the comics
as well that Fury Lighthaul, who is Wonder Woman
and Steve Trevor's daughter in the comics, works
with the Furies to take out Sandman. That was cool.
That was a nice little clawback, although she
wasn't a great character. I don't know if I bought
her wrath as much as I probably should have. There
was a lot left out regarding her story for this
adaptation, which I kind of wish was still there,
but it made it more believable in the comic when she
became the avatar of the kindly ones. Again, still
well done here, just not as well done as the books.
So Lightha is the daughter of the Golden Age,
Wonder Woman and Steve Trevor. And I'm guessing
that they named her after Diana's mother,
Hippolyta, right? Yes, that's correct. The
actress would have made a pretty decent Wonder
Woman, I think. Yeah, I agree. Moving on to Episode
10, Long Live the King. As Lightha continues to
kill denizens of the dreaming, Nala uses her boon
to send Dream back to his realm, where he reveals to
Lightha that Daniel is still alive and is able to
temporarily free her from the kindly ones
influence. When Dream attempts to kill Lightha in
the waking world, Matt Heddy convinces him not to.
Deciding to confront the kindly ones at the edge of
the dreaming, Dream prepares Daniel to take his
place and his staff for his potential end, sending
them away, though Matthew the Raven travels with
him. When the kindly ones inform him that Lightha
is back in the dreaming, destroying his palace
where his staff, including Lucien, Kane, the
Corinthian and Daniel are sheltering, Dream
sends Matthew to bring him his sister, Death, who
is waiting at the palace as well. When Nala
confronts Queen Titania regarding her returning
to the dreaming, Titania gives Nala her sword,
which Nala uses to kill Light as Avatar in the
dreaming, just as Dream admits after a
conversation with his sister that he's ready to
die to protect his loved ones and Death takes him.
It's then that Delirium finds that Bernard was
with Matt Heddy, who herself finds Lighta awake
and reveals that Dream is dead. As the Corinthian
and the others in the palace wonder what has
happened, Daniel reveals himself, aged and
transformed as the new Dream of the Endless. Now, I
remember when I was reading the comics, I expected
this epic battle between the kindly ones and
Sandman. And it was shocking to me that his life
ended with this anti-climactic whimper, but his
death is much more human, I guess you could say,
which is fitting for the character who, as you
mentioned, is like a god who over time changes to
become more human. I was under the impression that
Lighta understood what was going on, that her son
was still alive and had retreated from attacking
the dreaming. I guess I don't understand why she
went back to doing it just suddenly. Yeah, that
whole part was pretty rushed, but essentially the
kindly ones just influenced her again to go back
and finish the job. Interesting. Now, Dream died
just as Nala decapitated Lighta. If he had waited
like 10 more seconds, could he have like delayed
his death? You think? Yes. That's too bad. It's
part of the tragedy. Really, Titania is to blame
for all of this. Yes, Titania. She is the true
villain of the story. There you go. Or at least one
of many. We've gone to episode 11, a tale of
graceful ends as Lucian, Nala, Matthew and the
Corinthian prepare for dreams funeral. Kane
demands Daniel resurrect Abel, whom Lighta
killed. Daniel as Dream obliges as guests arrive
for the wake, including Johanna Constantine,
Hobgadling, Alex Burgess, Nada, as well as the
court of fairy and deities from various
pantheons, questions abound regarding Daniel,
who takes it upon himself to recreate other
various dream entities that Lighta killed,
including Murph Pumpkinhead and Fiddler's
Green, though the latter requests to remain dead,
along with the prior dream, as their deaths had
meaning. The rest of the endless arrive save for
destruction, who shows up later in secret to speak
with Daniel, offering advice and insights.
Destiny, desire, despair, delirium, death and
Lucian take turns speaking at Dream's wake before
his body is sent to drift on a cosmic river of stars.
While Hobbes speaks with death and Johanna and
Corinthian express feelings for one another,
Lighta reunites with her son Daniel, now Dream,
who chooses not to punish her for her role in his
predecessor's death. Daniel then makes Lucian
the Dreaming's Prime Minister before meeting
with Hobb and recalling Dream sharing a drink with
William Shakespeare after his completion of The
Tempest. Finally, Daniel meets his new family,
the Endless, who welcome him as the new Dream. In a
post-credits scene, the kindly ones equate
storytelling to yarn work and read a poetic
fortune about life and rebirth from a fortune
cookie. This episode dragged. It felt really like
an epilogue that didn't need to be. And so I think
just felt too long to me. I could see that. I kind of
felt the same way when reading The Wake, which is
its own volume of comics when I read the series. But
I also have to admit that there's something very
bittersweet and unique about it and that we don't
really get something like this in other stories,
something where we really get to celebrate not
only the main character of the story we just read,
but Shed's new light on how various characters
truly saw Dream. I will totally admit that I got
choked up when I saw Dream's boat kind of turning
into a shooting star because it reminded me
exactly of when I read the comic. How bittersweet
everything was in celebrating what I had read and
being given that time to grieve and mourn in a way.
Seeing Daniel from the outset be very much
everything that Dream could not be for most of his
existence, like forgiving, humble, nurturing
was also important, I think, for audiences to see.
You know, he's innocent and unsure of himself. But
Jacob Anderson gives a fantastic performance as a
grown Daniel of someone trying to mimic Tom
Sturridge's dream, but still making it his own.
Are you familiar with William Shakespeare's The
Tempest at all? No, I never read it, but it sounds
like it's the story of a God choosing to be mortal.
Of a sorcerer choosing to be mortal, yes, who is in
charge of his own realm, which is an island and
essentially choosing to forgive people, all of
his enemies. It was William Shakespeare's last
play that he wrote. And actually, in the comics,
the last issue of the main Sandman story revolves
all around William Shakespeare. Like it's not the
kindly ones who are the final panel. It's
Shakespeare. So I'm really glad that they found a
way to work that into this episode as well, because
I didn't think they were going to. Moving on to the
bonus episode, episode 12, Death, The High Cost of
Living, a young disillusioned journalist named
Sexton Fernival, where it's a suicide note to his
ex-girlfriend Sylvie before being interrupted
by his roommates and her girlfriend, leaving
their apartment so they could be alone. Sexton
meets death at a trash heap in the city, and death
suggests he come to her apartment so she can mend
his shirt, which tore when he fell in the trash.
Upon learning who she is and that today is her one
day out of every 100 years that she gets to spend as a
mortal human, Sexton attempts to leave, but is
captured and threatened by Mad Heddy, who asks
death to find her soul. Reluctantly, Sexton
agrees to follow death as she attempts to
experience as much as she can in one day. After
arriving at a dance club where he used to go with
Sylvie, Sexton meets his roommate there along
with her girlfriend, and he's introduced to
Jackie, who appears fond of him, though he's
preoccupied with the possibility of running into
Sylvie while getting a drink at the bar, the House
DJ and Club promoter Theo notices death's onk
necklace and manages to lure both her and Sexton
into a trap upstairs, where death realizes Theo
summoned death using an occult ritual in an effort
to resurrect his recently deceased girlfriend,
Natalie. Theo is injured while threatening the
two, and Sexton calls an ambulance for him. After
the sun rises, death buys a pendant, which she
gives to Sexton before she expresses how great it
is to be alive before suffering a fatal heart
attack at the end of her 24 hours. Mad Heddy appears
and Sexton learns the pendant contains a photo of
Mad Heddy's daughter from long ago, her soul. Back
at his apartment, Sexton deletes his suicide note
to Sylvie before Jackie arrives and he offers her
some tea. Now, I'm not entirely sure that this
episode needed to be adapted. I'm not actually
familiar with the comic that this adapts. I've
never read it, but it truly did feel supplemental.
Like it wasn't really necessary. Not in the same
way that the first season's episodes, I thought,
were a little bit more necessary. Maybe not the cat
one, but definitely Calliope. Yeah, this one felt
more interesting to me than the cat story from the
first season. It was really just kind of like a
celebration of life, I guess, the whole episode.
And I thought the performances were really solid.
Oh, yeah. Yeah, definitely. So overall, I enjoyed
it. Like I didn't regret watching it like I did the
cat one. Like I remember watching the cow one and
just being like, I want to be done with the show
already. I actually kind of liked the cow one, but I
also just liked that story in the comics. My
impression that time was like, you don't have to
adapt everything. I think they took that message
to heart with this second season. Thankfully,
perhaps. Yeah. Honestly, I would not mind more
bonus episodes. Like if you give me a season three,
just of just nothing but anthological shorts or
maybe some of the overture tales, stuff like that.
It's probably not going to happen, but I wish that
it would because now that Dead Boy Detectives we
know is for sure not moving forward. It feels just
like, well, this is it now. And that makes me sad
because I love Sandman. Yeah, I forgot that Dead
Boy Detectives was in the same universe. And I kind
of missed seeing those guys in this season because
I was hoping we would get a chance to. Yeah,
actually, I thought we were going to see them in
episode two, because one thing that's not
addressed in the season is that when Lucifer
empties hell, basically all of the evil people who
were there show up in the real world as like zombie
ghosts. And that's actually how Charles dies is
some zombie ghost bullies kill him. Oh, OK.
Interesting. Fascinating. So when the angels
take back control of hell, all of them get sent back
there and it kind of saves the world in a way. Yeah,
that was kind of a loose thread. Yeah, probably not
needed for this season. But what would have been a
great season to have Dead Boy Detectives? Yeah, it
would have been. Yeah, that would have been great.
But back to this show and this season, again, I'm
sad that it's over. It was a focused adaptation
that masterfully threads themes of love, growth
and mortality into a bittersweet and profoundly
existential tapestry. Again, it's a master work
adaptation, in my opinion. And I'm giving it five
out of five stars, a fresh rating on Ron Tomatoes.
Damn, you didn't even give the first season five
out of five stars. No, because the first season was
really just an introduction to this world. But I
think this season, again, did a really good job of
weaving together all the different threads to
really capture the essence of the themes and the
story of the comic, which is a story that I feel
should be adapted for other mediums, because the
more people that get to experience it, the better.
It's a worthwhile story, for sure. I'll agree with
your rating. I think I would probably have gone
4.5, but I can absolutely see the case made for
five, considering how transcendental and just
well written the story is, not only in the comic
books, but how it's adapted here. I don't think I
can recommend it anymore than I already do. So five
stars, then. Nice. I'm really glad you liked it. I
really hoped you would. I hope everyone likes it as
much as I do. I know a lot of critics don't because I
don't know why they're just petty as fuck,
probably because this season doesn't stand as
well on its own without seeing season one, maybe
either that or they're just like comic purists or
they never read the comic. I don't know. They're
weird. I'm right. They're wrong. This show is
awesome. And hopefully if you made it this far,
you've already seen it and already know that. But
that does it for this review. A.J .9K help close us
out. Thanks for listening to Dynamic Jewel. Visit
the show's website at dynamicjewel.com and
follow us on Instagram at Dynamic Jewel podcast.
You can support the show on Patreon at patreon.com
slash dynamic jewel and joining a tier that works
for you or by rating and reviewing Dynamic Jewel on
Apple podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser or on our
website. Don't forget to listen to the other shows
in the Dynamite podcast network, including Max
Destruction, Senjo World and Console Combat. In
our next episode, we're getting back to the duels,
guys. We're going to find out who would win in a
fight between the Green Lantern love interest
character, Star Sapphire and Ironheart, who
recently had her own Disney Plus television
series. Yeah, this is sort of a late time coming tie
into that. But that does it for this episode. We
want to give a big thanks to our executive
producers, John Starosky, Zachary Hepburn,
Justin Belcom, Mickey Muthinkeyan, Nathaniel
Wagner, Levi Yatyn, Austin Wieselowski, A.J.
Dunkerley, Nick Obanto, Scott Camacho, Gil
Camacho, Adam Spees, Dean Maleski, Devin Davis,
Joseph Kirsting, Josh Liner, Mike Williams,
Oscar Galvez and Paul Graves for helping make this
podcast possible. And we'll talk to you guys next
week up up and away. True believers. I reveal to you
that I am the youngest of the endless. I have gone by
many names, but my siblings know me as dongle,
dookie, doink, derp, a dumpy, dibble, the third.
You would do well not to forget it.