This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi, welcome to
the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin
brother, Marvelous Joe. And in this episode, we
are doing a surprise Team Duel episode between
DC's Birds of Prey and Marvel's A-Force. Yeah,
we're doing this special team duel in honor of
Women's History Month, so to celebrate all the
women's out there, here's your duel of badass
female superhero teams. Not gonna lie, I'm a
little nervous about this because I know A-Force
is essentially female Avengers and Birds of Prey
tends to be a little bit more street level, so we'll
see how it goes later on in this episode. Before
that, we are not going to break down the comic book
movie news from this past week because there isn't
any, not anything concrete anyway. Yeah, we did
get news that Sadie Sink has been cast in the new
Spider-Man movie, but there's nothing really to
discuss there because we don't know who she's
playing. But we will be having a question of the
week later on this episode. As always, we list our
segment times and our episode description, so
feel free to check out the show notes if you want to
skip ahead to a particular topic. Our
artificially intelligent duel simulator, AJ9K,
has a quick message for our listeners, so listen
up. Why hello there. Do you want even more from this
podcast? Then become a part of the Dynamic Duel
community on Patreon where you can choose from
three tiers. The Dynamic 2.0 tier gives you access
to our Discord chat server, the Fantastic Four
tier gives you two bonus episodes each month, and
the X-Force tier makes you an executive producer
of this show. Lastly, the Diner Mike podcast
network tier lets you create your own podcast
using this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe
will help you develop your show, provide graphic
support and consultation, and get you simulation
results. Pitch the twins your ideas via email at
dynamicduelpodcast at gmail.com. Check it out at
patreon.com/dynamicduel. Pip pip cheerio.
Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast. Guys, be sure to tune into the other
shows on the Dynamite podcast network this week,
including Max Destruction, which pits your
favorite action heroes from film and television
against each other. This Wednesday, host Scotty
and Gilly are finding out who would win in a fight
between Disney's Hercules and Maui from Moana. On
the Send Your World podcast, host Zachary Hepburn
speculates on fights between fan favorite anime
and manga characters. On Thursday, Zach is going
to discuss who would win between Vasto Lorde
Ichigo from Bleach and Six Tail Kyuubi from Naruto.
And on the Konsole Kombat podcast, host John and
Dean simulate battles between popular video game
characters. In yesterday's episode, they
reviewed Dungeons and Dragons, Honor Among
Thieves. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or click the
link in our show notes to listen to all of the shows
in the DynaMic podcast network. But with that out
of the way, quick to the no prize. A no prize is an
award Marvel used to give out to fans. Our version,
the Dynamic Dual No Prize, is a digital award we
post on Instagram for the person that we feel gave
the best answer to our question of the week. Last
week, we asked you guys, what is your favorite
Marvel and DC comics crossover and why? And this is
coming off the news that Marvel and DC are going to
put out two one shot crossover issues later on this
year sometime in 2025. We don't have any of the
specific details on it, but we love the idea and
thought it was worth asking about. Yeah, we got
three answers for this question. So let's break
down our two honorable mentions before revealing
this week's no prize winner. Our first honorable
mention goes to by DearBangora who said, Hello,
Dynamic Dual. I think the best Marvel DC crossover
is Batman versus Punisher. The fact that both
characters have strict codes that are vastly
different, but that unites them as well. I also
like that we can see the creation of Red Hood coming
from this crossover being a mix of both
characters. So for me, Punisher versus Batman,
the dichotomy and the difference between the
characters and their code and their will makes
this comic book. Yeah, it looks like he got cut off
there, but he's referring to the Punisher Batman
deadly knights crossover comic book in which
Punisher pays a visit to Gotham City. And if that
concept sounds intriguing to you, hell yeah, it
was. I really like that comic book, even though,
you know, Batman kind of beats a shit out of
Punisher towards the end and kind of like humbles
him. Punisher does get in a good line where he tells
Batman that he and the Joker deserve each other. So
I like that. Yeah, Punisher also makes Joker
essentially shit himself, too. So that was also a
great moment from the comic. Yeah, it was a great
look at just like the two moralities of the
character. You know, Punisher, he kills his bad
guys and he basically saw Batman as liable and all
of the Joker's murders because he wouldn't kill
the Joker. You know, it's always been an
interesting debate. And it was one that was
explored in that comic. So that philosophical
aspect alone, I think, sets it a level above quite a
few DC Marvel crossovers. Great answer by
DearBangora. Our next honorable mention goes to
Mason Thompson. Who said? Hey, what's up? It's
Mason. And I would have to say if it was my favorite
Marvel and DC crossover, I'd just do the two,
probably be one Batman Humboldt Punisher,
because I was stuff and or one if it's just DC, then
it would be Batman when he went over to Ninja
Turtles. Because that is always so cool to see him
fight with like all the turtles and yeah. Yeah, I'm
not sure if Mason is referring again to the
Punisher Batman deadly knights crossover,
because I'm kind of ashamed to say that Batman has
actually beat the shit out of Punisher in multiple
crossovers. I remember in J.L .A. Avengers,
Punisher was in the middle of killing some bad guys
while Batman was doing reconnaissance in the
Marvel Universe. And then Batman saw him doing
this and then broke through the warehouse and then
beat the shit out of Punisher to keep him from
killing everybody. I mean, is it any surprise,
though? Like Punisher is not at the level of
martial arts finesse that Batman is. He doesn't
need to when he has bullets. And plus, he's he's a
pretty damn good fighter. He's a really good
fighter, but he's also like 70. And Batman's like
not anymore. But no, Batman and the Teenage Mutant
Ninja Turtles crossover was also awesome. They
made a movie about it. And we actually did a review
of that film on a guest spot for the Ready to Retro
podcast where we talk all about that movie and the
comic. It was good time. So make sure to check that
out if you haven't. Yeah, we love the Ready to
Retro, guys. So great answer, Mason Thompson. The
winner of this week's No Prize is Christopher
Minotti, who said. Hi, guys, this is Christopher
Minotti. My favorite would have to be the four
issues of Marvel vs. DC, because it's exactly what
comic book fans love. The discussion of which side
is stronger, whose characters would win more
fights. And I feel like those four issues, it
showed that while sometimes DC character will win
and sometimes a Marvel character will win. In the
end, Marvel will always lose to Superman. Now, if I
remember correctly in that miniseries, Marvel
actually won a majority of those matches, but it
was total bullshit because a few of the winners
were determined by fan votes and there's no way
Wolverine at Storm would have beaten Lobo and
Wonder Woman. Yeah, they would have. It showed in
the comic just how that would have happened. It
literally didn't, though. Like Wolverine and
Lobo go behind a bar and then Wolverine just stands
up and smokes a cigar. It's like, what happened
behind that bar? He gutted him like he said he
would. That's what happened. OK, so he did
something that wouldn't kill Lobo. Gotcha. You
sound like a fucking whiny loser. Maybe don't be so
jealous about Marvel's victories. I'm super
bitter about it. I don't care. No, that crossover
event was a defining moment, I think, for my
Jonathan's childhood. I remember going to the
comic book store and getting the big Marvel versus
DC poster that they were selling there along with
the comic books. And it was just a magical time,
really. And in many ways, influenced us into doing
this podcast like 20 years later. Oh, absolutely.
Yeah, if you guys haven't listened to our guest
spot on the Rankers, where we talk about why DC or
Marvel is better, definitely check that episode
out as well, because I talk about how the DC versus
Marvel mini series influenced us when we first
started reading comics. But great answer,
Christopher. You win this week's No Prize. If
you're the listener who won a shot at winning your
own No Prize, stay tuned to later on in this episode
when we'll be asking another question of the week
and know that that's done onto the question of the
week. What character do you think Sadie Sink will
be playing in the upcoming fourth Spider-Man film
from Marvel Studios? And we received a word over
this past week that Sadie Sink has been cast. We
just don't know what role she's playing. There's a
lot of conjecture out there, but we want to hear
what you guys think and why. Record your answer at
dynamicdool.com by clicking on the red
microphone button in the bottom right hand corner
of the screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long and don't forget to leave your name in case we
include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a dynamic
dual No Prize that will post to Instagram. Be sure
to answer before March 22nd. But let's go ahead and
move on to the main event of this episode, where we
find out who would win in a battle between the all
female teams of Birds of Prey and a force. OK, Birds
of Prey versus a force. As we mentioned earlier,
these are two all female teams from DC and Marvel
respectively. Birds of Prey, notoriously, you
could say, had a live action film, but it was really
just a Harley Quinn film. A force has not had its own
movie. No, but they also notoriously had a moment
in Avengers Endgame where a lot of the female
superheroes that were fighting against Thanos in
the climactic battle joined together to help get
the Infinity Gauntlet over to Ant-Man and the Wasp
as they were powering up the Quantum Tunnel. A lot
of people found it pandering, but I actually loved
it as a comic book fan because I was like, it's
fucking a force. They're like doing an Easter egg
for that. I guess if you didn't know the comics and
just thought that they were doing it for girl
power, then I can maybe see where they were coming
from. But I personally enjoyed that moment in that
movie. Yeah, I didn't know what a force was at the
time when I saw that. So I definitely was like, oh,
look, they're all posing together. Girl power.
Yeah, I think the boys' television show made fun of
it, too, at some point. But they don't know they're
just fucking cynical. I mean, let's be real. That
scene was kind of better than the entirety of Birds
of Prey, though. You're not wrong. And Birds of
Prey wasn't even that bad. It was just a really bad
Birds of Prey film. Right. I mean, the movie should
have been called Harley Quinn and the Birds of
Prey. The Birds of Prey team shouldn't have taken
center stage because they really weren't the
focus and they weren't really adapted that well.
Right, exactly. So if the only thing you know about
the Birds of Prey is the movie, forget everything
you know about the Birds of Prey. Yeah, the origin
for Birds of Prey in the comic books is way
different from the film. But I got to say the origin
for a force is almost non-existent in the comic
books. They just manifested as a team within the
alternate reality of battle worlds that Dr. Doom
created. So there's no real origin story for a
force, but they do have, you know, a history. OK,
well, that's almost like Birds of Prey, too,
because they didn't even call themselves Birds of
Prey or think of themselves as an official team
until like issue 80. Oh, wow. Well, I can't wait to
hear all about their backstory as we go into that in
a bit here. But to explain the methodology behind
our duels, let's go to our sentient dual
simulator, Alfred Jarvis, 9000. Adrian and I, K
tell our listeners how you go about determining a
winner in our dual matchups. Yes, of course, sir.
The way I determine a winner between the two teams
is by running 1000 Monte Carlo simulations
between every character on each team using their
statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation is a
probabilistic model used to determine outcomes
through random sampling. In this case, I
randomize the statistics along a normal
distribution as a way to simulate the many
variables that can occur during battle. The stat
parameters are based on the official Marvel power
grid from which the DC characters statistics are
extrapolated. Additional stat categories are
included such as range, damage potential,
versatility and perception in order to create a
more detailed and accurate simulation. The
results of the 49,000 simulations provide a
percentage of wins for each character on both
teams. The team with the higher average win rate is
declared the victor as they have a higher
probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither team should win 100%
of the matches. The comic book stories have shown
that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman, so the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks to J9K.
Before we run the simulations, though, we like to
break down each team's histories and rosters
before improvising a scenario on how we imagine
one of the many simulations would play out beat for
beat. And I believe it's my turn to go first with the
DC team's backstory. So let me tell you about Birds
of Prey. The Birds of Prey began as a partnership
between Barbara Gordon, the former Batgirl, now
operating as the information broker known as
Oracle, and Dynal Lance, the martial arts expert
and vigilante known as Black Canary, each of whom
you can learn more about in their respective duels
against Hawkeye, Kate Bishop, and Black Widow.
Now after suffering a spinal injury at the hands of
the Joker, Barbara reinvented herself as Oracle,
creating a vast intelligence network that
provided real-time information to superheroes
worldwide. Initially, she sought out Powergirl
as her first field agent, but after an early
mission resulted in tragic casualties,
Powergirl severed ties with Oracle, leaving
Barbara searching for a more compatible
operative. Oracle eventually turned to Black
Canary, a veteran crime fighter who had lost her
Canary cry, but continued patrolling the streets
as a highly skilled combatant. Operating from the
Gotham City clock tower, Oracle and Black Canary
formed a formidable duo, with Dynah handling
field operations and Barbara coordinating
commissions behind the scenes. Their
partnership thrived, despite occasional
ideological differences, and over time, Oracle
expanded her intelligence network to include a
growing roster of agents. The team solidified
when Black Canary was captured by the villainous
Savant, an information broker and former
vigilante who sought to control Gotham's
underworld. Unable to call upon the Bat Family for
assistance, Oracle reached out to Huntress, a
brutal and relentless vigilante with ties to the
city's criminal underbelly. Working together,
Oracle and Huntress successfully rescued Black
Canary, leading Barbara to formally recruit
Huntress as a full-time agent. And you, of course,
can learn more about Huntress in her dual episode
against Jessica Jones. Soon after, Lady Black
Hawk, a time-displaced World War II pilot and
former member of the Black Hawk Squadron, joined
the team after a mission involving a hijacked
aircraft. Though she was originally an outlier
due to her outdated views and hard drinking
demeanor, Lady Black Hawk quickly became an
invaluable member, serving as the team's pilot
and transport specialist. With its core trio of
Oracle, Black Canary and Huntress, along with
Lady Black Hawk providing air support, the Birds
of Prey expanded their operations, tackling
threats that other hero teams ignored or were
unable to address. They faced off against
criminals such as Cheshire, Senator Pullman, and
the Blackmailer Savant while also dealing with
espionage, human trafficking, and
international crime syndicates. For years, the
Birds of Prey operated from Oracle's Command
Center inside the Gotham Clock Tower, but their
headquarters came under attack during a
full-scale gang war. Black Mask, the crime lord
who had taken control of Gotham's underworld,
targeted Oracle's operations, leading an
assault that resulted in the Clock Tower's
destruction. Forced to abandon Gotham, Barbara
temporarily disbanded the team and went into
hiding. After a brief time operating covertly,
Oracle reassembled the Birds of Prey, now
stationed aboard the ARE-1, a high-tech mobile
command aircraft outfitted with cutting-edge
surveillance and tactical equipment. From
there, they took on high-risk missions across the
globe, tackling threats ranging from
super-powered crime syndicates to political
conspiracies. Seeking a more stable base of
operations, Oracle relocated the team to
Metropolis, but their presence in Superman's
city led to clashes with local authorities and
rival vigilante groups. Eventually, they
settled in Platinum Flats, a high-tech city on the
West Coast with deep ties to organized crime and
corporate corruption. With a growing roster that
now included Big Barda, Manhunter, Gypsy, and
Judo Master, the Birds of Prey fought against the
city's underground syndicates while facing
opposition from the metahuman criminal
underworld. During their time in Platinum Flats,
the team found themselves targeted by Spy
Smasher, the alias of Katarina Armstrong, a
former government operative and Barbara's
childhood rival. Katarina sought to take control
of the Birds of Prey, leveraging her influence to
force Oracle out. This led to a dramatic
confrontation where Barbara challenged the Spy
Smasher to a one-on-one fight, with the winner
taking control of the organization. Despite her
physical limitations, Oracle outmaneuvered Spy
Smasher and won the fight. However, Katarina
refused to honor their agreement. Before she
could make a move against Oracle, the Birds of Prey
assembled in full force alongside numerous
allies including Black Canary, Wildcat, and even
the assassin Lady Shiva. Overwhelmed and
outmatched, Spy Smasher had no choice but to back
down, and Oracle secured the Birds of Prey's
independence once and for all. As Oracle's
intelligence network grew, so did her list of
enemies. Chief among them was the Calculator, a
cyber-criminal and information broker who
sought to unmask Oracle and eliminate her as a
threat. Their ongoing digital war escalated when
the Calculator attempted to harness fragments of
the Anti-Life Equation, a cosmic formula capable
of controlling minds. To counter his growing
power, Oracle led an all-out cyber assault
enlisting allies such as Cassandra Kane,
Huntress, and even members of the Justice League
to dismantle his operations. Though she
successfully thwarted Calculator's plans, the
battle left her questioning her own
effectiveness, leading her to temporarily
disband the Birds of Prey once again to reassess
her role. Following Batman's apparent death,
Oracle resumed operations in Gotham City,
assisting Nightwing in maintaining order as
criminals seized the opportunity to expand their
influence. She reassembled the Birds of Prey with
a new lineup that included the Medi-Human Bruiser
Hawk, the Pacifist Warrior Dove, and a returning
Countress. Establishing a new headquarters in
Cord Tower, during this time, Black Canary left
the team to raise her adopted daughter, Sin, but
eventually returned when the Birds faced a
resurgence of organized crime in Gotham. The team
also recruited two new members, Black Alice, a
teenage sorceress with the ability to
temporarily steal magical powers, and Misfit, a
homeless runaway with teleportation abilities
whom Oracle took under her wing. As the Birds of
Prey continued to expand, they took on major
players in the criminal underworld, including an
underground Medi-Human trafficking gang and the
growing influence of the villainous
organization known as the Secret Six. Their
battles led to high stakes confrontations
against figures like Harley Quinn, Talia El Ghul,
and her League of Assassins. Following the
Flashpoint event, the history of the Birds of Prey
was rebooted, and the team was reestablished as a
covert operations unit based in Gotham City.
Black Canary formed a new incarnation of the
group, recruiting Starling, Batgirl, Katana,
and Poison Ivy for a series of high-risk missions.
Their early cases involved stopping a villain
known as Choke, who used nanotechnology to turn
people into living bombs. The team faced internal
strife when Poison Ivy attempted to manipulate
them into joining her crusade against
environmental criminals. Katana ultimately
killed Ivy in self-defense, leaving the team
shaken. Shortly after, Starling betrayed them to
both Mr. Freeze and the Court leading to further
fractures within the group. After learning that
her presumed dead ex-husband, Kurt Lance, was
being held captive by the terrorist organization
Basilisk, Black Canary went rogue to rescue him.
This put her at odds with Amanda Waller, who had
manipulated the team from behind the scenes. When
Ras Al Ghul entered the conflict offering Black
Canary a Lazarus pet serum in exchange for her
cooperation, she turned him down, setting off a
chain of events that nearly led to the team's
destruction. In the latest incarnation of the
team, Black Canary has once again taken charge,
forming a new squad consisting of Cassandra Kane,
Big Barda, Zellet, and Harley Quinn. Now
team-wise, I knew that Barbara Gordon would be a
no-brainer to include on my 7-person roster,
since she's the entire reason the team exists.
She's joining as Batgirl, not Oracle though, as
Batgirl has been a member in recent years in the
comics. Black Canary and Huntress were also
Shoe-ins considering they and Barbara form the
core team of Birds of Prey. I decided to also go with
Powergirl, since she was technically Barbara's
first field agent prior to recruiting Black
Canary, as well as Dove, one half of Hawk and Dove,
though replacing Hawk will be Hawk Girl, who has
helped the team against the Seeker 6 and is a bird of
prey in her own right. For my 7th and final team
member, I could have gone with Lady Black Hawk, who
I would consider to be a 4th core member if there
ever was one, but there have been much more
interesting characters on the Birds of Prey team,
especially ones that I knew wouldn't drag down the
team's stats like Lady Black Hawk would, who's
pretty weak. In the end, I decided to go with Vixen
as my final team member, as she's a powerhouse that
I believe will help raise what is traditionally a
street level team like Birds of Prey to a force
level. So that's my team. Batgirl, Black Canary,
Huntress, Powergirl, Dove, Hawk Girl, and Vixen.
Has Vixen ever been associated with the team? Yes,
she has been a field agent for Oracle in the past.
She helped Huntress bring down some cults in the
Pacific Northwest. Okay, all right. That's a
pretty damn good lineup. It was interesting to
hear how for the majority of their existence, the
Birds of Prey were supported and founded by
Barbara Gordon as Oracle. It's kind of hard to know
what the team functions like when Barbara Gordon
is Batgirl as opposed to Oracle. Well, she just
does all of her information brokering in the
field. She still has computer gadgets attached to
her suit and stuff like that. She's definitely
still like the brains of the team, just that now
she's fighting alongside them. That's pretty
cool. I like that. It was also interesting to see
that Harley Quinn has become a member of the team. I
feel like they only did that because of the movie. I
agree. Yeah, 100%. That's the case. I was actually
thinking of including Harley Quinn on this team
since she does have that tie in in the general
public's mind considering she was in the movie.
But I already used Harley Quinn in the Suicide
Squad versus Defenders team doled that we did
earlier. Yeah, that's right. Well, let me go ahead
and get into a forces backstory. A Force was an all
female superhero team that emerged in the
alternate reality of Battle World, a patchwork
planet created by Dr. Doom following the
destruction of the multiverse. They operated as
the defenders of Arcadia, a utopian island
territory within Battle World under the
leadership of She-Hulk, who also served as
Arcadia's appointed Baroness. Wait, is Arcadia
an all female island? No, they had dudes there, but
it was just run by women. But it's an island utopia.
Yeah. Oh, just like them. It's not like them. RIP
off. Anyway, the founding roster included over 40
women heroes, including Captain Marvel, Ms.
Marvel, Spider Woman, Medusa, Dazzler, Nico
Minoru, and Mockingbird to The team protected
Arcadia from a Megalodon attack off the island's
coast. They successfully subdued the creature,
but Miss America hurled it beyond the massive
shield wall that separated Arcadia from the
zombie infested Deadlands and inadvertently
damaging the barrier. This act violated Dr.
Doom's laws and despite She-Hulk's protests, the
Thor core, who were the elite enforcers of Doom's
rule, arrived to arrest America Chavez. She was
sentenced to exile, forced to serve as guardian of
the shield for the rest of her life. In response,
She-Hulk tasked Arcadia's undersea residents,
including Namor, Namorita, and Namora, with
investigating the origins of the Megalodon
attack. Meanwhile, Nico Minoru discovered a
mysterious girl who had fallen from the sky. A
female variant of Loki advised Nico to bring the
mysterious girl to Ape Horse for further
examination. As the team tried to determine her
origins, portals began opening across Arcadia,
allowing dangerous creatures to enter the
territory. One such portal unleashed a mutant
Sentinel, which Ape Horse managed to destroy with
the unexpected help of the mysterious girl.
Medusa immediately accused her of being
responsible for the portals, but She-Hulk
refused to accept this claim without proof. When
another portal opened, She-Hulk chose to travel
through it, seeking answers. She-Hulk arrived in
the Sentinel territories where she was pursued by
the robots and confronted by members of the Thor
Corps for trespassing across battleworld's
borders. She fought off the Thors and returned to
Arcadia, realizing that the portals were created
with magic from Arcadia, suggesting that someone
within Ape Horse had betrayed them. Before the
team could investigate further, the Thor Corps
arrived in Arcadia, demanding She-Hulk's
surrender. Medusa sacrificed herself to repel
the Thors, buying time for She-Hulk and her allies
to regroup. With the team now branded outlaws,
Loki seized the opportunity to climb the portal.
A-Force quickly deduced that Loki was the true
traitor responsible for creating the portals to
destabilize She-Hulk's rule. Before she could be
crowned Baroness, A-Force launched an attack
exposing her deception. In retaliation, Loki
unleashed one final assault, using her powers to
breach the shield barrier, allowing the hordes of
undead from the deadlands to invade Arcadia.
A-Force joined by the remaining forces of
Arcadia, including the members of the Thorkor,
the X-Men and the Submariner's forces, mounted a
desperate defense against the undead. As the
zombies overwhelmed them, the mysterious girl,
now named Singularity, sacrificed herself to
save her new friends. She absorbed the horde into
the pocket dimension within herself and ascended
into the sky before exploding in a flash of light.
The battle was won, but Arcadia had suffered heavy
losses, and A-Force was left forever changed.
Following the end of Battleworld and the
restoration of the multiverse, Singularity
re-emerged in the primary reality of Earth 616,
but none of the heroes she had known on Battleworld
remembered her. Her arrival was detected by Alpha
Flight, whom it took her for a threat. Seeking
familiarity, Singularity located Captain
Marvel, believing her to be the same version she
had known back in Arcadia. However, before Carol
Danvers could comprehend what was happening,
another cosmic entity named Antimatter arrived,
pursuing Singularity across Earth. Singularity
fled to New York City where she encountered
She-Hulk. Recognizing her from Arcadia, she
sought her aid, but Antimatter attacked them
both. The Inhuman Queen Medusa intervened with a
force of Inhuman soldiers and detained
Singularity, believing her to be a danger. But
when Antimatter killed one of the Inhumans,
Medusa, along with She-Hulk, fought back, using
Inhuman technology to teleport Antimatter to the
moon to buy themselves time. Realizing the need
for a stronger force, Singularity brought the
group to Japan where they enlisted the aid of Niko
Minoru. As Antimatter reappeared, Niko used the
staff of one to temporarily banish him. Seeking a
more effective means of defeating their foe,
Captain Marvel devised a plan to use concentrated
light energy against Antimatter. To implement
this strategy, they sought out Dazzler in Miami
and recruited her to join them. Dazzler struck
Antimatter with a powerful burst of light while
She-Hulk and Medusa attempted to contain him,
allowing Captain Marvel time to charge a
containment device. However, Antimatter proved
too powerful, overloading the system and
escaping. Niko then cast a spell to remove
Antimatter's ability to track Singularity,
allowing them to regroup aboard the Alpha Flight
Space Station. There, scientists analyzed the
data from their Miami battle and developed a
device capable of dismantling Antimatter.
However, it was discovered that Antimatter and
Singularity were quantum entangled, meaning
that destroying him would also destroy her. Due to
this revelation, She-Hulk attempted to reason
with Antimatter, but their negotiations failed.
In retaliation, Antimatter critically wounded
Dazzler. Enraged, Singularity blamed herself
and left to confront Antimatter alone. She-Hulk,
Minoru, and Captain Marvel followed her to the
Blue Area of the Moon where Medusa planted a bomb
that would destroy Antimatter. As the device
detonated, Dazzler appeared, teleporting
Singularity to safety in an act that severed their
entanglement. Antimatter was finally defeated,
but the battle had left A-Force shaken. A-Force
remained active for some time, but their battles
grew increasingly dire. A-Force found itself
divided by ideological differences during the
Second Superhero Civil War. Captain Marvel,
siding with Ulysses Cain's ability to predict
future crimes, turned against Nico Minoru when
the Inhuman Prophet foresaw that she would one day
kill a woman named Alice. Nico fled to Ure,
Colorado, where she encountered Elsa
Bloodstone, who was battling a monstrous
infestation that was transforming the town's
residents into insects. When Alice was found, it
was revealed that she had inadvertently caused
the outbreak, and only her death could reverse the
transformation. Nico refused to kill Alice,
leading to a deadly confrontation in which her
A-Force teammates, who tracked her to Colorado,
were also infected. Ultimately, Nico cast a spell
that took Alice's life undoing the infection. The
moral and ideological rift between Captain
Marvel and Nico Minoru deepened following this
incident. The strain within the team, coupled
with She-Hulk's temporary retirement and
Medusa's departure into space, led to A-Force's
eventual dissolution, and the remaining members
drifted apart. Though A-Force no longer operated
as a formal team, their legacy remains to this day
in comics as a testament to the strength of the deep
bonds they forged while together. And that's
their backstory. For this team duel,
seven-person roster, I'll be going with some of
the primary members of A-Force, along with some of
the members from the team's start and battle
worlds that pairs best with your Birds of Prey
team. This was pretty easy, since almost every
Marvel superhero was part of A-Force at that time.
To start with, I went with She-Hulk, Captain
Marvel, Spider Woman, Jessica Drew, I should say,
Nico Minoru, and Miss Marvel. All of whom you can
learn more about in their own individual duels. I
should note that since our Miss Marvel duel, the
character underwent a slight power upgrade to
match her abilities in the movies and shows. It was
revealed that Kamala Khan was an inhuman who
underwent pterogenesis prior to the awakening of
her mutant gene, which is the power to create
purple hard-light constructs. Wait, really?
Yeah, so she'll be having that power in this duel.
For the final two spots on the A-Force roster, I
went with characters who haven't had their own
individual duels, but were prominent heroes that
paired well with your team. The first one is
Dazzler, who I'm pairing with your Black Canary.
Dazzler is a mutant whose real name is Alice in
Blair, who has the ability to absorb sound
vibrations and convert them into light energy,
including lasers, strobes, and all kinds of light
effects. She's a singing pop star in the books,
basically the Taylor Swift of comics, and she's
famous for using her powers to generate laser
light shows during her concerts. She's been a part
of the X-Men and X-Factor, and was shown in live
action in the Dark Phoenix movie played by Halston
Sage. For the final spot on the A-Force team, I'm
going with Mockingbird, who I'm pairing against
your Huntress. Now Mockingbird is one of Shield's
top spies and scientists with a skill set similar
to Black Widows. She's an expert biochemist and
martial artist who famously uses two steel alloy
battle staves, or billy clubs, that she can screw
together to extend into a bow staff or vaulting
pole. She was a founding member of the West Coast
Avengers, and she's been depicted a few times in
live action, first as Hawkeye's Wife, played by
Laura Cardellini in the MCU. The character was
also played more accurately, and really to
perfection, in the Agents of Shield television
show by Adrian Palakie. So to reiterate, my
7-person roster for A-Force is She-Hulk, Captain
Marvel, Ms. Marvel, Spider Woman, Nico Minoru,
Dazzler, and Mockingbird. And since we like to
create pairings for these team duels in order to
keep things on an even kill basically and make sure
that the matches are fair, the pairings go as
follows. Captain Marvel and Power Girl, She-Hulk
and Hawke Girl, Dazzler and Black Canary, Nico
Minoru and Batgirl, Mockingbird and Huntress,
Ms. Marvel and Vixen, and Spider Woman and Dove.
Yeah, the Batgirl, Nico pairing kind of throws me,
but the rest of them are great, I think. Well, I
figured what Batgirl lacks in powers she makes up
in intelligence, and what Nico lacks in
experience she makes up in having a really cool
power set. Yeah, well, we'll see how it goes. So you
haven't done duels with Dazzler and Mockingbird.
I know about Dazzler, but I didn't know much about
Mockingbird. It sounds like she's essentially
just Black Widow who also uses battle staves. Not
commonly, though. Like, I know that in Avengers
Age of Ultron, the director, Joss Whedon, gave
Scarlett Johansson's Black Widow these Billy
Clubs, and she's really used them in all the
Avengers movies since then, you know, until
Avengers Endgame. I feel like he kind of stole them
from Mockingbird in order to make Black Widow a
more physical threat against characters like
Ultron. But the Batons, those are typically known
to be used by Mockingbird, not Black Widow. I won't
say that she hasn't used, like, tonfas from time to
time, but that's really Mockingbird's signature
weapon. Okay, well, I can't wait to find out how
this turns out. So, here's where we're at. We're at
the final stage of the game. Now that we've got
their histories and abilities out of the way,
let's speculate on how one of the thousands of
simulated matches will go. The winner is
determined by simulations, not the speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how this fight could play
out. Agent NK, what are the rules of our
speculation? Well, I should say there are no
rules. The teams must earn victory on their own
merit. Alright, then let's get into it. Birds of
Prey and A-Force meet on the battlefield. Who goes
first? I think Black Canary would go first. So,
right away, she's gonna blast all of them with a
Canary cry, sending all of them flying backward.
No, because Dazzler, she's at the front of the team
when this happens, and she's gonna absorb the
entirety of Black Canary's Canary cry. And, like,
you just amped Dazzler up to, like, 11. She turns
all of that sound energy into light energy, and she
spins around on her roller skates and, you know,
strikes a pose, and she's like, let's go, girls!
And, like, cue the EDM music, because this fight
just turned into a dance rave, and A-Force is gonna
charge at the Birds of Prey while Dazzler is
shooting out these laser lights, and these lasers
are gonna, like, cut Black Girl's utility belt in
half, and one of Hawk Girl's wings just gets
clipped, and I'm pretty sure that Power Girl is
bald now. She was given a laser haircut. Okay, I saw
this coming. Not the haircut. I mean, Power Girl
has Kryptonian hair, so... But you're dealing
with some of the most agile characters in DC with
the Birds of Prey team. So they're actually
dodging Dazzler's lasers with, like, flips and
shit, and Black Girl's gonna counter with a smoke
pellet, hiding her team, so Dazzler and the rest of
A-Force can't see where the Birds of Prey are. All
they're gonna see is a set of glowing tiger eyes
just before Vixen leaps out of the smoke with a
tiger aura, pouncing on Niko Minoru and just
slashing her ribbons. Okay, alright, well, okay.
Niko gets hurt, but before she gets turned into
ribbons, that's when She-Hulk leaps in, just
straight up grabs Vixen by her waistband and
throws her into space. Okay. And then Niko casts a
healing spell on herself using the Staff of One.
She's gonna say, like, Medic, and she's good to go.
She's back in this fight. Meanwhile, Captain
Marvel is gonna energize her body to, like, light
her way through this smoke screen that Batgirl
created, and she sees Power Girl, and she's gonna
give her one of those good old-fashioned
energy-powered punches right in her face,
sending her reeling backward. Oh, it's Power
Girl, so yeah, she'll take the punch and then she's
gonna give as good as she got right back towards
Captain Marvel, so they're just gonna start
trading blows in the sky, I guess. Okay, alright.
Speaking of sky, Miss Marvel is gonna stretch,
like, 50 feet tall, and with this embigged hand,
she's just gonna backhand Hawk Girl and swat her
out of the sky, sending her crashing into the
ground. Okay, well, yeah, Hawk Girl probably was
in the sky, but her enhanced senses actually
alerted her to Miss Marvel's attack, so she's just
gonna loop right around that giant hand and slam
Miss Marvel right in the face with her energized
mace that's gonna cause her giant body to fall and
crash into the ground. Alright, Miss Marvel's
nose is probably caved in, but she's elastic,
right? So she's gonna topple down to the ground,
she catches her fall by creating a purple
construct to cushion it, and while she's, like,
reforming her nose, healing that up, she's gonna
throw up another purple energy construct in the
air, like a wall that Hawk Girl just flies into,
like a bird into a window, alright, and it just
cracks her neck, probably one of her wings. Jeez.
Hawk Girl falls to the ground, like, splat, and she
is out of this match. What? Dang, okay. Um, I guess
she's out. Meanwhile, Huntress, she fires a bolt
from her crossbow at Mockingbird right through
her foot, and that's gonna pin Mockingbird right
to the ground. No, because Mockingbird knocks
this crossbow bolt out of the air with one of her
battle staves, and then she's gonna screw her
clubs together to form one long staff that she's
gonna use to vault herself over to Huntress and,
like, leap, snap, kick her right in the back of her
head. Yeah, except Huntress blocks
Mockingbird's kick with her own bow staff, and the
two face off using their own staffs. It's like two
windmills fighting against each other.
Eventually, though, Huntress is gonna get in
close enough to fire a quick crossbow bolt point
blank into Mockingbird's chest, eliminating her
from the match. And now Huntress has two staffs
that she can dual-wheel like a badass.
Dual-wielding two staffs? Like a badass. But I
would really love to see what those bow staffs can
do against someone as durable and strong as Spider
Woman, who glides in and she's gonna block
Huntress' staff attack with just her forearm
before backflip kicking Huntress right in the
chin with enough strength to knock her
unconscious, and now Huntress is out of this
match. So sorry about that fancy dual-wield.
Didn't go anywhere. All right, well, I mean, Black
Canary saw what happened to her friend, so she's
gonna blast Spider Woman with a targeted Canary
cry that's gonna obliterate her eardrums and just
disorient her. And then Black Canary's gonna grab
Spider Woman with this like Sonia Blade-esque
forward handspring leg grapple, and she's gonna
drive Spider Woman's head right into the ground
right before she chokes Spider Woman out between
her fishnet clad thighs. Yeah, all right. I think
that is statistically the best way to go out of this
match, except that Spider Woman doesn't get
choked out because she emits these pheromones,
right, that pacify Black Canary into loosening
her grip. And then Spider Woman just venom blasts
her, stunning her with enough electricity to take
her out of the match. Okay, well, Power Girl and
Captain Marvel, you know, they're probably still
brawling above the battlefield. And when Miss
Marvel tries to intervene to help her mentor,
Power Girl freezes her with her super breath and
then dashes right through Miss Marvel,
shattering her into a thousand pieces. She's out.
Damn, that's a bold move. Like Captain Marvel,
she's gonna be shocked by that and enraged and
she's gonna straight up super sane Kamehameha
Power Girl's ass with a blast that's gonna knock
her down to the ground right into She-Hulk's
fists. Okay, that's some A-Force teamwork right
there. And Captain Marvel and She-Hulk are gonna
team up and lay a straight up beatdown on Power
Girl, knocking her further and further into a
crater that gets deeper with each hit and Power
Girl eventually just goes limp. She can't take any
more. She's out. No, dang. All right, well, while
Captain Marvel and She-Hulk are in the hole,
Dove's gonna swoop in and emit her pacifying light
aura, which is gonna cause She-Hulk to transform
back into Jennifer Walters and Captain Marvel
just, you know, to calm the fuck down. At which
point, Batgirl's gonna drop down a bat grenade
into the crater, which detonates right after Dove
flies out of the hole, killing Jennifer. That's
Bird's a prey teamwork. Yeah, I don't like that
teamwork. But, uh, Nico, in retaliation for what
Batgirl did, she's gonna yell out, Basubius, with
her staff of one, which is gonna erupt a little
mini-volcano from the ground that's beneath
Batgirl and it's gonna explode Batgirl up into the
air and just burn her alive within the fountain of
lava. Wait, so there's like lava around the
environment now? Oh, just a pool of it where the
mini-volcano was. Okay. All right, well, Vixen,
she managed to survive space by summoning the
survival abilities of a tardigrade and so she's
fallen back to Earth after She-Hulk's throw and
she's gonna summon the power of a falcon to quickly
dive right toward Nico and then at the last minute,
harness the weight of a whale to land on Nico who
just splatters everywhere. And meanwhile,
Dove's going to blind Spider-Woman with a flash of
light. So now Spider-Woman's blind and deaf, you
know, thanks to Black Canaries attack earlier. So
Spider-Woman, she's gonna stubble into that pool
of lava from the mini-volcano created by Nico and
just burn to death. Uh, Dazzler then is gonna skate
over on her roller skates and we'll say that she
absorbed the sound of the mini-volcano eruption.
So she's juiced, you know, and she fires a light
beam that just punches the hole straight through
Dove's torso and now Dove's out. Now actually,
Dove has a danger sense. So she's gonna dodge
Dazzler's attack and then quickly like slide
tackle her legs to trip Dazzler on her skates. So
Dazzler just topples face first right onto Hawke
girl's mace and knocks herself out. What? Why are
all my guys going out like punk asses? Like, why is
Dove only getting people to take themselves out?
Well, she's a pacifist. Okay. Well, you know who's
not a pacifist? Captain Marvel and she's had it
with Dove's shit. She's gonna swoop in like a comet
super fast, lift Dove into the sky with her arms
above her head and then straight up dive power bomb
Dove into the ground. She's dead. No, no, Dove has a
pacifying aura. Yeah, but Captain Marvel already
knew that from earlier with She-Hulk. So Captain
Marvel acted quickly, like I said, a comet like
swoop slam. Whatever. Okay. Captain Marvel, you
know, she's gonna look around for the final bird of
prey, which is Vixen. But oh no, looks like she
doesn't see her. That's because Vixen is using the
camouflage powers of a squid to make yourself
basically invisible. And when Captain Marvel
isn't looking, that's when Vixen combines the
abilities of a dung beetle, which is really
strong, like it could lift over 1000 times its
weight and a mantis shrimp, which could strike at
the speed of a bullet to land a killing blow right in
the back of Captain Marvel's head. Boom, match
over. How many animals is Vixen using for this move
here? Three. Mantis shrimp and a dung beetle?
Yeah, it's pretty shitty. Literally. Okay.
Captain Marvel feels this little love tap on the
back of her head and she's gonna turn around like,
bitch. And then she's gonna fly and uppercut Vixen
into Red Mist. That's how the match ends. Love tap.
Dude, do not underestimate the power of the mantis
shrimp. It's called a shrimp for a reason. All
right. It's shrimpy. Right. It's not going to hurt
Captain Marvel proportionately. Yes, the hell it
is. Okay. Well, we'll go ahead and leave the match
there. Either Vixen mantis shrimp dung beetle
punches Captain Marvel on the back of the head, or
Captain Marvel literally just uppercuts Vixen,
exploding her into oblivion. Let's go ahead and
input the stats for these teams, run the
simulations and find out which scenario happens.
Agenenke, hit it. Inputting data, running
calculations, processing results, simulations
complete. All right. Full disclosure, guys. For
this particular matchup, a lot of the executive
producers weren't convinced that the Birds of
Prey were going to be powerful enough to go up
against a force. So at one point, we thought it
might work to have Jessica Cruz on the Birds of Prey
team, which I didn't love because Jessica Cruz has
never been a member of the Birds of Prey. But we
thought it would help balance things out. Yeah.
When we ran the stats though, like Green Lanterns
are so impressive statistically that not only did
Jessica Cruz end up being the most powerful member
out of either of the teams, but she also raised the
value of the team to the point where it was unfair.
Because despite what people may think, Birds of
Prey are quite impressive statistically, at
least when it comes to fighting skill and
intelligence and perception. Yeah, they're
pretty well rounded characters, which was
surprising to see. Like you definitely had the
most powerful character out of either team in
Captain Marvel. And for the most part, like your
characters were way stronger than mine in terms of
strength and damage. Yeah, that's definitely
what my team excelled at, especially with
characters like Dazzler and Nico Minoru and Ms.
Marvel. They were really good in terms of like
range and damage potential and not a whole lot
else. Although because of Ms. Marvel's construct
shielding and Dazzler's energy shielding and
Nico Minoru's magic shields, A-Force did come out
slightly ahead in evasiveness. I didn't use
nearly enough shields in that speculation. But
thankfully my team was faster and more
perceptive. Yeah, in terms of speed, you had Power
Girl and Dove who are like really fucking fast.
Also, Hawk Girl was really fast and so was Vixen.
Really the fastest person on my team was Captain
Marvel and everybody else was just okay in terms of
movement speed. When it came to perception, like
you said, Power Girl has multiple advanced
senses. So does Vixen. Dove has her dangerous
sense. And the ladies in A-Force, you know, you
have Spider Woman with her acute hearing and
Captain Marvel with her cosmic awareness. But
everybody else on my team basically just had their
eyes and ears. Right. So taking all of this into
account, Joseph, who do you think came out on top?
A-Force. Final answer. I think Instagram is
backing me up on this one too. They are. I put the
poll up pretty late, but so far it looks like 62% of
our Instagram followers who voted are siding with
A-Force. But let's see if they actually get the
win. NK, the results please. Here you are, sir. The
winner of the TeamDuel matchup between Birds of
Prey and A-Force is Birds of Prey. Bullshit.
Bullshit. Birds of Prey, motherfucker. Run the
stats again. Run them again. We already ran
thousands. How is that possible? I am as surprised
as you are. But it looks like based on these
results, Birds of Prey wins 51.4% of the matches
compared to A-Force who won 48.6. That's really
close. I still don't buy it. Not going to lie, I did
not see this coming. My guys are powerful. Yeah,
your guys are smarter, but what are they going to
do? Just like outsmart my guys? Well, it looks like
the biggest discrepancy came down to fighting
skill. Like, my guys are way better fighters. Some
of the best fighters in DC with characters like
Black Canary. Well, I have Mockingbird on my team.
And? She's the best fighter on my team. But why do
you need fighting skill when you have raw energy
power? Why do you need raw energy power when you
have raw intelligence? Backroll was by far the
smartest member out of either team. She really
leveled up my team in that regard. And actually,
one of Dove's superpowers is that she has enhanced
intelligence. It just makes me think that while
the final results were close, Birds of Prey were
able to execute teamwork, cheap shot tactics over
the A-Force who isn't quite as cohesive a team,
maybe. Yeah, well, I mean, if I had to choose a team
leader between Batgirl and She-Hulk, it would
definitely be Batgirl. She's much more of a
strategic mind. Well, She-Hulk won a little over
half of all of her matches, whereas Batgirl won
just over a third of her matches. Actually, the
person with the highest win rate was Captain
Marvel, winning a little over 84% of all of her
fights, followed by Powergirl, who won 80%. Which
makes sense, because like I have She-Hulk on my
team, Captain Marvel, they'll definitely put up
more of a fight than some of my other characters.
You also had the character with the lowest win
rate, which was Mockingbird. That's right, she
really dragged down my team, for sure. I think
maybe I should have replaced her with someone
else. How am I going to bring a chicken to this fight
with two metal poles going up against essentially
Supergirl? Yeah, the original Supergirl. I don't
know what to say, man. I eeked this one out, but boy,
am I glad I did. Here's to all the Lady DC fans. This
one's for you. For Women's History Month, DC is
going down in history as the winners. It's not
history in March, man. It's called herstory.
Okay? Get it right. That does it for this duel. A.J.
and N.K. help close us out. Don't forget to listen
to the other shows in the Dynamite podcast
network, including Max Destruction, Senjo
World, and Console Combat. In our next episode, we
will be doing a review. This time of the
direct-to-video DC animated film Batman Ninja
vs. Yakuza League. I cannot wait to see it. I've
been looking forward to this for a long time. I
think it's going to be fun. I hope it sucks, but that
does it for this episode. We want to give a big
thanks to our executive producers, John
Strausky, Zachary Hepburn, Mickey Mata-Gian,
Brandon Essigard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Aitin,
Austin Wieselowski, A.J. Dunkerly, Nick Abonto,
Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Spees, Dean
Moleski, Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, Josh
Leiner, Mike Williams, and Oscar Galvez for
helping make this podcast possible. We'll talk to
you guys next week. Up up and away. True believers.
I love women's.