This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi, welcome
back to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a Rotten
Tomatoes-approved show that reviews superhero
films and series through the lens of the DC and
Marvel fandoms. I'm Jonathan. You're not Johnny
DC anymore? Heck no, I'm so sick and tired of
calling you Marvelous Joe. Okay, I'm Joseph. If
people haven't figured out that Jonathan is Team
DC and Joseph is Team Marvel after 10 years, I don't
know what to tell them. Well, maybe people are
listening to the show for the first time with this
episode. They're going to want to know things
like, I'm your twin brother and we had a show where
we pit Marvel and DC characters going up against
each other for 10 years and then we retired that
show and that we're bringing it back as a monthly
podcast reviewing Marvel and DC projects. Yeah,
it's been just over a month since we reached this
semi-retired phase. I got to say, I really missed
it. It's hard to get back into this now. I feel like
I'm so out of practice. I don't even know what a
podcast is anymore. But thank you to our listeners
for sticking with us as we transition into this new
phase. In this episode, we're going to be
reviewing season one of Wonder Man. Jonathan, did
you watch it? I tried to. I think I got a little bit
more than halfway through the first episode.
Well, that's okay that you didn't watch it because
we're going to be doing non-spoiler reviews from
here on out. Those of you who are used to listening
to our earlier reviews, you know that we typically
dive deep into the plot and we break down basically
everything that happens and discuss spoilers.
But in this brand new era of dynamic dual, we're
going to be taking a more traditional approach to
our film and TV criticism in that we're not going to
be doing full story breakdowns. We're not going to
be discussing anything that would be considered a
spoiler, hopefully. Instead, these reviews are
going to serve more as an overview of our thoughts
on the project and whether or not we as longtime
Marvel and DC fans would recommend it. I think our
new aim here is really to provide that superfan
perspective among the whole sea of other types of
film and TV critics who may or may not have
familiarity with these characters. So our
format's changing a little bit. Hopefully you
still enjoy it. But first real quick, our
artificially intelligent co-host, AJ9K, is also
backing you as a quick message for our listeners.
So listen up. Thanks, AJ9K. Before we get into the
review, since this is a Marvel and DC review
podcast, one of the new things that we'll be doing
is going over the comic book characters that
appear within the projects that we're reviewing,
giving people a refresher or an introduction to
the source material, origins, and powers. This is
a new segment we're calling Who's Who. So let me go
over the comic book characters that appear in
Wonder Man Season 1, starting with Wonder Man. A
competitor to Tony Stark, Simon Williams was an
industrialist who lost his munitions company and
was imprisoned after being caught in bezeling
funds. Baron Zemo freed Simon from prison and
exposed him to ionic radiation, transforming him
into Wonder Man. He infiltrated the Avengers as a
mole for the Masters of Evil, but later had a change
of heart and ultimately sacrificed himself to
save his new heroic friends. Though believed
dead, Simon survived in a death-like coma and was
eventually revived. He rejoined the Avengers and
became a prominent member of the team. Simon later
co-founded their West Coast branch in Los
Angeles, where he also established a
semi-successful acting career. Powers-wise,
Wonder Man's ionic form grants him vast
superhuman strength, near-total
invulnerability to physical and energy attacks,
and flight. On rare occasions, he'll expel his
ionic energy in the form of eye blasts. You can
learn more about Wonder Man in his dual episode
against Captain Adam. Now, it was going to go into
the backstory of the Mandarin, but I don't think
that will be helpful to people watching Wonder
Man. The backstory of Trevor Slattery is more
important there, and Trevor is an original
character to the Marvel Cinematic Universe. So
let's dive into another character that appears in
Wonder Man Season 1, called Dorman. Damar Davis
was a mutant whose ex-gene granted him the ability
to act as a living doorway. Adopting the name
Dorman, he joined the unconventional and
unsanctioned Great Lakes Avengers, quickly
becoming the team's primary means of
transportation and tactical repositioning. By
merging his body with solid surfaces, Dorman can
go intangible and open a portal through himself,
allowing others to pass instantly from one side of
an object to another. You can also access the Dark
Force dimension using the realm as a conduit for
longer-range travel. We never did a duel with
Dorman, but you can learn more about the Dark Force
dimension in our Cloak and Dagger dual episode
where we pit the two characters against the Wonder
Twins. The final character that I'll get into in
Wonder Man Season 2 is called the Grim Reaper. This
is Eric Williams, who is the elder brother of
Simon, who refused to join their family munitions
business and instead joined the mob. When Simon
became Wonder Man and seemingly died saving the
Avengers, Eric blamed the team for his brother's
fate. Consumed by grief and instability, he
adopted the identity of the Grim Reaper,
outfitting himself with advanced tech. Eric
became obsessed with avenging Simon and later
fixated on the android Vision, whose mind was
patterned from his brother Simon's brainwaves.
He became a recurring enemy of the Avengers and
West Coast Avengers, although Simon eventually
returned to life. Eric's fractured psyche
prevented their reconciliation. The Grim Reaper
is an experienced hand combatant with a
cybernetic arm ending in a scythe-like blade
capable of projecting energy blasts and whirling
as a shield or helicopter blade. He has a genius
level aptitude for electronics and robotics, and
after he died in battle once, he was resurrected as
a zombie-like being and gained the power of
Necromancy, able to reanimate the death. That is
Wonder Man's brother. We did not do a dual episode
with Grim Reaper, but if you guys come up with a good
idea on who he could have gone up against, go ahead
and let us know on our Discord, which is linked in
our show notes and maybe we'll run the stats on
them. Yeah, him or doorman. Now that you know all
about the comic book characters that appear in
this series, let's go ahead and get into our main
event, where we review Wonder Man Season 1.
Alright, Wonder Man Season 1 was released by
Marvel Television in January of 2026 on Disney
Plus. The series stars Yaya Abdul-Mateen II and
Sir Ben Kingsley. It's showrun by Andrew Guest and
was co-created by Shang-Chi and the upcoming
Spider-Man brand new day director, Dustin Daniel
Cretton. The series follows struggling actor
Simon Williams, who tries to land the role of
Wonder Man in a remake of the 1980 superhero film of
the same title. He learns about the role after
running into Trevor Slattery, an actor trying to
make a comeback after being imprisoned and
disgraced in Hollywood for impersonating a
terrorist known as the Mandarin. And of course
that happened in Iron Man 3 and we saw the fallout of
that event in Shang-Chi and the Legend of the Ten
Rings. Simon and Trevor befriend each other in
their pursuit of the roles of Wonder Man and his
sidekick Barnaby, respectively, while Simon
struggles with the fact that his Ionic super
abilities make him ineligible for the role under
an industry wide ban on superpowered beings. Now
is Barnaby a character from the comics? No,
Barnaby is original to this particular series.
They needed something for Ben Kingsley's
character, Trevor Slattery, to try out for.
Obviously he couldn't be Wonder Man, they needed
somebody that was close to the character that
would be like a lead role that they were both going
for. So Barnaby is like Wonder Man's Alfred in this
series? Exactly, yes. All while this is
happening, Simon is under investigation by the
Department of Damage Control who is seeking to
arrest him for potentially harboring dangerous
powers. Now my biggest takeaway from the show is
that it is not anything like the comic book
character. It's not faithful in any way, it's not a
satisfying adaptation of Simon Williams from the
comic books. And in fact this might be one of the
poorest translations of the source material and
certainly Marvel televisions for this
departure, even more than like Moon Knight, which
was a pretty far departure. I might even label
Wonder Man season one as Wonder Man in name only.
Now if you're not a fan of the comic book character,
the fact that Simon Williams in this show is almost
nothing like his comic book counterpart isn't
going to mean anything to you. And if you are a fan,
I'm going to say that it's not going to mean
anything to you either. Because despite the fact
that we have a poor adaptation situation going on
here, what we also have I think is one of Marvel
Studios most interesting and approachable
experiments that they've ever produced. Yeah it
was shocking to see that this was produced under
the Marvel spotlight banner. I didn't realize
that until I started the first episode. Of course
Marvel's other spotlight series was Echo, but I
know spotlight is specifically used to highlight
projects that are tackling lesser known
characters or unconventional stories, I
believe. Well it's for projects that are more
standalone. I don't know what to think about the
Marvel spotlight banner as it pertains to this
particular series. But the lack of adherence to
the source material as a Marvel purist, it did
raise difficult questions for me about the trade
off between seeing faithful and exciting
interpretations of the characters that I know and
love and seeing quality projects in general, even
those perhaps entirely outside of the superhero
genre. Oftentimes when I'm watching something
that is being adapted for film in a way that
completely deviates from the source material, I
often find myself realizing different ways they
could have incorporated different elements from
the source material into the series or the film,
but just didn't. Maybe because they weren't
knowledgeable enough or I don't know, just missed
it. Which makes me respect it less. Well like let me
raise a quandary for you. Okay you're a DC fan.
That's the quandary. What? No, no. Okay, so take
the character of Booster Gold, who's not only a
superhero, but also a football player, right?
Now, what if DC Studios released a Booster Gold
show that was 95% not about him as a superhero and
rarely showed his powers, but was still one of the
better and more interesting sports shows that
you've ever seen? What do your opinion of the show
as an adaptation affect your judgment of the show
as a quality project? That's not the best example
because Michael Carter, Booster Gold, was not a
football player for very long. He was caught
making sports bets and of course became a janitor
in a superhero museum. That doesn't matter
because Wonder Man wasn't an actor for very long
either. Oh. You know, in bits and pieces here and
there. But the fact is that regardless of that,
because he has this history as a comic book
character as a football player, they decided to
make the entire show about that. I would hate that
because Booster Gold is not about football. He's
about time travel. Really Wonder Man, the comic
book character is not about acting, but yet they
made the entire show about that. I'll say this. I do
have issues with Wonder Man, but nearly all of
those issues stem from the series as an adaptation
and not as a show in itself. But I ask myself, what
does that mean? Does that mean I have to be like an
apologist for the comic fandom? I don't know. Like
really, I defer to your struggles, Jonathan, with
the Joker film. Like the first Joker film, Joaquin
Phoenix's Joker was really Joker in name only. The
movie evoked the best of Scorsese's films,
though. It also was not a superhero film. It's also
not a great example because it was tackling
something that we really had no prior knowledge
of, which was the origin of the Joker. In the
comics, it's sort of intentionally left
ambiguous. There's multiple versions, but we're
not quite sure which one is the real one. The Joker
film tried to sell us on a specific version. So I
guess maybe that's how you're approaching Wonder
Man. This is a very specific version. I guess all I
know is that the Joker film was good. Wonder Man
season one was good. And what I don't want to do is
make your mistake of coming down on a project for
not being what you expected and failing perhaps to
fully praise it for the transcendent project that
it was. I think in hindsight, you yourself would
have rated Joker the first Joker higher than the
four stars that you did. Yeah, maybe. Yeah, though
I rated it low not because it was a bad adaptation,
but because it was just disturbing. Right. Right.
The project as an adaptation didn't matter to you
was more about the story. Yeah. I don't want to get
too far into the weeds here because Wonder Man is
not Joker, but I'll say that Wonder Man did evoke
some other great Hollywood projects. Like I
watched it and found myself drawing comparisons
to films like Once Upon a Time in Hollywood,
Midnight Cowboy, or even dialogue heavy
two-handers like Before Sunrise. There is some
action in the series. Don't get me wrong, but I'd
say it's like less than two minutes total of
runtime in eight 30 minute episodes. Say no more.
It's pretty crazy. Say no more. I'm not watching
it. It is pretty crazy for a superhero project. And
I do wonder if people will find that appealing. I do
think people will need to check their
expectations going in and not necessarily expect
your standard Marvel fare, but really expect
something entirely different. Did you find
instances as you were watching where they could
have inserted more action? No. I feel pretty
organic. I think what Marvel Studios has in the
Wonder Man series is basically an attempt to
venture beyond the standard formulas, tropes and
plot beats of good versus evil superhero fare and
do something unique. I've come down on Marvel
projects for straying outside the comics in
previous reviews. I liked Moonlight, but I'm
convinced it would have been better as a crime
thriller. There was She-Hulk, which tried to be a
legal comedy, but failed as both a satire of
superhero tropes and as a legal procedural.
Wonder Man is definitely its own thing. I would
define it as an American buddy comedy. And it
succeeds at being that, which makes all the
difference in the world. You know, if something is
done well, it makes me forgive what it could have
been, or maybe what I would have wanted as a comic
book fan. There are three things that Wonder Man
gets exceptionally right. Probably more than
that, but I'm going to narrow it down to dialogue,
performance, and cinematography. Starting with
the former two, like, never in my wildest dreams
would I have ever imagined Yaya Abdul-Mateen and
Sir Ben Kingsley as a quintessential buddy
pairing. But I am convinced that their chemistry
is exactly why Yaya was cast. Now, Trevor Slattery
has always been an out-of-left-field gem of a role
for Ben Kingsley, and to see Yaya match him line for
line reminds me of just how incredible Yaya is as an
actor. Like I remember thinking back to his
amazing delivery in the HBO Watchmen series, that
bar scene that he had with Regina King, that was an
iconic scene. And like between that series and
Wonder Man now, I'm entirely convinced that Yaya
Abdul-Mateen II is one of the best actors of this
generation. Not only can he act, he can act about
acting in this series. It's so meta that it feels
like you're watching a real behind-the-scenes
process when you see him do his thing. He is good. He
is really good. And it's funny because I think I
first heard about him when he was cast for Black
Manta in Aquaman. I don't remember hearing about
him prior to that. Yeah, same. In the course of the
series, Yaya convincingly lays out the arc of a man
who was alone and emotionally isolated from the
world around him due to feeling different, and
begins piecing together through this newfound
friendship that he retreats into acting as a means
to have any sort of semblance of emotional
connection with the world around him. Yaya took
this insecure over-thinker character and made
him endearing, while also making him the perfect
partner to Kingsley's infinitely quirky and
charming Trevor Slattery. The two leads are so
good together, just in their acting, that they can
take something as mundane and simple as
discussing their favorite movie monologues and
make that worth watching. It's those personal
interactions that are so low stakes for a Marvel
project, but they're like some of the best parts
about the show. The more toned-down, personal
approach to the story is definitely reflected in
the look of the show. I don't think I've seen
another MCU project with this type of
cinematography, this very naturalistic style,
which serves to highlight that this is not only not
a superhero adventure with super saturated
visual effects, it makes it feel like a
documentary almost, like a day in the life of an
aspiring LA actor. It's really different, but it
works, and it makes you feel like you're watching
some kind of art house fair. What's really
interesting is that the naturalistic
cinematography makes it really fucking shocking
when on the very rare occasion that something does
go down. Like, I don't think this is a spoiler, but I
will say that Wonder Man has one of the most violent
single shots out of any Marvel Studios project,
and because of that documentary feel to it, I
remember my jaw dropping at the moment. Like it was
very real and uncomfortable. And I'm talking like
this is more violent than any of the playful
ultra-violent stuff in Deadpool and Wolverine. I
remember going like, what the fuck? I was
surprised to hear you say that you thought the
cinematography was good, just because I didn't
really notice the documentary style you're
alluding to. Oh really? It definitely looks
different than any other Marvel Studios project.
There's even an entire episode that's shot in
black and white. It's fucking gorgeous. It's in
the middle of the season. It was really done well.
Regarding the story of the season, I really have to
say it was so hard writing this review and
deviating from a spoiler format because I just
want to talk about everything that happens. But at
the end of each episode, there's a decent turn that
makes you want to watch the next one. And the series
plots along pretty nicely, even though not a whole
lot happens in a couple of episodes. Like this
could have been a six-episode season. But at least
nothing meanders for too long, like it would in an
hour-long episode show because each episode was
only about 30 minutes. At the end of the day, the
show is less about the plotting or having
characters reach the next goal or resolving any
single conflict. It's more about the
relationship between the lead characters. And
more so than any other project, the story is about
the journey. Not really the end. Although I will
say that the end will still leave you with a smile on
your face. And still gets me really excited for
what comes next for these characters. I think
we'll definitely need a season two, the way this
season ends before we see Wonder Man crossover
with any other MCU characters. I would really love
to see Wonder Man join the Avengers though at some
point. Even though it wouldn't be entirely
necessary for this version of the character, I
think it would be fascinating. Yeah, maybe
they'll have him decide to join the Avengers as
part of some study in Casper View for a role he wants
to audition for in playing Tony Stark or
something. Who knows? I don't know. There's your
Tony Stark connection. He seems like he'd be more
at home with the Thunderbolts team. Maybe that's
just commenting on the cinematography of the
series. But I guess the Thunderbolts aren't
really a team anymore. They are the Avengers. So
who knows? When the time comes for you to write your
first review in this non-spoiler format,
Jonathan, I know you're going to have a hard time.
There's so much more I want to discuss about what
happens here. The plot does raise some
interesting points regarding superhero ethics.
And you know how much I love discussing superhero
ethics. I think it would be an interesting
conversation as to whether or not Simon should
even be acting, but I can't really get into any of
that without getting into spoilers. Oh, because
with great power comes great responsibility? No,
not at all. Okay, that's not what I'm talking about
at all. It has more to do with the nature of his
powers, which are not really like how they are on
the comic books. But I do think that it's actually a
pretty cool interpretation. Ultimately, the
Wonder Man series I think is important for Marvel
Studios. It's a really interesting first review
out of the gate for our new podcast format in that
the show made me question my own inconsistencies
and my approach to criticism, which eventually
made me land on the revelation that faithfulness
matters to me. So one of the most important things
out there when it comes to my approach to these
reviews, but quality matters more. I think at the
end of the day, I'd rather see a really, really damn
good project like Wonder Man Season 1 over a
faithful one. That being said, faithfulness is
still important. Would you say that quality is
more important to the survival of the genre than
faithfulness? Because as a fan of the comics, I'm
always like, just follow the comic book. It's
there. Just do that. Like panel for panel and you
can't go wrong because it's great. Right. But so
many Marvel and DC projects aren't as good or at
least as exciting as I feel like they used to be. So
yeah, I'm not sure what's going to save the genre.
Does Wonder Man save the genre in the way it kind of
promised to in the marketing? Does it beat
superhero fatigue? Was that a claim that it made in
the marketing that it would beat superhero
fatigue? Yeah, it was like, oh, yeah, this is the
answer to superhero fatigue. Yeah, I think so. I
would definitely say that I think an out of box
approach is necessary in this era of alleged
superhero fatigue. And that's exactly what
Wonder Man does. Like this series is the once upon a
time in Hollywood for Marvel Studios. Like no one
does meandering character exploration like
Quentin Tarantino. It isn't even until the third
act of once upon a time that you even realize, oh,
this is revisionist history on the Manson murder
of Sharon Tate. But even that ending is secondary
to the film's like meta industry commentary and
the personal relationship between the two lead
characters, Leonardo DiCaprio and Brad Pitt. And
that's the exact same thing with Wonder Man, I
think it's more about the relationship between
these two characters. There is a story in Wonder
Man Season One, but it's secondary. And that's
pretty unique, I think, which is fascinating
because I know there are films out there that don't
have too much story. They're essentially just
plot for you to say that a comic book project has no
story and is just plot kind of has me a little
intrigued, but also kind of has me a little
disgusted. I'll say that in all, though Wonder Man
Season One falters as a comic book adaptation, it
succeeds as a worthy and unique experiment in
dialogue driven chemistry fueled character
study and rating Wonder Man Season One four stars
out of five, a fresh rating on rotten tomatoes.
Well, now that we know whether or not you recommend
the project, you probably give us a few spoilers.
How about some out of context spoilers? Sure. OK,
some out of context spoilers. In Wonder Man Season
One, you see Olaf enter another man. Also, you can
see the most shocking head explosion since the
movie Scanners, I think. And you'll learn about
Mandarin's Mandarin's. Take from that what you
will. I don't want to. I might go to dark places. All
in all, guys, that was a review of Wonder Man Season
One. AJ9K helped close this out. Thanks for
listening to Dynamic Jewel. Visit the show's
website at dynamicjewel.com and follow us on
Instagram at dynamicjewelpodcast. Don't forget
to listen to the other shows in the Dynamite
podcast network, including Max Destruction,
Senjo World and Console Combat. Well, Jonathan,
what else is coming down the pike that you're
looking forward to reviewing later on this year?
Well, for DC, our next project is Supergirl, but
that's not coming down until the summer.
Honestly, the thing I'm most looking forward to,
though, is Spider Noir. Oh, yeah, that looks
really good. The trailer came out for that. I will
not be watching it in color. I will absolutely be
watching it in black and white. Nicholas Cage
looks a little unhinged in it, but that doesn't
come out until May. I know that Daredevil, born
against season two, drops its first episodes in
March, but we probably won't get to that until
later when the entire series is out. That does it
for this episode. We will see you guys in March. We
don't know what we're going to review yet, so look
forward to that surprise next month. Yeah, it'll
probably be something DC. I'll find something.
Thanks guys for listening. Up, up and away. True
believers. Turns out I suck a fat sack at playing
the blues, so glad to be back, guys.