This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi and welcome
to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat based battle
simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe and I'm his twin
brother Johnny DC. And welcome to this whooping
that the DC team is going to receive this week when
Ironheart beats the shit out of Star Sapphire.
Definitely not the other way around. I would not
discount Star Sapphire. She's just as powerful as
Green Lantern. So you're taking crazy pills if you
think she's losing. Crazy like a fox pills. I've
always wanted to pit Iron Man versus a Green
Lantern. I feel like this is the closest we're
going to get to that. We're going to run the
simulations later on this episode. Before that,
we're going to break down the latest comic book
movie news to come out this past week, of which we
have one news item and that is the Hulk and Scorpion
have been confirmed to appear in the upcoming
Spider-Man brand new day film. Exciting stuff. As
always, we list our segment times and our episode
description, so feel free to check out the show
notes if you want to skip ahead to a particular
topic. Our artificially intelligent dual
simulator, AJ and NK has a quick message for our
listeners. So listen up. Why hello there. Do you
want even more from this podcast? Then become a
part of the dynamic dual community on Patreon
where you can choose from three tiers. The dynamic
2.0 tier gives you access to our discord chat
server. The fantastic 4.0 tier gives you two bonus
episodes each month and the X-Force tier makes you
an executive producer of this show. Lastly, the
Dynamite podcast network tier lets you create
your own podcast using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and
consultation, and get you simulation results.
Pitch the twins your ideas via email at
dynamicdualpodcastatgmail.com. Check it out at
patreon.com slash dynamicdual. Pip pip cheerio.
Thanks AJ and NK and thanks to everyone who
supports the podcast. Guys, be sure to tune in to
the other shows and the Dynamite podcast network
this week, including the console combat podcast,
where hosts John and Dean simulate battles
between popular video game characters. We don't
know the next episode because John hasn't told us
yet, but definitely tune in on Monday to console
combat. Over on the Max Destruction podcast hosts
Scotty and Gilly, Pay Your Favorite Action Heroes
from film and television against each other.
They're taking a hiatus during the month of
August, so make sure to get caught up on their
latest episodes. And on the Senjo World podcast
hosts Zachary Hepburn speculates on fights
between fan favorite anime and manga characters.
In his next episode, Zach's going to reveal who'd
win between Akuto Sai from Demon King Daimou and
Amos Voldegoed from Misfit of Demon Academy.
Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in
our show notes to listen to all of the shows in the
Dynamite podcast network. And with that out of the
way, quick to the no prize. There's no no prize.
We're actually recording this episode early. So
last week's question of the week is still active.
So let's go ahead and move on to the question of the
week. What was the best live action Spider-Man
suit and the best Batman suit and why? Record your
answer at dynamicdool.com by clicking on the red
microphone button in the bottom right hand corner
of the screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message can be up to 30 seconds
long and don't forget to leave your name in case we
include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a dynamic
dual no prize that we'll post to Instagram. Be sure
to answer before August 16th. But now that that's
out of the way, on to the news. Right, this past week
we learned from the Hollywood Reporter that it has
been confirmed that Mark Ruffalo as the Hulk and
Michael Mando as the Scorpion will be joining the
cast of Spider-Man brand new day. Now this has been
rumored for a while, but it was not officially
locked in until the script was locked in and the
writers for sure wanted to go in that direction.
And so they're bringing aboard these two new
characters. We still don't know exactly what the
story is going to be, but the persisting rumor is
that Mr. Negative is going to be the main villain.
He corrupts the Hulk back into a savage form and the
Punisher and Spider-Man team up in order to stop
the Hulk's rampage. I don't know how the Scorpion
factors into that, so we'll have to see. All he
knows is it's about time we get the actual Scorpion
on screen. Yeah, he's been teased ever since
Spider-Man Homecoming when the character was
speaking with the vulture in prison. Geez, I
really wonder what's happening with Michael
Keaton's the vulture right now. Like, what is he
doing these days now that he's in an alternate
dimension and just thinking about Spider-Man, I
guess. I don't know. But as far as the Scorpion
goes, I really hope that we get the main universe
comic book version of the Scorpion and not the
ultimate comic book universe version of the
Scorpion. Because I want to see the green suit. I
want to see the prehensile tail with the stinger
that shoots acid. I want the works. Yeah, didn't we
get the ultimate version of Scorpion in the
Spider-Verse films? That was like a hybrid
version of the character. He was kind of like a mix
between the ultimate version and the comic
version. I really hope that the rumors are true
that we're actually going back to the Hulk and not
any more of this smart Hulk BS. I do have to wonder
though if with the Hulk comes She-Hulk, his son,
Scar, Red Hulk. That's a great question. I have a
feeling we're done with Red Hulk and I'm not sure
we'll see She-Hulk, but we at least have to have
this whole Scar thing addressed because, you
know, having a kid in your life and to just not
address it would be rather strange, I think. Each
of the Spider-Man movies has always had like a
veteran performer starring in the movie
alongside Spider-Man. Like in Homecoming, there
was Iron Man. In Far From Home, there was Nick Fury.
In No Way Home, there was Doctor Strange. So it
seems like they're keeping that trend going here,
but even doubling up with John Berndthal and Mark
Ruffalo. These Spider-Man movies have really
become more of like a Marvel team-up series of
films, which is fine because I've always liked
that comic book series and Spider-Man still is the
main character, but it's just interesting how
they chose to do that. It's almost like they don't
have faith that the Spider-Man character can
stand on his own, or they're just really trying to
tie him into the greater MCU universe since these
films are still being released by Sony. Yeah,
maybe it's just a way for Marvel Studios to keep
control over the script. Maybe. I have no idea. But
it should be interesting to see how these
characters play out in this Spider-Man movie. I'm
really excited to see the first marketing for it
when that's released, which won't be for a while, I
think as I said last episode, because the movie
won't come out until the end of July of 2026. I bet we
get our first trailer with the Avatar movie.
Maybe, but I'm guessing it's going to be more
around January or February. At least for a proper
trailer, we might get like a small teaser or
something in front of Avatar. Well, a cool story,
bro! We've already done the Question of the Week,
so I guess now let's go ahead and move on to the main
event where we find out who would win in a fight
between the Green Lantern Villain, Star
Sapphire, and the Iron Man ally, Iron Heart.
Alright, Star Sapphire vs Iron Heart. Now we're
doing this episode as a tie-in to the first season
of the Iron Heart show, which debuted on Disney
Plus about a month and a half ago. It's been a while.
We haven't been able to get to this duel right away,
because we had so much to review that came down the
pike around the end of July. Yeah, between
Superman and Fantastic Four and Sandman, those
took precedence, but we always knew we wanted to do
an Iron Heart duel. Yeah, I think in a lot of Marvel
vs DC fan matchups, especially when it comes to the
Justice League vs the Avengers, a lot of people
will pit Green Lantern against Iron Man, which I
always thought was pretty interesting. And I'm
hoping that they're pretty evenly matched. I
guess we'll find out in the course of this episode.
Yeah, initially we were thinking of doing Iron
Heart vs Natasha Irons, Steel, but then we figured
that might be too much of a retread between Steel
and War Machine, which is a duel that we've already
done, so I'm glad this pairing found its way into
our lineup. Now since this is a tie-in duel, we all
know that Iron Heart has been portrayed by
Dominique Thorne, both in the Wakanda Forever
movie and in her series, but Star Sapphire, aka
Carol Ferris, has also been in a movie, and that was
the 2011 Green Lantern film she was played by Blake
Lively. Yeah, she wasn't a Star Sapphire in that
film, but I'm sure if they ever made a sequel to
that, it would have happened. Do you think Blake
Lively was well cast as Star Sapphire? Fuck no!
What really? No, I think Warner Brothers just
really liked Blake Lively as an actress, so they
wanted to put her in their big blockbuster film,
but I can think of much better actresses for Star
Sapphire. Like who? I don't know, off the top of my
head, Elle Fanning? What? I don't know. She
doesn't even have brown hair. We all know that hair
color is the most important part of superhero
casting. Way to fail on that one. Anna DeArmes
then. Anna DeArmes. Heck yeah! You know this
person is supposed to be a love interest to Kyle
Chandler, who is the current Hal Jordan in the DCU,
right? That means you gotta go with someone who's
at least above 40, because Kyle Chandler's like
almost 60. To me more, that's my final answer. Good
call, good call. Moving on to the duel, to explain
our methodology behind the duels, let's go to our
sentient duel simulator, Alfred Jarvis 9000.
AJ9K tell our listeners how you go about
determining a winner in our duel matchups. Yes, of
course, sir. The way I determine a winner between
the contestants is by running 1000 Monte Carlo
simulations using the characters statistics. A
Monte Carlo simulation is a probabilistic model
used to determine outcomes through random
sampling. In this case, I randomize the
statistics along a normal distribution as a way to
simulate the many variables that can occur during
battle. The stat parameters are based on the
official Marvel power grid from which the DC
characters statistics are extrapolated.
Additional stat categories are included such as
range, damage potential, versatility and
perception, in order to create a more detailed and
accurate simulation. The results of the 1000
simulations provide a percentage of wins for each
character. The contestant with the higher
percentage is declared the victor as they have a
higher probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither character should win
100% of the matches. The comic book stories have
shown that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman, so the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks, A.J .9K.
Before we run the simulations though, we like to
break down each character's histories and
abilities before improvising a scenario on how we
imagine one of the 1000 simulations would play out
beat for beat. And it's my turn to go first with the
DC characters backstory, so let me tell you all
about Star Sapphire. Now Carol Ferris was the
daughter of Carl Ferris, owner of Ferris
Aircraft, a defense contractor based in Coast
City. Groomed to take over the company, Carol was
intelligent, ambitious, and confident,
eventually rising to the role of president after
her father's retirement. Under her leadership,
Ferris Aircraft expanded military contracts and
experimental aviation research, including the
recruitment of a bold new test pilot, Hal Jordan.
Their mutual attraction developed into a
complicated, romantic relationship,
repeatedly tested by Hal's unexplained
absences, which were due to a secret role as Green
Lantern. Carol, unaware of his dual life,
struggled with his unreliability but remained
emotionally tethered to him. You can learn more
about Hal Jordan in our Green Lantern vs Nova dual
episode. While on a flight, Carol was abducted by
the Zemorans, an immortal race of female warriors
who once shared ancestry with the Guardians of the
Universe. Believing Carol embodied their ideal
of love, they transformed her into Star Sapphire
by giving her a powerful violet gemstone. The
gem's consciousness warped Carol's emotions,
turning her affection for Hal into obsession and
driving her to battle him as Star Sapphire, often
without memory of her actions afterward. In her
early appearances as Star Sapphire, Carol
repeatedly fought Green Lantern under the
gemstone's influence. As she was often unaware of
her actions while possessed, she believed
herself in love with Hal but acted violently to
control or punish him. The Zemorans viewed love as
possession, and the gem reinforced this
philosophy through Carol. After numerous
clashes with Hal and other heroes, the Zemorans
eventually removed the gem, allowing Carol to
resume her leadership at Ferris Aircraft. She
retained only vague memories of her time as Star
Sapphire. Though she returned to civilian life,
Carol remained entangled in coast cities
recurring superhuman conflicts. Ferris
Aircraft suffered repeated attacks, including a
major incident involving a rogue AI named Airwave
and another in which Hector Hammond
telepathically manipulated Carol's staff.
These events led to internal investigations and
legal scrutiny. When Hal's identity was later
exposed, public trust in Ferris Aircraft eroded,
forcing Carol to rebuild both the company's
reputation and its infrastructure. Carol's
relationship with Hal deepened but remained
strained. She rejected several of his marriage
proposals, valuing her independence and wary of
becoming consumed by his unpredictable life.
Still, she stood by him during his suspension from
the Green Lantern Corps, and he even funded the
creation of the short-lived civilian air force
known as the New Guardians Initiative. During
this period, Carol was once again drawn into
cosmic affairs when the Zemorans evolved their
philosophy and created the Star Sapphire Corps, a
full lantern corps powered by the emotional
spectrum's violet light of love. Reluctantly
accepting a new violet power ring to help counter
the rising threat of the Sinestro Corps, Carol
regained her powers, this time with full autonomy
and consent. Unlike the gem, the ring allowed her
to maintain self-control while channeling the
same emotional power. She helped the Star
Sapphires grow their ranks and expand their role
to enforcers of romantic obsession to guardians
of emotional bonds and compassion. During the
emergence of the Black Lantern Corps, Carol
played a vital role in reviving key fallen heroes
by channeling the violet light alongside
representatives of other emotional spectrums.
Her bond with Hal Jordan allowed them to briefly
unite all seven rings, helping to repel Necaron's
forces. Afterward, Carol stayed on earth while
continuing to support the Star Sapphire Corps
from afar, coordinating efforts from the newly
formed Zemoran central battery. As threats to the
emotional spectrum escalated, Carol assumed a
more prominent role in interstellar diplomacy.
She helped prevent a full-scale war between the
Indigo Tribe and the Red Lanterns, tracked the
emotional anomalies across multiple sectors,
and uncovered rogue Star Sapphires who had
twisted their rings power for selfish control.
She also confronted the Predator itself, a
sentient embodiment of love when it tried to bond
with a corrupted host on earth, successfully
separating it and reabsorbing its energy into the
violet battery. Carol briefly worked alongside
the Blue Lanterns during their effort to
stabilize planets destabilized by war, using her
understanding of compassion and loss to mediate
ceasefires. She even partnered with Guy Gardner
and Atrocitus to prevent the destruction of a
mining colony caught in a three-way emotional
conflict. You can learn more about Guy and
Atrocitus in their duels against Gord the God
Butcher and Juggernaut respectively. Although
her relationship with Hal continued to rekindle
and fade, the two developed mutual respect as
equals rather than star-crossed lovers.
Following the Flashpoint event that reset DC's
continuity, Carol's background remained
largely unchanged. She continued to run Ferris
Aircraft and maintained a complicated romantic
history with Hal Jordan. When Hal resigned from
the corps to investigate emotional disturbances
in deep space, Carol declined to join him, citing
the need to focus on her company and her own path.
Nevertheless, the Violet Ring returned to her
during an alien invasion, forcing her to confront
the reawakened Predator and the emotional chaos
it triggered in Coast City. After rejoining the
Star Sapphire Corps, Carol chose to operate
independently, rejecting the Zemmoren's call to
return to Zemmaron full-time. She used her ring
selectively, deploying it during major crises
that required her unique insight. During a
conflict in sector 1416, Carol uncovered a
conspiracy involving brainwashed Violet
recruits, an incident that caused her to
reevaluate the corps' recruitment methods and
eventually overhaul the Star Sapphire
initiation process. She also intervened in
matters affecting Earth, including dismantling
an undergrad traffic ingrain using
blind-controlled Violet constructs and halting
a cult on RAN that worshipped a corrupted version
of the Predator. Carol worked closely with Saurin
Iknatu of the Sinestro Corps to co-develop
protocols for emotionally volatile ring
bearers, forming the foundation of a joint
inter-core training program. Her independence
remained a defining trait, even as she worked with
how Jordan admissions involving temporal
anomalies, failed peace accords, and the
resurrection of Corona, she refused to be defined
by the relationship. At one point, she rejected
her ring entirely to experience life without
cosmic responsibilities, only to return when the
Zemmoren battery began destabilizing due to
neglect. She stabilized the corps herself, using
commeditation and precise emotional
calibration, then resumed her duties on her own
terms. By the end of the timeline, Carol had
assumed the role of emotional spectrum
ambassador, serving as both warrior and
counselor to multiple corps. She helped contain
outbreaks of emotional entropy, uncovered new
entities forming from fractured love, and guided
Star Sapphire trainees through their psychic
bonds. Power-wise, Star Sapphire wields a Violet
Power Ring powered by the emotional spectrum's
energy of love. The ring allows her to create hard
light constructs limited only by her imagination
and the clarity of feeling, including weapons,
shields, prisons, and transportation fields.
She can generate crystalline casements that
induce emotional reflection in her targets, and
teleport through violet light channels across
interstellar distances. The ring grants her
flight, energy projection, translation of alien
languages, and survival in the vacuum of space.
Her bond with the predator enhances her ability to
detect and interpret emotional connections, and
strengthens her power against other emotional
spectrums. Carol also possesses combat skills,
leadership experience, and a strong rule that
allows her to operate independently of her ring's
influence. That's Star Sapphire. Every time you
mentioned the predator, I just kept thinking of
the predator that would fight Arnold
Schwarzenegger and go up against the Xenomorph
aliens. Yeah, different predator. This one looks
more like a dragon that is glowing purple, I guess.
Isn't it weird that the embodiment of love would be
called predator? Yeah, sketch, right? It was
retroactively made the embodiment of love. Still
a weird choice. I'm not gonna disagree. It's like
he's like a love predator. Not a sexual one.
Fucking creepy. But that's DC for you. Let me tell
you about Ironheart who has nothing creepy about
her backstory. Riri Williams was born in
Chicago's South Shore neighborhood to Demetrius
and Ronnie Williams. Her father died shortly
before she was born, and she grew up with her mom and
stepfather, Gary. Showing impressive aptitude
even as a toddler, Riri was just five years old when
tests showed her to be a super genius. Ordinary
classes bored her, and she spent most afternoons
in the family garage building gadgets from scrap
instead of playing outside. On one fateful day,
she and Gary were rescued from a group of scrawls by
the hero Iron Man, whom he could learn more about in
his duel against Cyborg. Despite being inspired
by the story, Riri was born in Chicago. Desired by
the armored hero from a young age, her teacher told
her that she would never be Tony Stark. At age 10,
Riri made her first close friend, Natalie
Washington, who loved watching Riri turn ideas
into machines. Two years later, MIT, or the
Massachusetts Institute of Technology, offered
Riri a scholarship, resulting in the now
12-year-old leaving home for college. For her
13th birthday, Riri met the first black woman
astronaut, fueling a lifelong desire to reach the
stars. The dream was shattered months later,
however, when a drive-by shooting killed Natalie
and Gary, while Riri looked on helplessly. The
loss convinced her to refocus her aims from
venturing to space to instead protect the ones she
loved. Back at MIT, Riri studied every video of
Iron Man she could find and found and downloaded
old armor design files. She smuggled spare metal
and circuits from campus labs and built a bulky
gray suit modeled from one of Tony Stark's early
armors. When security knocked on her dorm room
door, Riri climbed into the prototype and blasted
through a window, flying off and quitting school
mid-flight. The suit managed to make it all the way
to New Mexico, where she stopped two escaped
prisoners. Her crash landing, however, cracked
her chest plate. Returning to Chicago to repair
the armor, Riri found Tony Stark waiting in her
driveway. Impressed that a teenager had copied
his tech, Stark encouraged her to keep working on
it and offered advice when needed. Soon after,
Tony Stark was left in a coma after a battle between
two hero factions over the ethics of
pre-cognitive and preemptive crime fighting.
Before falling, he had saved a copy of his mind as an
artificial intelligence which moved into Riri's
garage computer. With its help, she chose to take
on Stark's legacy and build a slimmer, red and gold
armored suit, choosing to codename Iron Heart as
an homage to the loved ones she lost. Iron Heart's
early outings were tough. Fighting beside Pepper
Potts and Rescue Armor, she stopped the armored
criminal called Technogolom and her Biohack
Ninjas. Agents from the Worldwide Spy Group
Shield took notice and quietly urged Riri to stop
Lucia von Bartus, a cyborg who had seized control
of the Eastern European nation of Latveria. Riri
flew overseas, defeated von Bartus, brokered
peace between Liberian forces and Shield, and
helped arrange the first free elections in that
country. Back in the United States, Tony Stark's
biological mother, Amanda Armstrong, handed
Riri the keys to one of Tony's labs. Riri's old
school asked her to return, and a teenage
superhero squad called the Champions invited her
to join their ranks. Riri accepted all three
offers, dividing her days between inventions in
the lab, classes at MIT, and missions with her
peers like Ms. Warble and Miles Morales
Spider-Man, both of whom you can learn more about
in the respective duels against Elastowomen and
Batwing. The teamwork with the Champions proved
vital when a reality-warped Captain America
helps the terrorist group Hydra overthrow the US
government. Guided by Black Widow, the Champions
joined in underground resistance. The young
heroes watched the Widow die, were jailed, and
were freed only after the real Steve Rogers was
restored. You can learn more about Captain
America and Black Widow in the respective duels
against Commander Steel and Black Canary. After
that adventure, a living cosmic cube named Kobik
flung several heroes through time. Riri landed
decades in the future, where a magic-using Tony
Stark told her to follow her own path. She returned
to the present, determined to do exactly that,
though she still stayed active with the Champions
as well. On her rescue near the Arctic Circle, she
recruited the new hero's snow guard to the team,
then flew into space to help Nova during a Chitauri
Civil War. During the battle, she impulsively
charged at Thanos, who vaporized her armor,
pushing Riri to later design a tougher model using
a Chitauri alien alloy. You can learn more about
Thanos in his duel against Darkseid. Soon after,
the Champions traveled to Tanzania to install
water filters for a village where they fought the
misunderstood swamp beast Man-Thing. A strange
portal later trapped half the team in a
medieval-style realm called the Siege Parallel,
turning each hero into a fantasy version of
themselves. Riri became Lady Ironheart, a
shining paladin and the only one who still
remembered Earth. She regrouped her friends and
led them home. Weeks later, her Android teammate
Viv, the daughter of Vision, kissed Riri.
Uncomfortable with Viv's actions, Riri pulled
away and their friendship grew strained. That
tension let the demon Blackheart twist
Ironheart's mind during a later attack. Viv's
heartfelt apology broke the spell, and together
they drove Blackheart off. Riri admitted she
could not return Viv's romantic feelings, but
still value to their friendship. Using advanced
scanners from her MIT lab, Riri mapped her brain
patterns to build a new suit AI. The program took
the form of her old friend Natalie and called
itself Natalie, or the neuro-autonomous
technical assistant and laboratory
intelligence entity. Around the same time
Ironheart clashed with the Ten Rings crime
syndicate. Their agent, Midnight Fire,
kidnapped children in Chicago while hunting the
mystical wellspring of power. Riri was able to
rescue the kids and use the reward money to open a
neighborhood tech studio. Chasing the Ten Rings
to Wakanda, Riri teamed with Princess Shuri, the
Shadow Walking Hero silhouette, and a koye of the
Dora Milaje to locate the hidden wellspring
beneath a mountain. You can learn more about Shuri
and her duel against Aqualad. Inside, she faced
Midnight's Fire and Dune, who was revealed to be
Demetrius, the father she thought was dead, now
loyal to the Ten Rings. Grabbing the wellspring's
key, Riri fell to its energy, saw visions of her
past, and emerged temporarily supercharged with
mystical energy. She used its power to defeat the
Ten Rings, and Wakanda honored her with the
Circlet of Bast, a ceremonial award and the
highest honor Wakanda can bestow to an outsider.
She later helped build Wakanda's first deep space
fleet and fought alongside them against an
invading force. Back home, Congress passed a law
banning heroes under 18. Fearing legal trouble
for her mother, Riri tried to retire, but a
government unit called Cradle raided her house
and hunted the champions members across the
country. Riri uncovered proof that the energy
giant Rockson had funded the law to sideline teen
heroes. Public outrage forced Cradle to shut down
and the law to be repealed. During a separate
sting, Iron Heart, Iron Man, and War Machine all
tried to stop a black market shop named Source
Control from selling the Mandarin's Ten Alien
Power Rings. Riri ended up taking the rings for
study, but they whispered dark thoughts into her
mind. On a later mission to the dwarf realm of
Nedevalir with Mewit inventor Forge, a McLuhan
dragon warned her the rings housed evil spirits.
Riri used Forge's portal cannon to hurl all Ten
Rings into deep space before they could corrupt
her. You can learn more about the Ten Rings in our
Abra Kadabra vs Mandarin dual episode. Soon
after, an advanced virus shut down every
high-tech zoo Tony Stark had ever built, causing
him to call Riri and Natalie for help. The
investigation led to an old Stark plant in Chicago
where Lucia von Bardus tried to steal some
surveillance gear. Fighting besides Stark,
Shield Agent Melinda May, and the Scarlet Witch,
Iron Heart defeated von Bardus and used fragments
of her stolen armor to wipe the virus, restoring
Iron Man's systems. And that's Iron Heart's
backstory. Powers-wise, Iron Heart's alien
alloy armor grants her high durability,
increased lifting strength of around 70 tons,
supersonic flight speed, repulsor blasts, a
uni-beam chest laser, mini precision missiles,
flashbangs, sonic emitters, taser cables,
ferrous liquid spray for magnetic attacks, EMP
restraints, EMP blasters, repulsor powered
drones, remote communications access, an
on-board artificial intelligence called
Natalie which performs tactical analysis and
target scanning, thermal vision, night vision,
and that's just to name a few of the gadgets her
armor has. In addition to all that, Iron Heart is a
highly gifted engineer and inventor with a genius
level intelligence. Yeah, half that shit isn't
even gonna work against Star Sapphire. 100% of it
is gonna work against her. Are really an EMP blast?
Yeah, I mean, don't the Green Lantern rings or not
for electricity or something? I'm gonna slap the
shit out of you. Runs on love, bro. Pure love. Do you
have an LMP? I don't think you do. In a world where
fantasies collide and heroes clash, one podcast
network rises above the rest. Prepare yourself
for the ultimate showdowns in comic books, video
games, movies, and anime. The Dynamite Podcast
Network presents Console Combat, where video
game legends brawl every Monday. Dynamic Duel,
where comic book titans smash every Tuesday. Max
Destruction, where TV and action heroes battle
every Wednesday. And Sendro World, where anime
champions clash every Thursday. Join us as we
speculate on the matches and armed with the power
of mathematical simulations, discover who will
emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
Well, now that we've got their histories and
abilities out of the way, let's speculate on how
one of the 1,000 simulated matches will go. The
winner is determined by simulations, not the
speculation, but it's fun to imagine how the fight
could play out. Adrian Nk, what are the rules of our
speculation? Well, I should say there are no
rules, other than the characters have no prior
knowledge of the other going into the fight. All
they are aware of starting out is that the other
character is a threat that needs to be eliminated.
For the speculation, the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the match
itself, as no environmental statistics are
considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. Alright,
then let's get into it. Star Sapphire and Iron
Heart meet on the battlefield. Who goes first? I'm
going to say that Iron Heart goes first by having
Natalie, her AI, quickly scan Star Sapphire. And
she's like, Natalie, who is she? And Natalie's
like, who the else would it be, bish? That's Star
Sapphire. And I'm picking up major vibes from that
ring of hers. So Riri's like, let's take it out. And
she targets the ring and launches a barrage of many
heat seeking missiles from her forearms at Star
Sapphire. Right away, Star Sapphire, she's going
to generate a bunch of heart shaped shields that
block all of the missiles mid flight. And she's
going to counter with a thorny, flowered vine
that's going to wrap around Iron Heart and bind
her. Alright, okay, so Iron Heart's wrapped up in
this vine construct and she's going to struggle to
break free from it. But I think to bite her some time
while she's struggling, she's going to emit a
sonic attack comboed with some strobe
flashbangs. And that's going to disorient Star
Sapphire because Star Sapphire is going to be
covering her ears because they're in pain and you
know, closing her eyes. And that's going to give
Iron Heart enough time to break out of the vine. And
then she's going to eject like four different
repulsor drones from her armor, and they're going
to fly alongside her and blast alongside her as
Iron Heart and the drones encircle Star Sapphire.
So Star Sapphire is getting like repulsor blast
from five different directions. Okay, Star
Sapphire, you know, she gets hit briefly, but
she's going to quickly counter Iron Heart's
drones with little flying cherub archers that
fight back against them, shooting them down while
Star Sapphire herself is going to fire her own
massive arrow at Iron Heart, plunging it right
into her arc reactor on her chest. The heart shaped
one? Yep. Okay, but Natalie, you know, she was
targeting Star Sapphire's ring energy earlier.
So she's like zoned in on it and is able to engage
Iron Heart's evasive maneuvers and have her dodge
the arrow. And that's when Iron Heart blitzes Star
Sapphire, just punching her right in the face with
her fist, knocking her out. Okay, so Iron Heart
lands a punch on Star Sapphire. She's just going to
spin around with a giant hand construct that's
going to just backhand Iron Heart right to the
ground. And Star Sapphire is going to follow up by
generating a massive swarm of small butterflies
that are going to land on Iron Heart, just covering
all of her armor, and it's going to crawl into it to
shut it down. Are you trying to have Star Sapphire
just generate like, lovey-dovey things like
butterflies? And? I don't know, butterflies seem
kind of weak. Like, they're going to try to get into
Iron Heart's armor, but you know, that thing is
like locked down tight. I mean, they're made of
energy. All right, while this fruitless endeavor
is happening, from the ground, Iron Heart's going
to raise up her arm, fire out taser cables that
attach to Star Sapphire's skin and stun her, and
make her fall down to the ground too, as all the
energy butterflies dissipate. Yeah, but before
the cables have been reached, her Star Sapphire is
going to protect herself by quickly generating
this castle tower construct that just kind of goes
up around her a few stories into the sky. And at the
top of this tower is going to be a dragon that looks
like the predator entity, and it's going to dive
down at Iron Heart, just clawing and biting at her
armor. Again, this is not the predator with like
the dreadlocks and the shoulder cannon and all
that. Well, I mean, if you want to imagine that,
just that with wings. Okay, well, while Iron
Heart's being attacked, she's going to fire a
unibeme laser from her chest that's just going to
shatter the predator dragon construct. And all
pissed off, she's going to rock it from the ground.
And then she's going to shoot an actual rocket from
her back that's going to shoot over to the tower
construct and blow it right up. So Star Sapphire is
exposed now. And that's when Iron Heart shoots out
a spray of the Ferris adhesive liquid metal that's
just going to coat Star Sapphire, turning Carol
Ferris into Carol Ferris. You see what I did there?
Wait, so she's like a metal statue now? Yeah. And
Iron Heart has like some limited magnetic control
like basic repel attract stuff. Okay, well, I
mean, the metal is going to melt off of her right
away. Like if that stuff was liquid, it's not going
to take long for her to get heated up pretty
quickly. You know, you're going to see these
purple flames just begin to emerge from beneath it
as it just melts off of her. And that's when Star
Sapphire encases Iron Heart in this violet
crystal chamber that's going to lock her in a
trance where she hallucinates being with her
stepfather and Natalie again, you know, the
people she loves. And with Iron Heart distracted,
that's when Star Sapphire causes a giant gemstone
comic to just crash down on Iron Heart,
obliterating her and ending this match. But it's
going to take a while for the metal to melt. So like
Iron Heart's not going to wait for that to happen.
Right away, she's going to activate her magnetic
system and that's going to yank the ring off of Star
Sapphire's finger, since it's covered in metal.
So without her ring, Carol's not doing shit. And
she falls to the ground. And that is where Iron
Heart just turns her into a smear with a repulsor
blast. And Natalie's like, Bish, bye. All right,
that was a nice move. I bet Iron Heart really loved
that finisher a lot, because it was actually all a
love induced hallucination, because she's still
in the fucking crystal chamber. And here comes the
comment. You said that she hallucinates her
stepfather, Gary and Natalie. Well, yeah, she
hallucinates Gary and Natalie and defeating Star
Sapphire, like they're just in the background
while she does it. Well, I'm calling bullshit on
that. And we could go ahead and leave the match
there and find out which scenario happens by
running the stats. Either Iron Heart yanks the
ring off of Star Sapphire's hand and then repulsor
blasts her, or Iron Heart gets trapped in a
sapphire construct where she hallucinates and
then gets crushed by a big gemstone meteor.
Comment, whatever. Let's enter the stats, run the
simulations, and come back with a winner.
Adrian9k, hit it. Inputting data, running
calculations, processing results, simulations
complete. All right, so this dual matchup kind of
serves as a proxy for a Green Lantern Iron Man duel.
And I think the stats for these characters lined up
pretty well with that type of matchup. In that,
Iron Heart is smarter than Star Sapphire in the
same way that Tony Stark is smarter than Hal
Jordan. Oh yeah, and also in the same way that Star
Sapphire is faster and more versatile than Iron
Heart in the same way that Hal Jordan is to Iron Man.
But we're saying Iron Heart is marginally more
perceptive than Star Sapphire because not only
does she have like her enhanced sense modes, but
also has the artificial intelligence Natalie
backing her up, as well as drones to get external
data. But can't she create force fields like Star
Sapphire? Well, probably not to the same extent as
Star Sapphire, but she doesn't need to because she
has a fucking indestructible suit of armor. So
she's more durable. Star Sapphire barely wears
any clothes. Another win. Right, so taking that
and all of the other stats into account, Joseph,
who do you think came out on top? Iron Heart. Iron
Heart because she has a whole suit of armor and Star
Sapphire only has a rinky dink ring. And last time I
checked, armor beats ring. Well, when's the last
time you checked our Instagram? Not there
recently, but looking at it now. Yeah, Star
Sapphire won our poll with our followers by 81%,
which is a lot. Actually, I'm looking at 82%. Well,
looks like you need to get your phone checked
because I have 81%. Matter of fact, it just went
down to 80%. I did put this up just a few hours ago. So
maybe. The point is, Star Sapphire is winning in
the poll, but does she win in the simulations?
Let's find out. AJ9K, the results, please. Hey,
you are, sir. All right, the winner of the matchup
between Star Sapphire and Iron Heart is Star
Sapphire. All right, that does it for this
episode, guys. I want to give a big thanks to our
executive producers. No, no, no, no, no. You have
to sit through this. Star Sapphire won 547 of the
1000 simulated matches or 54.7% of the time
compared to Iron Heart, who only won 45.3% of the
time. That's not a bad showing. It's actually
closer than I thought it was going to be. I thought
Star Sapphire was going to be high 50s, low 60s
instead of just mid 50s. Yeah, what an idiot. Shut
up. You lost. You can't say anything. I can say that
I don't think this match would serve as a good proxy
for a Green Lantern Iron Man fight because clearly
Iron Man would win that fight. You literally just
said when you were talking about the stats that it
would be. That was before I heard the results. Just
accept it. No way Iron Man beats Hal Jordan. Just no
way. Except Iron Man's armor has proven to be more
capable and versatile than Ree Reeves' armor in
the comic book so far. So I'm not so sure about that.
Wow, way to throw Iron Heart under the bus, bro. No,
she's still cool. She's still cool. She still
pulled off a damn decent showing against Star
Sapphire. Whatever helps you cope. But that does
it for this duel. AJ9K, help close us out. Our next
episode is going to be another duel where we pit the
former Aquaman sidekick Tempest. Against the
Inhuman Crystal. They're both manipulators of
the elements so it should be an interesting match.
Yeah, they're both young and they're both in the
royal courts of their respective royal houses.
Yeah, it'll be great. But that does it for this
episode. We want to give a big thanks to our
executive producers, Jon Starroski, Zachary
Hepburn, Dustin Balcombe, Miggy Mathen Guillen,
Nathaniel Wagner, Lee Vietn, Austin Wazelowski,
AJ Dunkerly, Nick Obanto, Scott Camacho, Gil
Camacho, Adam Speese, Dean Moleski, Devin Davis,
Joseph Kirsting, Josh Leiner, Mike Williams,
Oscar Galvez, and Paul Graves for helping make
this podcast possible. And we'll talk to you guys
next week. Up, up and away, true believers. My
nickname in college was Love Predator, but only
because I made clicking sounds in bed.