This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi, welcome to
the DynaMic Duel Podcast, where we review
superhero films and debate the superiority
between Marvel and DC by comparing their
characters in stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin brother Marvelous
Joe. And welcome to the episode of all episodes,
the one where we finally determine which universe
would win against the other. DC vs Marvel. It's our
penultimate episode. That's right, there's only
one more episode after this one. Jonathan, this is
our last duel. How do you feel about that? It's
pretty bittersweet. I'm not going to lie, but I'm
also super stoked just for you to find out how bad
Marvel would actually lose in a battle with DC.
Well, to be fair, this isn't the entire Marvel
Universe against the entire DC Universe. This is
12 of its top main characters against DC's 12 top
main characters. Right, we're in 2026 now, and
this is the 30th anniversary of the DC vs Marvel
four-part comic mini series that came out in 1996.
That was highly influential to us growing up. And
to honor that, we're kind of taking the same
approach with this final duel. Joseph and I are
brothers, just like the red and blue brothers from
that mini series. We've picked 12 champions from
each of our respective worlds, and we're going to
pit them against each other full force. It is going
to be the team duel to end all team duels. Really
excited to share with you guys who I've picked for
my 12-person roster. Before we get into the duel,
though, we're going to break down the latest comic
book movie news to come out over the past few weeks,
including the Avengers Doomsday teasers, at
least the first three. And the news that Sebastian
Stan and Scarlett Johansson have joined the cast
of the Batman part two. As always, we list our
segment times in our episode description, so feel
free to check out the show notes if you want to skip
ahead to a particular topic. Our artificially
intelligent duel simulator, AJ9K, has a quick
message for our listeners, so listen up. Hello,
these are the final episodes of Dynamic duels
Weekly podcast, leading up to our grand finale on
January 20th. We hope you've enjoyed the past 10
years of Marvel and DC duels and reviews, and we'd
love for you to stick with us as we count down these
last episodes. We're inviting you, the listener,
to help us close out the show by visiting
dynamicduel.com over the next few weeks and
clicking the red microphone button in the bottom
right corner to leave us a voicemail that we'll
play during the final episode. Tell us what first
got you into DC or Marvel, how long you've been
listening, a favorite episode or moment, or
anything else you want to share about what the
podcast has meant to you. Your messages will be
aired and responded to on the January 20th finale.
Again, head to dynamicduel.com and leave your
final message. We would love to hear from you. Pip
pip cheerio. Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone
who takes the time to call in and leave a voicemail.
Guys, this is your last chance to leave a voicemail
to ever be featured in the show. So be sure to do
that. Thank you so much to those who do. Yeah, you
guys have until tomorrow, January 14th, the day
after this episode drops to call in, you know, let
us know how long you've been listening, your
favorite episode or moment, anything else that
you want to share about what the podcast has meant
to you over the past 10 years. Be sure to tune into
the other shows on the DynaMic Podcast Network
this week, guys, including Konsole Kombat, where
they discuss video game battles, max
destruction, where they discuss movie and TV
character battles, and Senjoh World, where they
discuss anime character battles. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our show
notes to listen to all the shows in the DynaMic
Podcast Network. But with that out of the way for
the final time, on to the news. Right over the past
few weeks, we've gotten teaser trailers for the
upcoming Avengers Doomsday movie that's going to
be coming out in December of 2026. Now, allegedly,
the short little teasers, which are only like 30
seconds long, will be leading up to a more official
teaser, but I'm not sure when that's going to
happen. I was actually kind of hoping that Marvel
would drop that before the show ended, because I
would love to talk about it. Looks like that's not
going to happen. They might be saving the longer
teaser for maybe the Super Bowl or something. But
there have been three of these trailers released
so far, officially a fourth one was leaked, but I
don't necessarily want to discuss that one in case
anybody hasn't seen it. But the first 30 second
teaser was with Steve Rogers. The big huge reveal
there was that Chris Evans is returning as Steve
Rogers in Avengers Doomsday. That was pretty huge
news because he wasn't revealed on that chair
promo where they revealed all the cast member
names that were going to be within the movie. So
that was pretty cool. Turns out he has a kid with
Peggy. I don't know if that's going to be James
Rogers, who was the character that was in that
Marvel Next animated movie. I think that's the
most likely candidate for who that baby is going to
be. Yeah, you figure he would have to have been born
around the middle of the 20th century, right?
That's true, actually. I didn't even think about
that. He likely would have been born around the
1950s, 1960s at the latest. So yeah, he's going to
be substantially older by the time the events of
Avengers Doomsday takes place. If they even show
him in the current timeline, right? Like Steve
Rogers might be plucked out of the timeline where
his kid was born and he doesn't get to see him
anymore or something like that. Who knows? The
second 30 second teaser that we got involved Thor,
who prays to his father Odin for the strengths to
fight for his daughter, Love. As much as I don't
love the character of Love because the movie Love
and Thunder sucked, it is really, really nice to
get a more serious Thor back on the screen. A mature
Thor, which is wild because the Thor movies have
gotten pretty wacky and almost crude with the
humor. So it's definitely a different take that
the Russo's have on the character from what we've
seen in his solo films recently. For sure. Yeah.
Big breath of fresh air right there. The third
teaser is probably the one that actually got me
excited because it showcased the return of the
X-Men. We see an elderly Magneto and Professor X
playing chess in the dilapidated X mansion. At the
end, though, we see James Marsden as Cyclops going
full on 90s Cyclops X-Men. It's glorious. He's
shooting an optic blast to the sky. Everything's
red. I'm pumped that they're finally doing
Cyclops justice on the big screen. And to add to
that, it's James Marsden in the role who was really
given the short end of the stick in the previous
X-Men franchise. Good for him. The character is
getting his due and the actor is. Totally shows how
awesome it is to have Marvel properties with
Marvel Studios and that having some other studios
try and figure out the characters. Exactly.
Exactly. In addition to the next leaked teaser
that's come out, I think we're going to get one
other teaser allegedly with Doctor Doom. But who
knows, you know, the Internet has tons of rumors
these days. AI doesn't help because I've seen like
four different AI teasers of the leaked one that we
don't want to spoil. Just trying to find the actual
footage. It's bullshit. I'm getting major legacy
vibes from all of these teasers that we've seen
with Captain America's son, with Thor's
daughter. Yeah, for as final as Avengers Endgame
felt, this Avengers Doomsday movie seems even
more like the lid on an era after Secret War. Which
thank goodness, because everything pretty much
after Endgame feels like it hasn't really been
connected in a satisfying way. So if they can sort
of officially pass on the baton in a way that they
weren't able to earlier, I think that'll go a long
way in mending relationships with a lot of fans.
For sure. Yeah, just tie everything back together
again. Can't wait for the movie to come out this
December. We will be reviewing it. In DC News, we
learned that Sebastian Stan and Scarlett
Johansson have been cast in the Batman Part Two
directed by Matt Reeves and starring Robert
Pattinson. Now, it's been confirmed that
Sebastian Stan is playing Harvey Dent, a.k .a.
potentially Two Face, though we are not yet sure
who Scarlett Johansson is playing. The current
rumors are that she will be playing Gilda Dent, who
played a major role in the long Halloween comic
book series by Jeff Lowe and Tim Sayle, which I did
not see coming. We've seen Harvey Dent a lot in a lot
of media. So I didn't think they were going to go
that route. But the fact that they cast Sebastian
Stan opposite Robert Pattinson, I think is a
really solid choice. So when you say that we've
seen Two Face and a lot of media, are you referring
to like Joker, Folie a Deux? I'm talking about
basically every single Batman onscreen
franchise from the Tim Burton films to the
Schumacher films to the Nolan films. He's pretty
much been everywhere. So I'm not sure how they
would do him in a new kind of way. But again, if
you're going to do it, yeah, cast Sebastian Stan.
No, I'm sorry. I don't accept this because
Sebastian Stan is the winter soldier and he always
will be. And Scarlett Johansson will always be
Black Widow. So keep your hands off shit that you
can't have DC. Now, Scarlett Johansson is
definitely not a Black Widow anymore. But
Sebastian Stan just freaking played Bucky in the
Thunderbolts film. He's still the winter
soldier. So the fact that he's playing double duty
might be a little confusing. But the fact that the
Batman Matt Reeves universe does not take place in
the DCU helps a little bit. Maybe maybe Bucky dies
in Avengers Doomsday. Good. What? Yeah, I hope he
does. Oh, you're such a piece of shit. Now, rumors
are, like you said, that Scarlett Johansson is
playing Harvey Dent's wife, but she only had
relevance within the Long Halloween storyline in
the comic books. But the first The Batman Movie was
already heavily influenced by the Long
Halloween. The Long Halloween is one of the best
Batman comics. I'm not surprised that it
continues to be a wellspring from which movie
creatives continue to draw from. I'm wondering if
this will be the story of Harvey Dent becoming two
face or they're just including him here as a way to
build up something that could be paid off, maybe in
a third film. The rumors are that part two will
focus heavily on Arkham Asylum. So my suspicion is
that Gilda will play into that somehow, which is
probably why insiders are saying her role is a
major one within the film. And here I was hoping for
Mr. Freeze. What was I thinking? Hey, I'm eager to
see anything from the Matt Reeves Batman
universe. Sign me up. Yeah, if the Penguin showed
us anything, it's that there's a lot to explore
here and it's all really fucking good. Now, it'll
be a while before we actually see the film. It's not
scheduled to come out until October 2027. So we
have over a year and a half to go. I'm sure it's going
to feel really long until then, but I'm sure it'll
be worth the wait more than Avengers Doomsday for
sure. People have been waiting way longer for this
Avengers sequel than they have for the Batman
sequel. So sorry, but you're done. I said what I
said. But now let's get to the Duel matchup 10 years
on the making and find out who is going to win in a 12
versus 12 matchup of DC versus Marvel. OK, guys, DC
versus Marvel. It was a four part mini series that
both comic publishers released in 1996. Joseph
and I collected it. We had the poster for it. We were
all about it. For the longest time, it was like the
de facto DC versus Marvel event in comics up until
J. L. A. Avengers. And really, those are the big
two. Yeah, at least when it comes to like universe
wide events, not just individual character
crossovers. Now, we loved that story because it
was so ambitious in the world building created
with the two brothers and the Amalgam universe,
where DC and Marvel characters were merged and
everything that came from that. We even named our
awards show that we do at the end of every year after
the brothers that represent the DC and Marvel
universes from this mini series in which each
brother chose champions, essentially the most
popular characters at the time to pay against each
other to decide which universe lived and which
universe died. And those matches were Superman
versus Hulk, Batman versus Captain America,
Wonder Woman versus Storm, Green Lantern versus
Silver Surfer, Flash versus Quicksilver,
Aquaman versus Namor the Submariner, Shazam
versus Thor, Catwoman versus Electra, Superboy
versus Spider-Man, Lobo versus Wolverine and
Robin versus Jubilee. Yes, some questionable
matchups there. Also some questionable results
due to the fact that about half of those matchups
were voted on by readers. So it was kind of a
popularity contest, which is not how things are
supposed to be done. As you know, on our podcast, we
use character stats to run simulations to find out
who would actually win. And today we are going to
set the record straight 30 years after the comic
debuted as to who would have actually won in those
matches. Yeah, we're going to reveal some of the
results now because the other ones still pertain
to our current matchup and we'll keep those a
surprise for the end of the show. First to explain
the methodology behind our duels, let's go to our
sentient Duel simulator, Alfred Jarvis 9000.
AJ9K tell our listeners how you go about
determining a winner in our Duel matchups. Yes, of
course, sir. The way I determine a winner between
the two teams is by running 1000 Monte Carlo
simulations between every character on each team
using their statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation
is a probabilistic model used to determine
outcomes through random sampling. In this case, I
randomize the statistics along a normal
distribution as a way to simulate the many
variables that can occur during battle. The stat
parameters are based on the official Marvel power
grid from which the DC characters statistics are
extrapolated. Additional stat categories are
included such as range, damage potential,
versatility and perception in order to create a
more detailed and accurate simulation. The
results of the 49000 simulations provide a
percentage of wins for each character on both
teams. The team with the higher average win rate is
declared the victor as they have a higher
probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither team should win 100%
of the matches. The comic book stories have shown
that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman. So the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks, AJ9K. Yeah,
let's kick things off with probably the most
confusing matchup to me from the 90s miniseries,
Spider-Man vs. Superboy. Now, I understand that
at the time, Spider-Man's clone saga was going on,
so they wanted to pit a clone against a clone. But of
all the clones you could have chosen, Superboy was
by far the weirdest. Now, in the comic, Spider-Man
beat Superboy. But according to our results,
Superboy would actually beat Spider-Man. 59.5%
of the time compared to Spider-Man's win rate of
40.5%. Yeah, no surprise there. That's a weird
matchup. In the Aquaman vs. Namor the Submariner
matchup, they actually got that result right.
Aquaman would defeat Namor as we actually have
previously confirmed in an earlier episode of
Dynamic Duel Aquaman vs. the Submariner. Aquaman
wins 60.7% of the time. We also confirmed that
Flash would defeat Quicksilver 76.9% of the time.
But in a matchup we haven't done, Lobo vs.
Wolverine, it looks like they got it wrong. Lobo
would actually stomp Wolverine 82.1% of the time
compared to Wolverine's win rate of 17.9%. How
does that feel, Joseph? Unsurprising. It was a bad
matchup. Also a bad matchup, Wonder Woman vs.
Storm. Wonder Woman actually beat Storm not the
other way around as it happened in the comic.
Wonder Woman has a win rate of 63.9% compared to
Storm with the win rate of 36.1%. In the matchup
between Silver Surfer and Green Lantern, Silver
Surfer won in the comic and that's accurate. He's a
stat powerhouse who wins 67.8% of the time
compared to Green Lantern's 32.2% win rate. In the
comic, Electra defeated Catwoman, which we
determined would actually be the case with a win
rate of 67.7% compared to Catwoman's 32.3%. And
for the final result that we'll give from the
miniseries, Robin vs. Jubilee, they had that one
correct as well. Robin wins 75.2% of the time
compared to Jubilee's win rate of 24.8%. In the
comic, Marvel actually won a majority of the
matches, but it looks like statistically that
would not have been the case. Yeah, DC would have
won a majority of those matches. They just didn't
have a good pairings at the time for those
characters. I think we chose better pairings for
this particular Duel matchup. So forget that 30
year old miniseries. Let's talk about who the
brothers should have actually chose. Superman
and the Hulk, Batman and Captain America, Wonder
Woman and Captain Marvel, Green Lantern and
Scarlet Witch, the Flash and Spider-Man, Aquaman
and Black Panther, Blue Beetle and Iron Man,
Shazam and Thor, Hawkgirl and Wolverine, John
Constantine and Doctor Strange, Green Arrow and
Daredevil, and finally Harley Quinn and
Deadpool. That is how you do a versus roster for
both sides. Now, these are all matches that we have
not done in prior episodes. So we have no idea who is
going to win yet. The rosters we chose were decided
upon with help from our executive producers. From
a long list of characters on potential matches, we
thought these ones were the most interesting with
the best respect of rosters from each universe.
Now let's speculate on how one of the thousands of
simulated matches will go. Again, the winners
determined by simulations, not our speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how the fight could play
out. AJ and IK, what are the rules of our
speculation? Well, I should say there are no rules
other than the teams have no prior knowledge of the
other going into the fight. All they are aware of
starting out is that the other side is a threat that
needs to be eliminated. For the speculation, the
groups will begin approximately 50 meters apart
in a nondescript environment that will have no
bearing on the match itself, as no environmental
statistics are considered in my simulations. The
teams must earn victory on their own merit. All
right, then let's get into it. For the final
matchup ever, Team DC and Team Marvel meet on the
battlefield. Who goes first? Is it even a
question? I mean, the Flash. the Flash goes first.
Always. Always he goes first. And he's going to
start things off by speeding around the planet
like five times in less than a second, just
gathering mass and momentum to the level of nearly
a black hole before slamming his fist hard right
into the face of your side's biggest guy, the Hulk,
which is going to send him Korean backward all
before your team can even blink. You think if he hit
him with near the mass of a black hole, he would do
more than just cream backward. I think the
infinite mass punch is kind of bullshit, right?
Because the speed force negates the laws of
physics. I'll grant you that it was a really,
really powerful punch, but all that's going to do
is piss the Hulk off. As the Hulk flies backward,
Dr. Strange recognizes through the Eye of
Agamotto that it was a speedster that hit the Hulk.
And so he's going to generate a magic spell called
the following flames of the Faltine, which is this
blue fireball that's just going to endlessly
chase the Flash until it eventually catches up
with him and engulfs him and burns him alive. So the
flash is going to have to be constantly running to
avoid the flame. And while that's happening, Thor
spins his hammer and hurls a whirlwind over toward
the DC guys that immediately grows into this
powerful tornado that picks them all up and
scatters them across the battlefield. Oh, it
doesn't hurt them. It just scatters them. Yeah. I
mean, like he keeps them from strategizing,
though, because they're not near each other
anymore. OK, that's fine. Harley Quinn, she's
probably like, wee. And we'll say she gets flung
toward Deadpool, who doesn't have time to react
before she just wallops him across the face with
her giant mallet. Her giant mallet. Deadpool is
like, what in the penis envy is this? And he's just
going to slice Harley Quinn's hammer in half with
one of his katanas. And then he's going to slash at
her again. Like, let's do this hot topic. My safe
word is chimichanga. All right. Harley, she's
going to dodge the swords and she'll drop like a
cupcake grenade that blows off one of Deadpool's
legs as she skates away, laughing. Meanwhile,
Green Lantern is going to trap Captain America in a
green rocket ship construct that's going to
launch him into space just right away, taking him
out of the match. What? And at the same time,
Aquaman is going to hurl his Trident at Scarlet
Witch impaling her. No, no, no. Scarlet Witch is
going to throw up a hex shield that's going to cause
the Trident to reflect off of her shield and fly
right into one of Hawkgirls' wings, which is
going to impale it and ground Hawkgirls so she
can't fly anymore. And then Scarlet Witch is going
to teleport up to Captain America's rocket ship
and bring him back down to the battlefield, saving
him. You do realize that Hawkgirls' wings are not
organic, right? Like they're made of anthmedal.
Actually, that's the same material that
Aquaman's Trident is. So it doesn't pierce her
wings. Actually, the Trident is just going to
ricochet off her wings and get lodged into the
ground beside her. So she'll pick that up and now
she's Duel-wielding two-anthmedal weapons with
Aquaman's Trident and her own mace. And she's just
going to combo strike Spider-Man like a stab,
bash, spin, slash stab, combo. No, but Spider-Man
has Spidey Sense, and that'll allow him to dodge
and flip and spin and avoid getting hit by Hawke
Girls' weapons. And while he's dodging, he's
going to shoot a couple of web strands at Aquaman
and use them to slingshot Aquaman right into Hawke
Girls. So they collide and get knocked down. And
while that's happening, Captain Marvel flies
over to Green Arrow and shoots an energy blast that
turns him into a smear on the ground. Except that
the blast is blocked by Wonder Woman, who, you
know, leaps in to protect Green Arrow with her
silver bracelets. And Green Arrow from behind
Wonder Woman is going to hit Captain Marvel with an
explosive arrow that's going to knock her out of
the air. OK. Meanwhile, Wolverine straight up
lunges and pounces on Constantine, pinning him to
the ground and stabbing him right through the gut
with his claws. OK, that'll hurt Constantine. But
as he curses at Wolverine from the floor, he's
going to take the cigarette that he was smoking
from his mouth and put it out right in Wolverine's
eye and then snap his finger. And Wolverine's
going to get engulfed in flames. So he's going to
leap off of Constantine just freaking out. And
Constantine is going to perform a quick healing
spell on his stab wounds so that he doesn't bleed
out. OK, so Wolverine's on fire, but Iron Man is
going to fly over to him and use extinguishers in
his suit to douse Wolverine. So Wolverine's
charred, but, you know, his healing factor will
kick in. Simultaneously, Iron Man is going to
shoot out a homing missile that locks onto Batman
and flies over to him and explodes him. There
Batman, he'll dive out of the way of the missile.
And, you know, as it like circles back toward him,
he's going to shoot out a bat flare as a decoy that
the missile will lock onto instead. And actually,
you know, he shoots that flare at Captain America
across the battlefield so the missile blows him
up. Captain America is like, oh, shit. And he holds
up his shields just in time to protect him from the
flare and the missile explosion. So he's on phase
and he's going to hurl his shield at Blue Beetle,
which is going to hit Blue Beetle like a
sledgehammer right into his back where the alien
scarab is fused to a spine. And that's going to
cause the scarab to short circuit. Yeah, Blue
Beetle, his scarab will probably sense the
approaching shield. So it's just going to snatch
you out of the air with his mechanical insect arms
that, you know, protrude from his back. So now you
just gave him a back shield. And while that
happened reflexively, he was actually shooting a
grapple line that is going to connect to Black
Panther. And it's a Taser grapple. So it just fries
the vibranium suit and stuns him. OK, Black
Panther would be stunned because vibranium
wouldn't protect him from an electrical attack.
But through being shocked, he musters the
strength and will power to sever the grapple line
with his claws. So that's just going to cut off the
flow of energy from Blue Beetle's suit. At that
point, Black Panther is going to hurl a volley of
energy daggers at Shazam that are going to stick in
his cape and then explode with kinetic energy,
knocking Shazam to the ground. That would barely
faze Shazam. Meanwhile, Superman, he's going to
fly over to Daredevil and freeze him into an ice
block with his freeze breath. What? What? OK,
Daredevil's frozen. But Hulk is going to break
Daredevil out of the ice block before Daredevil
freezes through. And then Hulk is going to leap
like 20 stories into the air and then come down like
a meteor crashing into Wonder Woman, just
slamming her into this like Wonder Woman shaped
crater on the ground, shaking the entire
battlefield with his landing. OK, but Shazam sees
this and he's going to knock the Hulk away from
Wonder Woman with a lightning bolt so large and
powerful that it's going to fry the Hulk's skin to a
crisp. Big deal. He can heal from that. It'll just
take a few seconds. While that's happening,
Daredevil, fresh from being freed from the ice
block that he was in, you know, this whole time he's
been tracking the Flash with his radar sense.
What? And he knows that the Flash is trying to
outrun the fireball that Dr. Strange created and
with perfect timing, Daredevil fires his billy
club out and trips the Flash up, who then falls,
gets caught by the fireball and burns alive. OK,
except that the Flash trips and falls into Iron
Man, or through him because he phases through him
and that's going to cause the fireball to collide
with Iron Man and just melt his armor. No, no, no,
no, that would happen. The following flames of the
Faltine are magic. They're homing. They would
actually go around Iron Man and still burn the
flash up while he was on the ground. That shit. Or
well, Constantine, he could use his trench coat,
which is fireproof, to smother the magic flames,
which he does before flinging that coat at
Daredevil and causing it to wrap around his face.
And since that coat is demonically possessed,
Daredevil becomes trapped in this illusion that
he's in hell. Meanwhile, as flash rapidly heals
from his burn wounds, Green Arrow is going to
straight up turn Wolverine into a pincushion full
of arrows. Yeah, that's not even going to slow
Wolverine down. It's just going to send him into a
berserker rage where he straight up eviscerates
Green Arrow, legit turning him into deli slices,
except that those arrows that Green Arrow shot
into him were taser arrows. And Green Arrow is
going to trigger them as Wolverine charges right
for him. So Wolverine gets electrocuted and now
he's down for the count. No, because Dr. Strange is
going to magically extract the electricity
flowing through Wolverine's skeleton and form it
into like a sort of Zeus's thunderbolt. And then
he's going to hurl it at Hock Girl with her metal
wings. And she's going to get zapped. Meanwhile,
Deadpool, his leg is now healed from being blown
off, he's gonna teleport behind Green Lantern and
straight up shoot him in the back of the head. He's
gonna be like, your movie sucked. Okay, but Batman
sees Green Lantern about to get shot and so he rolls
this sharp ass battering that lodges right into
Deadpool's wrist before he pulls the trigger. And
that's gonna sever all of the nerves to his hand.
Isn't he like, oh no my girlfriend! And with Green
Lantern now aware that Deadpool is behind him,
he's going to generate a giant green wrench and
just whack Deadpool. That's gonna send him
tumbling across the battlefield. Okay, well,
Spider-Man is gonna web up Harley Quinn, web up her
skates. We're just gonna make her a trip and eat
shit. She tries to curse him out like, fuck you,
pajama man, but he's gonna web her mouth shut and
she's actually gonna put her in like this web
cocoon, just web her all up. Meanwhile, Iron Man
fires a repulsor blast at Blue Beetle that knocks
Blue Beetle to the floor and knocks Captain
America's shield off of his back. Okay, Blue
Beetle would probably get hit, but you know, he
would set up a giant shield in front of him to block
any additional beams from Iron Man. And then he'll
transform that shield into like this massive
energy cannon that he'll use to fire a giant laser
beam like the size of a semi truck right back at Iron
Man. Knocking his ass into outer space. It would
never even hit him because Captain Marvel flew
into the laser's path and absorbed all of that
energy from Blue Beetle. So she's like pulsing
with cosmic energy now and she just unloads all of
that into Superman. So it's Superman's ass that
gets knocked into outer space, not Iron Man. Okay,
meanwhile Aquaman has his Trident back and he's
locked in with a battle with Thor who we'll say has
generated this massive storm and has hurling
lightning at Aquaman. But Aquaman, he's gonna
slam his Trident into the earth to ground the
lightning strikes and then pull it out and use its
magic to gather all of the rainwater from the storm
into a swirling pillar of water, a whirlpool
around Thor that's going to drown him. And Aquaman
can control water now? Well, I mean technically
yes, like he controls water in the comics even
without the Trident now. But I mean he's been able
to do that more or less with various Tridents for
some time in the comics. I guess I don't understand
what a whirlpool is gonna do to Thor because he can
simply fly out of the whirlpool because no
current's gonna be able to hold him. Meanwhile
Hulk is gonna punch the ground hard enough to
create a fissure in the earth that the Flash falls
into and then dies. Dude, you think Flash can't
outrun a fissure? Or like run up a fissure wall? You
know, he's gonna do just that and then run literal
circles around the Hulk, vacuuming the air out of
his lungs and causing him to transform into Bruce
Banner. And when Flash notices that this happens,
he's gonna pick Banner up and just drop him off on
the other side of the planet and leave him there
before running back to the battle. Meanwhile
Shazam and Captain Marvel are gonna be trading
blows mid-air, but the wisdom of Solomon tells
Shazam that while she may have absorbed Blue
Beetle's energy attack, she probably can't
absorb magic. So that's when he summons this
massive bolt of living lightning that's gonna
crash Captain Marvel straight into the ground.
Okay, yeah, she can't absorb magic, that makes
sense, but Scarlet Witch is gonna fire a hex bolt at
Wonder Woman's lasso that's on her side causing it
to unravel and wrap around Wonder Woman and just
hog-tie her. And these knots are indestructible,
so Wonder Woman is powerless to escape her lasso.
Meanwhile, Black Panther leaps onto Hawkgirl's
back and uses his anti-metal claws to tear her
metal wings right off. She crashes into the ground
and probably tries to hit Black Panther with her
mace, which she does, but Black Panther absorbs
the blow of that with his Vibranium suit. So he gets
knocked away, but he's like vibrating with all of
this kinetic energy now. I don't think anti-metal
would break down like common Earth metals, so
while Black Panther sure does cause Hawkgirl to
crash to the ground from slashing her back, I'm
gonna say her wings remain intact, and Black
Panther, yeah, he's still knocked away by her mace
strike. But while that happened, Superman is
gonna swoop back to the battle from outer space and
he's just gonna rain down heat vision onto Captain
America who does not have a shield. No, he has a
shield. He got it back when it was knocked away from
Blue Beetle when Iron Man blasted him. So Captain
America uses the shield to block Superman's heat
vision and actually it reflects off of Captain
America's shield, hitting Aquaman, who burns and
gets dehydrated from the heat. Then Captain
America runs over to Daredevil and yanks
Constantine's coat off of his face, which pulls
him out of the Hell illusion. And now Free,
Daredevil flips over to Batman, dodging all of
Batman's strikes, and he wraps his Billy Club
cable around Batman's neck and just garots him.
Okay, well you know what, Daredevil didn't see
coming though? He doesn't see anything coming.
Exactly. But especially Harley Quinn's chaotic
tendency to show up just out of nowhere. Because
after getting out of Spider-Man's webbing with an
acid pellet, she's gonna load a stink bomb round
into her pop gun and fire that at Daredevil. And
that's gonna overload his senses with a smell
worse than hell. Allowing Batman to get free. And
while Daredevil is distracted, Harley Quinn's
gonna follow up with another round, this time a 9mm
one, which she's gonna use to send him to heaven. So
Daredevil's out? Yes, and meanwhile, Wonder
Woman, you know, she's been shimmying back and
forth while wrapped in her lasso, and that's gonna
give her enough slack to clap her bracelets
together. And that's gonna emit enough force to
cause a gap in the wrapping that allows Wonder
Woman to free herself. And now that she's free,
she's gonna lasso Captain Marvel by the neck and
just yank her toward her, slamming her fist right
into Captain Marvel's face, just to link her out
cold. Okay, but right before Wonder Woman's fist
makes contact with Captain Marvel, Captain
Marvel just explodes like an energy bomb, which is
gonna knock Wonder Woman away, and Captain
Marvel's gonna free herself from the lasso. While
that's happening, Captain America is going toe to
toe with Harley Quinn, and Harley Quinn just is not
gonna stand a chance in that fight. He's gonna
disarm all of her attacks and just knock her out
unconscious with his shield before she even has
anything funny to say. So Harley Quinn is now out of
the match. Okay, all right, well, Green Arrow and
Deadpool are gonna be battling, and Green Arrow is
gonna manage to fire several cheap shot boxing
glove arrows right at Deadpool's nut sack like it
was a speed bag. And while Deadpool's lying on the
ground wincing, that's when Green Arrow's gonna
pin his head to the floor with an adhesive arrow,
gluing it to the ground permanently so Deadpool's
also out. Okay, gluing his head to the ground with
an arrow through the brain? Yeah, that's pretty
clever. Okay, well, Doctor Strange uses the
Ayavaga Moto to find Bruce Banner on the other side
of the world, and he's gonna open a portal to bring
Hulk back into the battle. Okay, but the portal is
gonna be set up right above Hulk Girl, so Hulk drops
back into the fight, right onto Hulk Girl's back,
crashing her into the ground and smashing her to a
paste. Because he's like mega pissed right now, so
Hulk Girl's out of the match. Okay, all right, well
Flash, he's going to disarm Captain America, just
straight up take a shield from him, which he then
uses as a battering gram, speed battering him from
like every angle until he's knocked unconscious
and is out of the match. Okay, well then Flash tries
that battering gram shit on Spider-Man, but
Spider-Man's Spidey sense warns him to hop out of
the way at the last second, and then he webs Flash's
feet to the ground as the Flash is speeding by and
that sudden stop and momentum is gonna break the
Flash's ankle, completely hobbles him like he's
James Caan in misery. Geez. And then Spidey is
gonna flip drop heel kick Flash right in the head,
which is gonna completely knock the Flash out of
the match. That's messed up, but meanwhile
Constantine, he's, you know, using sigil shields
to ward off blasts from Captain Marvel, and he has
his coat back on, by the way, so he's gonna reach
into one of his coat pockets and pull out a flask,
which he hurls at her. And when Captain Marvel
blasts it out of the air, the flask actually
latches onto her energy, converting her into pure
light as it sucks her into the flask like a genie.
And once she's completely absorbed, he grabs it
out of the air, puts it back in its coat pocket, and
so she's out of the match. Oh, that was
interesting. Okay. Uh, well, speaking of Captain
Marvel being out, Scarlet Witch is gonna place a
psychic hex on Shazam, and that's gonna cause
Shazam to transform and de-age back into Billy
Batson, but the hex is like compounding. So Billy
continues de-aging until he's just a baby, and
then finally just a pair of microscopic
reproductive cells. So Shazam's out. Oh, look at
that. Scarlet Witch just got blown to smithereens
by a green tomahawk missile. Looks like Green
Lantern was sick of her shit. Black Panther is sick
of Green Arrow's shit. Not only does he sever the
line on Green Arrow's bow with his claws, which is
gonna render Green Arrow completely useless,
Black Panther is gonna follow up by releasing all
of that stored up kinetic energy he has in his
vibranium suit with a punch to Green Arrow's chest
that's just gonna shatter all of his ribs into
gravel. Alright, meanwhile, Aquaman, he's been
summoning a wellspring beneath him to rehydrate
him. And finally, like Old Faithful, this hot
geyser shoots out from beneath him, launching him
into the air, where he magically redirects the jet
stream onto Spider-Man, which is gonna pin him to
the ground before Aquaman lands right on top of him
and impaling him with his Trident. Wow, okay, Iron
Man didn't appreciate that. He saw that, and he
lets Aquaman know that he didn't appreciate it by
frying him with a beam of microwave energy that
evaporates all of the moisture in Aquaman's body
until he's fully cooked and now dead. Alright, you
know what? Superman, he's gonna grab Hulk with his
super speed, fly him straight into space, and just
hurl him towards the sun, harden fast enough that
Doctor Strange doesn't have time to magically
teleport him back. Now what? Wolverine is gonna be
fighting against Batman at that time, and Batman
gets taken out of the match by some claws that go
right through his skull, because plot armor will
not protect him against Adamantium. Wait, what
the heck? You're taking out Batman like so
unceremoniously? Yeah, Wolverine doesn't give a
fuck. Well, okay, guess what? Wolverine, he's
suddenly gonna get yanked to the ground by Blue
Beetle, who then pins his neck and wrist to the
ground with a few rounds from a giant blue staple
gun, essentially. And with Wolverine
immobilized, that's when Blue Beetle drops this
scarab-shaped grenade near him. That's gonna
generate a small nuclear blast that's gonna leave
only Wolverine's bones as Blue Beetle flies away.
Okay, but Thor is gonna finally settle the end of
our Justice League Avengers team duel, our first
team duel that we ever did. He's gonna channel his
supernatural godly energies into his hammer, and
he's gonna fire it from Mjolnir as a god blast that's
gonna punch a hole right through Superman, who is
vulnerable to magic. What? So, Thor's weakens
now, yes, but it was worth it because Superman is
out of this match. Okay, I thought he was gonna be my
last guy, not gonna lie. But when Thor does that,
that's suddenly when Mjolnir is gonna get snatched
by Wonder Woman's lasso. And so now she's Super
Asgardian Wonder Woman, and she's gonna lift the
hammer into the air and bring it down right on top of
the weakened Thor, taking him out of the match.
Come at me, bro. Okay, so Wonder Woman has Thor's
hammer, but Doctor Strange is gonna detach his
cloak of levitation and is gonna fly at Wonder
Woman, envelop her, and is gonna swallow her up
basically and teleport her to Asgard. Where Odin
sees this chick who killed his son and is wielding
Mjolnir now, Odin's gonna remove the hammer's
power and then just imprison Wonder Woman in their
dungeons. So Wonder Woman's out of the match. What
the hell? Alright, I was not expecting that, I will
admit. Uh-huh. But meanwhile, back to the battle,
Blue Beetle Scarab has analyzed the vibratory
nature of Black Panther's suit and produces a
counter-frequency that Blue Beetle fires at him
from a sonic cannon, shattering the vibranium
suit like it was glass. And with T'Challa exposed,
that's when he's gonna get impaled by a giant blue
lance from Blue Beetle's arm. So now Black
Panther's out. Interesting move, but little did
you know Iron Man has slowly been hacking the Blue
Beetle suit using nanotech drones that are gonna
force the Scarab to destroy its host, basically
disintegrating Jaime Reyes from within. And then
the Scarab is gonna fly over to Iron Man, now
programmed to incorporate itself into Iron Man's
armor. So now Iron Man is Iron Beetle. And good luck
with that. Oh yeah, no problem. The Scarab Kajida
is rich alien technology, but it's been corrupted
by magic before. So that was actually stupid on
behalf of Iron Man because Constantine knows the
history of the Scarab, and so he's gonna recite a
self-destruct incantation that Iron Man can't
decode in time, so kaboom, Iron Man's out. Ah,
okay. Dr. Strange sees this, and he's gonna detect
the dark occult magic that's in Constantine, and
he's gonna trace that to all the demons that are in
hell that own a part of Constantine's soul. So Dr.
Strange is gonna use a little bit of dark magic to
summon these demons to the battlefield, or to each
rip Constantine to pieces and drag him to hell in
small bits. No, dang. That's like the worst way to
take out Constantine. Good. Well, I guess it's
down to Green Lantern and Dr. Strange. Here it is.
The last one standing, the duel to end all duels,
and Green Lantern is gonna be the one to quick draw
first. He's gonna point his ring at Dr. Strange,
trapping and freezing him in a giant Green
Lantern, like a power battery that's on Oa, which
has held entities like Parallax, and the Lantern
battery drains Dr. Strange of all of his magic
power. And Green Lantern is going to use it to power
his own ring with like star-heart magical energy,
and he's gonna be like, beware my power. Green
Lantern's light! And he's gonna snap his fingers,
and Dr. Strange just ceases to exist. End of match.
You're right. Yep. Yep. And then Dr. Strange wakes
up from his trance, recognizing that that was one
of the thousands of simulations where his marble
team didn't win. So with the compounded knowledge
of everything that his team needs to do to win, he's
gonna confer with the rest of the Marvel heroes
outside of time, and then he's gonna rewind the
clock back to the start of the match with everyone
knowing exactly what they need to do to win
decisively and swiftly. And the DC guys just
fucking get annihilated. They're gonna be
thinking they suck so hard because they get
defeated so quickly, and even Batman's gonna be
like, what the hell? Before he dies. And Marvel
wins. Match over. In the ten years of this podcast,
the stupidest thing I've ever heard come out of
your mouth. Or the coolest. The podcast network
presents Konsole Kombat, where video game legends
brawl every Monday. Dynamic Duel, where comic
book titans smash every Tuesday. Max
Destruction, where TV and action heroes battle
every Wednesday. And Senjoh World, where anime
champions clash every Thursday. Join us as we
speculate on the matches and armed with the power
of mathematical simulations, discover who will
emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com,
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
Let's go ahead and find out which of these
scenarios happens. Either Green Lantern traps
Dr. Strange in a power battery, drains his magic,
and uses it to power up his ring and snap Dr. Strange
out of existence. Or Dr. Strange foresees that
happening, rewinds time, and uses the battle
information to help the Marvel heroes defeat the
DC side. Let's go ahead and input all the character
stats, run all the simulations, and find out who
wins. Marvel or DC. AJ9K? Hit it! Alright, I think
that felt sufficiently epic for our final ever
duel and team duel. This was a whole lot of math. It
took us a couple days to actually run all of these
simulations. There's a whole lot of data here, a
lot to pour into. To start off, the most powerful
guys from each side were Green Lantern and Dr.
Strange. My weakest guy on Marvel was a tie between
Daredevil and Captain America, but the weakest
person overall on both teams was Harley Quinn.
Weakest statistically, I should say. Right.
Breaking it down by category, the biggest stat
discrepancy between the two teams overall was
intelligence. Marvel actually came out ahead in
that category because of people like Bruce
Banner, Spider-Man, T'Challa, Iron Man, and Dr.
Strange. We had a lot of intellectual
powerhouses, whereas DC mostly had Constantine,
Batman, and that's pretty much it. Yeah, that was
the biggest discrepancy, but DC also came out
pretty far ahead in terms of speed. Thanks to
characters like Flash, Shazam, Superman, Wonder
Woman, we were a lot faster than the Marvel guys.
And the DC team was a lot more versatile,
especially among characters like Green Lantern,
Blue Beetle, Constantine, Green Arrow, Batman.
They're all really well equipped. Marvel's side,
though, wasn't a slouch when it came to the
fighting skills stat. Characters like Captain
America, Wolverine, Daredevil, Deadpool are all
really skilled in fighting. Yeah, compared to my
side where my best fighters were Batman, Wonder
Woman, and Green Arrow. And Hawkgirl was up there,
too. Let's break down the pairings individually.
In the matchup between Superman and the Hulk,
Superman won 75.3% of their matches. I'm not too
surprised by that, just because Superman is
arguably strong, if not stronger than the Hulk,
and has all the versatility of his other
Kryptonian powers. In the Batman vs. Captain
America pairing, also no surprise for me, Batman
won that 72.8% of the time. I guess the result there
isn't surprising for me, but the win rate for
Batman is surprising. In the end, Captain America
is just as good as a fighter as Batman, but can't
compete with Batman's versatility or
intelligence. That's what it came down to. In the
Wonder Woman vs. Captain Marvel fight, DC won
again, with Wonder Woman beating Captain Marvel
56.2% of the time. This one was a little bit closer.
Captain Marvel just wasn't quite as durable or as
strong as Wonder Woman. Yeah, honestly, in
regards to this matchup, I was actually
surprised. I was thinking Captain Marvel was
going to come out ahead, but I was really happy to
see that Wonder Woman did. In the Green Lantern vs.
Scarlet Witch matchup, DC wins yet again, with
Green Lantern pulling off a 72.5% win rate over
Scarlet Witch, which I'm calling bullshit. The
problem is that Green Lanterns are just so
impressive statistically, because they have all
the powers, and Scarlet Witch, even though she's
almost maxed out in stats like damage level,
invasiveness and versatility, she was lacking in
other key areas like fighting skill,
intelligence, and durability. Right, so DC has
won all four matches so far, but that ended when we
picked Spider-Man against the Flash. I totally
thought the Flash was going to win this, but
Spider-Man did. 54.3% of their 1000 matches.
Which, what? Yeah, for as fast as the Flash is,
Spider-Man is arguably a slightly better
fighter. He has a Spider sense which helps him, and
he's stronger. So that was a close matchup, but
Spider-Man did narrowly get the victory there. In
the Aquaman vs. Black Panther matchup,
unfortunately Aquaman won that one, winning
54.1% of the time over Black Panther. Again, that
was a pretty close one as well. It looks like
Nth Metal does win the war against Vibranium. I
don't know about that, but Aquaman did eke out a win
due to his strength stat. In the matchup between
Iron Man and Blue Beetle, Earth comes out ahead
against the aliens because Iron Man won 67.7% of
the matches compared to Blue Beetle's 32.3%. I'm
not surprised by that one. I will say that Blue
Beetle was a lot more statistically impressive
than I thought he would be against Iron Man. But
Iron Man still had a pretty damn high win rate, so it
just goes to show that Iron Man is just way better
than Blue Beetle, largely due to his
intelligence. Yeah, Iron Man was one of your most
powerful characters, very impressive
statistically. In the Thor vs. Shazam fight, now
this is one of the fights that took place in the 90s
crossover, we can definitively say that Thor does
beat Shazam, 59.5% of the time. In the end, Shazam
was just a little bit too much of a one-trick pony,
with Thor being able to do everything that Shazam
could do, but even more. In our closest pairing,
Wolverine beat Hawkgirl 50.2% of the time.
Cointoss. Now this is kind of a throwback to our
Hawk Man vs. Wolverine duel episode. I'm really
glad we redid that though because if you listened
to that episode, the power set we used for Hawk Man
was very specific to the new 52 era and completely
outdated. They didn't have identical stats, Hawk
Girl was more evasive because she could fly and she
was stronger, but Wolverine was a better fighter
and more durable. They kind of evened each other
out, therefore, a Cointoss. In the matchup
between Doctor Strange and Constantine, Doctor
Strange won 73.8% of the time due to a variety of
stats. I think largely it just comes down to the
fact that Doctor Strange is a sorcerer, whereas
Constantine is an occultist, and therefore
things just come a little bit slower and harder for
him. But also Doctor Strange is a powerhouse
statistically. He has all the powers, he's super
smart. Right, again, your most powerful
character. In one of my favorite pairings, Green
Arrow vs Daredevil, I'm happy to say that Green
Arrow won 54.5% of the time, which I think means
that Bullseye would totally stop in a real matchup
against Daredevil. Out of all the matches so far,
this one pisses me off the most because I don't see
how Green Arrow would ever hit Daredevil. I guess
sometimes Bullseye does hit Daredevil in their
fights, but what really eaked Green Arrow over the
top was his versatility. Daredevil just has his
Billy Club, and it doesn't have as good of a range as
Green Arrow's plethora of arrows. Eventually,
Green Arrow's going to tag him or choose some kind
of arrow that overwhelms his senses. It's
bullshit. In the final matchup, where we pit
Deadpool against Harley Quinn, I don't think this
is any surprise, Deadpool won 61.1% of the time.
Harley Quinn had a more varied arsenal with all of
her silly gadgets, but Deadpool's healing factor
was just second to none, unless you're Wolverine.
Or the Hulk. But I mean, like we said earlier,
Harley Quinn was my weakest character. She
actually did not come out ahead in a majority of her
matches. Now, tallying it all up, we had 12
matches, and surprisingly, we each had 6 wins. Yah
yah, really lucky with the Wolverine vs. Hulk girl
fight, because that was a coin toss, and if
Wolverine didn't win that one, the overall score
would have been DC7 Marvel 5. But, since we each won
6 matches, I guess it's a tie for Marvel and DC. No,
no, no, no. We have the total wins for all of the
matches for all of these characters, so let's find
out who actually wins between everyone. AJ9K, the
results please. Hey, you are, sir. The winner of
the matchup between Team DC and Team Marvel is...
Team DC! Fuck you! Fuck you! This doesn't really
mean that DC would win, it just means that these
particular 12 characters would beat these
particular 12 Marvel characters. Hey, we chose
these characters as the 12 representatives of our
respective universe. We've never done a team
matchup with this many characters before. You
have to accept DC's victory. They won 51.4% of the
total matches compared to Marvel who won 48.6%.
Sir, DC officially wins. DC is officially better,
and I officially demand an apology from you. After
nearly 40 years, vol of your bullshit, saying that
Marvel characters are better when clearly they
are inferior. First of all, you can go straight up
fuck yourself. Second of all, those results are a
coin toss. If DC only won 50.4% of the matches...
51.4%. Oh, well, it's still pretty close. Third of
all, go fuck yourself again, harder. And then
fourth of all, I think we should judge these
results based off of the number of individual
pairing wins, which is 6-to-6, which is a tie.
You're trying to get me to admit that Marvel loses
overall when really it was just a breakdown of
these 24 characters. Dude, what do you think this
podcast has been about for the past 10 years? Yes,
I'm trying to get you to admit that Marvel would
lose. They did. Hashtag deal with it. Also
hashtag, give me an apology. What we're going to do
is actually tally up all the wins and losses for
Marvel and DC throughout the 10 years of this
podcast in our next episode to reveal the actual
true winner between these two universes. But
we'll save that for our final episode. And just a
general retrospective of the podcast over the
past decade. Yeah, join us for our final episode
next week as we say goodbye to you guys for now.
Right, again, the podcast isn't going away
completely. We're just ending the weekly show.
We're ending the duels and switching to
exclusively a review focused show. AJ9K, help
close this out. Thanks to everyone for tuning into
this penultimate episode. Again, if you haven't
left us a voicemail, please visit our website at
dynamicduel.com to do so. Yeah, click the red
microphone button. We'd love to hear from you guys
and say our goodbyes. Thanks to everyone who's
helped to make this podcast possible. And we'll
talk to you guys next week up up and away. True
believers. Oh, so no more duels from here on out,
huh? Thanks, guys. I guess I'll just go fuck
myself.