This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi, welcome to
the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Johnny DC and I'm his twin
brother Marvelous Joe. And welcome to our spooky
Halloween episode where we find out who is going to
win between DC's House of Mystery and Marvel's
Crypt of Shadows. So we're gonna do things a little
bit differently this time. Basically the House of
Mystery and the Crypt of Shadows were both comic
book series that told anthological horror
stories, kind of like Tales from the Crypt, if you
guys remember that. That was a television show
that was based off of a comic book series.
Basically they all tell horror stories in comic
book format. Here we're gonna find out who can tell
the better horror stories based off of characters
from Marvel and DC. Yeah, these are original
stories that Joseph and I came up with. We're gonna
try and scare the shit out of each other and maybe
the listeners Well I'm not easily scared so you're
gonna have a hard time with this one. Before we get
into this matchup we're gonna break down the
latest comic book movie news of which there was
none. Again probably because we're just fresh off
of New York Comic Con where the studios kind of
revealed their hands and won't have much else to
show for a while. As always we list our segment
times in our episode description so feel free to
check out the show notes if you want to skip ahead to
a particular topic. Guys our artificially
intelligent dual simulator AJ9K has a quick
message for our listeners so listen up. Why hello
there do you want even more from this podcast? Then
become a part of the dynamic dual community on
Patreon where you can choose from three tiers. The
dynamic 2.0 tier gives you access to our discord
chat server. The fantastic 4.0 tier gives you two
bonus episodes each month and the X-Force tier
makes you an executive producer of this show.
Lastly the Diner Mike podcast network tier lets
you create your own podcast using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and
consultation and get you simulation results.
Pitch the twins your ideas via email at
dynamicduolpodcast at gmail.com. Check it out at
patreon.com slash dynamicduol. Pip pip cheerio.
Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast. Be sure to tune into the other shows in
the Diner Mike podcast network this week
including the console combat podcast where hosts
John and Dean simulate battles between popular
video game characters. In yesterday's episode
they did a comparison of the 2002 Resident Evil
film and 2021's reboot Resident Evil Welcome to
Raccoon City. Over on the Max Instruction podcast
hosts Scotty and Gilly pick your favorite action
heroes from film and television against each
other. On Wednesday they're going to review
Freddie versus Jason. And on the Send Your World
podcast hosts Zachary Hepburn speculates on
fights between fan favorite anime and manga
characters. In his next episode Zach is revealing
who would win between Shigeyo Kageyama aka Mob
from Mob Psycho 100 and Tatsumaki the tornado of
terror from One Punch Man. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our show
notes to listen to all the shows in the Diner Mike
podcast network. But with that out of the way quick
to the no prize. A no prize is an award that Marvel
used to give out to fans. Our version the dynamic
dual no prize is a digital award we post on
Instagram for the person that we feel gave the best
answer to our question of the week. Last week we
asked you guys where the fuck were you guys last
week wrong answers only and that of course was
coming off of the previous week's question from
which we got no answers mainly because it was a bad
question. You guys had a lot of fun with this one.
This week we actually have five honorable
mentions which we'll go through all at once before
naming the no prize winner. The honorable
mentions will be going to Lee Tapscott, Alex
Albro, Matt from Texas, Daniel Alonzo and Travis
Herndon. Who said? Lee Tapscott here and another
Marvel DC team up event. I was kidnapped and held
hostage because I had a better name for their
movies than they did. But I was told it would be okay
for me to call in this week in an attempt to win the no
prize as long as I didn't give you the names that I
came up with for their movies. This is where I was
last week and was unable to call in. Sorry. Okay
look I'm so sorry I was having a really amazing
conversation with some DC fans about how their
movies are great their acting is great the CGI is
always amazing. Just telling them how great
they're like costume designs they're designed
for just their characters their stories. So yeah I
just got so busy really telling these DC fans how
how awesome DC is. Hey guys Matt from Texas here.
See what had happened was I was going to call in from
this earth but then somehow ended up on an earth
where DC movies actually have consistent
continuity. It was fucking wild man. 10-10 would
go back. If you don't like that excuse well
flashpoint happened and somehow it became my own
grandpa and that's weird so I'm dealing with that
right now. Thanks for looking out. What's up
dynamic dudes Travis here shout out to me in
between. Well you see what happened was I was going
to answer your question but a portal opened up in my
house and I got sucked into to this alternate
universe where I fought a giant monkey man and
saved the ninth dimension. Then I went before I
went back to our universe I got sucked into another
portal and fought a smaller monkey man and saved
the eighth dimension. So yeah I was fighting giant
monkey man and I'm a hero in two dimensions. You're
welcome. Great excuses guys. Generally excuses
are not a good thing but in this case I enjoyed
listening to them. So thank you for calling in this
time. But the winner of this week's No Prize is CJ
Kraft who said hey guys CJ Kraft here just wanted to
apologize for not calling in last week. Me and my
girlfriend drove up to a secluded cabin in
Michigan and read from some book of the dead called
the Necronomicon. Anyway a long story short I got
this nifty new chainsaw arm and I had to go back in
time and save the human race. Luckily I got back in
time to at least hear the new episode though it was
amazing. I kind of feel like that was spoilers
which is the most horrifying thing of all.
Spoilers for the Evil Dead franchise. Yeah
congrats to CJ Kraft. You won this week's No Prize
because it was a scary movie reference and this is
the Halloween episode. Speaking of Evil Dead I did
end up watching Evil Dead Rising a few weeks ago and
it was pretty hardcore. I think I still like the
reboot the most though. Are the one directed by
Fetty Alvarez? Yeah yeah I refused to watch that.
Congrats again to CJ Kraft for winning this week's
No Prize. If you the listener want to shout out
winning your own No Prize stay tuned to later on
this episode when we'll be asking another
question of the week. All right the House of
Mystery opens along with the Crypt of Shadows.
Let's go out and find out who has the more
terrifying tales and emerge as the winner. Okay
House of Mystery and the Crypt of Shadows of course
as we mentioned earlier these were two horror
anthology series produced by DC and Marvel
respectively. The House of Mystery was once the
home of the DC character of Kane but has since
become the headquarters of the Justice League
Dark. So the House of Mystery was not only a comic
book series it was actually like a location within
DC Comics. Yeah it's become one. Same thing with
Crypt of Shadows actually so the Crypt of Shadows
was a horror anthology series by Marvel that
turned out to be in the basement essentially of the
Sanctum Sanctorum where Dr. Strange lives. It's
like a mausoleum underneath his house and the
stories have had like different narrators over
the years kind of like how the tales from the crypt
had the crypt keeper and the creep show comics had
the creep. Well living in the mausoleum was Dr.
Strange's brother Victor Strange and he would
often narrate the stories but also like I think in
last year's Crypt of Shadows special it was Agatha
Harkness who narrated the stories or she saw the
stories in her like crystal ball. For a while the
narrator of House of Mystery was Elvira. For DC
really? Yeah I had no idea she was a DC character.
She isn't really? I don't know how they pulled that
off but they did for a time. She replaced Kane.
Interesting. Well for this particular matchup
the narrator of the Crypt of Shadows tales is going
to be Nightmare who is a Dr. Strange villain. He's
basically the ruler of the dream dimension and a
fear lord born from the collective subconscious
of all of Marvel's sentient beings. He feeds on
fear by invading dreams and trapping souls within
his realm and he often plagues Marvel's mystic
characters. In his realm the dream dimension he
has omnipotent power and in the mortal plane he
still has considerable might I would say. He's
like super strong, can teleport, he can
manipulate dark energy, cast illusions, he has
some like psychic abilities and he also has a wand
that could warp reality. So he's a formidable
character but he's also going to tell you the
scariest stories that you've ever heard
Jonathan. Which makes sense for a character like
Nightmare. I feel like that's a really good choice
for your Crypt of Shadows narrator. For the House
of Mystery narrator this round I'm going with the
Phantom Stranger who originated in a horror
anthological series titled Phantom Stranger. Oh
interesting. Like Nightmare he's also basically
omnipotent but he's also omniscient. He knows way
more than people realize. He's very mysterious.
Like that's his main power. His true origins have
never definitively been revealed. He's possibly
a fallen angel or the wandering Jew or Judas
Iscariot condemned to wander the earth. Over the
ages he's appeared throughout history as this
unseen guide to those standing at moral
crossroads and serves unseen powers in the
endless struggle between good and evil forever
walking between them. That sounds pretty
interesting. Before we get into our duel matchup
though let's go ahead and go to our sentient duel
simulator Alfred Jarvis 9000 who will tell our
listeners how he goes about determining a winner
in our duel matchups. Yes of course sir. The way I
determine a winner between the two teams is by
running 1,000 Monte Carlo simulations between
every character on each team using their
statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation is a
probabilistic model used to determine outcomes
through random sampling. In this case I randomize
the statistics along a normal distribution as a
way to simulate the many variables that can occur
during battle. The stat parameters are based on
the official Marvel power grid from which the DC
characters statistics are extrapolated.
Additional stat categories are included such as
range, damage potential, versatility and
perception in order to create a more detailed and
accurate simulation. The results of the 49,000
simulations provide a percentage of wins for each
character on both teams. The team with the higher
average win rate is declared the victor as they
have a higher probability to win any given battle.
In an equitable pairing neither team should win
100% of the matches. The comic book stories have
shown that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman so the confidence rate of my method falls
in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks HNAK. Before
we run the simulations though we're going to get
into the spooky stories. So Nightmare emerges
from the crypt of shadows, Phantom Stranger steps
out of the house of mystery, they meet at a campfire
between the two locations and let's say that
Nightmare goes first with his three stories. The
first tale of terror being about a naughty night
writer who's been axing all the wrong questions.
But don't worry her road trip will be cut short by
Ghostwriter who has a real bone to pick. Buckle up
kids, it's time for a joy ride straight to hell in a
story called The Heart of Black. Olivia Yand, she
had been driving for nearly 10 hours straight
through the empty desert but even exhaustion
wasn't going to stop her from what she had to do. She
looked at the axe resting on her passenger seat. A
glint of moonlight showed the deep red stains on
the blade. Olivia smiled, her stepson had gotten
what he deserved and now it was her husband's turn
to join him as pieces in the trunk. It wouldn't be
long now. The car was starting to stink, a little
like rotten eggs. Suddenly the axe gleamed
catching the light from the car's rear view.
Olivia peered through the mirror to see what was
behind her. On the road were two approaching
headlights. Another car was on the road. It
flashed its brights again, illuminating her car
interior. Just pass, Olivia murmured. The
headlights flashed her again as they grew closer.
She rolled down her window and motioned the car
forward. Go on Jackass! She shouted. Suddenly the
headlights turned off. Peering back into her rear
view mirror, Olivia saw nothing but endless
black. What the hell was that? She grumbled to
herself. Maybe she imagined it or maybe the car
broke down and died. Maybe the driver needed help
and would be stranded in the middle of the desert to
die. Olivia preferred the latter option. It would
serve them right. Suddenly brightness flooded
her car again as the headlights turned back on. The
car was right behind her. Olivia gasped as her
throat went dry. What was this guy doing? The car
crashed into her back bumper. Her head rocked
forward, slamming into the steering wheel. What
the fuck? She screamed. She stomped on the gas
pedal, swerving as she regained control of the
wheel. Her heart raced. This guy must be trying to
kill her. He must be a psycho. He must know what she
did. She thought about pulling over and grabbing
her axe. Now on the car floor, she felt blood from
her head injury drop onto her brow. The car slammed
into her again. No! Olivia cried out as she fought
to regain control of the wheel. Then the bright
blue light flooding her car turned orange. And
warm. Olivia glanced in her rear view again. The
car was on fire? The impact must have ruptured a
fuel line or maybe his engine overheated. Maybe
now he'll leave. She fixed her eyes on the fiery car
as it slowly fell back. She peered behind her
trying to make out the driver. It looked like he was
on fire inside his car. Yes, good. No. Wait. The
driver was smiling. He was smiling and his face was
on fire. No, his face was gone. It had melted off
from the flames. And he was still driving. Olivia
felt a cold chill run down her spine. This third
slam caused Olivia to lose control. Her head
slammed into her side window as the car drifted
into a spin before screeching to a halt. With blood
pouring over her eyes, she saw the fiery car parked
in front of her. The driver was a flaming skeleton
clad in black. It stepped out and walked toward
her, grinning and holding chains. Olivia tried to
gasp but her throat was closed in shock. Jesus
Christ! She managed to squeak out. I'm close. Said
the voice in the back seat behind her. In her
mirror, she saw a rose of glistening teeth and big
red eyes. The last thing she remembered was the
smell of sulfur and the sound of her own ripping
flesh. The next morning, a highway patrolman took
a statement from Robbie Reyes. The back seat of
Olivia's car was melted into black glass. So the
limbs in the car are from a separate body than the
limbs in the trunk then, the officer said. He
scratched his head. Just what the hell happened?
Robbie's eyes burned faintly as he turned back to
his car. Black heart, he responded. Come again,
the officer asked. He turned her heart black, he
said and shut the door. Poor Olivia thought she
could bury the hatchet in her husband, but instead
she ended up getting burned. I guess you could say
Olivia suffered from unintended consequences at
the hands of Blackheart, which Phantom Stranger
notes have also been faced by a character in his
universe, Nightshade, in a tale he calls the Vale
of Fog. As the princess of the land of Nightshades,
a twilight realm between reality and nightmare,
Eve Eden knew better than anyone that shadows are
born of light. As the hero Nightshade, she used
shadows themselves to fight the forces of
darkness within her adoptive realm alongside
Earth's most powerful magicians. It was her
mystical attunement that drew her like a moth to
flame to the secluded coastal town of Greyhaven.
Blanketed in a Vale of Fog, the town's landscape
and buildings appeared suddenly, as if conjured
at the whim of its perpetual grey mist. The thick
fog seemed to weigh on Greyhaven citizenry, slow,
quiet, and uninterested in the newcomer to their
town. Hunched adults shuffled down sidewalks,
children sat in solitude. The silence was
deafening. At night, the faint glow of the dim
streetlights illuminated nothing but the dense
fog around them. The streets were empty, and not a
single light shined through a shop or house
window. Eve was able to see in the dark, but not past
the heavy grey mist of Greyhaven. She summoned a
dozen homunculene shadow creatures under her
control to scout the environment. A few of them
guided her to a towering lighthouse, atop a
cliffside. It's beacon, dark. Eve stepped
through its shadowy doorway, using the darkness
to portal straight to the top of the tower. A young
boy sat atop its ledge, gazing at the mist over the
ocean. Starterled upon seeing Eve, he slipped
from the ledge and fell. Eve reacted instantly,
her shadow lashing out like a whip and catching him
by the ankle. She drew him back to safety. I'm
sorry, she said softly. I didn't mean to frighten
you. The boy laughed, breathless. It's alright.
You're the first person I've seen up here, and I
don't know how long. As sunrise approached, the
two of them conversed. She asked him about the
town, and the boy told her that Greyhaven had been
covered in a fog for as long as he could remember.
The town used to be a port, but when the lighthouse
beacon went out, the ship stopped coming. When Eve
asked why no one fixed it, the boy said the town
didn't have the supplies to do so. Their secluded
village was dependent on the provisions from the
ships, and without them, they had to manage by
their own means. Eve examined the beacon. There
was something strange about it, beyond it being
physically broken, as if someone had placed a
spell on it. She resolved to fix it. At sunrise, Eve
floated down from the top of the lighthouse into a
shadow portal she created below. It took her about
a day to research how to repair the beacon and for
her homunculi to find the necessary supplies,
which she portaled back to the Greyhaven
lighthouse. The boy watched as she and her shadow
creatures repaired the light. It didn't take
long, and Eve paused to admire her work before
flipping the switch. The beam of light swept
across the town, piercing and dispelling the
blanketed fog within its path. To Eve's horror,
the boy dissipated when the light struck him, as
though he were made from the same mist. His
horrified expression lingered before
evaporating. She quickly looked down on the town
below. With the fog vanishing, she could see the
people looking up at her, as they too disappeared
once the light touched them. The elderly,
children, all gone. She shattered the beacon with
a massive shadowy fist and teleported to the now
exposed town square below. A mere handful of
people remained within the lingering bit of fog,
crying and confused as to what just happened to
their friends and relatives. It wasn't long
before Eve learned that the people of Greyhaven
were ghosts, protected from the light and the
truth for decades by whoever conjured the fog. As
she apologetically ushered the remaining
Greyhaven ghosts through a portal into the land of
nightshades to start a new life, she remembered
that shadows are born of light, and likewise, the
purest intentions can have the darkest of
consequences. A ghost town is pretty scary, but
uh, not scary enough, not like Nightmare's Next
Tale, which takes us deep in the Florida
Everglades, where you'll meet Jennifer Kale, a
witchy woman with a swamping suspicion that
something nasty is bubbling beneath the surface.
Here's a story of corpses, creeps, and carnage I
call Crimson Lands. 10. This Way Jennifer Kale
shouted at Manthing. The swamp creature snapped
out of his trance and slowly lumbered to her
location. For as important as Manthing was to the
protection of this reality, he wasn't very
bright. That's why Jennifer knew that her
presence alongside him was so important.
Guarding the Nexus of All Realities may have been
Manthing's responsibility, but he was hers. A
portal of magic in the middle of the Florida
Everglades, the Nexus connected the swamp to
infinite worlds and endless dimensions.
Sometimes, things came through it that you
wouldn't want to, and all too often, people died in
the swamp. Jennifer pointed down at the murky
water, not far from the Nexus. Manthing reached
his monstrous hand down into the sludge, pulling
something back out. A corpse. Jennifer gagged.
The body was half decayed, modeled and infested
with maggots crawling in and out of its rotted
flesh. Black ooze seeped out of its riddled skin.
Its body was covered in vines, and its face
distorted in a terrified, silent scream.
Jennifer flicked away a leech crawling out of its
cheek. She looked closely at the body to get a hint
as to why it called to her. Her witchcraft was
powerful, but it's not as if she could raise the
dead. The corpse lashed out and clamped its hand
around her jaw, spewing black, putrid ooze over
her. She vomited as Manthing crushed the body in
his grasp and threw it into the trees. He put his
hand on Jennifer's back as she wiped sludge from
her eyes. Pfft. It moved! Jennifer sputtered. She
looked up and saw a dozen corpses slowly rise from
the murky water all around them. What evil is this?
She whispered, and stuttered, jagged motions,
the vine-riddled bodies crept toward them, their
decayed arms reaching out. Jennifer raised her
hand, using witchcraft to engulf one of the
corpses and flames. Manthing lunged at another,
using his claws to tear it to pieces. He lunged
again, grabbing one and squeezing it like jelly.
The corpses started to pile on him as he tried to
pull them off. There were too many, and more were
rising from the swamp by the second. Ted! Jennifer
called out at Manthing. Suddenly a wall of roots
and wooden vines erupted from the ground,
separating them. No! She shouted, punching
through the barrier with a magic blast. Behind it
was another wall. They rose up all around her like a
hedge maze. She tried levitating above the maze,
but the vines reached up to pull her down into the
mud below. She crawled out and trudged her way
through the corridors, looking for a way out, but
the maze shifted and reformed, trapping her in its
passage. A horde of corpses rose and stumbled
toward her, spewing ooze and fetid sludge, and the
passage itself narrowed, closing in on her.
There's no use fighting, came a voice in an Irish
brogue. The swamp belongs to me, and it has no more
need for the walking mulch heap. Jennifer froze,
realizing whom the voice was referring to. Ted!
She screamed. She unleashed a magic wave of energy
that tore down the walls and corpses around her.
Across the clearing, she saw Manthing's body
strewn across the swamp, decimated by a man
holding a gnarled wooden staff. It was Black Tom
Cassidy, manipulator of wood and plant life. The
corpses then awakened not from necromancy, but
from the vines, roots and mold threaded through
their rotted flesh, his puppet strings. What are
you doing, Tom? Jennifer shrieked at him as she
walked toward the swirling nexus. As I said to her,
the swamp is mine, Black Tom shouted. Therefore,
the nexus is mine, and therefore, everything is
now his. He paused to smile and wave as he entered
the portal, disappearing into the nexus. For a
moment, there was only silence. Jennifer
wondered who Black Tom was referring to. Was it his
friend, the juggernaut? Was he enthralled to
someone else? Suddenly, she felt the ground
shudder beneath her. The nexus convulsed, its
light flickered and cracked like a wound
splitting open. Waves of blood gushed from the
rift in a roaring flood pouring across the swamp.
The water churned red as if the land itself were
bleeding. The corpses rose again, lurching
through the Crimson Mire, their jaws dripping.
Jennifer looked out around her, waist deep in the
nightmare. The dead spoke in one voice. CITAROCK!
The Crimson God, his bloody campaign had just
begun. Jennifer Kale got more than a little bogged
down there, and Black Tom Cassidy working with
Citerock sounds like an alliance that will leaf
the whole multiverse screaming. Yeah, evil
forces working behind the scenes are definitely
terrifying, and it's a concept not unknown to a
particular character in DC known as the Ragman and
his tale that the Phantom Stranger is calling A
Thief in the Night. They say you should never pray
for patience, for God presents you with the
opportunities to practice the traits that you ask
for. Rabbi Judah Lowe knew this in 16th century
Prague, so rather than patiently wait for the
prophesied savior of his people, he took it upon
himself to craft his own, a Gollum from mud and
mysticism. The grotesque monster initially
protected his people from attacks, pogroms, and
genocide, but the Gollum fell out of the rabbi's
control and went on a murderous rampage that
spilled the innocent blood of his people.
Realizing his quest for justice had led to a
serious and equal measure to the one he sought to
stop. Rabbi Lowe destroyed his creation. He and
other rabbis within Prague soon came together
seeking a solution to their plight, rooted not in
justice, but in redemption. Thus they formed a rag
suit from the tattered clothing of those killed by
the Gollum, a suit that bore their souls and could
offer their strength to a new savior, the Ragman.
Throughout the centuries, those who wore the suit
of rags protected the Jewish people, absorbing
the souls of men who would do their people harm,
using that soul's strength until it had paid the
price for its sins. As the souls of evil doers
waited patiently for their redemption within the
rags of the current ragman, Rory Reagan, the
impatience of another council of religious men,
this time in the vaults of the Vatican, resulted in
the yet another abomination, made not from mud,
but from sacred blood extracted from the shroud of
Turin, the burial cloth of Jesus Christ during
their studies of the artifact. They used the DNA to
impregnate a young, naive Jewish virgin with a
Christ clone in an effort to usher in the second
coming. For nine months, the woman named Miriam
lay chained to a bed beneath the Vatican, until
suddenly, like a thief in the night, the clone tore
its way into the world, its wrinkled red eyes
shining with an ancient malice too old for any
newborn. Horrified at the realization of what
they had done, the Vatican scientists attempted
to kill the clone, but not before Miriam.
Suffering as she was from the violent birth,
managed to escape with her child, swaddled an
apportion of the very shroud that helped create
her unholy offspring. From the time Miriam was her
son's age, she was told stories of the Jewish hero,
the ragman, who protected her people from evil.
She barely made it to him before collapsing, her
last words begging him to save her baby. Rory
barely heard her as his writhing rags emerged
reactively, the souls trapped within whispering
confusedly in his head from the nearby presence of
entities so holy and evil. Upon touching the
shroud, it adhered itself to a suit. Threads of
holiness pierced the damned fabric like nails
through flesh, and Rory's senses were
overwhelmed by the power that now coursed through
his body, his typical ragged green cape, now in the
visage of an angel's white wings. The infant in his
arms shrieked, its shrill cry underlaced with a
lion's roar that restored Rory to his senses and
the sobering realization that he was now staring
down the barrels of dozens of armed Vatican
soldiers. Surrounded, he weighed surrender
against a mother's last wish. With his surging new
power, he could easily survive the Vatican's
attack, but to what purpose he was unclear.
Looking down into the infant's glowing eyes,
Ragman foresaw the apocalypse and heard foul
promises from the babe inside his head. Rory,
praying for the strength to do what had to be done,
cried in pain to the heavens as he absorbed the
child's soul into his suit, transforming it from
white to gray. As he laid the lifeless baby upon its
dead mother on the ground, he heard the child
whisper from within him, and Ragman wondered if
what he had done was mercy or a sin greater than the
golem. Time would tell. Patience is a virtue, they
say, as is a promise kept, but a patient promise is
prophecy itself, and prophecy is inevitable. I
prophesize that Nightmare's final tale here is
going to make the Phantom Stranger shit his pants.
This final lesson in horror takes us to the halls of
Strange Academy, where the young pupil Calvin
Morse worries about passing his tests when maybe
he should be worried about passing away. Classes
in session for a tale I call the Many-Angled One.
Calvin Morse Calvin Morse opened the door to
Wong's office. As the instructor for the Mystical
Defense course at Strange Academy, Wong was known
for holding one-on-one sessions for students
seeking academic help. In Calvin's case,
however, the meeting was more of a check-in. You
asked to see me, sir? Calvin asked. Wong closed the
book he was reading and set his glasses on his desk.
Calvin Morse, please have a seat. Calvin walked
over to the wooden chair. Like the rest of the
office, the seat looked ancient. The room's
shelves were lined with magical artifacts and
tomes. From class, he recognized the lifeline
tablet and the Carnix war horn. Some of the scrolls
looked so old that they were practically dust, and
some of the books were bound in iron under lock and
key. Of all the rooms at Strange Academy, Wong's
office was one of the more intimidating. Wong
pressed his palms together, resting his elbows on
his desk. Calvin, over the past few weeks, I've
noticed a change in your attentiveness during
class. You have appeared agitated and unfocused.
Your grades have begun to slip. Wong slid two
parchment across his desk for Calvin to see. One
was an exam on the eight principalities on which he
earned a B+. The other parchment was an essay on the
Hyborian Age, which was stamped with an F. What is
the story here? Wong asked, is everything okay?
Um, I guess. Calvin murmured. He looked up from the
parchment to Wong's concerned expression. I
don't really know. Wong stood from his seat and
walked around to the front of his desk, leaning on
it. Calvin, I'm concerned not just for your
studies, as important as mystical defenses. I'm
concerned for your mental well-being. As you
know, it is important for sorcerers to remain
clear and level-headed, lest their minds succumb
to dark forces. I'm sorry, Mr. Wong, Calvin said.
It's just, I've been seeing, like, bad visions and
hearing whispers. Wong's eyebrows raised. Bad
visions, whispers. Can you explain? He asked.
Well, in Dr. Voodoo's class, we were learning
about the orb of Agamotto, and after looking into
it, I saw... Calvin paused. Wong prompted him.
What did you see, Calvin? A giant eyeball? Calvin
said. And tentacles. Wong's concerned
expression turned grim. And what are the voices
saying? Calvin hung his head and quietly
whispered. Shumagorath. Wong walked back around
his desk and sat down, his hands gripping the
armrests. I don't know what that means, Calvin
said, feeling tears begin to well in his eyes. But I
feel scared. I saw my friends dying. I saw Emily and
Irak and Zoe, their heads were gone. Wong took a
deep breath. Shumagorath is one of the elder gods
known as the Many-Angled Ones, he explained. It
was responsible for the death of the ancient one.
Dr. Strange was once forced to commit ritual
suicide to prevent it from coming through to him
into this dimension. You can shape-shift, you can
alter reality, it is the ruler of hundreds of
universes and can destroy galaxies. Well, is it
coming here? Calvin asked, wiping his eyes. Wong
paused. Of course not, he said. Calvin sighed,
relieved. So, maybe I've just been having
nightmares. Perhaps, Wong said. But if it makes
you feel better, why don't you grab the talisman of
Shurair from the classroom? It is on the red wooden
chest. It is said to ward off dark visions. Calvin
nodded and walked to the mystical defense room.
Resting on the red wooden chest was the book of
Cogliostro and the Coral Crab, but there was no
talisman. Calvin scratched his head and walked
out of the classroom, returning to Wong's office.
He opened the door. Mr. Wong, I couldn't find the
talisman. Calvin stood, frozen. In front of him,
Wong hovered a foot off the ground. A large smile
spread across his face and his eyes opened wide.
Calvin felt the blood drained from his face.
What's the matter, Calvin? Wong said. As you said,
it's just a nightmare. Wong peeled off his face to
reveal a big, round eyeball underneath. Calvin
gasped as a tentacle wrapped around his neck and
squeezed. His body fell over, limp. His head
rolled across the floor until it came to a stop. On
his face, a frozen look of opened mouth horror.
Looks like Calvin flunked out in the worst way,
going straight from the student body to just a dead
body. So Nightmare's prophecy proved incorrect
because Phantom Stranger did in fact not shit his
pants. Come on, that was scary. It was scary. I'm
not going to lie. And very mysterious, as is the
Phantom Stranger's final tale titled Manitou.
Manitou, to the Algonquin people, the word meant
mystery and referred to the mystic life forces and
spirits of the world. Many of these spirits were
named and revered, and some in the ancient need of
wisdom were never named, never whispered about,
for they can never be tamed, and their wild hunger
never satiated. The shaman, Manitou Raven, named
after the spirit of magic and a protector of the
planet, bound one of these dark wild spirits 3,000
years ago on the land of his people. Upon traveling
through time from the Obsidian Age to the modern
one, he knew it would be his responsibility to trap
the spirit once again. But to do so, he would again
need the help of five youths. He sat atop a
cliffside, waiting for them to enter the valley
below, as the dark clouds foretold. He heard their
echoing voices as they approached. Looks like
rain's coming. Let's move, guys. Adam told the
others as they reached the bottom of the valley.
Are we lost? Virginia asked nervously. I swear if
we are, I will strangle Skyler for leaving our
phones, said Cherry. I told you I needed them for my
telescope. Skyler snapped back. Yeah, you'll get
a great view of the stars tonight through these
clouds, muttered Jesse. We're not going to make it
to the campsite before dark, Adam said. We'll have
to find shelter soon and wait out the rain. Maybe
spend the night. Cherry whispered into his ear,
and he blushed. Look, there's a cave, Jesse said,
pointing ahead as the rain began pouring. They
entered the cave soaked, nervously peering into
the blackness. Adam cautiously explored the cave
with his flashlight, while Skyler and Jesse
argued over how to start a fire. Cherry and
Virginia huddled together near the entrance,
wondering the loud if maybe the cave belonged to a
bear or mountain lion. Adam found no sign of an
animal, and were it not for the illumination from
the fire the others managed to get started, he
wouldn't have seen the black skull amidst the
rocks. It was human. Guys, let's get out of here.
Adam said as he rushed back to the others. He
tripped suddenly, a thorny vine wrapped around
his leg. Are you okay? Virginia asked. In the light
of the fire, they watched as more vines sprouted
beneath Adam, wrapping around him like dark
tendrils, binding tight against his body and
pulling downward, effortlessly sawing through
his neck and limbs like razor wire. Screams filled
the cave, lava belched from the fire, landing on
Cherry. Her jacket and haircut fire as her skin
blackened beneath the blistering bright orange.
Skyler emptied his canteen on Cherry, dousing the
flames too late. Steam rose and swirled around
Skyler, plunging into his mouth and nose. He fell
to his knees, black sludge pouring from his mouth,
tears and eyes as his skin turned gray. A howling,
piercing wind suddenly came rushing from deep
within the cave. Jesse rushed to shield Virginia
from a blast of butchered air that knocked them
both to the ground. Jesse, Virginia shrieked,
Jesse's body lay still. She rolled him off of her,
only to look in horror at his now deformed figure as
if the wind had blown his facial features and limbs
to places they shouldn't be. A teary eye atop his
patchy-haired head blinked at her. Virginia? He
struggled to say from the mouth now on his neck.
Virginia screamed and ran out of the cave into
thick rain and the arms of Manitou Raven. He
embraced her as she looked up at him, pleading for
help. He didn't respond. His gaze locked within
the cave. Virginia turned in his arms and her
horror saw the corpses and body parts of her
friends roll toward each other at the cave's
opening, merging into one another and forming a
grotesque serpent with Adam's face. Virginia
tried to flee, but Manitou Raven held her firmly in
his arms. She looked up at him, confused. He looked
down at her with regret in his ancient eyes.
Forgive me, he whispered as the serpent lashed its
shadowy tail around her neck, yanking her toward
its gaping maw. It chewed loudly, then sprouted
bat wings and wore Manitou Raven, whose sacred
tattoos and angry eyes now glowed blue as he
unsheathed tomahawks blazing with fiery magic.
History repeated itself. Five innocent youths
were sacrificed to give the dark spirit a physical
form that could be destroyed and trapped for
another 3,000 years. As Manitou Raven finished
chanting his binding ritual, he pondered the
mystery as to what was darker, the Manitou that
hungers or the one that feeds it. I'm gonna say it's
the Manitou that feeds it. Manitou Raven is one
cold-hearted son of a bitch in that story. I'm not
gonna lie, that was a pretty good one. I really like
the moral dilemma that Manitou had in that story.
And Nightmare does not appreciate how scary that
story was. You're not trying to one-up him, so in
order to teach Phantom Stranger a lesson, he's
going to summon a whole team of supernatural and
mystic characters from Marvel to basically beat
the shit out of Phantom Stranger. And Phantom
Stranger is not frightened by that, because he
will do the same. From the House of Mystery, he's
going to summon Madame Zanadu, an immortal
sorceress and seer who commands powerful magic
drawn from ancient sources most often channeled
through tarot and ritual. She could foresee
destiny summon spirits and manipulate the unseen
threads of fortune. She could also levitate,
teleport, heal, and manipulate mystic energies
across time and space. From one of the stories he
told, he'll also be summoning Manitou Raven, who
was born among an ancient tribe in the time before
recorded history. He serves as a shaman who
communes with the spirits of Earth and Sky, who
joined a circle of ancient champions to defend the
world against the darkness that threatened to
consume it. When he was transported forward in
time, he carried with him the wisdom and burdens of
the obsidian age into the modern world. He
commands elemental and spiritual forces, can
summon animal spirits, travel the astral plane,
alter his size, and even bend time itself. Also
being summoned is Lori Zecklin, aka Black Alice,
who grew up in a fractured home. Her mother's death
and her father's decline pushed her toward
isolation and despair. In her grief, she turned to
the occult, discovering a dark connection
between her emotions and the arcane forces
surrounding her. In her pursuit of meaning, she
was drawn to the world of magic, allowing her to
siphon and wield the magical powers of others,
drawing their arcane essence and memories as her
own. Nightshade emerges next, who as I mentioned
earlier is Eve Eden, born to the Queen of the Shadow
Realm known as the Land of Nightshades. As a child,
she witnessed her mother be abducted by the
demonic Incubus, who sought dominion over both
her realm and Earth. Eve vowed to master the
mysteries of darkness to one day return to her
mother's world and free it from corruption. She
can open portals through darkness, conjure
creatures of shadow, phase through matter, and
vanish into her two-dimensional form. Ragman
will also be joining the fray. You just heard a
story about him. He is Rory Reagan and was raised in
the slums by his father, a junk dealer, who was
killed along with his friends by criminals,
allowing Rory to discover the mystic legacy they
had protected, a garment woven from the souls of
the guilty. Bering its burden, he became the
latest in a long line of reluctant saviors who
atone for other sins through their own suffering.
His mystical suit of souls grants him the
strength, speed, and skill of the wicked spirits
it absorbs. Each soul becomes a living thread
within the rags, which can guide and teleport him
toward evil actions. Finally, Phantom Stranger
summons Blue Devil, aka Daniel Cassidy, who is a
Hollywood stuntman whose ambition led him to
dabble in supernatural forces beyond his
understanding. When a demonic encounter bound
him permanently to the monstrous suit he had
created for entertainment, his life of illusion
became one of grim reality. Struggling to
reconcile fame and faith, he sought redemption by
turning his curse into a calling. He possesses
immense strength, durability, and resistance to
sorcery. His enchanted trident, known as the
Trident of Lucifer, can channel hellfire and
banish demons. So to reiterate, Phantom
Stranger's team consists of Madame Zanadu,
Manitou Raven, Black Alice, Nightshade, Ragnan,
and Blue Devil. I'd like to see who Nightmare
summons to go against that team. Well, coming out
of the crypt of shadows, first is Jennifer Kale,
Ghostwriter's cousin who hails from a long line of
mystics in Florida's Kale family who are
descendants of Atlantis' ancient cult of
Jeredna. Her latent magical abilities emerged
while studying ancient tomes beneath their
family cemetery, honing her skills in
witchcraft. Guided by the man thing, and later
trained by Dr. Strange, she became one of Earth's
prominent sorceresses. As a battle mage, she can
don witch armor, manipulate magic energy,
mesmerize minds, cast teleportation portals,
along with a myriad of other spells. Also emerging
from the crypt is Wong, a descendant of a family
sworn for generations to serve the ancient one.
Wong was trained from youth in martial arts
disciplines, and when he was sent to Car Martage,
she became the personal attendant and ally of Dr.
Strange. Though bound by duty, Wong's wisdom and
combat skill made him a protector of Earth against
supernatural threats. In addition to being a
master martial artist, Wong is a skilled sorcerer
able to manipulate magic energy for portals,
shields, and various other effects. Klai is the
next one out of the crypt. She is the daughter of
Umar and the niece of Dormammu, born in the Dark
Dimension. She first encountered Dr. Strange
while he battled Dormammu and aided him against
her tyrannical uncle. After years of tutelage
under Dr. Strange, Klai grew into a powerful
sorceress and ultimately became the sorceress
supreme of the Dark Dimension. Due to her half
mortal, half faulting heritage, she has enhanced
physiology including durability and magical
resistance. She calls on more elder magics for
powerful spells including energy manipulation,
elemental control, teleportation, psychic
manipulation, telekinesis, scrying,
necromancy, transmutation, and more. Next out of
the crypt is Pixie. Megan Gwyn grew up in Wales as
the daughter of Mastermind and a descendant of
Fairy Lineage. She joined the Xavier Institute
where during an adventure in Limbo, the new magic
tainted a portion of Megan's innocent soul to
manifest a soul dagger, similar to magic's own
soul sword. Pixie can fly with her insect wings and
can produce hallucinogenic dust. She can also
cast spells for teleportation, sleep, and she can
summon her soul dagger at will, which can harm
magic entities and stun non-magic entities.
Second to last out of the crypt is the Scarlet
Scarab whose real name is Leila L. Fowley. She was
an Egyptian mercenary who once worked with Mark
Spector before he became Moon Knight. Killed
during a mission, her soul entered the Duot, which
is the Egyptian realm of death, where the goddess
Tawadet transformed her into the realm's
guardian, the Scarlet Scarab. Revived to the
mortal world by Osiris, she now serves as a
protector of both the living and the dead. She can
fly at high speeds with her wings and summon swords
and chakram discs. Her ruby scarab grants her
enhanced strength and durability, the ability to
fire concussive mystical energy, and can drain
the power of anyone who touches the scarab.
Finally out of the portal is Ghost Rider, aka
Robbie Reyes, who was a teen mechanic that was
murdered by a gang members while he was racing in
his possessed Dodge Charger. Resurrected by the
spirit of his Satanic uncle, Eli Morrow, Robbie
became the Ghost Rider, a fiery Avenger bound to
hellish power. Torn between protecting his
brother, Gabe, and resisting Eli's bloodlust,
Robbie tries to punish the guilty across Los
Angeles. As Ghost Rider, he possesses enhanced
strength and full regenerability, pyrokinesis,
mystic chain manipulation, and he wields the Pen
and Stare, which can inflict an opponent's the
pain and suffering they have caused in others. He
can also summon and remotely control his
possessed Dodge Charger, which contains a portal
to hell in its trunk. So that's Nightmare's team.
Again, it's Jennifer Kale, Wong, Klaia, Pixie,
Scarlet Scarab, and Ghost Rider. In a world where
fantasies collide and heroes clash, one podcast
network rises above the rest. Prepare yourself
for the ultimate showdowns in comic books, video
games, movies, and anime. The Dynamite Podcast
Network presents Console Combat, where video
game legends brawl every Monday. Dynamic Duel,
where comic book titans smash every Tuesday. Max
Destruction, where TV and action heroes battle
every Wednesday. And Cendro World, where anime
champions clash every Thursday. Join us as we
speculate on the matches and armed with the power
of mathematical simulations, discover who will
emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
But now that we've got their rosters out of the way,
let's speculate on how one of the thousands of
simulated matches will go. The winner is
determined by simulations, not the speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how a fight could play out.
Ajin Enkei, what are the rules of our speculation?
Well, I should say there are no rules, other than
the teams have no prior knowledge of the other
going into the fight. All they are aware of
starting out is that the other side is a threat that
needs to be eliminated. For the speculation, the
groups will begin approximately 50 meters apart
in a nondescript environment that will have no
bearing on the match itself, as no environmental
statistics are considered in my simulations. The
teams must earn victory on their own merit. All
right, with both of our horror narrators teams
assembled, they're going to chronicle how this
terrifying battle will play out. The mystery is,
who goes first? Nightmare says that Ghost Rider is
going to go first, and he starts by summoning his
Hell Charger, which comes out of the ground, and he
controls it remotely to crash into the Phantom
Strangers group, just running them all over.
Except Blue Devil's Trident helps him sense
demons, which he could banish to hell. So once he
recognizes that the car is possessed, that's
exactly what he's going to do. He's going to slam
his Trident into the ground, open up this fissure
that's spewing Hellfire, and the car's going to
fall straight into it, and that fissure is just
going to seal back up. Okay then, I guess that move
didn't work. Pixie, she's going to fly into the air
and release her hallucinogenic Pixie Dust. So
Phantom Strangers group just starts tripping
balls, start freaking out, and that's going to
cause Manitou Raven to set Ragnan on fire, because
he like sees him as like birthday candles that he
needs to light or something. Birthday candles for
a 3000 year old shaman? All right, it's a choice.
Yeah. Well as Ragnan is stopped dropping and
rolling, Black Alice, who has done some trippy
magic drugs before, is less affected, and she's
going to steal Cleia's magic from her. So Cleia's
powerless now, and Black Alice is going to summon a
magic wind that blows all of Pixie's dust off of her
team, and also it's going to put out Ragnan's fire.
Okay, I have to warn you, this is going to sound like
bullshit, but I swear that this was a thing from the
comic books. Cleia has been depowered or like had
her magic negated before, but the thing is,
because she's half mortal, half faulteen, she's
special in that she pulls from different realms of
magic, such as like Earth's magical field, or like
the Dark Dimension, or the very ancient Faltine
magic. So Black Alice may be able to drain Cleia's
power, like say her Earth magic or whatever, but
Cleia then calls upon her Faltine magic, and then
she casts a spell called the Talons of Tarkus, and
that's going to manifest this magic hawk that
grabs Black Alice and just pulls her into another
dimension, this magic-less dimension. So Black
Alice is out of the match, Cleia still has her
magic, she's kind of I'm gonna say that Madame
Zenadu foresaw that Cleia was going to do that to
Black Alice, so she cast a counterspell so that
whoever used magic against Black Alice would also
forget all magic forever. So Cleia is powerless
when Manitou Raven summons a massive swarm of
Ravens, a fuck ton that are gonna blacken the sky
and devour Nightmare's team. I guess you did find a
way to depour Cleia, okay she gets devoured by the
Ravens, but Jennifer Kale and Wong throw up magic
shields that protect the rest of the team, and the
Ravens just crash into the shields like birds into
a window. And then Scarlet Scarab, she hurls a
chakra disk that she manifests, and the blade just
slices right through Manitou Raven's neck,
decapitating him, and causes the Ravens to
vanish. Okay, well suddenly Ragman teleports
behind Scarlet Scarab due to his danger-sensing
rags, and his cloak is gonna wrap around her,
stealing her soul for the murder she just
committed, and her body's gonna fall to the floor
lifeless. Okay, Ghostrider is gonna hold his
chains over to Ragman then pulls him over to him and
then does the pen and stare, which causes Ragman to
feel all the pain that all those souls in his cloak
have inflicted on innocent victims. Oh no. So like
Ragman is fucking dead dead, like he was just
killed like a thousand times over from this
incalculable level of pain, like no one has ever
died just as much as Ragman just died. Dude stop,
he's already dead! But you know who else is gone?
Pixie, because she's gonna get slammed out of the
air by this 10 story tall shadow figure created by
Nightshade, straight into the ground. Well that
probably would take her out of the match, but Wong
meanwhile, he conjures a magical bow staff, and he
uses it to vault into a flying kick at Madame Zanadu
and kicks her Deku Tarot cards right out of her
hands, and she's like, ah shit! And then Wong
roundhouse kicks her in the face, followed up by a
leaping scissor kick to the face, like WAP WAP! And
then he wax her in the head with his magic bow staff,
and then he summons a portal beneath her where she
falls through it into an icy mountain crevasse,
like up in the Himalayas, and she dies. I feel like
she would have seen all of this coming. First of
all, it takes way too much time to read those cards.
Second of all, even if she did see it coming, she
would have been way too mesmerized by the beating
that she just took. What? Why would you be
mesmerized by a beating? Because it was like
martial arts mastery awesomeness. That's so
dumb. Alright well, Blue Devil saw this, so he and
Wong go toe to toe with their staff weapons, and
while Wong may be a better fighter, Blue Devil is
super durable and strong like Hellboy, so all it
takes is one punch for Wong to go night night. And
even if Wong tries some kind of like sorcery in his
attacks, Blue Devil is magic resistant, so Wong's
out. He's magical resistant. You know, Jennifer
Kale's gonna test that resistance with a
mesmerizing spell. She's gonna capture Blue
Devil's gaze and convince him to, as a demon
himself, banish himself to Hell. So now Blue
Devil's out. Except that Blue Devil can't be
mesmerized by what he can't see, because
Nightshade, just envelops the entire
environment in darkness, and that's gonna negate
Jennifer Kale's spell. So both Jennifer and Ghost
Rider are going to be torn to shreds in the dark by
dozens of homunculi shadow creatures she
created. No, because Jennifer Kale would cast a
Lumo spell, where like her fist shines like a
beacon, and it's so bright that it tears and burns
through the darkness around them, including
tearing and burning through Nightshade herself
into nothing. Lumos? Isn't that a Harry Potter
spell? I said luminos. Luminos. Whatever. She
could do it. Regardless. Okay, well, I mean, it's a
good thing that Blue Devil is burnproof then, and
thanks to his heightened senses, he was able to
maneuver behind Jennifer in the dark, so she
doesn't see it coming when he pierces her through a
gap in her witch armor, and pailing her on the
trident of Lucifer. She doesn't have any gaps in
her witch armor? Dude, I've seen scans of what she
looks like. She has so many gaps. Well, Ghost Rider
does not appreciate Blue Devil messing with his
fellow spirit of vengeance's mother's brother's
daughter. Okay, so he's just gonna flame breath
him with this like giant blast of Hellfire so
powerful, it actually melts Blue Devil and burns
his soul. I literally just said the guy was
burnproof. Blue Devil deals with Hellfire all the
time, but I doubt Ghost Rider deals with Hellfire
straight from Lucifer's trident. That's like the
hottest of the hot. Motherfucker, DC's Hellfire
is like a lukewarm bath. It's not doing shit, okay?
Marvel's Hellfire is way hotter, plus Ghost Rider
grabs Blue Devil by his horns and just tosses him in
the trunk of his car, which he resummoned from
Hell, and inside Robbie Race's trunk is a portal to
Hell, so Blue Devil gets banished and Ghost Rider
wins. No, I already said the car was banished to the
deepest pit of Hell, so no, it's not coming back. If
anything, Blue Devil banishes Ghost Rider. It's
what he does. It's what Ghost Rider does. Yeah, but
Blue Devil just doesn't better. According to who?
Phantom Stranger, duh. Well, I say that Ghost
Rider not only banishes Blue Devil to Hell,
Nightmare banishes Phantom Stranger to the crypt
of shadows for all of eternity for being a dumbass.
That's fine, Phantom Stranger would probably
love it there. He loves that mysterious shit. I
doubt Nightmare is going to love it in the House of
Mystery, where Phantom Stranger traps him for
eternity because the Nightmare is there would be
out of his control. Why? Again, because the
Phantom Stranger says so. Well, let's find out who
gets trapped where. Let's go ahead and run the
simulations on this cast of characters after we
input their stats. We'll be right back, folks,
with a winner. A.J .9K, hit it! Inputting data,
running calculations, processing results,
simulations complete. Okay, Nightmare and
Phantom Stranger both summoned this team of
warriors to fight against each other, but we also
incorporated their stats as well into this team
duel. Right, so we had seven characters each. And I
have to say, it's kind of a good thing that Phantom
Stranger and Nightmare did not include
themselves in their speculation because they are
hella powerful. Yeah, they're basically
omnipotent, basically omniscient. They won a
majority of their battles. Nightmare won 90.6% of
all his matches and Phantom Stranger won 91.8%. So
we had these very lopsided characters stat-wise
compared to the rest of the supernatural and
mystic characters on the teams. Another heavy
hitter was Clea. She won about 70% of all of her
matches. Yeah, besides Nightmare, she was your
most powerful character. My most powerful
character outside of Phantom Stranger was
surprisingly Nightshade. She is super powerful.
My weakest character on my team was Pixie. I don't
think that's any surprise. She only won 14.5% of
her matches. Surprisingly, my weakest character
was Black Alice, but I think it has to do with the way
we had to determine her stats. Because her power is
so variable in the fact that she steals power from
others, we had to average all of the Marvel
character stats to determine hers. And with that,
she still emerged as my weakest character,
although Ragman was not too far behind that.
Looking at the team battles overall, it looks like
the DC team's biggest advantage was in strength.
Your characters were more strong, whether it was
through physical strength or telekinetic
strength. Characters like Pixie, Wong, and
Jennifer Kale really brought me down there. But
Marvel kicked the shit out of DC when it came to the
category of versatility. Like, all of my guys are
highly versatile, whereas Phantom Stranger's
team had a few less versatile characters like
Ragman and Blue Devil. Considering all that,
Jonathan, do you have a guess as to who's going to
win this? There's no way I could ever vote against
these badass DC characters, many of whom I'm kind
of sad did not get their own individual duels like
Ragman, like Blue Devil, like Manitou Raven. So
yeah, I gotta go with DC's House of Mystery team.
And Instagram agrees with me, 79% of them also
voted for the House of Mystery. 79%? What the hell
is wrong with our Instagram followers? No one
knows what the Crypt of Shadows even is. Like,
House of Mystery had its own movie. Well, it was
like a part of a collection of animated DC shorts,
though. That's on par for what the House of Mystery
is, a series of short stories. Yeah, we'll
probably chalk it up to that, I think. Really,
people didn't know who they were voting for,
because we kept the roster of this team duel a
surprise within that Instagram poll. I'd like to
think that if they knew who was on the Marvel team,
they would have voted for Marvel. Really, you
think they would have voted for Pixie? Yeah. Let's
find out if they're right, though. AJ9K, the
results, please. Hey, you are, sir. All right, the
winner between the Phantom Stranger's House of
Mystery and Nightmare's Crypt of Shadows is the
House of Mystery. Yes! It was pretty close. Out of
the thousands of simulated matches, the House of
Mystery won 52.3% of the time compared to the Crypt
of Shadow team's 47.7%. In the end, you know who was
the tipping point? Which character? No, which
one? It was actually Black Alice, whose variable
power set actually ended up averaging into a win
for you guys. Despite the fact that she was your
weakest character. Oh, dude, I did not see that
coming. I thought she was going to bring me down for
sure. But, you know, it makes sense. Like, all she
has to do is steal Nightmare's power and your whole
team is done for. I don't think you can actually
drain Nightmare's powers, or if you did, I feel
like you would just remanifest with his power in
the Nightmare dimension. Not if he's powerless.
Like, she's absorbed the power of the Spectre
before. It doesn't care if Phantom Stranger's
team won. Nightmare still told the more scary
stories. You think so, huh? I say we let the people
decide. That brings us to our question of the week.
Which scary story this episode was your favorite?
And why? Record your answer at dynamicduld.com by
clicking on the red microphone button in the
bottom right hand corner of the screen, which will
prompt you to leave us a voicemail. Your message
could be up to 30 seconds long, and don't forget to
leave your name in case we include you on the
podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer and award
that person a Dynamic Dual No Prize that we'll post
to Instagram. Be sure to answer before November
1st. I think the results of that question of the
week will determine the real winner of this
particular team duel. No, you can't get out of your
loss. You own that. But that does it for this duel.
AJ9K helped close us out. Thanks for listening to
Dynamic Dual. Visit the show's website at
dynamicduld.com and follow us on Instagram at
Dynamic Dual Podcast. You can support the show on
Patreon at patreon.com slash dynamicduld and
joining a tier that works for you, or by rating and
reviewing Dynamic Dual on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, Podchaser, or on our website. Don't
forget to listen to the other shows in the Dynamite
Podcast Network, including Max Destruction,
Senjo World, and Console Combat. In our next
episode, we will be reviewing Season 2 of
Peacemaker, a review that we delayed in order to
make room for October's spooky duels. But that
does it for this episode. We want to give a big
thanks to our executive producers, John
Starosky, Zachary Hepburn, Destin Belcom, Miggi
Mothagean, Nathaniel Wagoner, Levi Yatten,
Austin Wieselowski, AJ Dunkerley, Nick Ibonto,
Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Spees, Dean
Molesky, Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, Mike
Williams, and Paul Graves for helping make this
podcast possible. We'll talk to you guys next
week. Up, up, and away, true believers. I soiled my
armor. I was so scared.