This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Superhero
fans, this is it. Black Friday and Cyber Monday
week are here and OldGlory.com is the place to gear
up for the holidays. They've got thousands of
official Marvel and DC t-shirts, hoodies, and
gifts ready to ship the same day so you can find
something for every hero on your list, or
yourself. This week you get 15% off everything in
the shop when you use the promo code Duel at
checkout. That's right, D-U-E-L as the promo code
for the best deal of the year. Shop now before
heroes and villains alike sell out at
OldGlory.com. Hi, welcome to the Dynamic Duel
Podcast, a weekly show where we review superhero
films and debate the superiority between Marvel
and DC by comparing their characters in
stat-based battle simulations. I'm Johnny DC.
And I'm his twin brother, Marvelous Joe. And in
this episode we are doing a duel between two
classic and classic looking DC and Marvel
villains, Vandal Savage against Sebastian Shaw.
We didn't think that we were actually going to get
to this duel episode, but we had a few openings
largely because we won't be reviewing Wonder Man
before the podcast ends in mid-January because
Wonder Man got pushed back. So yeah, that left the
opening. I'm really glad to be squeezing in
Sebastian Shaw into one of these duels because
he's a total badass X-Men villain and I thought he
was done really well in the X-Men first class film
played by Kevin Bacon. Yeah, and Vandal Savage is a
really prominent DC villain who I'm surprised we
haven't gotten to yet. He was the main antagonist
of Legends of Tomorrow Season 1, but you know, he's
also shown up pretty much all over DC media,
including being the main villain of several
animated films. Yeah, like Justice League Doom or
Suicide Squad Hell to Pay. But before we get into
that duel, we're going to break down the comic book
movie news from the past week, of which there
wasn't movie news, but there was comic book news
and that this past week was the release of the
Batman Deadpool crossover comic book that
featured new DC and Marvel crossover stories that
we're going to talk about. As always, we list our
segment times and our episode description, so
feel free to check out the show notes if you want to
skip ahead to a particular topic. Our
artificially intelligent duel simulator, AJ9K,
has a quick message for our listeners, so listen
up. Why hello there. Do you want even more from this
podcast? Then become a part of the Dynamic Duo
community on Patreon where you can choose from
three tiers. The Dynamic Duo tier gives you access
to our Discord chat server, the Fantastic Four
tier gives you two bonus episodes each month, and
the X-Force tier makes you an executive producer
of this show. Lastly, the Diner Mike podcast
network tier lets you create your own podcast
using this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe
will help you develop your show, provide graphic
support and consultation, and get you simulation
results. Pitch the twins your ideas via email at
dynamicdualpodcast at gmail.com. Check it out at
patreon.com slash dynamicdual. Pip pip cheerio.
Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast. Be sure to tune in to the other shows in
the Diner Mike podcast network this week,
including the console combat podcast, where
hosts John and Dean simulate battles between
popular video game characters. In yesterday's
episode, they found out who would win between the
boss from Metal Gear and Colonel Mail Radick from
Killzone. Over on the Max Destruction podcast
hosts Scotty and Gilly pit your favorite action
heroes from film and television against each
other. The Macho Twins are taking a quick break for
the month of November, but they'll be back in
December with some Christmas season duels. On the
Cingro World podcast, host Zachary Hepburn
speculates on fights between fan favorite anime
and manga characters. In his next episode, Zach is
revealing who would win between Shigeyo
Kagayama, aka Mob from Mob Psycho 100, and
Tatsumaki the tornado of terror from One Punch
Man. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link
in our show notes to listen to all the shows in the
Diner Mike podcast network. But with that out of
the way, quick to the no prize. A no prize is an award
that Marvel used to give out to fans. Our version,
the dynamic duel no prize, is a digital award we
post on Instagram for the person that we feel gave
the best answer to our question of the week. Last
week, we asked you guys, what Marvel versus DC
crossover have you always wanted to see in the
comic books? And why? We got a few answers, so let's
run down our honorable mentions as well as the no
prize winner. Our first honorable mention goes to
Was, who I'm just going to assume is Steve Wasniak,
the co-founder of Apple. He said, Hi, this is the
Was, and I'm calling to give my opinion on who I
would want to see from DC and Marvel fight. And
maybe this has already been done in the comics and I
just haven't seen it. You can let me know. But I want
to see Superman versus the Hulk, because what
really can kill the Hulk? Not much anything. So I'm
not surprised you didn't know the answer to this,
Steve Wasniak, because you were helping to
develop Apple in the mid 90s when the DC versus
Marvel comic crossover came out, in which
Superman did in fact fight the Hulk and defeat him.
Yeah. So wasn't the Superman Hulk matchup one of
the voted on battles within that comic book
series? I believe it was, yes. So really, it was
just a popularity contest. The Hulk could have won
if the fans had voted that way. But luckily, we have
a podcast that has determined that Superman would
in fact beat the Hulk, no matter which iteration,
because Superman is just better. We don't know
that. We haven't determined that. What are you
talking about? Kingdom Come Superman beat
Maestro. Oh, yeah. Bizarro beat Abomination.
Isn't that enough? I still think there's a chance
that the Hulk can beat Superman. We'll see. Maybe
in a few months, we'll actually run the stats on
that. Hey, shut up. Great answer, Steve Wasniak.
Our next honorable mention goes to Daniel Alonso,
who said, Okay, so I know this is going to be really
hard for everybody because DC has so very few
actually good characters that are cool. But one
that I actually just really, really, really would
love to see is King Daredevil and Fallen Grayson
Nightwing team up together. I think that would be
so sick if like they were going up against the hand
that teamed up with the quarter vowels. I mean,
come on. And they would look amazing. Yeah, they
would look amazing because of their beards,
right? This is the era of each character's arcs
where they grew heavy beards. Daredevil had taken
over as like the new kingpin and he had some magical
amped up senses. Yeah. And in the Fallen Grayson
storyline, Dick Grayson is captured and
seemingly killed. So they have to essentially
fake his death. And during that time, he became a
secret agent who, yes, also had a beard. And then
going up against the hand and the quarter vowels.
Hell yeah. Hell yeah. Great answer, Daniel
Alonso. Our final honorable mention would go to by
Dear Bangor. But unfortunately, the audio was too
quite to make out, but we still want to say thank you
for calling in. The winner of this week's snow
prize is Alex Albro, who said, Hey guys, for me,
it's got to be Black Panther versus Hawkman. Maybe
they're trying to enhance new medical security
weaponry developments with vibranium keeping
out extraterrestrial threats the whole deal. And
they realize it's not enough and they need to use
enthmetal. Hawkman doesn't take too kindly to
this and decides maybe he wants vibranium for
himself and his people. And so it just brings down
the wrath of Danagar and Wakanda. I think seeing
these two guys go to war would be epic. I think they
have a lot more in common than the Metsuii. And this
would just be insane. This sounds amazing as
everyone knows metal that can absorb vibrations
is way better than metal that can defy gravity. I
mean, is it? I don't think it is. I think gravity
defying metal and really universal forces
defying metal is way cooler than just metal that
fucking vibrates, bro. It doesn't vibrate. It
absorbs vibrations. You're confusing it for
Antarctic vibranium. Think about it. Would you
rather stop vibrations or freaking fly? It's
essentially bulletproof metal. I mean, so is a lot
of metals. Fair enough. Fair enough. I think the
dynamic between a character like Black Panther
and Hawkman would play out pretty well, too,
though. They're both pretty badass. Oh, yeah.
Yeah. I would love to see those characters
crossover. Who do you think would win in a fight
between the Wakandans and the Thanagarians? Oh,
Thanagarians. All they would have to do is just
drop a bomb on them from space. Although Wakandans
would have to do is just fire a missile at them from
Earth. Oh, and then they could just move their ship
out of orbit and dodge the missile entirely. Can
you move Wakanda? No, but it has a protective dome.
So, oh, yeah, that's right. Air superiority, my
man. What else can I say? Well, Wakandans were the
first people from Earth to really start
interstellar colonies. So I mean, they're no
strangers to space. Oh, they're just starting
out. That's cute. No, they've been at it for a
while. Like it was due to a time anomaly. There are
Wakandan space colonies in Marvel Comics. Full
on. Dude, Thanagar is a space empire. Think of them
like the Shi'ar. The Wakandans are nothing like
the Shi'ar. No, they're better. Do they have an
imperial guard? No, but they have the Dormalage.
Anyway, we're getting off track here. We could
probably dedicate an entire episode to Wakanda
versus Thanagar, I think. Just hold your
thoughts. Let's agree that Wakanda would win.
Let's move on. So thank you, Alex Albra, for
calling in with your no prize winning answer. Oh,
I'm not ready to move on. If you, the listener, want
a shot at winning your own no prize, stay tuned to
later on this episode when we'll be asking another
question of the week. But now that that's done, you
know why Thanagar would win? Why? Because they
reincarnate, whereas Wakandans just go to their
ancestral plane and they could stay there. But
it's not like they fall down dead and then rise up
right away. They reincarnate like on the other
side of the fucking universe. So it's fine. It's
fine. They move fast. OK. And now that that's done,
on to the news. All right, last week, we talked to
you guys about the digital comic books that Marble
and DC released that were crossovers for Thor and
Shazam and The Flash and Fantastic Four. Those
digital issues were released in lead up to this
past week's physical comic book release of Batman
Deadpool, which was the second part of a comic book
crossover between Marvel and DC. We talked about
the Deadpool Batman crossover when that came out.
And we talked about what we liked and didn't like
from the issue. I do have to say that the DC series of
stories didn't blow me away like the Marvel one
did. Like I was a huge fan of the Deadpool Batman
crossover story written by Zeb Wells. I was a big
fan. Grant Morrison wrote this issues, Batman,
Deadpool crossover. And, you know, Grant
Morrison is a he's a legend. He's really talented.
That being said, I found his work in this issue to be
a little bit masturbatory for lack of a better
word, because not only did he insert himself into
the story, he also inserted his Cassandra Nova and
Damien Wayne creations. And the story in all was
just a little all over the place. It wasn't as clean
and pure as the Zeb Wells story. Well, you know,
with Grant Morrison, his stories haven't been
cleaned for a long time. I'm not a huge Grant
Morrison fan. Really? I think because of that
reason. I think if you're going to tell a good
story, it shouldn't be that dense. It shouldn't be
that difficult to interpret what is going on. He's
like the Christopher Nolan of comic book writers.
He tries to be, but he's less accessible. You know,
I thought the story was actually really good upon
second read, but you had to read it twice to
appreciate it. Sometimes that's just the case
with like nonlinear storytelling. There are a lot
of stories out there that I enjoy more upon second
read or second rewatch. Well, it's not about
enjoying it more. It's about basically
understanding it. And I understood it more the
second time. Therefore, I enjoyed it more. It's a
choice. It's a choice that I think proves to be less
successful than the Marvel version of the
crossover. I do think you're right in that Marvel
is better than DC. Yes. I did not say that. Yeah,
it's hard to tell which set of stories was better
because while the Marvel release had the better
Deadpool Batman story, it also had shit like The
Dark Knight, an old man Logan story and like the
crypto and Jeff the Landshark story. There was
nothing that was quite as pointless in this DC
issue. In addition to the Batman Deadpool story,
we also got Constantine meets Doctor Strange,
Nightwing and Laura Kinney's Wolverine, Harley
Quinn and the Hulk and Static versus Miss Marvel.
And I enjoyed all of those, except for maybe the
Harley Quinn Hulk one. I was expecting more from
that, although I don't know why. Yeah, that was my
least favorite, too. The rest were fine. Overall,
a decent effort. And the last comic, my favorite
was the Wonder Woman Captain America story. And
this one, I would say my favorite was the Nightwing
Wolverine one. That was good. I also really liked
the Static Miss Marvel one. It was really short,
but it was nice to see the parallels between the two
characters. I'll leave it vague there. We highly
recommend visiting your local comic book store
and picking up a few issues of Deadpool Batman and
Batman Deadpool. Take advantage of this
historical moment while you can, folks. It only
happens once every few decades. I mean, I hope they
do more crossovers. I'm actually really loving
this Infiniverse or whatever they want to call it,
where the two universes join together. And next
time they better do a Hawkman Black Panther story.
That would be cool. I would also accept a Black
Panther Aquaman story. Oh, that'd be cool, too,
for sure. But speaking of comic book crossovers
within this issue, that brings us to our question
of the week. What was your favorite story within
the Batman Deadpool crossover comic? And why this
is for the comic book readers out there? Those of
you who picked up and read the issue, go ahead and
record your answer at dynamicdool.com by
clicking on the red microphone button in the
bottom right hand corner of the screen, which will
prompt you to leave us a voicemail. Your message
could be up to 30 seconds long, and don't forget to
leave your name in case we include you on the
podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer and award
that person a dynamic duel no prize that will post
to Instagram. Be sure to answer before November
29th. But that is it for all of the news for this
episode. Let's go ahead and move on to the main
event where we find out who is going to win between
the villain characters of Vandal Savage and
Sebastian Shaw. Vandal Savage vs Sebastian Shaw
OK, Vandal Savage vs Sebastian Shaw. Now, for the
longest time, I didn't really know who we could pit
Vandal Savage against considering his main power
is essentially that he's immortal. He has
something of a healing factor as well. But I
couldn't figure out who a good analog would be
against him until whenever executive producers,
Devin Davis, suggested pitting him against
Sebastian Shaw largely because of how the
characters look. They both look very, I guess you
could say, Victorian. I guess you could describe
it as that they both wear very old fashioned suits,
like three piece suits. It's part of the wardrobe
for the inner circle of the Hellfire Club, of which
Sebastian Shaw is one of the leaders.
Traditionally, he's known as the Black King
because all of the inner circle members are named
after chess pieces. Yeah, they have an
interesting wardrobe, like the guys dress up like
they're from 1800s Britain and the women dress up
in lingerie. What is going on there? I don't know. I
don't know. It does seem like a double standard, if
I must say. Of course, we did a duel with the White
Queen Emma Frost against Poison Ivy quite a few
years ago. And that was a fun episode. You guys
should definitely go check that out if you want to
learn more about the Hellfire Club. We also did a
duel between mastermind of the Hellfire Club and
Psycho Pirate, where we also delved into that
club's history. Vandal Savage has been a part of a
number of teams, which I'll break down in the
character's backstory. But first, to explain the
methodology behind our duels, let's go to our
sentient duel simulator, Alfred Jarvis, 9000.
AJ9K tell our listeners how you go about
determining a winner in our duel matchups. Yes, of
course, sir. The way I determine a winner between
the contestants is by running 1000 Monte Carlo
simulations using the character's statistics. A
Monte Carlo simulation is a probabilistic model
used to determine outcomes through random
sampling. In this case, I randomize the
statistics along a normal distribution as a way to
simulate the many variables that can occur during
battle. The stat parameters are based on the
official Marvel power grid from which the DC
characters' statistics are extrapolated.
Additional stat categories are included such as
range, damage potential, versatility and
perception in order to create a more detailed and
accurate simulation. The results of the 1000
simulations provide a percentage of wins for each
character. The contestant with the higher
percentage is declared the victor as they have a
higher probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither character should win
100% of the matches. The comic book stories have
shown that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman, so the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks, AJ9K.
Before we run the simulations, though, we'd like
to break down each of the character's histories
and abilities before improvising a scenario on
how we imagined one of the 1000 simulations would
play out beat for beat. And it's my turn to go first
with the DC characters backstory, so let me tell
you all about Vandal Savage. Now, Vandar Og was
born roughly 50,000 years ago as the chief of the
Crow Magnan Blood Tribe. As a young hunter, he
witnessed a glowing meteor crash to Earth.
Exposure to its radiation, later understood to
contain microscopic tech-tites, dramatically
increased his intelligence, halted his aging and
made him effectively immortal. A rival caveman of
the Bear Tribe claimed a fragment of the same
meteor as an amulet and became the immortal man,
destined to reincarnate endlessly and oppose
Vandar throughout history. Over the centuries
that followed, Vandar adopted many names and
roles. At times, he acted openly as Warlord, King,
Conqueror or Pharaoh. At others, he served as
advisor, strategist or manipulator behind the
scenes. He claimed numerous historical
identities, though many were exaggerations
meant to magnify his legend. His immortality
allowed him to gather knowledge of warfare,
politics, culture and science across multiple
eras. And his mastery of strategy made him a
recurring architect of upheaval. In ancient
Atlantis, Vandal founded a secret society known
as the Children of Light, whose influence helped
destabilize Atlantean power. Before the
continent sank, his followers spread across the
world as the Illuminati. In Egypt, he ruled as
Coffrey, until Nubu the Wise forged a mystical
symbol of power to overthrow him, beginning a
conflict that echoed through their
incarnations. In Europe, Asia and the
Mediterranean world, Vandal served or opposed
leaders ranging from Napoleon and Bismarck to
Genghis Khan. Across the ages, he repeatedly
clashed with reincarnating enemies, such as
Prince Khufu and Shaira, later known as Hockman
and Hock Girl, and with the immortal man and
resurrection man, whose tectite-linked powers
mirrored his own. His immortality was imperfect,
however. The tectite's healed wounds but also
preserved an early intestinal cancer, causing
periodic agony throughout his life. To survive
catastrophic injuries or organ failure, he
periodically relied on descendants whose
genetic material could restore failing tissues.
As civilization progressed, Vandal Savage
continued shaping events from the shadows. In the
20th century, he confronted the Justice Society
of America, beginning a recurring rivalry with
the Green Lantern Alan Scott, who you can learn
more about in our Green Lantern vs. Iceman duel
episode. When the Justice Society retired in the
1950s under pressure from the House Un-American
Activities Committee, Savage helped engineer
political pressure to force their withdrawal,
clearing the stage for later plans. As
superheroes re-emerged, Vandal expanded his
operations with scientific research, funding
projects through shell organizations and
adopting new identities. Under aliases such as
Burt Villars, he confronted Wally West, the
Flash, who exposed Savage's involvement in
experiments and illegal dealings. Savage
pioneered the Super Speed Drug Velocity 9,
distributing it through criminal networks with
the intent of creating an army of addicted
supercriminals. The drug caused rapid aging and
strokes, and the Flash dismantled the operation.
You can learn more about Wally West in our Flash vs.
Speedball episode. Savage's immortality
occasionally faltered, forcing him to pursue
methods to replenish it. Savage financed a
clandestine research group known only as the Lab,
directing its scientists to replicate the
tectites that sustained his immortality. Their
experiments on unwilling subjects, including an
amnesiac man named Mitch Shelley, led to the
creation of the Resurrection Man. When a time
warped tectite creature threatened reality,
Savage temporarily allied with Immortal Man and
Resurrection Man. Immortal Man sacrificed
himself to destroy the creature, ending the
ancient rivalry. The Resurrection Man inherited
the role of Savage's primary adversary. Seeking
further influence, Savage manipulated
conflicts involving the new Titans. He founded
the villain team Tartarus using Gohman's powers
to select members, then targeted Adeline Wilson
for her blood in a new immortality serum. The
Titans stopped him after a violent confrontation
that left several villains dead or defecting. You
can learn more about the Titans in their team duel
against the X-Men. Savage's descent toward more
extreme measures continued. He became the leader
of a doomsday cult and obtained an alien summoner
device capable of dragging an asteroid named
Thanatos toward Earth. Savage intended to
engineer a mass extinction and remake
civilization from the ruins, though the Flash
reversed the summoner's pull, sending the
asteroid away. Savage deliberately threw
himself onto the beam, believing a second meteor
exposure would elevate his power, and he was
hurled into space on the redirected rock. He
survived the journey and in time returned to
Earth. His next major conflict placed him at odds
with the Justice Society again. Savage formed the
Fourth Reich, a group of neo-Nazi metahumans
tasked with exterminating the descendants of
Golden Age heroes. They murdered several
families before being defeated. Savage was
struck down by a fire truck in the final battle but
later escaped. Savage was eventually captured
and sent to the Salvation Planet alongside other
villains. He established a temporary domain by
exploiting female villains, but the group
rebelled and he fled during an attack from
apocalyptic forces. Savage resurfaced during
the final crisis as a high ranking member of the
Society of Supervillains. The religion of crime
stabbed him with the spirit of destiny,
resurrecting him as Cain, the biblical first
murderer. As Cain, Savage overpowered the
Spectre and separated him from his host before
being stopped by the question. The Spectre
branded Savage with the mark of Cain, condemning
him to wander the Earth, reviled, and unable to
hide the mark. Savage later manipulated Franny
Montoya into taking the mark from him. You can
learn more about the Spectre and the question from
their respective duels against Galactus and
Echo. Eventually, Savage became involved with
the surviving faction of his prehistoric tribe,
the Insiders, who had also been altered by the
meteor. He formed a temporary alliance with
Russell Gull and the Outsiders to prevent the
insiders from claiming more meteorite
fragments. When Savage's immortality again
began to fail, he attempted to prolong his life by
stealing Alan Scott's DNA using a mutated Sandman
clone, but the scheme collapsed. Savage
ritualistically consumed a clone of himself to
temporarily restore his vitality. In
post-Flashpoint continuity, Vandal Savage was
born 47,000 years ago into the Wolf Tribe. He
murdered his father after a meteor landed nearby,
which bathed him in transformative radiation,
granting immortality, superhuman strength, and
heightened senses. Members of the Bear Tribe
exposed to the same meteor became fellow
immortals forming the Council of Immortals. He
waged war against the Han dynasty, served as Sir
Savage in the Crusades, and clashed with Pandora
in Antioch. Savage joined the Demon Knights after
the fall of Camelot, fighting alongside Etrican,
Madame Zanadu, and the Shining Knights. During
failed attempts to monitor returning meteors
predicted by Shang-Hen, he murdered both John and
Copernicus. His activities continued into the
19th century when he carried a plague into Gotham
City using his immune body as a vessel before being
stopped by Jonah Hex. Who you've learned more
about in our last episode, Jonah Hex vs.
Deathwarp. He supported Nazi operations during
World War II and attempted to reach a returning
meteor via rocket flights. When the pilot
rejected his plan, Savage killed him after the
craft crashed. In the modern era, Savage
periodically operated as a serial killer and was
imprisoned until freed by the Seeker Society
during the crime syndicate's invasion. He became
involved in multiversal studies with Lionel
Luther and manipulated his immortal children
during an attempt to intercept another meteor.
During this period, he infected Superman with
radiation that hindered his solar absorption.
Savage captured multiple Justice League members
and stole the Fortress of Solitude while
preparing for the Comet's return. When the Comet
passed near Earth, Savage absorbed enhanced
power but reverted after Superman dispersed the
Comet's energies. Later Savage opposed Lex
Luthor's attempt to wield the Totality and of the
few forces capable of ending his immortality and
was killed by a shard of its power. Following the
restoration of the multiverse after the final
crisis with the darkest night, Savage was among
the many beings returned to life. He later joined a
new organization called the Totality, a
multiversal council created to monitor rising
cosmic threats. And that's his history.
Powers-wise, Vandal Savage is an immortal
enhanced by tectites or meteor-borne energies
that halt aging, regenerate tissue, and grant
superhuman strength, resilience, stamina, and
high-end senses. He could recover from lethal
wounds, survive extreme conditions, and endure
diseases that would kill others. His
intelligence has developed over millennia,
making him a master strategist, tactician,
linguist, and combatant. His skill spans ancient
and modern weaponry, hand-to-hand combat,
battlefield command, and scientific and
political manipulation. His healing has limits,
severe organ damage may require graphs from
descendants or clones, and that's Vandal Savage.
But how strong is he though? He's Crow Magnum
strong. You could consider him as strong as a
silverback. Okay. And how quick is his healing
factor? Is it like Wolverine deadpool speed or
slower than that? I wouldn't say it's quite as fast
as Wolverine's, which has gotten progressively
faster in the comic books I might add over the
years. Let's say it's inconsistent in the comics.
Like I've seen him literally take an arrow to the
head and still keep fighting. Okay, interesting.
You know, his origin reminded me a lot of Ulysses
Bloodstones from the comic books, who is the
father of Elsa Bloodstone. I don't know if you
remember his origin from her duel against
Frankenstein. Vaguely. I'm not sure who came
first, but I'm just gonna say that Vandal Savage is
a huge rip-off of Ulysses Bloodstone, and no, I'm
not gonna fact check that. Vandal Savage has been
around since 1943, so I feel like that's a bold
claim. I stand by what I said. Would you stand by if
you found out that Ulysses Bloodstone first
appeared in 1975? Yes, I would. Okay. But enough
about Bloodstone, let me go ahead and tell you all
about the X-Men villain Sebastian Shaw.
Sebastian Shaw was born in Pittsburgh,
Pennsylvania, where his father Jacob had settled
after fleeing the United Kingdom. Jacob had spent
years working in secret for the geneticist Mr.
Sinister, whose experiments on mutants
convinced Jacob that Sinister posed a danger to
his family. You can learn more about Sinister in
his duel against the Ultra Humanite. Wanting a
different life for his son, Jacob escaped
Sinister's control and tried to raise Sebastian
in America far from that influence. Despite this
effort, the two lived in deep poverty, and
Sebastian worked in a steel mill from a young age to
help support himself and his father. Despite
their circumstances, Jacob pushed him toward
education, and Sebastian excelled
academically. After Jacob's death, Sebastian
received a full scholarship to the Stevens
Institute of Technology in New Jersey, but
celebrating this achievement led to disaster. A
group of wealthy young men angry that someone from
a poor background could attend such a prestigious
school, cornered and beat him. The trauma of this
attack triggered his mutant power for the first
time. Sebastian discovered he could absorb the
force of physical impacts and convert the energy
into strength, allowing him to overpower his
attackers. At college, Sebastian devoted
himself to engineering and business. After
graduating, he quickly became known as a genius
with a remarkable talent for understanding
economics and technology. He founded Shaw
Industries, a company that grew rapidly through
defense contracts and munitions development. By
30, he was a millionaire, and by 40, he was a
billionaire. During these years, Shaw also
became romantically involved with a woman named
Lorde Chantel, a mutant teleporter, and he began
raising a boy named Shinobi as his own. Shaw's
wealth drew the attention of the Hellfire Club,
which was an elite society of influential
business and political leaders. Its public
reputation was one of luxury and exclusivity, but
many members belonged to a secret leadership
group called the Inner Circle. Shaw accepted the
invitation to join and soon became the Black
Bishop. His partner Lords distrusted the club,
fearing it would corrupt him, but Shaw saw
opportunity and ignored her concerns. Within the
Inner Circle, Shaw worked alongside Emma Frost,
Harry Leland, Donald Pierce, and the White King
Ned Buckman. The White King had the Hellfire Club
financially support the Sentinel program under
the cover of scientific research. In reality, the
Sentinels were anti-mutant robots designed to
hunt and kill mutants. You can learn more about
them in our Amazo vs Bastion dual episode. When
Shaw discovered the truth about Sentinels, he
confronted Buckman, but the White King betrayed
him and sent Sentinels to eliminate Shaw and his
allies. During the attack, Lords died protecting
Shaw. Grief stricken and furious, Shaw and Emma
Frost turned on the Inner Circle. Using Emma's
telepathy, they forced Buckman to kill the other
members and then himself. Shaw then declared
himself the new Black King of the Hellfire Club and
Emma Frost became the new White Queen. You can
learn more about Emma Frost in her dual against
Poison Ivy. As Black King, Shaw worked to expand
the club's influence over world politics and
corporations. He used Shaw Industries to build
and control Sentinel technology, believing it
was safer for mutants if he held power over the
machines, rather than leaving them in the hands of
anti-mutant forces. Shaw also courted powerful
figures like Senator Robert Kelly and Henry Peter
Geirich, pretending to be a human supremacist to
allay suspicion while advancing his own plans. He
also attempted to recruit Namor of Atlantis as the
Hellfire Club's White King. Namor refused and
Shaw's retaliatory use of Sentinels against
Atlantis created a lasting enemy. You can learn
more about Namor in her Aquaman vs Submariner dual
episode. Shaw's ambitions soon collided with the
X-Men. Through one of the club's assassins, he
planted surveillance devices in Xavier's
mansion, allowing the Hellfire Club to track new
mutants as soon as Cerebro detected them. The club
attempted to recruit or capture new mutants such
as Kitty Pryde and Dazzler, leading to direct
confrontation between the Inner Circle and the
X-Men. During this conflict, Mastermind
manipulated Jean Grey, not realizing she was
actually the Phoenix Force. When Phoenix broke
free of his control, she fought back with
devastating power, forcing Shaw and the Inner
Circle to retreat. You can learn more about
Professor X and Jean Grey in their respective
duels against the Chief and Raven. The Hellfire
Club later fought alongside the X-Men against the
future Sentinel Nimrod. During the battle, Harry
Leland used his gravity powers to send Shaw
crashing into Nimrod at incredible speed. The
attack destroyed Nimrod, but the exertion killed
Leland, leaving Shaw without an ally in the Inner
Circle. Not long after, Magneto joined the club as
the new White King. He, the Black Queen Selene, and
Emmafrost the White Queen voted to remove Shaw
from power, citing his reckless support of the
Sentinel program. Shaw attempted to rebuild his
influence, but his adopted son, Shinobi,
attacked him, phasing a hand into his chest to
induce a heart attack and then blowing up Shaw's
chalet. Although presumed dead, Shaw survived
and later resurfaced allied with Holocaust, a
destructive mutant from another timeline, to
capture X-Force. However, the plan failed when
Cable freed his team, whom we've learned more
about in our Outsiders vs X-Force duel episode.
Shaw next pursued the Elixir Vitae, a substance he
believed could cure the legacy virus, which was a
disease that was lethal to mutants, which you can
learn more about in our Beast Boy vs Beast duel
episode. Shaw later regained control of the
Hellfire Club and worked to rebuild the Inner
Circle by turning the New York branch into a
nightclub for gathering secrets from wealthy
patrons. He recruited Miss Sinister, a female
clone of Mr. Sinister, and attempted to
manipulate Wolverine's son, Daken. Emma Frost
eventually recovered the memories of her past
connection with Namor and blamed Shaw for the
Sentinel strike that had destroyed Atlantis. She
struck a deal with Namor. If she removed Shaw
permanently, Namor would pledge to defend mutant
kind as his own people. Emma lured Shaw into a trap,
telepathically incapacitated him, and rather
than killing him, secretly transported him to
Utopia, which was the X-Men's island
headquarters off the coast of San Francisco.
There, she had him placed in the X-Brick, which was
an underwater prison facility that the X-Men used
to confine dangerous mutants. For a time, Shaw
remained imprisoned, his whereabouts unknown to
most of the mutant community. Emma eventually
decided that keeping Shaw was too dangerous and
had Shaw released using her telepathy to wipe his
memories and leaving him unaware of his identity
or any past crimes. Months later, Shaw was found in
Pakistan and taken to the Avengers Academy where
he was placed in a special cell that absorbed
kinetic energy. Shaw escaped by repeatedly
striking himself with a book to build enough power
to break free. He eventually regained his
memories and returned to the Hellfire Club. When
the Tarigin Clouds released into the atmosphere
by the Inhumans began killing mutants, Shaw
allied with Magneto. However, his involvement
with the genetic modification and mutant
creating drug called Mother Vine Backfire. After
taking the drug, he gained the ability to absorb
ambient kinetic energy, but the unstable
mutation began damaging his cells from within.
Emma Frost covertly had his drink poisoned with a
paralytic that prevented him from releasing this
energy, causing the overload to kill him. Shaw was
later resurrected on the mutant island of Krakowa
and welcomed as part of the New Nation. You can
learn more about Krakowa in its duel against Danny
the Street. Shaw earned a seat on the Quiet Council
as the Black King of the Hellfire Trading Company,
which was responsible for the global
distribution of Krakowa medicines. Determined
to regain influence, he attempted to install his
resurrected son, Shinobi as the Red King, but Emma
Frost countered him by appointing Kitty Pryde in
that role. Shaw orchestrated Kitty's murder,
believing she could not be resurrected, but she
returned after several attempts. When Emma Frost
learned the truth by reading the memories of
Kitty's pet dragon, Lockheed, she and Kate
brutally punished Shaw, leaving him temporarily
crippled. Shaw eventually recovered, but his
power struggles with Krakowa continued until its
eventual downfall. And that's his backstory.
Powers-wise, Sebastian Shaw, the Black King, is a
mutant with the ability to absorb kinetic and
thermal energy, converting it into superhuman
strength, speed, stamina, and healing ability.
Even bladed attacks against him result in only
superficial scratches because of his ability to
sap the blade of all its thrusting and cutting
energy. He is a formidable hand-to-hand
combatant, a cunning strategist, anti-gifted
engineer and economist. His weakness is that his
absorption ability does have a limit, and if he
overloads on energy, he can pass out if he does not
exert it. And that's Sebastian Shaw. Okay, so both
of these guys have healing factors and strength,
yeah. Although Sebastian Shaw's strength has to
develop, but he can absorb kinetic energy, which
is something that Vandal Savage doesn't have. I
don't know how Vandal Savage is gonna hurt him
because punching Shaw is like punching someone in
your dreams, right? Like you punch him as hard as
you can and it's just, it's like hitting good
mattress. Well, this should be a fun speculation.
No wonder we haven't used this character yet. Good
luck. In a world where fantasies collide and
heroes clash, one podcast network rises above the
rest. Prepare yourself for the ultimate
showdowns in comic books, video games, movies,
and anime. The Dynamite Podcast Network presents
Console Combat, where video game legends brawl
every Monday, Dynamic Duel, where comic book
titans smash every Tuesday, Max Destruction,
where TV and action heroes battle every
Wednesday, and Sendro World, where anime
champions clash every Thursday. Join us as we
speculate on the matches and armed with the power
of mathematical simulations, discover who will
emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
Superhero fans, this is it. Black Friday and Cyber
Monday week are here, and OldGlory.com is the
place to gear up before the holidays. They've got
thousands of official Marvel and DC t-shirts,
hoodies, and gifts ready to ship the same day so you
can find something for every hero on your list, or
yourself. This week you get 15% off everything in
the shop when you use the promo code Duel at
checkout. That's right, D-U-E-L as the promo code
for the best deal of the year. Shop now before
heroes and villains alike sell out at
OldGlory.com. Now that we've got their histories
and abilities out of the way, let's speculate on
how one of the 1,000 simulated matches will go. The
winner is determined by simulations, not the
speculation, but it's fun to imagine how this
fight could play out. AJ9K, what are the rules of
our speculation? Well, I should say there are no
rules other than the characters have no prior
knowledge of the other going into the fight. All
they are aware of starting out is that the other
character is a threat that needs to be eliminated.
For the speculation, the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the match
itself, as no environmental statistics are
considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. Alright then
let's get into it. Vandal Savage and Sebastian
Shaw meet on the battlefield. Who goes first? I'm
going to say that Sebastian Shaw goes first by
kneeling down and punching the ground with his
fists as hard as he can in order to build up his
kinetic energy reserve. And since he also spends
most of his mornings punching walls or he'll have
his security team beat the shit out of him, we'll
see he starts this match off at around 10% peak
power. Okay. So right off the bat he's at least as
strong as, you know, a gorilla who can lift like,
what, like two tons? Well, I'm going to say that
Savage, you know, he sees Shaw punching the ground
and just from his historical experience, deduces
Shaw's ability of kinetic energy storage.
Alright. Okay. And that's when he's going to twist
a jewel knob that's atop his walking cane. And
that's going to cause it to emit a blinding flash,
which is going to blind Shaw. And when he's done
blinking away the spots from his eyes, Savage is
already behind him. And Savage is going to taser
Shaw in the back of the neck with the tip of his cane,
just overloading him with millions of volts of
electrical energy. Millions of volts? Yeah, like
way too much for him to absorb. No, no, he's just
going to get a little bit of a boost from the
electricity, but he also absorbs thermal energy
in addition to kinetic. So while he's getting
electrocuted, he's slowly going to get stronger
and stronger. And he's going to stop convulsing
and just start laughing. He's going to grab Vendil
Savage's little stick in his hand. And then he's
just going to break it in half and proceed to give
Savage a severe caning, just beating him like he
owes him money. Okay. But as As soon as Shah grabs
Vandal's cane, Vandal's gonna unsheathe a saber
from the handle. So Shah's just broken a sheath
essentially. And while he attempts to beat Vandal
with that, Vandal is gonna calmly deflect all of
his attacks, slicing the cane halves up in Shah's
hands, and he'll finish off by slitting his throat
as well. Well, I mean, like I said, the blade would
only leave a superficial scratch across Shah's
neck because his skin would sap the saber of all of
its kinetic energy as it made contact. So again,
all you're doing is powering up Shah. At this
point, he's probably like at 25% power because of
the electrical attack. So he's just gonna stomp
toward Vandal Savage, you know, keeping his
opponent on the back foot. He's gonna straight up
smack the sword out of his hand and then grab Vandal
Savage, lift him up in the air and just power bomb
him onto the ground right onto his head, which
causes Vandal Savage's neck to break. I mean,
Savage, his bones are pretty thick and durable.
Like, I don't think it would paralyze him or
anything, plus he'd heal right away. And to give
him the chance to do so as he's on the ground, he's
going to pull out a pen that he kept in his pocket.
And that's a sonic emitter. So while Shah is
covering his ears with his hands like, oh no, my
freaking ears. That's when Savage is gonna
straight up shove that pen up Shah's nose and
unleash the acid ink within it, just dissolving
Shah's head from the inside. What the fuck? How
many gadgets does Vandal Savage have? He's like
fucking James Bond or something? What's going on
here? Yeah, he's like the ultimate James Bond in a
way. Stop making shit up. Dude, I'm not. He
literally invents all kinds of stuff. He invented
the knife. He invented fire. Like he's always
prepared with some kind of gadget. Whatever.
Okay, the sonic pen would hurt Shah's ears, yes,
but the sonic vibrations from it once again would
power him up. So when Vandal Savage goes to stab him
up the nose with the pen, Shah just grabs him by the
wrist and straight up rips his whole damn arm off.
Okay, I mean, that's fine. Savage has probably
lost that same arm several times throughout his
life. He'll just regrow another one later. But I
will say that some of that acid from the pen did
manage to land on Shah's chest and it's slowly
eating its way through it. So Shah's freaking out.
And while he is, Savage is going to remove his belt
and Garrett, Shah from behind with it, strangling
him to death with his one arm. For some reason, when
you said Savage removed his belt, I thought you
were going to say he's going to give Shah an ass
whooping. That would have been awkward. Anyway,
Shah can't absorb acid. It would hurt him and he can
also be suffocated. But like I'm saying, he's so
strong by this point as Savage is trying to
strangle him, Shah would just grab the belt around
his neck and rip it in half. And then he takes that
belt and does give Vandal Savage an ass whooping
before straight up ripping his spine out of his
body. Match over. But dude, how is he going to do
that with the acid still eating at his chest? Like
by this point, his organs are exposed. That was
really strong acid. It was just a little splash
that got on him of acid. He'll be fine. I mean, did I
also mention that Savage's saber blade from his
cane was laced with poison? Because it was. So that
poison entered the superficial cut in his neck and
has been slowly sapping away Shah's strength this
whole time. So after Shah rips the belt, he just
pukes and dies. Well, yeah, poison changes
things. I'm going to say that, you know, Savage's
poison barely got in Shah's system. It didn't
really affect him in enough time to prevent Vandal
Savage's ass whooping and getting his spine
ripped out. There you go. OK, so it was just a little
poison that affected him a little bit of acid.
Yeah. Come on. Shah's just too strong. I don't know
what to tell you. But we could go ahead and leave the
match there. Either Sebastian Shah gets poisoned
early in the match by a poison laced blade and
therefore succumbs to it and dies. Or the poison
doesn't affect him that much because he doesn't
get enough in his system and he rips Vandal
Savage's spine from his body. Let's go ahead and
input the character stats from the simulations
and find out which of these scenarios is more
likely to happen when we come back with a winner.
AJ9K, hit it. Inputting data, running
calculations, processing results, simulations
complete. I actually really like this matchup.
Like I was intrigued by it when it was pitched, but
having gone through it, Vandal Savage had more
going for him than I thought he would against
Sebastian Shah. Yeah, I thought this was going to
be an easy win for Sebastian Shah, considering
that he's actually super powered. Well, I mean,
Vandal Savage is actually super powered too, but
not to the full potential that Sebastian Shah can
reach. So I was going in this fairly confident and
then just statistically Vandal Savage is pretty
impressive. So I'm less confident now. We'll say
that. I think this will be a closer match than I ever
wanted it to be. Well, I mean, from a stat
perspective, Sebastian Shah has the capability
of being much more of a physical powerhouse than
Vandal Savage. When it came to stats like speed,
durability, strength and even damage, the edge
went to Shaw. But on the other side of the spectrum,
we found that Vandal Savage was a better fighter.
He had slightly more range just because of the
gadgets he carries. He's smarter. He's more
perceptive since he has enhanced senses and
overall just a bit more versatile. I don't think he
should come into this match with any gadgets. I was
never told that he would have gadgets. Tell that to
all of the superheroes he goes up against who don't
expect him to pull out gadgets. I have receipts,
sir. I have receipts. All right, whatever. So
considering all of the stats that were run, who do
you think is going to come out on top? I still think
it's going to be Sebastian Shah, but I think it's
going to be really close, basically a coin toss.
And really, this should have been a curb stop on
behalf of Sebastian Shah, but it's going to end up
being probably a coin toss. Although, you know
what? Instagram disagrees with me. So maybe
people out there know something I don't because
68% of our poll takers on Instagram sided with
Vandal Savage over Sebastian Shah. I think Vandal
Savage just has a cooler look to him. Like he
actually pulls off that Victorian era look,
whereas Sebastian Shah does not. What are you
talking about? You don't have any clue what you're
talking about. The fact that Vandal Savage won the
poll does scare me, though, because I would have
thought that Sebastian Shah would have won the
popularity contest, at least considering that he
was played by Kevin Bacon in one of the greatest
sexman films that has been made. Well, let's find
out who won the match. AJ9K, the results, please.
Here you are, sir. The winner of the matchup
between Vandal Savage and Sebastian Shah is
Vandal Savage, baby. What? He won 593 of the 1000
simulated matches or 59.3% of the time compared to
Sebastian Shah who only won 40.7%. So that wasn't
even a coin toss. No, Vandal Savage won handedly,
which would have been surprising to me prior to us
doing the stats. And I don't even think I mentioned
we accounted for Sebastian Shah being at his
strongest in these stats. The power level he's not
always at. I was supposed to win this entire month
of November. And were you? Yeah, I was supposed to.
Well, it looks like that didn't happen. Did it?
Universe owes me for not coming through on this for
sure. Universe doesn't owe you shit. You know
what? I'm thankful for this Thanksgiving. Having
an awesome twin brother. What? Yeah. No. I'm
thankful for this win in particular because DC has
been on a losing streak and I was getting scared.
Well, I'll be thankful that at least you were
scared at some point this month. Sure, I'll let you
have it. But that does it for this duel. A.G. and
N.K. help close this out. In our next episode, we
are doing a team duel between the powerhouse teams
of the new gods against the Eternals. Look forward
to that next week. That does it for this episode. We
want to give a big thanks to our executive
producers, John Staroski, Zachary Hepburn,
Destin Belcom, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yatyn,
Austin Wazalowski, A.J. Dunkerly, Nick Obonto,
Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Spees, Dean
Moleski, Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting and Paul
Graves for helping make this podcast possible.
We'll talk to you guys next week. Up, up and away.
True believers. The Amalgam version of these two
characters would be named Sandal Bandage and they
would repair shoes as their day job.