This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi, welcome to
the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Johnny DC and I'm his twin
brother Marvelous Joe. And in this episode we are
doing our monthly team duel, this time pitting
Infinity, Inc. versus the New Warriors. Now tell
me if I'm wrong, Jonathan. Infinity, Inc. is to the
Justice Society as the Teen Titans are to the
Justice League. Yeah, it's basically a team made
up of legacy characters or successors to the
Justice Society members. Now I wouldn't call the
New Warriors a legacy team because a lot of them are
original to the team but they are a young group of
badasses. And I can't wait for them to mop the floor
with Infinity, Inc. Clearly you know nothing
about Infinity, Inc. I don't really know. That's
true. A lot of people don't. It was a short-lived
team but a cool team and we're gonna learn all about
it later on in this episode. Before that we're
gonna break down the comic book movie news from the
past week of which there was just one major news
item and that was the release dates that have been
pushed back for Avengers Doomsday and Avengers
Secret Wars. As always we list our segment times in
our episode description so feel free to check out
the show notes if you want to skip ahead to a
particular topic. Guys are artificially
intelligent dual simulator AJ9K has a quick
message for our listeners so listen up. Thanks
AJ9K and thanks to everyone who supports the
podcast. Be sure to tune into the other shows and
the DynaMic Podcast Network this week including
the Konsole Kombat podcast where hosts John and
Dean simulate battles between popular video game
characters. In yesterday's episode they
reviewed The Last of Us season one. Over on the Max
Destruction podcast hosts Scotty and Gilly pay
your favor action heroes from film and television
against each other. They are on a brief season
break currently but are coming back in full force
starting in June with Ben 10 versus Aang from
Avatar The Last Airbender. And on the Senjoh World
podcast hosts Zachary Hepburn speculates on
fights between fan favorite anime and manga
characters. In his next episode Zach is going to
reveal who would win between Makka Albarne from
Soul Eater versus Akame from Akame God Kill. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our show
notes to listen to all of the shows in the Dynamite
Podcast Network. But with that out of the way.
Quick to the no prize. A no prize is an award that
Marvel used to give out to fans. Our version the
Dynamic Dual No Prize is a digital award we post on
Instagram for the person that we feel gave the best
answer to our question of the week. Last week we
asked you guys who had the better official trailer
from a couple weeks ago. Superman or Iron Heart and
why and both of those trailers were released on the
same day and we wanted to see you know what you guys
liked more. So let's go ahead and say two honorable
mentions and a no prize winner. Our first
honorable mention goes to Lorenzo Valdez who said
this is Lorenzo Valdez calling in once again. I
quite like the Iron Heart trailer and I'm very much
looking forward to that show but it doesn't hold a
candle to the Superman trailer. I mean the shot of
Clark young Clark running into Jonathan's arms
that shot alone gives the Superman trailer the
edge I think I would I would vote for it just based on
that shot alone. Clon of forever and always. Bye
bye. Yeah if there's one thing that I've come to
associate with James Gunn and his filmmaking it's
that he is pretty damn good at pulling on the heart
strings whether it was the Suicide Squad or even
Peacemaker and Guardians of the Galaxy for sure he
knows how to tell an emotional story and I
absolutely am expecting that for this upcoming
Superman movie especially when you have things in
the trailer like a little boy just running up to his
dad excited. I'm not gonna lie I stopped listening
to Lorenzo's answer about a third of the way
through so all I know is that he really liked the
Iron Heart trailer which makes sense it's gonna be
a great show. I don't know what to say clean your
ears apparently. Great answer Lorenzo our next
honorable mention goes to Buster Barnes who said
hi guys Buster Barnes here and the best trailer out
of Iron Heart and Superman was definitely Iron
Heart. I mean been waiting to see if you really was
on the screen for a long time you know after with
Canada forever really just couldn't wait to see
her you know said absolutely no one ever. I mean
Superman definitely cleared and it's gonna be
amazing best superhero movie of 2025 and yeah I
can't wait for July let's go. Not gonna lie you had
me there totally thought you were gonna go the Iron
Heart route but then you had that twist reveal at
the end and totally saved your answer and yes
you're correct Superman is gonna be so much better
than Iron Heart it's not even funny. I'm not gonna
lie either I stopped listening to Buster's answer
about midway through so all I heard is that he
thinks that the Iron Heart trailer was better and
that he can't wait to see Riri Williams again. Okay
so you need to get your ears checked and your brain
checked. Great answer Buster but the winner of
this week's no prize is Brian Rochester who said.
Hello I'm gonna be controversial in this question
and say both trailers are good. I cannot pick
between Marvel and DC I've always liked both and
I'm going to be the outlaw on this so there you have
it. Now normally Jonathan on this podcast we don't
like people to straddle the fence we like them to
pick a side but I think in this particular case with
this question of the week this was clearly the best
answer of the group. The only reason this is
getting the no prize win for anyone who's curious
is because we do give points for originality and
since he gave a unique answer that no one else gave
yeah we're gonna give it to him even though he knows
in his heart that the Superman trailer was better
he knows in his heart that Iron Heart was fantastic
correct yes. When's the last time you had a CAT
scan? Because he needed another one your due.
Great answer Brian you and this week's no prize if
you the listener want to shout out winning your own
no prize stay tuned to later on this episode when
we'll be asking another question of the week and
now that that's done. Lots of the news! So this past
week we got the total bullshit news that the
Avengers Doomsday and Avengers Secret Wars films
are going to be pushed back from May in their
respective years to December. Specifically
Avengers Doomsday has been moved from May 1st of
2026 to December 18th and Avengers Secret Wars has
been pushed from May 7th of 2027 to December 17th.
So these films are no longer opening the summer
movie frame but instead coming out in the winter
holiday season. No one knows why it's very likely
that these films are being pushed back because
they're just so gargantuan that there wasn't
enough time within the span of this upcoming year
to adequately fulfill what is necessary in terms
of like special effects and post production and
perhaps reshoots if necessary. Sometimes those
are the breaks and things like this just happen in
life. Yeah, I keep hearing rumors about more
people joining these casts, specifically
Doomsday's cast. And I have to imagine with all of
those actors there's got to be schedule
conflicts. So I'm actually not surprised that
this has been pushed back if they want to bring on
more people and just need to work around their
schedule adding more buffer time to kind of get
things sorted. Yeah, right, because it seems like
the Avengers Doomsday cast is larger than even
Infinity War or Endgame and it's possible the
Secret Wars cast is just as large. So considering
that scale, I totally understand why Marvel
Studios would make this call. I understand it, I
respect it, but damn does it disgust me still. I
don't want to wait. I feel so impatient for these
upcoming Avengers films. The hype is already
building. It's been building ever since, you
know, the cast announcement and we've heard so
much speculation regarding the plot of these
films. I just can't help but be super excited and
therefore super disappointed that we have to wait
seven months longer, eight months longer. One of
those two. Yeah, I could take them or leave them,
you know, maybe they won't even come out. Shut the
fuck up. Don't you put that evil out there in the
world, Jonathan? Speaking of speculation, it's
also currently being speculated that the
upcoming Spider-Man film will also get a release
date push. Oh my God, shut up. We don't want to hear
that. We don't want to hear that. It was originally
supposed to come out between Avengers Doomsday
and Secret Wars. So if they want to keep that story
continuity, yeah, that's probably going to go
back as well. You know what the plus side of this
could be that if they were to fast track the Blade
movie, they could probably still get it out before
the Avengers film. It would have to be sort of like a
small stakes story without much special effects
or anything like that. But they could pull it off if
they really wanted to, if they just got their shit
together and got the Blade movie going. I agree.
Marvel does need to get their shit together. No
more so than DC. Like what's going on with the
Batman movie? Exactly. That's none of your
business. What's going on? Wouldn't you like to
know, Weather Boy? No, I don't really care
actually. But speaking of the upcoming Avengers
Doomsday film, we have a question to ask you guys
for our question of the week. What is your favorite
theory as to why Victor Von Doom would look like
Tony Stark? If you guys have been listening to this
podcast, you'll know that Jonathan and I
absolutely hate the idea of Robert Downey Jr.
returning as Victor Von Doom because it doesn't
give the character of Victor Von Doom, as we know
him from the comics, his do as his own original,
incredible character. Maybe he's going to turn
out to be a variant or something like that. But
there are a lot of interesting ideas that
rationalize why Victor Von Doom would have Tony
Stark's face. So whether it's your original
theory or something you heard online, let us know
how this casting can best be explained. Record
your answer at dynamicdool.com by clicking on the
red microphone button in the bottom right hand
corner of the screen, which will prompt you to
leave us a voicemail. Your message could be up to 30
seconds long, and don't forget to leave your name
in case we include you on the podcast. We'll pick
our favorite answer and award that person a
Dynamic Duel No Prize that we'll post to
Instagram. Be sure to answer before May 31st. From
this moment on, none of your safe. New episodes
every Wednesday, wherever you get your podcasts.
But that does it for the news portion of this
episode. Now let's go ahead and move on to the main
event, the team duel between DC's Infinity Inc.
and Marvel's new warriors. Okay, Infinity Inc
versus new warriors. As we mentioned at the top of
the episode, these are both teams comprised of
younger heroes, or at least heroes that are
starting out. You'll be familiar with quite a few
of the Infinity Inc. team members if you watched
the Star Girl television series that was on CW.
Characters like Wildcat 2, Brainwave, Our Man,
and even Dr. Midnight, the Beth Chapel version,
were all members of Infinity Inc. Now there was
going to be a new warriors television series up
until Marvel Studios took over all of the Marvel
television series. Right, yeah. When the Marvel
television division was folded under the Marvel
Studios umbrella, a lot of the existing
television projects got reshuffled and some got
cancelled entirely. The new warriors television
show was going to start Milana Vayntrabe as
Squirrel Girl, and reports said that the show was
actually really good, but sometimes things just
don't pan out that way, which is a shame. But the new
warriors is a pretty cool group of heroes. It
includes characters that we've done duels with,
including Speedball and Nova, and some
additional characters that we haven't done
individual duels with, but I'll be sure to get into
their backstory within the larger new warriors
history. I will never forgive Kevin Feige for
taking away the AT &T girl Squirrel Girl from us.
Yeah, I don't think anyone will. That's his
biggest crime so far as a producer. 100%. But
getting into this team duel to explain the
methodology behind it, let's go to our sentient
duel simulator, Alfred Jarvis 9000. AJ9K, tell
our listeners how you go about determining a
winning team in our team duel matchups. Yes, of
course, sir. The way I determine a winner between
the two teams is by running 1000 Monte Carlo
simulations between every character on each team
using their statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation
is a probabilistic model used to determine
outcomes through random sampling. In this case, I
randomize the statistics along a normal
distribution as a way to simulate the many
variables that can occur during battle. The stat
parameters are based on the official Marvel power
grid from which the DC characters statistics are
extrapolated. Additional stat categories are
included such as range, damage potential,
versatility and perception in order to create a
more detailed and accurate simulation. The
results of the 49000 simulations provide a
percentage of wins for each character on both
teams. The team with the higher average win rate is
declared the victor as they have a higher
probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither team should win 100%
of the matches. The comic book stories have shown
that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman, so the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks, Agent 9K!
Before we run the simulations though, we like to
break down each team's histories and rosters
before improvising a scenario on how we imagine
one of the thousands of simulations would play out
beat for beat. And it is my turn to go first with the
Marvel team history, so let me tell you all about
the new Warriors. Under the leadership of Dwayne
Taylor, better known as Night Thrasher, the new
Warriors emerged as a team of young superheroes
determined to prove themselves in a world
dominated by older, more established crime
fighters. Dwayne's crusade began in tragedy when
as a child he witnessed the murder of his wealthy
parents. Raised by their associates Andrew Corde
and Ty, Dwayne grew up obsessively training in
combat and tactics, eventually taking to the
streets as a costumed vigilante. Inspired by the
familial bond of the Fantastic Four and
encouraged by Corde to build his own team, Dwayne
identified and sought out like-minded young
heroes to join him. Among his first recruits was
Richard Ryder, the former Nova who had been
depowered after his time at the Nova Corps.
Believing Ryder's powers could be reactivated
under stress, Night Thrasher forcibly dropped
him from a building, a move that successfully
reawakened Ryder's abilities and brought him
reluctantly into the fold. Dwayne also
approached telekinetic mutant Vance Astrovic,
then operating as Marvel Boy. Vance had recently
tried to join the Avengers but was rejected for
being too inexperienced. Eager for validation
and community, he accepted Dwayne's offer. The
final founding member Dwayne sought out was
Angelica Jones, known as Firestar, a mutant with
microwave energy powers who had previously
trained under the White Queen Emma Frost at the
Massachusetts Academy. Though hesitant,
Firestar joined after Night Thrasher uncovered
her identity and applied pressure. You can learn
more about the White Queen in her duel episode
against Poison Ivy. Before the group could
formally establish themselves, they were thrust
into battle against Terriks, a cosmic threat and
former Herald of Galactus. During this
encounter, the group was joined by two additional
heroes, the hyperactive Speedball with kinetic
absorption powers and Namorita, who was the
cousin to Namor the Submariner and a genetically
engineered clone of her mother, Namora.
Speedball coined the team's name, the New
Warriors, based on a news broadcast and the team
established their base in the penthouse of the
Ambrose building, funded by Dwayne's Family
Foundation. The team quickly became involved in a
range of battles, helping Thor combat the
juggernaut and confronting the sinister genetic
research corporation, Genitech. Genitech,
using data from the Mad Thinker, created a rival
team of unstable superhumans called Psionics.
These adversaries would become recurring foils
for the New Warriors, with shifting alliances
forming over time. Additional threats to the team
included the White Queen's Helians,
Environmental Extremists known as the Force of
Nature, and the corrupted corporate giant
Obadiah Stain, Stain International. While the
Warriors expanded their ranks, adding heroes
like Darkhawk, Rage, Turbo and Silhouette, the
team began experiencing internal changes.
Namorita, while juggling her responsibilities
with the Warriors, faced revelations about her
own identity. Having grown up believing she was
Namora's daughter, she was shocked to discover
she was, in fact, a clone. This revelation, along
with increasing leadership demands after Night
Thrasher's periodic absences, led to mounting
personal struggles. Her brief tenure as team
leader ended in disaster when she unwittingly
allowed the villainous Poison Memories gang
access to the Warriors' personal information.
The gang attacked the team's families, killing
Rage's grandmother and deeply traumatizing the
group. Namorita briefly left the team, only to
return later as Chimera after undergoing a
transformation into a more traditionally blue
Atlantean form. Vance's romantic relationship
with Firestar deepened, but his personal life
remained complicated. He had been raised in an
abusive household and during an altercation,
accidentally killed his father. The resulting
trial revealed years of domestic abuse, and
although Vance was acquitted of murder, he was
convicted of negligent homicide. Choosing to
serve a sentence in the vault, he demonstrated a
firm moral compass and resolve, later returning
to the new Warriors' team under the new code name,
Justice. Angelica Jones, aka Firestar,
meanwhile, continued to struggle with the
consequences of her powers. As an Avengers
recruit early on, she discovered that prolonged
use of her microwave emissions could render her
infertile. This discovery caused tension in her
engagement to Justice, but was eventually
addressed when Hank Pym designed a suit that
regulated her radiation powers. With new control
over her abilities, Firestar played key roles
both on and off the team, including aiding
Spider-Man against Carnage and participating in
Avengers' missions against Ultron and King the
Conqueror. Night Thrasher's journey took an
increasingly darker turn as he uncovered
corruption within the Taylor Foundation. His
adoptive guardian, Court, had been mystically
compelled by his other guardian, Ty, to murder
Dwayne's parents as part of a larger occult plot.
Ty, a member of the Dragon's Breath cult, intended
to sacrifice super-powered youth to harness the
energies of a mystical nexus called the Well of All
Things. Ty's long-term manipulation, including
orchestrating the formation of the new warriors
as potential sacrifices, was exposed during a
climactic showdown in Cambodia where Night
Thrasher killed Ty to save the team. Following
Ty's death, Dwayne and Court began to rebuild the
Taylor Foundation and the new warriors' trust.
Dwayne became legal guardian to rage and the
mutant Microbe brought an ink his role as a mentor.
However, as Dwayne's crime-fighting methods
grew increasingly unorthodox, including using
wealth to coerce or buy out criminals, his
leadership came into question. This culminated
in his expulsion from the new warriors, although
he would rejoin them again after Stintin Japan
studying martial arts and aiding Iron Fist
against the Hand. The team faced additional
challenges including confrontations with the
villainous Folding Circle, genetically
engineered threats like Helix and cosmic foes
such as the Sphinx. At one point, the warriors were
scattered across time, requiring a secondary
team to rescue them. As the core members matured,
the team experienced repeated shifts in
leadership and lineup. Justice and Firestar
eventually joined the Avengers, while new
recruits like Aegis, Boltz, and Debris helped
keep the team active. As public interest in the
team waned, Night Thrasher rebooted the new
warriors as a reality TV series to fund their
activities. This controversial move brought
back core members like Nova, Speedball, and
Namorita alongside newer heroes like Microbe and
Debris. The show chronicled their
crime-fighting exploits across small-town
America, but during one such mission in Stamford,
Connecticut, the warriors confronted a group of
supervillains that included Nitro, who had the
ability to self-detonate and reform from a
gaseous state. In an attempt to subdue him,
Namorita slammed Nitro into a bus and taunted him,
prompting Nitro to detonate an catastrophic
explosion that killed over 600 civilians,
including schoolchildren and most of the new
warriors. The Stamford disaster sparked the
Superhuman Registration Act, which divided the
superhero community and led to the superhuman
Civil War. Only Speedball survived the blast,
though it was emotionally devastated. Believing
he deserved punishment, he rebranded himself as
the self-flatulating vigilante Penance and
joined the Thunderbolts. In the wake of this
tragedy, former Warriors member Dwayne's
half-brother, Don Yell, formed a new team of
underground vigilantes in the new Warriors'
name, composed of depowered mutants using
advanced technology. Operating outside the law,
this group struggled with internal trust issues,
especially around Don Yell's secrecy and
personal agenda to locate his brother Dwayne's
body. Their mission ultimately ended in failure
with the team disbanding after a misguided
attempt to use time travel to undo the Stamford
disaster. Meanwhile, Justice led another
iteration of the team known as Counter Force,
joined by Rage, Debris, Ultra Girl, and
Slabstick. Acting as watchdogs against the
government's initiative program, the group
eventually took back the new Warriors' name and
formed the Avengers Resistance in response to
Norman Osborn's rise to power. After Osborn's
fall, many of the members moved on to become staff
at Avengers Academy. The new Warriors would
resurface again under Justice and Speedball's
guidance as they recruited new young heroes,
including a resurrected neighbor Rita, to stop
the high-evolutionaries' plan to eliminate
superpowered beings. And that's the new
Warriors' history. For the roster, I'm going with
the original team roster, starting with the team
founder and initial leader, Night Thrasher, who
is a master martial artist, particularly with his
Escrima sticks. His bulletproof and fireproof
suit comes equipped with a variety of gadgets,
including small firearms, gas-emitting
gauntlets, incendiary explosives,
communication devices, an LED camouflage
system, infrared goggles, a glider's chute, and
most importantly, a jet-powered armored
skateboard. Next up is his first recruit, Nova,
who we go over in his duel against the Green
Lantern, Hal Jordan, and who has greatly enhanced
strength, able to lift over 100 tons, ability to
fly at faster-than-line speeds, and can channel
the Nova Force as extremely powerful concussive
blasts or force fields. Then on the roster, we have
Justice, who emits a telekinetic aura that he can
use to psychokinetically move objects, fly,
project concussive blasts, and erect protective
force fields. Next up is Firestar, who can tap into
the nuclear forces and surrounding atoms and
convert them into microwave radiation. She can
use this energy to fly and can project beams of
intense heat. Following her is Neymarita, whose
human-Atlantian physiology grants her the
ability to breathe underwater and gives her
enhanced physicality, including increased
strength, able to lift 75 tons and increased
durability. She can fly with the wings on her
ankles, has limited armor, and atlantian combat
training. Last to the original team is Speedball,
whom you can learn more about in his duel against
Wally West The Flash. Speedball has a kinetic
force field that can redirect all force exerted
against him, but with greater momentum. He can
slightly extend this field to protect others in
his immediate proximity, and can hurl blasts of
kinetic energy or lend kinetic force to his
physical attacks. The last member of my New
Warriors roster has never actually been a member
of the team, but has notoriously been associated
with them over the decades, and that's Squirrel
Girl. Comic book writer Fabian Nichieza, I think
I'm pronouncing that right, reportedly wanted
Squirrel Girl on the New Warriors team, and he
wrote her as being a huge fan of the team and having a
heavy crush on Speedball. She was also a member of
the New Warriors in the unerred pilot of the TV show
as we discussed before, so I do feel like she's a new
warrior in spirit. As detailed in her duel against
Ratcatcher, Squirrel Girl has the proportionate
physicality of a squirrel and can communicate
with the rodents. She has claws, enlarged
incisors, and advanced negotiating skills.
That's my roster. To reiterate the New Warriors
fighting today will be Night Thrasher, Nova,
Justice, Firestar, Namorita, Speedball, and
Squirrel Girl. So right off the bat when you
started this backstory of the New Warriors, I
thought, wow, what a ripoff of Batman Night
Thrasher is. Not really. Like verbatim, almost.
What is going on? Yeah, but Night Thrasher has a
jet-powered skateboard. Does Batman? He's a
Batmobile. He doesn't need some punk-ass
skateboard. That's right. He doesn't. I didn't
know that Squirrel Girl was not a member of the New
Warriors team. I feel like when I've looked for
imagery of New Warriors, I see a lot of Squirrel
Girl. Yeah, she's associated with the team a lot of
times. So yeah, I felt comfortable adding her to
this roster. Interesting. Okay, well, let me get
into the DC team's backstory and tell you all about
Infinity Inc. Now, Infinity Inc. was formed when
several young heroes, most of them children or
heirs to members of the Justice Society of
America, were denied membership in the legendary
team, which you can learn more about in our Justice
Society vs. Fantastic Four Team Duel episode.
These hopeful young heroes included Hector Hall,
a.k .a. Silver Scarab, the son of Hawkman and
Hawkwomen, Lita Trevor, a.k .a. Fury, the
daughter of Earth Two's Wonder Woman and Steve
Trevor, Norda Candrell, a.k .a. Northwind, the
godson of Hawkman and Hawkgirl, and Albert
Rothstein, known as Nuclon or Adam Smasher. Be
sure to learn more about in our Adam Smasher vs.
Stinger Duel episode. They were later joined by
Jenny Lynn Hayden or Jade and Todd Rice, known as
Obsidian, the children of the Green Lantern, Alan
Scott. After the rejection by the JSA, the group
caught the attention of Sylvester Pemberton, the
former Star-Spangled Kid, who had once been a
youthful adventurer himself during World War II
as part of the Severance Soldiers of Victory.
Sympathetic to their cause, Pemberton left the
JSA and founded a new team with them, bringing in
additional heroes like Power Girl, Huntress, and
Brainwave Jr. The group was officially named
Infinity Inc. and headquartered in the Infinity,
Inc. debuted publicly during a press conference
in which its members revealed their secret
identities and announced Hector Hall's
engagement to lead at Trevor. The team's first
major conflict was against the Justice Society,
who had been turned evil by the Ultra Humanite.
After subduing the JSA and defeating the Ultra
Humanite, who you can learn more about in his duel
against Mr. Sinister, the team established
themselves as protectors of Los Angeles,
operating under a public contract with the city.
Their dual roles as both public figures and
vigilantes brought media scrutiny as well as a
loyal fan base. The team soon clashed with Helix, a
group of metahumans created through unethical
genetic experiments. During one encounter, Fury
was kidnapped and in another, the second wildcat,
Yolanda Montez, discovered familial ties to
Helix member Karcharo. Though Helix initially
escaped one of its members, Mr. Bones, a
chain-smoking albino with transparent skin and
cyanide-laced touch, was later apprehended by
authorities. Despite his criminal past and grim
appearance, Bones expressed remorse and a desire
to change. After some hesitation, Infinity, Inc.
allowed him to join their ranks. His addition
introduced tension within the group, especially
due to the lethal nature of his powers, but also
reinforced the team's mission of offering
redemption and purpose to those who saw it. During
the crisis on Infinite Earths, the team played a
supporting role in the multiversal conflict and
gained three new members, the new Wildcat, a new
Our Man, and a new Dr. Midnighth named Beth
Chappell, the latter two of whom you can learn more
about in their respective duels against Bishop
and Falcon. Together they helped stabilize
collapsing realities and provided backup to the
JSA and other heroes. The team suffered a tragic
blow when Hector Hall fell under the influence of
the evil Hath Set and became a corrupted
incarnation of the Silver Scarab, wielding the
ancient Eye of Ra. After a final confrontation at
Hall Mansion, which was revealed to contain a
hidden pyramid, Hector was destroyed by the Eye's
power. Northwind and Fury left the team in the
aftermath, and Fury later reunited with Hector,
who had become the new Sandman in the Dream
Dimension. He could only return to the real world
for one hour per day, but it was enough to rekindle
their relationship. Eventually the two were
married and chose to live together in the Dream
Inc, severing their ties to the mortal world.
Infinity Inc experienced a devastating blow
during the wedding of Hector Hall and Lita Trevor,
when Marcy Cooper, secretly the third Harley
Quinn and a double agent working against the team,
orchestrated a lethal trap. She manipulated
events so that Skyman, Sylvester Pemberton, the
team's founder and leader, would be alone with
Solomon Grundy, a powerful and unpredictable
creature who you could learn more about in his duel
against Warwolf by Night. At the same time she
lured Mr. Bones into the room, knowing his flesh
carried a deadly touch. Under Harley Quinn's
influence Grundy grabbed Bones and forcibly
pressed his hand against Skyman, instantly
killing him. Bones, horrified at what had
happened, fled the scene. The team tracked him to
the villainous group Helix, who had taken him in
once more. But when Dr. Love, their manipulative
creator, ordered Helix to kill Bones, the group
turned on their maker and killed him instead.
Disillusioned, Helix disbanded, and Bones, now
free of their influence, was granted full
membership in Infinity Inc. Still, the loss of
Skyman shattered the team's foundation. With
their headquarters at Stellar Studios burned
down and their guiding force gone, the remaining
members of Infinity Inc found themselves
leaderless, directionless and overwhelmed. In
time they chose to disband, each member going
their separate way. Although the team dissolved,
their legacy lived on. Several former members of
Infinity Inc joined Black Adam's campaign to
liberate Condoc, forming part of his
superpowered army. Brainwave, Northwind,
Nemesis, Adam Smasher, and a host-possessed
Eclipse, aided in Black Adam's violent mission.
Though his militant assembly bore little
resemblance to the idealistic team once
headquartered in Los Angeles. In a parallel
timeline, resurrected after Infinite Crisis, a
new Earth 2 emerged, one where the Justice Society
and Infinity Inc had merged into a single
multi-generational unit known as the Justice
Society Infinity. This version of the team
featured doppelgangers of familiar faces like
Silver Scarab, Fury, Jade, and Northwind. Unlike
their counterparts, this team operated in a world
where Alan Scott had died, Jade Carrick retired,
and Superman had vanished. Back on Earth 1,
decades after the original Infinity Inc
disbanded, the name was resurrected as part of Lux
Luthor's Everyman project to turn ordinary
citizens into superpowered crime fighters under
his control. Luthor purchased the rights to the
Infinity Inc name and identities of the lauded
superhero team composed of regular people given
metahuman abilities through a synthetic
medigene therapy. These new heroes included
Natasha Irons, known as Starlight, a new Skyman,
Nuclon, Fury, Everyman, and the Speedster,
Trajectory. The team operated as both Luthor's
personal metahuman unit and a corporate stunt,
appearing frequently in media and managing rogue
Everyman subjects. Their headquarters and
operations were largely overseen by Lexcorp
under the careful watch of Luthor and bodyguard
Mercy Graves. Though they fought threats such as
Blockbuster and Cobra operatives, the team's
darker purpose was eventually revealed when
Luthor deactivated Trajectory's powers with
flight leading to her death. He later murdered
Skyman through Everyman, who took his identity to
expose Natasha Irons as a double agent working
with her uncle, Steel. Luthor's own powers
derived from the exo-gene treatment were
nullified when Natasha used Steel's hammer to
emit an EMP, ending his control. In the wake of
Luthor's exposure, remaining members were
arrested. However, some resurfaced during World
War 3 when Ellen Scott called on them to aid in the
battle against Black Adam. They refused and fled
the battlefield, realizing that true heroism
required more than manufactured power. A year
after the dismantling of the Everyman project,
several of its former subjects, Natasha Irons,
Eric Strom, aka Fury, and Juro McKenna, aka
Nuclon, entered therapy to cope with the become
mist-like. Jerome could duplicate himself and
Eric manifested a dominant female alter ego.
Together with a pain-inducing psychic named
Lucia and Lex Cork bodyguard of Mercy graves, they
attempted to reform as a new Infinity Ink, now
independent of Luthor and determined to forge
their own identity. This group operated briefly
from a mobile base, engaging in missions while
trying to control the erratic changes in their
powers. However, they were soon targeted by a
facade of Apocalypse, who manipulated Jerome's
psyche and attempted to siphon their powers using
a specialized machine. The plant backfired when
the machine caused Infinity Ink to vanish. Steel,
arriving too late, swore to find his niece. The
team later reappeared, imprisoned in the Terror
Titans compound. The rescue was orchestrated
with the help of Miss Martian, but the reunion was
short-lived. The trauma of their experiences and
instability of their abilities left the team
scattered once more, their futures uncertain in
the wake of a legacy marked by tragedy and
reinvention. And that's the team's history. For
my Infinity Ink roster, I'm sticking with the
classic roster composed of legacy characters to
the Justice Society of America. Starting with a
former member of the JSA, the Star-Spangled Kid,
aka Skyman, who is the leader of the team for most of
its history, and whose cosmic converter belt
grants him flight, energy projection, and
enhanced physicals. Joining him will be Silver
Scarab, the son of Hawkman and Hawkwomen, whose
Anthemetal Armor also grants him flight, energy
projection, and enhanced physicals. Silver
Scarab's wife, the Amazon known as Fury, will also
be on the team along with the twins Jade and
Obsidian, who can create constructs from light
and shadow, respectively, among other things.
Adam Smasher, who is known as Nuclon while on the
Infinity Ink team, and the second Wildcat, whose
agility and retractable claws make her a fiercer
fighter than her predecessor, will also be on this
team. So to reiterate, my roster will include
Skyman, Silver Scarab, Fury, Jade, Obsidian,
Adam Smasher, and Wildcat. So the character of
Fury we've actually seen in live action in the
Sandman television series on Netflix, right?
Yes, she was Hector Hall's wife, Lita Hall. The one
who was like dreaming about him and then like she
got pregnant? Yeah, yep, that's correct. That
actually happened in the comics as well. Well, at
least one of these characters has got a live action
rendition. Well, a lot of the Infinity Ink members
have. I'm not talking about Stargirl, no one
watched that show. Although, I don't know how many
more people watch Sandman, so maybe I don't know
what I'm talking about. You never did. Well, now
that we've got the team's histories and rosters
out of the way, let's speculate on how one of the
thousands of simulated matches will go. The
winner is determined by simulations, not our
speculation, but it's fun to imagine how the fight
could play out. Agent 9K, what are the rules of our
speculation? Well, I should say there are no rules
other than the teams have no prior knowledge of the
other going into the fight. All they are aware of
starting out is that the other side is a threat that
needs to be eliminated. For the speculation, the
groups will begin approximately 50 meters apart
in a nondescript environment that will have no
bearing on the match itself, as no environmental
statistics are considered in my simulations. The
teams must earn victory on their own merit.
Alright then, let's get into it. Infinity Inc and
New Warriors meet on the battlefield, which team
goes first? I'm going to say Night Thrasher is
going to lead the New Warriors into battle, riding
on his skateboard, his Jeb Howard skateboard, and
he's going to do this like badass 360 spin kickflip
as he peppers the Infinity Inc team with a bunch of
sleeping gas capsules. So extreme, so badass, and
most if not all of Infinity Inc is knocked out and
they're just getting the shit stomped out of them
by the New Warriors. Except that, you know, when
Night Thrasher is in the air doing this so extreme
badass skateboard trick, before he even fires any
capsules, he's going to get snatched out of the air
by a giant sized atom smasher who's just going to
blink him right towards the horizon. Meanwhile,
Jade is going to use her chlorokinesis to have
these thorny rose vines sprout out from the ground
to beneath the New Warriors and just trap them in
place. Okay, if Pokemon has taught me anything
though, it's that Fire Beats Plant. So Firestar,
she's going to get her team out of this mess by just
burning away all the vines using focused
microwave beams, but Nova, he doesn't even need
her to do that actually, he's just going to bust out
of the vines himself and he's going to shoot atom
smasher with the Nova Force Blast that's so
powerful that it's going to send atom smasher to
the horizon in the other direction. What? So like
you just see this 100 foot tall giant man like
flailing through the air until he's out of sight.
Wow, okay. Well, Skyman, the team's leader,
noticed how Firestar is helping her team. So he's
going to take to the sky and blast her with these
stellar energy force beams that's going to knock
her to the ground. Meanwhile, Silver Scarab is
going to do the same thing to Speedball, but he's
going to blast him with a solar energy beam that's
going to burn him. Well, okay, so I'm going to say
that Speedball is going to save Firestar from
Skyman's Force Blast by leaping in the way and
redirecting the blast back at Skyman using his
kinetic field. So Skyman just knocks himself out
of the sky and since Silver Scarab was aiming his
solar beam at Speedball, Firestar is going to
return the favor by stepping in front of him and
absorbing the heat radiation. So they protected
each other, right? Defensive teamwork. They're
going to high five and everything. Okay, you know,
Skyman, he falls to the ground, but he's tough. So,
you know, he'll recover. Wildcat, meanwhile, is
going to take the fight to Squirrel Girl, landing
this combo of slashes and kicks against her while
shredding any squirrels that get near her with her
attractable claws. Geez, why the squirrels, man?
Fuck squirrels, bro. Well, Squirrel Girl has her
own claws, just like Wildcat. So Squirrel Girl
holds her own for a bit, going claw to claw. I won't
say she's as talented of a fighter as Wildcat, but I
think what she lacks in combat training, she makes
up in her speaking skills, right? So she talks to
Wildcat and gets her to hesitate in her use of
violence for just the slightest second, we'll
say. And that's when Squirrel Girl just straight
up chomps down on Wildcat's fist with her giant
front teeth and totally rendering one of
Wildcat's hands useless. And while Wildcat's
like, oh shit, my hand, that's when she's overrun
by a squirrel stampede and she's basically chewed
to bits. Well, except the obsidian sees the
stampede coming, so he just blacks out the entire
environment. So the squirrels can't see anything
and they don't know what they're doing. But
Wildcat can see in the dark. So that's when she
lands a single devastating knockout uppercut
right to Squirrel Girl's face, just shattering
those buck teeth right in her mouth. And you know
what the squirrel's being affected by the
nightmarish shadow land energy that obsidian has
them trapped in, they're gonna turn on Squirrel
Girl and they're gonna devour her in the
confusion. Now you can't do that. It's Squirrel
Girl. She's the unbeatable Squirrel Girl. I looks
like she is in fact beautiful because that's just
what happened. She's out. Okay, well, you know who
else could see in the dark? The marita, right? So
she goes over to obsidian, slaps him down to the
ground, which will turn the lights back on on the
battlefield, essentially. And she's gonna lift
obsidian into the air by his ankle and spin him
around and just hurl him into Jade, which sends
them both tumbling across the ground. No, I mean
Jade, you know, she'll create a green energy
construct of like a giant pillow to soften their
landing. And Fury, meanwhile, she's gonna charge
towards Namorita and tackle her out of the air once
the lights turn back on. And the two of them are
gonna trade blows. So it's Amazon versus
Atlantean. But I'm gonna say with Fury's superior
Amazonian fight training, she's gonna be able to
rip off Namorita's ankle wings. I don't think that
Amazonian training would be superior to
Atlantean training. Oh, it is. But if Fury's going
for Namorita's ankles, even if she's successful
in ripping them off, you know, looking down like
that, she's gonna miss Namorita's elbow that
comes right down on her head. That's gonna stun
her. And you know, as she's in her days, Nova flies
by like a cannon ball, just completely knocking
Fury out with a supersonic punch. So yeah, either
Fury's in a coma, or she's just a goner. And either
way, she's out of this match. Well, that's gonna
piss off Silver Scarab, you know, who probably saw
his wife get taken out. So he's gonna fly after
Nova, just bombarding him with solar energy
beams. And while Nova is distracted by those,
that's when Adam Smasher's hand just comes out of
nowhere, slapping Nova down to the ground and
knocking him out. When did Adam Smasher get back
into this fight after being blasted to the
horizon? Well, he's been leaping back from there,
which Silver Scarab noticed. And he
intentionally directed Nova in Adam Smasher's
direction while distracting him. He's smart like
that. Okay, well, it's gonna take more than that to
take out Nova, I think, just getting slammed to the
ground. But Justice is gonna telekinetically
lift Adam Smasher's hand off of Nova. And then he's
gonna force Adam Smasher to make a fist and punch
himself right in the gonads. It's gonna make him
fall over in pain, and he's gonna feel sick and puke
in his mask. And he's gonna be out of commission for
a bit, just reeling. Meanwhile, Wildcat, she's
gonna try to hit Speedball, but like he keeps
absorbing the kinetic energy from all of her
punches that just bounced right off of him. And
then with all this kinetic energy stored up, he's
gonna run into her and slam into her, just bouncing
her across the battlefield until she's like a mile
away. And that's probably gonna knock her out, I
would assume. But either way, she's out of this
match, because she's just too far to easily get
back regardless. Okay, but as Speedball is
running around, zipping through the
environment, that's when he's suddenly gonna
fall into Adam Smasher's giant shadow, thanks to
Obsidian. And so Speedball is now in the
Shadowlands, where he's being tormented by his
worst nightmares. So he's out of the match as well.
Oh, that wasn't a good ending for him. Okay. But by
this point, Night Thrasher has parachuted back
into the match, back from when he got thrown into
the horizon. And as he's gliding over Adam
Smasher, he's just gonna unload a few packs of
Incendiary napalm that's just gonna burn Adam
Smasher alive. So he's out. And then Night
Thrasher lands back on the ground, back on a
skateboard, actually, all extreme sports like,
and he's gonna pull out his emergency submachine
gun and just unload all of his bullets into Jade.
Nah, force field. And actually, in addition to the
force field, she's gonna create a ramp that's
gonna cause Night Thrasher to launch into the air
on a skateboard, just out of control, Williams
flailing, and he's gonna accidentally land on his
neck, snapping his spine, and he's dead. That is
not a cool way to go out. That's not extreme. Well,
while that's happening, Firestar is gonna beam
Skyman with radiation that's just gonna fry the
circuitry of his belt, and it's gonna cook him from
the inside out so that he just explodes like a baked
potato in a microwave. He's done so. Damn. Okay.
Well, while that happened, Silver Scarab, he's
gonna be cooking Namorita by bombarding her with
solar beams that are gonna dehydrate her like
really quick and just cause her body to shrivel
into a dry husk. So she's out as well. Okay. Well, I
have Justice left. He's going to telekinetically
remove Silver Scarab's armor from his body, and
then he's gonna compress all that metal into this
antmetal circular shield, kind of like Captain
America shield, and he's gonna hurl it through
Silver Scarab, just cleaving him into that
shield. What the heck? Is he like Magneto? This is
really strong metal. Now, he's telekinetic. He's
a strong telekinetic. Okay, whatever. I have Jade
and Obsidian left. So as this metal disc is flying
around, Obsidian, he's gonna open up a shadow
portal in its flight path, and the other opening is
gonna be right behind Justice so that disc is just
gonna straight up decapitate him. Oh, geez. Well,
killing Justice is gonna piss off Firestar, who's
gonna like just burn with rage, and the radiation
aura that surrounds her is gonna turn all fiery and
white hot. So with that, she's gonna fly right
through Obsidian, just burning right through his
shadow form, since he's weak to light, and she's
gonna dissipate him from within the shadow lens.
Oh, damn. That was a good move. But I mean, you think
Firestar was pissed at Justice's death? Like
Obsidian is Jade's twin brother, so Jade is gonna
trap Firestar in this vacuum chamber, made of
solid green energy, and that's gonna quickly
remove all of the air around her, and cause
Firestar to suffocate and die. All right, so who's
left? Okay, so it's really just down to Nova and
Jade at this point, and we all know that Nova could
take a green lantern, so he's just gonna blast Jade
with a Nova Force beam that's so strong it could
punch a hole in the entire planet. So she's just
gone. Well, I mean, except that Nova can't hit what
he can't see, you know, because Jade can use her
magical light-based power to band the light
around her, making her invisible to Nova. So,
well, Nova's looking around for her. That's when
Jade's gonna channel the full power of the star
heart into this massive, mystical, light-hot
energy beam that's gonna push Nova's force field
to the limit, and once he's drained, Jade's just
gonna pull his body apart with green energy
tendrils. Match over. Jade's not that powerful.
She can't overwhelm the Nova Force. Yeah, she is.
Like, she doesn't need a green lantern ring or like
a power battery or anything like that. She's a
direct conduit to the mystical star heart energy.
Like, she even wants to be Cain, the star heart. I
don't know what the star heart is. Well, it's
essentially concentrated chaos magic from
throughout the universe. It's more powerful than
the Nova Force. That's all you need to know. You're
smoking acid right now if you think the star heart
is more powerful than the Nova Force. What?
Smoking acid? Can you do that? I don't know. Yeah,
you just put all the papers into like a smoking
paper and then you roll it up and then you smoke it
and then you say crazy things just like you did. I
don't know. I guess maybe we'll leave it there.
Either Nova blasts Jade into oblivion or she turns
invisible and blasts him into oblivion,
essentially. Let's go ahead and put the team's
statistics into our simulator and come back with a
winner. Ageninke hit it. This is a damn good
matchup. I had a lot of fun with this one, both with
the speculation and seeing just how the stats
lined up between all the characters. Of course,
Nova was the most powerful character out of either
team. I had the most powerful character.
Jonathan, you had the least powerful character in
Wildcat. Yeah, which is kind of depressing. My
most powerful character is actually Obsidian,
which kind of makes sense to me because he was able
to take on the entire JSA like solo. Yeah, my
weakest character was actually Firestar, which
was surprising considering just how powerful she
is. But statistically, she wasn't that
impressive because other than in microwave
radiation, she didn't have a whole lot going for
her. Looking at the stat categories, it looks like
the biggest discrepancy between the two teams was
in the category of strength. And Infinity Inc had
the big advantage there. Yeah, basically all of my
guys, except for Wildcat, had enhanced strength
with Adam Smasher actually being my strongest.
Yeah, and you guys also had the advantage in
durability and versatility because my guys
weren't actually that versatile at all. I would
only say that Night Thrasher had a lot of
versatility. Night Thrasher was actually way
more impressive statistically than I would have
thought. Oh, for sure. I mean, you know, like he's
fast on his skateboard. He has really good armor.
He has a whole lot of weapons, including a whole lot
of explosives that could do some pretty decent
damage. And he's pretty damn smart. He was also the
best fighter on your team. Right, right, right,
right. So with all that said, Jonathan, who do you
think is winning this match? I'm worried, but I got
a root for Infinity Inc. I know you have the most
powerful character, but I have to believe that my
team is more well rounded. Our Instagram poll
takers do not agree with me. They voted in favor of
the new Warriors by 56%, which I don't know. Both
teams are pretty obscure. I'm not entirely sure
why new Warriors won out because our Instagram
followers are smart. That's why. But let's get the
official results. A g9k, the results, please.
Hey, you are, sir. Yeah. The winner between
Infinity Inc. And the new Warriors is Infinity
Inc. Yes. What the hell is happening here? New
Warriors, man. How did they lose? I mean, I guess it
was only by a few percentage points. Infinity Inc.
won 51% even of all of their matches, whereas the
new Warriors won 49% even. Nice. Not going to lie. I
am surprised. Like I was hoping that Infinity Inc.
was going to win. I did not actually expect it to
happen, though, especially considering it looks
like Nova's win rate was a whopping 87.6%. That's
insane. Yeah. He won most of his matches. Really.
None of my guys had a bad win rate. Even my weakest
characters still won about a third of It really
looks like Jade and Obsidian carried my team for
the most part. Both of them had really high win
percentages, though I also had the lowest win
percentage with Wildcat. She only won 18.3% of her
matches. Everyone else was about middle of the
road around 50%. Well, the new Warriors may have
lost, but they are still the better team because
they have that cool factor. Infinity Inc. is
probably the least cool superhero team I have ever
seen or heard of. What the hell are you talking
about? They have no style, no thematic through
line, none of the things that make a team cool. So
how does new Warriors have a stronger thematic
through line than a legacy team like Infinity
Inc.? Well, look at Night Thrasher. Total badass.
Nova. Total badass. Speedball. Really awesome.
Same thing with Justice Firestar and Namerita.
They're all like the rock stars of the Marvel
Universe. So while we may not have won this match,
at least we have that going for us. Again, CAT scan,
bro. CAT scan. That does it for this duel, guys.
HN9K, help close this out. Our next episode is
going to be another duel episode, just an
individual duel between Elongated and Medusa. We
have a guy who can stretch his body versus a chick
who can stretch her hair. So it's going to be really
stretchy and a lot of fun. Yeah, I can't wait. That
does it for this episode. We want to give a big
thanks to our executive producers, John
Snorosky, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Belcom,
Mickey Muthangian, Brandon Essargard,
Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yatyn, Austin
Wyselowski, AJ Dunkerly, Nick Obonto, Scott
Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Spees, Dean Maleski,
Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, Josh Leiner, Mike
Williams, Oscar Galvez, and Paul Graves for
helping make this podcast possible. We'll talk to
you guys next week. Up up and away, true believers.
New warriors come out to play.