This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi, welcome to
the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe and I'm his twin
brother Johnny DC. And in this episode, we're
going to find out who'd win in a fight between the
two trident-wielding badasses, Ocean Master,
who's an Aquaman villain, and Hellstorm, who is a
sometimes lord of hell and then sometimes hero.
It's a little bit strange. Yeah, actually
sometimes Ocean Master is somewhat heroic, you
know, when he's acting for the benefit of
Atlantis. Yeah, I don't know if I would call them
anti-heroes. I guess at one point Hellstorm was an
anti-hero, but I think I would consider them more
anti-villains, if that's even a term. If not, I
just coined it. I want a quarter every time
somebody says it. So now no one's gonna say it.
Either way, we're gonna find out who's gonna win in
this matchup later on this episode. Before we do
that, we're gonna break down the latest comic book
movie news from this past week, of which there was
no news, so I take back what I just said. But as
always, we list our segment times in our episode
description, so feel free to check out the show
notes if you want to skip ahead to our particular
topic. Our artificially intelligent dual
simulator, AJ9K, is a quick message for our
listeners, so listen up. Why hello there. Do you
want even more from this podcast? Then become a
part of the dynamic dual community on Patreon,
where you can choose from three tiers. The dynamic
2.0 tier gives you access to our Discord chat
server. The Fantastic 4 tier gives you two bonus
episodes each month, and the X-Force tier makes
you an executive producer of this show. Lastly,
the Dynomike podcast network tier lets you create
your own podcast using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and
consultation, and get you simulation results.
Pitch the twins your ideas via email at
dynamicdualpodcast.com. Thanks AJ9K, and
thanks to everyone who supports the podcast.
Guys, be sure to tune into the other shows and the
Dynomike podcast network this week, including
the console combat podcast, where hosts John and
Dean simulate battles between popular video game
characters. In yesterday's episode, they
reviewed the 2005 film, Doom. Over on the Max
Destruction podcast, hosts Scotty and Gilly,
pick your favorite action heroes from film and
television against each other. On Wednesday,
they're going to find out who would win between Sam
Wilson's Captain America and Peacemaker. And on
the Senjo World podcast, hosts Zachary Hepburn
speculates on fights between fan favorite anime
and manga characters. In his next episode, Zach is
revealing who would win between Whitebeard and
Kanpachi, both from One Piece. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our show
notes to listen to all of the shows in the Dynomike
podcast network. But with that out of the way,
quick to the no prize. A no prize is an award that
Marvel used to give out to fans. Our version, the
Dynamic Dual No Prize, is a digital award we post on
Instagram for the person that we feel gave the best
answer to our question of the week. Last week we
asked you guys, besides Batman, Spider-Man, and
Wolverine, which Marvel or DC character do you
most want to play as in a single player adventure
video game? And this was coming off of the trailer
that we received for the upcoming Marvel's
Wolverine action adventure game that's coming
out for the PS5 next year. We got a whole lot of
answers for this one, so let's go ahead and run down
our three honorable mentions as well as the no
prize winner. Our first honorable mention goes to
Kyo, who said, Hi guys, I was watching a CW flash
show the other day, and I was thinking how cool a
flash video game would be. Like the map traversal
would be pretty cool since it has super speed, and
then maybe the combat could have some moves like
the fear multi-takedown from the Batman Arkham
Knight game. But yeah, that's my answer. Also, why
are you going to review your friendly
neighborhood Spider-Man? We're not. We have too
many duels to get through before the end of the
show. But as far as a flash video game goes, I
imagine that the entire game would almost have to
be in bullet time, like slow motion, right, for it
to make sense. Maybe, so there was a
side-scrolling flash video game for the Game Boy
Advance. It was a Justice League Heroes tie-in,
but specifically for the character of the flash. I
don't know if you could do a flash game in 3D, but I
think if you made one that was like Sonic the
Hedgehog, just really fast-paced, you would
definitely need some homing attacks just because
I feel like with his speed, it would be really easy
to lose control of the character. But it could be
really cool. Yeah, I mean like Sonic has homing
attacks, so yeah, true. That would be badass. The
flash came in the style of Sonic the Hedgehog. Hell
yeah. Great answer, Kyle. Our next honorable
mention goes to Travis Herndon, who said, What's
up, the name of the dude is Travis here. Shout out to
my evil twin. So my pick would be Ghost Rider. I
mean, come on, Ghost Rider is a cool superhero. He
has a badass rogues gallery that can easily fit
into a game. And then you can either choose between
Johnny Blaze, Danny Ketch, Robbie Reyes, and just
go around fighting demons on a motorcycle or a
demonic charger. I mean, come on, that speaks for
itself. So yeah, my pick would be Ghost Rider. Hell
yeah, bro. You see what I did right there? Hell
yeah. That would be a great video game. I would love
a Ghost Rider game to be in the action-adventure
style video game. Kind of like Spider-Man and the
upcoming Wolverine game, but also have like
almost racing levels. I guess it wouldn't quite be
racing. It would be more like motorcycle combat,
which I think you could develop a really cool
fighting system based off of like high speed chase
fighting. I would love a game like that. Like some
adventures would be maybe in the desert, some
would be in the city, someone maybe even be in hell
and like hell landscapes where like you like ramp
off of things and jump over lakes of fire and do
loop-to-loops or shit. I don't think it would look
really cool in a video game. I mean, you kind of sold
me on the racing aspect. I think that'd be really
cool. Great answer, Travis. Our next honorable
mention goes to Frank, who said? Hey guys, a type of
video game I would like to see is a blade video game.
It's the obvious answer. You either go in with the
bad assery and get a hack and slash like Devil May
Cry, or you focus on the vampire horror and make it
like Resident Evil. It's just the obvious answer.
Absolutely. I think blade would be made for the
hack and slash genre. Very similar to Devil May
Cry. Just put it in a whole horde of vampires and
then just like Dynasty Warriors that shit, right?
That would be such a cool game. That would be
awesome. There was like a blade to video game that I
remember owning for the PS2 way back in the day in
the early aughts. It was so bad, but most movie
adaptations around that time were also bad,
except for Spider-Man 2. That was a great video
game. I think blade is rife for a new video game
undertaking in the single-player
action-adventure hack and slash genre. Dude, so
many video game characters are ripe for a video
game adaptation. If it's true what they say that,
you know, they're superhero movie fatigue, I hope
there's not superhero video game fatigue. And
that just continues to get better and better. Like
DC Studios is a division dedicated just to movies.
They need a DC division dedicated just to video
games. Well, Marvel has a Marvel Games division
because we have our shit together. Okay, look at
you. Hey, hi. Bragging piece of shit. Great
answer, Frank. We want to give a quick shout out to
Sheldon Moore and Lorenzo Valdes for taking the
time to call in with your answer. But the winner of
this week's snow prize is actually split between
two people, Alex Albro and Ryzeal, who gave the
same answer. And that is... Hey guys, I think Green
Lantern has a really good argument for a video
game. Starting on Earth, inevitably you get the
ring and then you leave Earth patrolling all the
sectors of the universe. And as you interact with
different Green Lanterns and different Lanterns
of different color spectrums, and as you defeat
more villains, you gain more abilities, more
power, I think each sector could have a different
style of gameplay and a different villain,
different power ups. And it's not necessarily
endless, but it has a lot of meat on the bone for a
good campaign. Thanks guys. Hey guys, Ryzeal
here. I'm thinking an RPG action game where like a
normal game would have mana, you have to pay
attention to do this one is battery level instead.
You make your constructs with templates
beforehand where you can make whatever you want.
But the more pieces you use, like Lego style, the
more battery it's going to use while you're out on
actual mission. Once the, you know, you run out of
battery, you just go back and have to start over or
you fail that one. Or you have to take time to save
the oath, which is really long, and you're
probably going to get your ass kicked as you're
doing it. We got to run home and grab your battery
first, and then say the oath. Oh yeah. Both these
guys gave great ideas for both the story and
mechanics of a Green Lantern action adventure
video game. I really love how Alex focused on how
like you unlock new moves as you go along and meet
different lanterns among the different
spectrums. And then Ryzeal came in with the whole
construct building mechanic. I think both of
those are brilliant. I think Warner Brothers is
fucking stupid for not having made this game
already because it literally sounds like money
waiting on the table. Yeah, talk about an open
world game. How about an open universe game where
you could go to different planets? That's wild.
Like you think about like the build system in games
like Fortnite or even probably more apt Breath of
the Wild and the recent tears of the kingdom for
Legend of Zelda. How you could basically build all
these creative things. Do that for Green Lantern.
That's his whole concept. Yeah, and you can make
the planet small. It's like you don't even need to
include Earth in a video game like this. Just
include a whole bunch of small planets. Right,
yeah. So throwing a little bit of like loose
gravity, like Super Mario Galaxy. I mean, it's
just a fantastic game idea. You know, it was a
really cool DC game that they actually could have
made into solely a Green Lantern game?
Scribbleknot's Unmasked. And in that game, you
can create anything just by typing in a prompt. Oh,
well, it doesn't make for the most fast paced
gameplay, but it's an opportunity to be really
creative and solve challenges with your
creativity. I'm there for it. Yeah, you just
introduced the idea of puzzle elements within
this game. There's just so much there with the
Green Lantern video game. It's ripe. It's there
for the picking DC. Take it. It would be way better
than anything Marvel could do. No, no, I don't
think so. That's not right. Sorry, but it's true.
Great answer either way, Alex and Ryzeal. You guys
win this week's Snow Prize. If you the listener
want to shout at winning your own No Prize, stay
tuned until later on in this episode when we'll be
asking another question of the week. And now that
that's done onto the question of the week. For the
Halloween season coming up here, what do you think
has been the scariest moment in a Marvel or DC film
or TV series? We're talking about the moments that
made you shit your pants or jump out of your seat or
jump out of your seat because you shit your pants.
We want to hear about it. I mean, not you shitting
your pants, but about the moment. Go ahead and
record your answer at dynamicduel.com by
clicking on the red microphone button in the
bottom right hand corner of the screen, which will
prompt you to leave us a voicemail. Your message
could be up to 30 seconds long and don't forget to
leave your name in case we include you on the
podcast. We'll make our favorite answer and award
that person a Dynamic Duel No Prize that will post
to Instagram. Be sure to answer before October
11th. But I think we'll go ahead and get into the
main event for this episode now, where we find out
who would win in a fight between the Aquaman
villain, Ocean Master, and one of the Lords of Hell
for Marvel, Hellstorm. All right, Ocean Master
versus Hellstorm. Now, the reason we decided to do
this matchup was one due to the executive
producers who thought this might make for a good
Halloween duel, considering Hellstorm is one of
the Lords of Hell in Marvel. And, you know, Ocean
Master, he's not like scary in a Halloween sense,
but he is a villain. So there's that whole dark,
evil aspect going there. So yeah, I think this is a
good Halloween episode. Yeah, both of the
characters are like the sorcerers who carry
tridents, essentially. Plus, you got the whole
water versus fire dynamic going on. It's pretty
cool, I think. I was excited when I heard this
matchup come up. Yeah, same. Both of these
characters have had live action, film, and
television appearances. Hellstorm actually had
his own series on Hulu called Hellstrom. Now, they
kind of played it out very differently than it is in
the comics. They really focused on his
supernatural detective era from the comic books.
But Ocean Master was pretty accurately depicted
in the Aquaman films, I feel, by Patrick Wilson.
Yeah, I would say they did a really good job
adapting Orm, for sure. But before we get into the
match to explain the methodology behind our
duels, let's go to our sentient duel simulator,
Alfred Jarvis 9000. AJ9K, tell our listeners how
you go about determining a winner in our duel
matchups. Yes, of course, sir. The way I determine
a winner between the contestants is by running
1000 Monte Carlo simulations using the
characters statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation
is a probabilistic model used to determine
outcomes through random sampling. In this case, I
randomize the statistics along a normal
distribution as a way to simulate the many
variables that can occur during battle. The stat
parameters are based on the official Marvel power
grid from which the DC characters statistics are
extrapolated. Additional versatility and
perception in order to create a more detailed and
accurate simulation. The results of the 1000
simulations provide a percentage of wins for each
character. The contestant with the higher
percentage is declared the victor as they have a
higher probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither character should win
100% of the matches. The comic book stories have
shown that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman. So the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks, AJ9K.
Before we run the simulations, though, we'd like
to break down each of the characters' histories
and abilities before improvising a scenario on
how we imagine one of the 1000 simulations would
play out beat for beat. And it's my turn to go first
with the DC characters backstory, so let me tell
you all about Ocean Master. Orm Marius was born to
the Atlantean Wizard King, King Atlan, and an
Inupia woman from the Arctic Circle. Though
Atlantean, Orm was raised far from the undersea
realm among the icy northern tribes of his
mother's people, he grew up restless and
alienated, a misfit in a world of tradition. His
mother often spoke of the sea and of the father who
had vanished beneath it, filling Orm's
imagination with dreams of a forgotten kingdom
that he believed was his birthright. When a young
Arthur Curry rescued Orm's cousin Kako from a
polar bear attack, the outcast Inupia saw in the
blonde stranger everything he lacked, strength,
charisma, and acceptance. Orm watched his people
embrace Arthur with warmth they had never shown
him. Jealousy festered until, in a moment of rage,
he attacked Kako after learning she had grown
close to the outsider. Though she survived, her
memory of the assault was lost, and Arthur was
blamed and cast out for bringing a curse upon the
village. Orm's hatred deepened, and when
Whispers of Atlantis reached him through magic
and legend, he abandoned the surface to find the
kingdom of his bloodline. He re-emerged years
later as Ocean Master, a pirate sorcerer wielding
the dark gifts inherited from his father's
lineage. Neither he nor Arthur yet knew they were
bound by Atlan's prophecy that his sons would one
day battle for dominion over the seas. You can
learn more about Arthur in our Aquaman vs
Submariner dual episode. Ocean Master's rise
began with fleets of submersibles and legions of
mercenaries who plundered the oceans, attacking
ships in coastal cities in his quest to force the
world to acknowledge his supremacy. His growing
collection of Atlantean relics and increasing
mastery of ancient sorcery grew with each
conquest, making him a formidable foe even to
Aquaman. Their first clashes revealed uncanny
similarities between them, strength,
willpower, and the same innate connection to the
sea. Though neither man understood their bond at
first, Arthur later uncovered the truth
throughout Atlantean records and realized that
Orm was his half-brother, the second son of Atlan.
Driven by envy and destiny, Orm became obsessed
with claiming the throne of Atlantis. To augment
his power, he sought forbidden sources of magic
and made a pact with the demon lord Neron, selling
his soul for an enchanted trident. The weapon
magnified his control over the elements,
allowing him to summon lightning and tempests,
but accursed him with unending pain whenever he
was separated from it, scarring his face and
warping his mind. With his new power, Orm
conquered the Dreaming City, an Atlantean
offshoot civilization and enslaved its
citizens. Aquaman confronted Orm, revealing
their shared parentage, but the revelation
shattered Orm's sanity. The trident's magic
burned through him, leaving him disfigured and
broken. In time, Orm recovered, turning his
intellect and sorcery toward manipulation and
conquest from the shadows. He joined Lux Luthor's
and Justice Gang and later the Seeker Society of
Super-Villains, forming alliances with other
enemies of the Justice League to extend his
influence beyond the seas. When Atlantis
suffered devastation from the wrath of the
Spectre, Orm enslaved the survivors, forcing
them to mine resources for his undersea empire.
His rule was merciless, his ambition
unrelenting, and his hatred for Aquaman only
deepened as the world continued to favor his
brother as its champion. Ocean Master's sorcery
reached its peak when he used a spell focused
through the bones of Aquaman's lost hand to
rewrite reality itself, exchanging identities
with his brother. In this false world, Orm ruled
Atlantis as its beloved king while Arthur, cursed
with Ocean Master's memories, was hunted as a
villain. For a time, Orm reveled in the adoration
and power he believed he deserved, yet the
illusion unraveled when Dr. Geist, a human
scientist known to Orm, revealed the deception.
Aquaman destroyed the spell's anchor, restoring
reality and leaving Orm once more stripped of the
throne he coveted. Orm later resurfaced within
the ranks of the Seeker Society's inner circle and
clashed repeatedly with both the Justice League
and his half-brother. As the age of magic shifted,
Orm enslaved what remained of Atlantis' people
again, orging a brutal new kingdom in the ruins.
When the magic wars consumed the oceanic world,
Orm was thought dead, but he survived, retreating
into the shadows to await another opportunity to
reclaim what he believed was his destiny. In
post-Flashpoint continuity, Orm was born the son
of Queen Atlanta and the Atlantean warlord Orvex
Marius, raised as a prince in the royal palace and
unaware that his mother had once born another son
with his service man Tom Curry. When he learned
that Arthur Curry, the so-called Aquaman, was his
half-brother, Orm grew conflicted. He loved his
brother and wished to reunite their family, but he
despised the surface world for its pollution and
arrogance. His father's militarism and his
mother's mysterious death hardened him into a
ruler who valued order above compassion. When
Arthur discovered Atlantis with the exiled
Volko's help, Orm welcomed him and briefly seeded
the throne, believing his brother's rule could
unite their divided worlds. But when the surface
launched missiles that accidentally struck near
Atlantis, Orm perceived it as an attack. Acting on
old war plans, he and Arthur had drafted together.
He unleashed devastating floods upon the coasts
of Boston, Metropolis, and Gotham, killing
thousands. Declaring war on the surface, he led
Atlantean armies to battle until the Justice
League intervened. Aquaman pleaded with Orm to
stop, but when the truth came to light that Volko
had manipulated events to restore Arthur to
power, Orm was defeated and taken to the surface
for trial. Stripped of his crown and imprisoned in
Bel-Riv, he came to despise the name Ocean Master,
a mocking title given to him by the surface media.
During a global crisis brought by the crime
syndicate, Orm escaped to sell and wander to the
surface, where he saved a woman named Erin Shaw and
her young son Tommy from Rioters. He found solace
in their companionship, living quietly as a
father figure and telling the boy stories of the
sea. Years later, when he learned Atlantis was
again at war and Aquaman presumed dead, Orm left
them behind to reclaim his throne. He confronted
Mera and Tula on the surface, demanding Atlantis'
crown, but Mera defeated him in battle using her
hydrokinetic powers. Imprisoned once more, Orm
was freed when alien sea gods invaded and
transformed Atlantis' citizens into monsters.
Fighting alongside Mera, he helped her seek an
artifact capable of killing gods, but was himself
corrupted by the invaders' waters and
transformed into one of their servants. After the
gods' defeat, Orm returned to his senses, hunted
by what he had become. In the aftermath, he
vanished into the lower depths of Atlantis,
living among the destitute of the 9th tribe. There
he learned of the legend of King Dagon, a forgotten
monarch who once ruled the oceans through a bound
elemental named Lernaea. Pursuing the myth, Orm
descended into the oceans of Biss and found the
imprisoned Lernaea herself. Fraying her from her
bonds, he gained her loyalty and founded a new
kingdom for the displaced and the damned, the city
of Dagon. Rejecting overtures from Apex Lux
Luthor to join the Legion of Doom, Orm instead
built his own domain, declaring independence
from both Atlantis and the surface world. When he
returned to the surface to explain his
disappearance to Eren, she rejected him,
unwilling to live in the shadow of his war like
ambitions. Orm left heartbroken, but vowed one
day to offer Tommy the chance to succeed him as King
of Dagon. From the deaths of his new city, Orm began
plotting once more, gathering outcasts and
mutants to his cause. When Queen Mera fell into a
coma, he sought to exploit the power vacuum,
manipulating Dagon's populace and even
orchestrating the abduction of Aquaman and his
daughter to discredit her rule. His deception was
exposed and his elemental ally turned to Against
him, forcing Orm to concede defeat and accept
Mera's plan to abolish Atlantis' monarchy.
Though stripped of power yet again, he remained in
the shadows, commanding loyalty among those who
believed in his vision of an ocean ruled by
strength and purity. In the years that followed,
Orm allied with the scavenger and other undersea
warlords to destabilize Atlantis, seeking to
resurrect his empire through subterfuge and
terror. Napaurs wise, as a pure-blooded
Atlantean of royal descent, Ocean Master
possesses immense strength, speed, durability,
and stamina, allowing him to survive the crushing
pressure and fragile darkness of the deep ocean.
His enhanced senses grant perfect vision in the
blackest depths and hearing capable of detecting
movement miles away. A skilled tactician and
warrior, Orm is trained in all forms of Atlantean
combat and command. His enchanted trident,
forged in Atlantis, channels lightning,
conjures storms, and focuses his arcane power,
while his royal mask crown amplifies his
hydrokinesis, enabling him to command the tides
and summon devastating tsunamis. And that's
Ocean Master. He's not that scary. I don't know if
this is a good Halloween episode after all. Oh, I'm
sorry. There's nothing scarier than the ocean,
bro. Do you know what's down there? Freaking no one
does. You go down there and you see him? Yeah,
you're going to be shitting yourself in that
water. I can think of a lot of things underneath the
water that would make me shit my pants more than
some dude wearing a goofy-looking helmet. That
being said, one of my most frequent recurring
nightmares is one of a tidal wave. Oh, really?
That's interesting. You know what that means,
right? What? It means that you have poor taste in
comic books. What? Yes. Science. I think it means
that I have awesome taste in comic books. I'm just
like swimming in all the awesomeness that is
Marvel. Is that what happens in your dream? The
tidal wave crashes on you and you're just
swimming? No. Yeah. It's more like I'm trying to
get to higher ground and run, basically. Anyway,
enough about that. Let's go ahead and get into the
backstory for Hellstorm. Damon Hellstrom was
born in Green Town, Massachusetts, the son of
Victoria Wingit and the hell lord who called
himself Satan. Victoria's parents had sold her to
the Chapel of Dresden, a fanatical occult sect
once allied with Nazi Germany who hoped to bring
about a messianic human demon hybrid. Rituals and
glyphs were carved into Victoria's body to
prepare her as a vessel and when Satan came to earth
in human guise, he seduced and married her. The two
settled in Massachusetts where Damon was born a
year later. Damon's infancy was marked by
sinister conditioning. He was fed human blood and
marked with a pentagram birthmark. His father's
interest soon shifted to his younger sister,
Satan, born three years later who proved more
receptive to his teachings. Damon meanwhile
bonded with his mother, never fully aware of his
father's identity. When their mother witnessed
Satan's true demonic form, she was driven insane
and the children were separated. Victoria was
institutionalized. Satan, taken to hell to be
raised by her father, and Damon placed in an
orphanage. On visits, his mother entrusted him
with an onc pendant claiming it was his sole
protection against Satan. She also revealed the
existence of Nethraeneum, a rare infernal metal
capable of harming his father. As Damon matured,
he pursued theology, studying under Father
Raymond Gosset in a Jesuit monastery. He prepared
for ordination but turned away from the
priesthood when his mother died and he inherited
the Massachusetts estate. Exploring the
mansion, Damon discovered her diary, confirming
his lineage. He was drawn to the portal in the
basement leading to hell where Satan revealed
himself and offered Damon eternal life and power
if he served him. Damon refused, instead stealing
his father's trident forged of Nethraeneum and
his Damon-drawn chariot escaping back to earth.
He also discovered the powers of his dark soul, the
infernal inherited energy that granted him great
magical might. So, wearing to fight his father's
evil, Damon became the hero called Son of Satan. He
balanced his civilian life as a scholar of the
occult with his secret role as an exorcist and
demon fighter. Damon assisted Linda
Littletrees, the witch woman, which led to his
first team up with Ghost Rider against Satan
himself. He clashed with demonic beings such as
German X-D's and Cathara and even battled his
sister Satan when she surfaced on earth as a
succubus. He grew known as a leading demonologist
and frequently collaborated with superheroes
including the Fantastic Four. His reputation
grew when he joined the defenders, assisting them
against the alien Nebulon, the Sons of the
Serpent, and the demonic alliance known as the
Six-Fingered Hand, whose manipulations nearly
merged earth with hell. During his tenure with the
defenders, Damon fell in love with teammate Patsy
Walker, aka Hellcat whom you can learn more about
in her duel with Catwoman. The relationship was
tested by his father, who transformed Patsy into a
demon to torment him. Damon agreed to stay in hell
to secure her freedom, but ultimately rebelled
and returned to earth. Rejoining the defenders,
he fought alongside them against threats
including Asmodeus, the Resistance, and the
Miracle Man. The Miracle Man stole Damon's dark
soul, trapping it in a serpent. Deprived of his
demonic half, Damon lost much of his power but was
freed from his infernal corruption. Believing
himself cured, he retired his son of Satan
identity. He married Patsy and together they
moved to San Francisco operating as paranormal
investigators while Damon taught
parapsychology. To shield his reputation as a
scholar, he began using the alias Hellstorm when
battling supernatural forces in public. The two
occasionally aided other heroes including the
West Coast Avengers and confronted foes such as
Master Pentamonium, the Cat People, and demonic
spirits tied to the Phantom Rider. But the absence
of Damon's dark soul left him gravely weakened. In
desperation, Patsy summoned Satan through the
Grimorium Barum, a book of dark spells pleading
for her husband's life. Satan restored Damon's
dark soul, but Patsy was driven insane at the sight
of his full demonic essence. Though Damon
admitted gratitude, he coldly confessed he would
have let her die in the same situation. Her mind
shattered. Patsy eventually took her own life
under the influence of a being named Death Urge.
Emboldened, Damon reclaimed his role in the
occult world, forging alliances with figures
such as Necra, the Gargoyle, Gabriel the Devil
Hunter, and his new lover, Janie Cutter. He struck
a bargain with the witch, Lavoison, fathering her
child in exchange for knowledge of his father's
true name. Armed with this secret, Damon slew
Satan, aka Marduk Curios, inheriting his black
halo and lordship of his hell realm. He proclaimed
his rule as a balance between heaven and hell,
ensuring neither could dominate humanity's
destiny. From this position, Damon grew ever more
manipulative. He participated in conflicts
involving Celine and Blackheart's demonic
Hellfire Club, a select group of mutants and
demons attempting to exert control over society.
Damon took a seat in its inner circle as the White
King, claiming to balance good and evil. He
deceived the Thunderbolts into rescuing Patsy's
soul from Mephisto's realm, enabling her
resurrection. At times he spread deliberate
falsehoods about his lineage, claiming even to be
the son of another hell lord named Satanish, a ploy
to distance Patsy from him and protect her from the
horrors of his life as a hell lord. Using such lies,
he briefly assumed control of Satanish's hell
realm and Dormammu's claim to rule through the
flames of Faltine, though Mephisto soon seized
most of the territory. You can learn more about
Dormammu and Mephisto in their respective duels
against Trigon and Santman. Damon remained
embroiled in battles among hell lords. When
Dormammu attempted to annex Hell, Damon allied
with Mephisto, Hela, Pluto, and Patsy to repel the
invasion. He later confronted angelic forces
during the Angel's Zadkill's Takeover of Heaven,
hunting a boy prophesied as the Antichrist, named
Anton Satan. Damon, Janie Cutter, Ghostrider,
and others pursued Anton, though Damon argued for
killing him outright, only relenting when
pressed to prioritize defeating Zadkill. He
later became involved in the contest for Sorcerer
Supreme after Doctor Strange stepped down,
though Brother Budu ultimately inherited the
mantle. After a demonic invasion of Las Vegas,
Damon discovered that a prophecy called the
Descent was real. A day when a hell lord would gain
greater power, those they had marked would
transform into demons, and their heirs would
ascend from hell. Damon betrayed the Avengers and
allied with the Red Skull's daughter, Sin, in a
plan to raise the world. He later fell victim to
revenge by Brother Budu's brother, a spirit named
Daniel Drum, who killed Damon, though his spirit
endured. Revived, Damon joined Baron Zemo's
Masters of Evil and fought in a war of gods in a
desperate stand against the Shinto God of Evil, to
whom Hell had fallen. Later, Damon accepted a
teaching role as Strange Academy in New Orleans,
instructing students in infernal magic
alongside the mutant, Magic, whom you can learn
more about in her duel against Deadman. And that's
Hellstorm's backstory. Powers-wise, Damon is
the son of the Hell Lord, Marduk Kirios, aka Satan.
His demonic soul grants him enhanced physiology
with enhanced strength, able to lift over one ton,
and bulletproof durability. He can generate and
manipulate Soulfire, a version of Hellfire that
can hurt demons, which he can also form into
constructs such as shields or restraints. He can
also use the Soulfire to fly or burn holes through
reality to create teleportation portals.
Hellstorm can use magic to project a psychic
astral form and read the thoughts of others. He has
spells for healing, hypnotizing, scrying,
exercising, shapeshifting and more, as well as
mystic senses. He wields a Nethraenium Trident,
through which he can channel his powers and use as a
weapon. He is a skilled supernatural detective
with advanced knowledge of theology, the occult,
and the supernatural. And that is Hellstorm. I
can't believe that Marvel is dumb enough to use the
name like Son of Satan as the name of a superhero.
Like, who's going to be calling for him to save
them? Oh, save me, Son of Satan! Yeah, actually,
the original name of that comic book was Mark of
Satan, before Marvel decided to change it. It was
supposed to be along the same lines of the Tomb of
Dracula comic book series. I don't know why Son of
Satan is a better title than Mark of Satan, but
yeah, if I had a choice of heroes to save me, it
wouldn't be him, largely because he's a selfish
son of a bitch. And that's probably why he grew more
villainous over time. Oh, that all of a sudden they
have him teaching a strange academy as if he wasn't
a villain. It's all very strange. Academy. And
that's it for this video. I hope you enjoyed it.
I'll see you in the next one. Well, now that we've
got their histories and abilities out of the way,
let's speculate on how one of the 1000 simulated
matches will go. The winner is determined by
simulations, not the speculation, but it's fun to
imagine how the fight could play out. AJ9K, what
are the rules of our speculation? Well, I should
say there are no rules other than the characters
have no prior knowledge of the other going into the
fight. All they are aware of starting out is that
the other character is a threat that needs to be
eliminated. For the speculation, the
contestants will begin approximately 50 meters
apart in a nondescript environment that will have
no bearing on the match itself, as no
environmental statistics are considered in my
simulations. The contestants must earn victory
on their own merit. All right, then let's get into
it. Ocean Master and Hellstorm meet on the
battlefield. Who goes first? I'm going to say
Ocean Master starts off by raising his trident and
summoning a giant ass tidal wave straight from
your nightmares, which rushes in from behind
Ocean Master and crashes right on top of
Hellstorm, just drowning his ass. No, because
Hellstorm would see the water coming at him. And as
the wave approaches, he just slams his trident
into the ground and parts that water like the Red
Sea, creating like this like wedge of heat that
like separates the waves. And so like there's this
lane of dryness between the part of waters. And
through that, Hellstorm shoots out this like
massive soulfire blast in the shape of a pentagram
at Ocean Master. And it just hits him and Ocean
Master gets burned alive. No, because as that's
coming at Ocean Master, he's just going to dive
into one of the walls of water to his side and use
that to swim towards Hellstorm. And he's going to
manipulate the body of water he's in to swirl
around Hellstorm, trapping him in this massive
whirlpool and allowing Ocean Master to just swim
around him and stab him a bunch of times. Hellstorm
could fly though. So no, he's not getting pulled
into the water. He actually hovers above it. And
then he dips his trident into the water, which sets
everything to an instant boil. So all the water
evaporates and all that's left is just Ocean
Master, who's freshly cooked. I mean, that's a lot
of water to boil. So let's say Ocean Master, he's
steamed, not boiled, but he'll cool off because
he's going to summon a rainstorm that's just going
to drench the environment once again. And it's
going to pummel Hellstorm with hail stones the
size of literal cats and dogs. Dogs like
Chihuahuas, you mean? Sipernards, bitch. Who
cares? Either way, Hellstorm is going to create a
like spherical fire shield around him. And hail is
not going to get through that because Pokemon
rules fire beats ice. And within his fire shield,
Hellstorm's eyes burn and he casts a hypnotizing
spell to take over Ocean Master's mind. And now
Ocean Master's eyes burn because he's under
Hellstorm's control. I Ocean Master literally
wears a mask that covers his eyes. I don't think
that spell is going to work on him. In fact, Marvel
probably has some dumb rule against that. Like,
you know how you can't be mind controlled if you
wear a helmet? No, I mean, like this is more demon
possession than psychic mind control. It's more
like exorcist than Professor X. Right. So Ocean
Master gets mind controlled and his eyes burned
through his mask. OK, but Ocean Master is Homo Magi
Atlantean royalty. So he's going to be able to
realize that Hellstorm is trying to possess him.
So he's going to cast his own Atlantean spell
that's going to stop what Hellstorm is doing and
flood Hellstorm's mind with negative thoughts of
all the crap he's done, like betray his wife and the
Avengers and, you know, just general evil doing.
And this is going to put him in mental anguish and
cause him to be like, oh, no, I suck. And he's going
to drop his shield and his Trident and he's going to
fall to the ground. I mean, like that may have
stopped Hellstorm's possession spell, but he's
not going to feel that bad. He's one of the Lords of
Hell, right? So like after he falls to the ground,
he's just going to get right back up, like unfazed,
and he points his Trident at Ocean Master and
manifests these fire rings around him, binding
him in fire. And then he telekinetically pulls
Ocean Master toward him right onto his Trident and
paling him like a shish kabob. OK, well, as Ocean
Master is being pulled toward Hellstorm, he's
going to cast a teleportation spell. Actually,
he's going to cast an illusion spell at the same
time. So Hellstorm thinks he's impaled Ocean
Master when in reality, Ocean Master is now behind
Hellstorm and he's going to impale him instead
with his electrified Trident that's going to
overload and kill Hellstorm. Match over. But like
the moment this illusion Ocean Master gets
impaled, Hellstorm's Trident is going to burn the
illusion away. So Hellstorm realizes the
deception with enough time to spin around and
block Ocean Master's electric Trident attack. He
just smacks his Trident away. And then Hellstorm
summons a Hellfire portal that sends them both to
hell, where Ocean Master just burns an agony,
instantly desiccates into this like skeleton of
Ash and Embers. And that is where the match ends in
hell. Yep. I mean, Ocean Master, he's just going to
conjure these massive geysers that are going to
flood the entire realm, drowning everyone, all
the demons in Hellstorm. So yeah, he's fine. He
just has a new realm to roll over, I guess. That's
the stupidest thing I've ever heard in my entire
life. But you can't flood Hell. It's too hot. All
the water would just evaporate. It's not like it's
magic water. It has a boiling point. It is
literally magic water. What? No, it's water
summoned through magic. It's not magic water that
makes it magic. OK, OK. Well, we'll go ahead and
leave the match there. One of two scenarios
happens. Either Ocean Master burns alive in hell
or he floods hell and drowns Hellstorm, which of
those sound even remotely possible. It was holy
water. Now what do you say? Hey, you may have me
there, but let's go ahead and put the stats, run the
simulations and come back with a winner. A.G .9K,
hit it. Inputting data, running calculations,
processing results, simulations complete. This
is a damn good matchup, man. Damn good matchup.
Both of these guys are insanely powerful. They can
both do teleportation. They can both do magic.
They both have elemental magical powers with
their tridents. They're both highly versatile,
although Hellstorm comes out a little bit ahead
there just because he has a lot more psychic feats
than Ocean Master, which is also why Hellstorm has
the advantage in perception. Right. Hellstorm
also had the advantage in invasiveness, but Ocean
Master had the edge in durability and strength
thanks to his Atlantean physiology, which is
apparently stronger than demonic physiology,
because Hellstorm is only credited with lifting
about a ton, whereas Ocean Master can lift about as
much as Aquaman. The range on Ocean Master and the
damage level is off the charts. His feet of
destroying entire cities thanks to his mask crown
and the bodies of water he's able to control with
that is just freaking brutal. I mean, I've seen
Hellstorm blow up a few buildings with Hellfire,
but I don't think I've ever seen him level entire
cities simultaneously. So Ocean Master got the
edge and damage level and I guess fighting skill
because Ocean Master is more formally trained
than Hellstorm. Right. He was like a master of
Atlantean combat at age eight. So taking all of
these stats into account, Joseph, who do you think
is coming out on top in this match? To quote an X-Win
movie, why do you ask questions to which you
already know the answer? Because I want to make
sure that you're thinking the same thing I am. Oh, I
am Hellstorm. That's not what I was thinking.
Well, it's what most of our Instagram followers
are thinking, because 56% of them are siding with
Hellstorm in this fight. Well, let's see if
they're right. AJ9K, the results, please. Hey,
you are, sir. All right, the winner of the matchup
between DC's Ocean Master and Marvel's Hellstorm
is Ocean Master. No, but it's the reverse of what
Instagram thought. Ocean Master actually won
56.1% or 561 of the 1000 simulated matches. And
Hellstorm won 43.9% of the matches. What is
happening? How is Ocean Master able to be a Lord of
Hell? Doesn't register with me. The fuck is going
on? Well, it's Ocean Master's physiology and just
sheer raw power. Hellstorm may be more versatile,
but it's not enough to overpower Ocean Master,
apparently. What the fuck is the tidal wave going
to do to Hellstorm? Defeat him, apparently. I
don't see that happening. I don't see any way that
Hellstorm could be Ocean Master. So easily just
burn him alive. And what is fire going to do against
water? Evaporate it. OK, so then it turns into a
cloud, which becomes rain, which then rains on the
fire, dousing the fire. Pokemon rolls. Water
beats fire, my guy. Stupid, not soul fire, not
magic water. Hey, dude, it's OK. The son of Satan
lost. Things are going to be fine. Did you want him
to win? Yeah, that's evil, bro. He's a good guy,
even when he's not a good guy with the worst name
that a good guy could ever have. No, Hellstorm is a
badass name. I don't care what you say. I was
talking about his son of Satan name. I can't get
over how dumb that is. I'm talking about
Hellstorm. Even that, even that. Oh, save me,
Hellstorm. No, save me, Ocean Master. I want you to
save me. Yeah, Master of the Oceans, especially if
you're in the ocean when you need saving. This is
dumb. I'm I'm so ready for it to be January already.
You piece of shit. Adrian and Kay, help close this
out. In our next matchup, we are doing another
Halloween spooky-esque duel, this time with two
villainous sorcerers, Felix Faust versus Baron
Mordo. Yeah, that episode has been a long time
coming. Can't wait for that one, when Marvel's
finally going to get their comeuppance. You have
yet to learn. You will, though. That is it for this
episode. We want to give a big thanks to our
executive producers, Jon Straski, Zachary
Hepburn, Destin Belcom, Maggie Mathen-Geehan,
Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Aitin, Austin
Wosalowski, AJ Dunkerly, Nikobonto, Scott
Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Spees, Dean Maleski,
Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, Josh Leiner, Mike
Williams and Paul Graves for helping make this
podcast possible. We'll talk to you guys next week
up up and away. True believers?