This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. And I'm his twin
brother Johnny DC. And in this episode we are
reviewing the Fantastic Four First Steps film
that came out this past week. I'm excited to talk
about it. I thought it was fucking fantastic.
Hashtag FF. For fucking fantastic. Hashtag FFS.
Fantastic First Steps. Towards a better MCU. And I
mean what a great time to be a comic book movie fan
right now. I mean not earlier in the year but right
now. A Marvel fan for sure. I have the opinion that
it's never a good time to be a DC fan. So I mean we'll
see if the box office agrees with you right? What
does the box office have to do with anything? I
don't know. Superman just looks like he's coming
on top so I thought I would rub it in. You don't know
that and the ongoing bet is for the final worldwide
box office figures. Not just opening weekend. For
the entire theatrical run. That's fair. But a
movie does make a majority of its money in the
opening weekend. I think that's true. I don't know
man. Superman's doing pretty well. I think a lot of
people are happy with both films really and they
should be because they were both great. Yeah.
Marvel's put out three decent to great movies this
year. DC has put out one movie. That's great.
That's super you could say. It was decent. So yeah.
This whole Marvel DC rivalry where Marvel's
winning is still going strong. Yeah winning gets
sucking. But we're going to talk all about our
thoughts on the Fantastic Four First Steps movie
later on in this episode. Before that we're going
to break down the latest comic book movie news to
come out this past week of which we got two
trailers. One for Peacemaker season two and one
for Aztec Batman Clash of Empires. As always we
list our segment times in our episode description
so feel free to check out the show notes if you want
to skip ahead to a particular topic. Our
artificially intelligent dual simulator AJ and
NK has a quick message for our listeners. So listen
up. Why hello there. Do you want even more from this
podcast. Then become a part of the dynamic dual
community on Patreon where you can choose from
three tiers. The dynamic to a tier gives you access
to our discord chat server. The Fantastic Four
tier gives you two bonus episodes each month and
the X Force tier makes you an executive producer of
this show. Lastly the Dynamite podcast network
tier lets you create your own podcast using this
Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe will help
you develop your show provide graphic support and
consultation and get you simulation results.
Pitch the twins your ideas via email at dynamic
dual podcast at gmail.com. Check it out at
patreon.com slash dynamic dual. Pip pip cheerio.
Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast. Be sure to tune into the other shows in
the Dynamite podcast network this week,
including the console combat podcast where hosts
John and Dean simulate battles between popular
video game characters. In yesterday's episode
they determined who would win between solid snake
from Metal Gear and Gabe Logan from Siphon Filter.
Over on the Max Destruction podcast hosts Scotty
and Gilly pick your favorite action heroes from
film and television against each other. This week
they will be finding out who would win between the
DCU Superman, David Cornswet and the MCU's
Sentry. On the Sentry World podcast host Zachary
Hepburn speculates on fights between fan
favorite anime and manga characters. In his next
episode Zach is going to reveal who would win
between Enjin from Gachiakura and Naito Mudano
from Tugin Anki. Visit dynamicpodcast.com or
click the link in our show notes to listen to all the
shows in the Dynamite podcast network. But with
that out of the way, quick to the no prize! A no prize
is an award that Marvel used to give out to fans. Our
version, the Dynamic Dual No Prize, is a digital
award that we pushed on Instagram for the person
that we feel gave the best answer to our question of
the week. Last week we asked, for those of you who
have seen the Fantastic Four first steps in its
opening weekend, what did you think? Yeah we got a
few answers, let's go ahead and run down the
honorable mentions as well as the no prize winner.
Before we get any further, I do want to put a spoiler
tag on all of these answers. All of our reviews are
spoiler reviews for this podcast, so if you
haven't seen the movie be sure you go check it out
before listening to our review or even listening
to these no prize answers. There's your warning,
go ahead and hit the pause button now if you haven't
seen the movie go see it and our first honorable
mention goes to Alex Albro, who said, Hey guys just
got back, I'd read it at seven, my wife said six and a
half. I really liked Read and Sue, they were really
really well done, I'm sold on Pedro. The thing in
the Surfer I didn't really like, the thing was too
comedic like Smart Hulk and Endgame. Surfer
didn't feel integral to the story, but seeing
Galactus for real was really cool and I can kind of
see where Franklin fits into Doom's potential
plan for Secret Wars. I thought that the Earth
moving was going to be the cause of incursions and
kind of start the playing field for Secret Wars,
but they kind of spurred me there. Overall, I
thought it was a pretty good movie. Yeah, there's a
point in the movie where Reed tries to teleport
Earth away from Galactus. I also thought that
maybe that was how the Fantastic Four were going to
find their way to the Earth 616 dimension since
they're from Earth 838, but the movie didn't do
that and actually for the end credit scene of the
Thunderbolts we see the Fantastic Four's ship
arrival to the main 616 dimension. I thought they
were going to address the why of that in the
Fantastic Four film, we never got that answer so it
looks like we're not going to find out what's going
on there until the actual Avengers Doomsday
movie. Yeah, I guess the film would have been
pretty anti-climactic if it just ended with them
in a new universe, either superimposed over the
existing Earth or possibly on the opposite side of
the sun. Something like that, we really would have
been able to see a final battle with Galactus if
that happened in that moment it was supposed to.
Right, and I'm glad we did get that climactic
scene. In regards to the thing, the thing is not the
Hulk, he's not supposed to be dark. I mean he does
have moments of self pity, but he's the
ever-loving blue-eyed thing, you know? He is a
little bit witty and funny. Great answer, Alex.
Our next honorable mention goes to Cornelius
Robinson, who said... Hey guys, this is Cornelius
and I've just seen Fantastic Four and it is
literally fantastic. I just love the cast and the
chemistry between them, which was a standout for
me. Galactus was terrifying and the visuals are
just out of this world for the MCU up to date. And
it's the most comic book MCU film that I have ever
watched, aside from Superman, and it was one of the
best. Now, I should clarify, Superman is not a part
of the MCU and it doesn't want to be. Yes, it does,
but yeah, I would say that the Fantastic Four movie
was comic book-y in the sense that it pulled a lot of
inspiration from the 1960s comic books written by
Stanley and drawn by Jack Kirby. It felt very much
of that era. Which is interesting considering
that both Superman and Fantastic Four both kind of
kicked off their respective comic book universes
in Action Comics Number One and in Fantastic Four
Number One, The Golden Age and the Silver Age of
Comics, as it were. Yeah, I mean Marvel was around
in the Golden Age, but they didn't really become
the pop culture supergiant that they were until
the 1960s. So it's kind of cool that both of these
films feel like they're among the most comic
book-y films of the genre. Great answer,
Cornelius. Our final honorable mention goes to
Lorenzo Valdez, who said, This is Lorenzo Valdez.
I just came out of a Thursday screening of the
Fantastic Four First Steps. I loved it. It is
Marvel Studios' best looking film from a visual
aesthetic standpoint. The final climactic
battle scene is super intense. The end credit song
is beautiful. The movie's still not as good as
Superman though. Clown of Forever and Always,
boba! You know what? I don't want Clark and Lana to
end up together. I guess I never did before, but
like, I'm more for sure about that now. Fantastic
Four was a great movie. Superman was pretty good.
I'll say that the Fantastic Four's artistic
direction with the retro-futurism style was a lot
more interesting. I agree with Lorenzo in that the
Fantastic Four movie is probably one of Marvel
Studios' best looking films to date. Yeah, I
definitely agree. I think the design approach
they took with the movie did a lot of favors. For
sure. We want to give a quick shout out to By Dear
Bangora for taking the time to reach out to us and
leave an answer, but the winner of this week's snow
prize is Gil Camacho. Who said? Ili Macho. And I,
Zezay Macho. And we are the Machos. Woo! That was a
good movie. We liked the movie. Only one word to
describe it. Fantastic. Zey, what time is it?
Clobbering time. You're darn right it's
clobbering time. Flame on! Hell yeah, it's
clobbering time! Although I gotta admit that due
to Scotty Camacho's answer, when we asked a
similar question regarding the Superman movie a
couple of weeks ago, not gonna lie, I thought his
son was gonna say it's clobbering time bitch just
for continuity. I was also anticipating that.
Although Johnny didn't say flame on in the movie.
Did he not? I don't remember. Yeah, I don't think he
did. That's fine because that was probably
another catchphrase from the cartoon too, you
know? Marvel hates catchphrases. Jerks. Thanks
for the fun answer, Gilly. You win this week's snow
prize. If you the listener want a shot at winning
Giro no prize, stay tuned to later on this episode
when we'll be asking another question of the week.
And now that that's done, on to the news. Okay, so
this past week was Comic-Con. And though Marvel
and DC didn't really have any kind of major movie
presence there, Peacemaker did have a panel to
which James Gunn showed up and revealed a new
official trailer for Peacemaker season two.
Peacemaker season one, which was a spin-off of
James Gunn's film, The Suicide Squad, was a really
good show. If you guys listen to our review, you'll
know that I really liked it. It was surprisingly
really heartfelt, as well as being freaking
hilarious. And it looks like season two is going to
be no different. Although now we have the gist of
the story in that Peacemaker is down and out in his
universe. And thanks to his father, he has portals
to other dimensions where he could go and find
better worlds to live in. It looks like Ric Flagg
Sr., the father of the man that Peacemaker killed
in The Suicide Squad film, doesn't like that. And
he wants to either shut down or confiscate
Peacemaker's portals. But it looks like it's
going to be good times. I love the cast of this show,
from Harcourt to Johnny Conomos, but my favorites
are definitely Adebio and Vigilante. Yeah,
they're fantastic. Does it seem like this season
is really setting up what the DC multiverse is and
how the DCU will compare to the DC EU? It kind of
seems that way, right? It almost seems like this
show is a way to bridge the gap between the DC EU and
the DCU, which is kind of strange because it's
coming out after the start of the DC EU. But
honestly, any kind of clarification is better
than none. And so like why some elements from the
DCU are the same, like John Cena as Peacemaker and
why some aren't. Like David Cornswet as Superman.
Right. I'm guessing in both dimensions though,
Peacemaker still killed Ric Flagg. Why would you
think that? Because otherwise the story would be
about Peacemaker escaping Ric Flagg senior
through an alternate dimension and then the
conflict is kind of just settled in that way. I
think there's something more to it. I don't know if
there's any more to it. What I think would be
hilarious is if it would kind of be like that one
Treehouse of Horror episode in The Simpsons,
where Homer Simpson messes with a toaster and ends
up traveling like through time and creating
different parallel worlds. And like each one has
something wrong with it. I kind of see that
happening here in a sense. Like in the end, though,
he kind of finally realizes maybe that his world is
best for him. Yeah. And then deal with the
consequences of his actions. Right. Exactly. The
portals to the other dimensions through these
doors, it reminds me a lot of the Shazam Rock of
Eternity. I wonder if they're going to make some
kind of tie into that considering the producer of
the Shazam films was Peter Saffron, who is also now
a producer on all of the DC Studios projects. But
we'll see. I loved the doorway to that like giant
skull spider dimension. And Tim Meadows just
looks at the other person is like, no, let's not go
there. That was good. There's a lot of really funny
moments like that, including the beginning of the
trailer when vigilante is like tossing beers to
economist and he just can't catch them. And then at
the very end, when vigilante is like, we're going
to my secret layer, you're not allowed to come to
his mom. And she just follows them and starts like
blabbing about how he thinks economists is a huge
dork, something like that. Season two is starting
up here soon on the redubbed HBO Max, no longer just
called Max. It's coming out to August 21st, and
we'll definitely be reviewing it. The trailer
definitely got me excited. I don't know if it was as
good as the first teaser, but this one definitely
got me intrigued as to what explanations could be
offered regarding this new DCU. In other DC news,
we got the first trailer for Aztec Batman Clash of
Empires, which is a direct video animated film
that's coming out in mid September. Now we've
known about this film coming out this year for a
while. And I've been looking forward to it,
particularly the animation style, because
apparently all of the animation was done in
Mexico. Oh, interesting. Yeah, in the same way
that the Batman ninja films were done all in Japan,
I do have to say I thought the art style would be
different, like a lot different than what we're
getting. I'm kind of disappointed by that. But the
premise seems intriguing, at least. It's sort of
like revisionist history, where the conquering
of the Aztec Empire by the Spanish conquistadors
leads to the creation of an Aztec Batman.
Apparently this Batman is named Yo-Haw-Li
Ko-Waddle, probably not the correct
pronunciation, and Cortez murders Maktuzuma in
front of him. So Yehwalee has to flee and train with
one of the Aztec priests in the Temple of the Bat
God, Sina Kang. It was interesting to see the Aztec
version of other characters like Catwoman and
Poison Ivy as well. Oh yeah, Catwoman is actually
going to be called Jaguar Woman, and I guess she was
like a female Jaguar warrior. It was interesting
that Poison Ivy was kind of like this forest
goddess, and that Cortez himself apparently is
going to be Two-Face. Yeah, it's a pretty cool
concept. I'm really wondering how many of these,
like, what-if scenarios DC is planning on putting
out for Batman, because we've had, you know,
Lovecraftian Batman, there's Ninja Batman, of
course, there was Steampunk Batman, a whole bunch
of different kinds of Batman. Now we have Aztec
Batman, what else does DC have in store, I wonder?
Well, I mean, Steampunk Batman and Lovecraft
Horror Batman, those are both based off of graphic
novels, but the Batman Ninja and Aztec Batman
projects are original. It's pretty interesting
to see where else they could take this for sure, and
that brings to our question of the week. If you
could reimagine a Marvel or DC superhero in an
ancient culture, what superhero and culture
would you choose? Yeah, this should be a fun one for
you guys. Just let us know, like, what the
character would be like, and how it would affect
their origin and or power set. Record your answer
at dynamicdool.com by clicking on the red
microphone button in the bottom right hand corner
of the screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long, and don't forget to leave your name in case we
include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a Dynamic
Duel No Prize that we'll post to Instagram. Be sure
to answer before August 2nd. But that does it for
all the news for this episode, so let's go ahead and
move into our main event where we review the latest
Marvel Studios film to hit theaters, The
Fantastic Four First Steps. Okay, The Fantastic
Four First Steps was directed by Matt Shackman and
stars Pedro Pascal, Vanessa Kirby, Ebon Moss,
Bach Rock, and Joseph Quinn. It is the start of
phase six in the Marvel Cinematic Universe, and
it's the second reboot of the franchise in as many
decades. The Fantastic Four have always kind of
struggled on the big screen with the earlier
entries under 20th Century Fox being okay to just
like fucking downright awful. And the big hurdle
that this latest iteration of the franchise had to
clear was giving fans and audiences an actual
worthwhile story. And in my mind, The Fantastic
Four First Steps movie just soared over that
hurdle and gave us not only a movie that's better
than previous attempts, but also one of the best
films that Marvel has ever put out, period. Yeah,
doing better than the past attempts was a low bar.
Yeah, totally soared over that, becoming my new
favorite Marvel Studios film of all time. And this
is coming right off of Thunderbolts, which was my
previous. They just keep getting better and
better and better. I don't know if it's my favorite
Marvel Studios film of all time, but it's
definitely one of my recent favorites. And I'd
probably put it like in the top five. And that's
pretty high praise considering the quality of
some of the movies that Marvel has put out. If you
haven't seen the film, that's really all you need
to know. Like what more recommendation do you need
to go out and see it? Like don't spoil this movie for
yourself by listening to this review. Go see the
film. There are some wonderful visual and
emotional moments in this movie that you don't
want to ruin the impact of by knowing what happens
beforehand. Just trust me. Go see the film, then
come back and listen to this review. Now,
Jonathan, you know that I've been a big Fantastic
Four fan for a long time and like it killed me to hear
other people over the years. Like even Marvel fans
say that they think the Fantastic Four are lame.
I'm always like, yeah, maybe they haven't had like
the cool factor of the X-Men or Spider-Man or the
Avengers and they never really had a good movie,
but they've always had kind of a soft spot in my
heart because they're the ones that really
revitalized Marvel comics back in the 1960s under
Stanley and Jack Kirby. Those early books really
captured the fantastical side of like science
fiction and had heartfelt character dynamics
that no other comic books at the time were really
doing. Yeah, honestly, I don't see how you can't
see the appeal of the Fantastic Four. I've always
thought they were interesting back when I liked
Marvel and even when they moved on to DC Comics,
they're really kind of the perfect team. Like
they're a more solid team in regards to not only
their personalities, but their powers than even a
lot of DC teams like the Justice League. Yeah, they
play well off each other and that's the big appeal.
Their books kind of tapered off for a long time, but
I think that Mark Waits work on them in their early
aughts and then Jonathan Hickman's run in the
2010s brought them right back to some of Marvel's
best comic book stories at the time. They're rich
characters, they go on amazing journeys and
because of that, I always knew that their
potential on the big screen was massive and I've
just been spending decades waiting for that to
manifest. And I'm thrilled to say that that
potential finally came to fruition. Like if you
see this movie and you don't like the Fantastic
Four still, I don't know what to say, there's no
hope for you because this really feels like the
quintessential Fantastic Four movie. Not only
did it tell the story of one of the team's greatest
adventures against the coming of Galactus, but it
also gave a spot on characterizations of the
heroes from the books and it captured the tone of
who the Fantastic Four are. And it also captured
the theme that has been with the Fantastic Four
since its inception that family is paramount and
it did it here in a really profound way, I thought.
For sure. Yeah, the Fantastic Four are a family.
They're not, you know, a cheesy band of one
dimensional cartoon characters like in the 2005
franchise and they're not like a reluctant
alliance of simple acquaintances and estranged
relatives like in the 2015 franchise. They're a
family in like the strongest sense of the word who
love and protect each other while exploring
what's beyond the unknown. And they're so
versatile, you know, like they can save Manhattan
like the Avengers, but they can also take a journey
to the edge of space like the Guardians of the
Galaxy. They can also travel past the edge of time
in reality like Doctor Strange. The fact that they
journeyed light years in this movie to talk to a
space god like it was a walk in the park, I think
really captured that whimsy from the books in a way
that made it seem like anything was possible. Oh,
absolutely. Yeah. The ambition of this film blew
my mind. Like it was much higher than I thought it
was going to be. It was almost like the same
reaction I had to the Pocket Dimension in the
Superman film. It was just very high concept and I
loved that. Yeah, I thought it was fascinating
that in the movie they were like, let's go talk to
this galactus guy. Tony Stark wasn't scanning
deep space for Chitauri energy signatures like
you probably should have after the first Avengers
film because he was too busy building the Ultron
program. And yeah, Tony Stark cracked time travel
via the Quantum Realm in Avengers Endgame, but
that kind of like out-of-the-box problem solving
was always more of the Fantastic Four's bread and
butter. I'm really glad that they captured that in
this movie. I think another thing that makes the
Fantastic Four as a team so appealing is the
emotional heart of their stories. Like as a
family, they just care about each other a little
bit more as families should. And so when they're in
danger, it hits a little bit harder because you're
going to have more at stake when you're fighting to
protect your sister or your father or whatever
close relative you have as opposed to fighting to
protect like a co-worker or something like that in
the case of the Avengers. And you know, every team
has interpersonal conflict, but when Riden Tsu
argue, it's more like your mom and dad are
fighting. It feels more personal. It's like a
whole new set of emotions with family. And I think
the Fantastic Four first steps nailed that
because I felt for these characters. Like when
Franklin was being born as they tried to escape the
gravity well, that was like such a beautiful
moment. And when Tsu fucking died, trying to save
her baby, holy shit, like I'm going to tear up again
just thinking about it. And I bawled my eyes out in
the theater when that happened. And I don't know if
it's just because I'm a father now and like
becoming a parent kind of rewires your emotions,
but I thought there was a lot to connect to in this
movie in terms of being a new parent. I don't think
any movie I've ever seen has nailed the anxiety of
having a newborn quite like this movie did or like
showing the vulnerability of being a new mom or the
strength that you muster when it comes to
protecting those you love. This movie just had
that in spades. Yeah, I mentioned that the film was
profound, not only in regards to how well it
captured the feeling of being a parent, but also
just in the notion that they were asked to give up
their only child to save humanity. It's almost
biblical in proportion. The stakes right off the
bat were so much larger, I think, than your
standard superhero fare and so much more
personal, so much more real. 100% the stakes in
this film is how you do stakes in film with
superheroes. Like honestly, watching this, I was
like, Superman should have done that. Like the
stakes shouldn't have been the city of Metropolis
being destroyed, but the world, because that's a
Superman level threat, in my opinion, and maybe
we'll get down that road in a sequel with like
Brainiac or something like that. And I guess I
shouldn't have been surprised that yes, the fate
of the world was in the Fantastic Four's hands
considering the villain was Galactus, but they
did such a good job of showing the reaction of the
people and what they expected of the Fantastic
Four and how much faith they put in this team that
yeah, it's like, how could you let all of these
people die? It was a true conundrum and they did it
really. Yeah, it was like a trolley problem, but
like on a global scale. Yeah, absolutely. You have
to appreciate a truly epic ethical dilemma like
this film, and I wish more superhero films had
something like this. Yeah, it's always neat when
the story is dive into the philosophical, right?
It's my favorite part of superhero media. I'll say
for as much as I connected with the characters in
this story, it took a while for me to get there
because the first act was entirely a montage.
Almost, yeah. The film really struggled to hook me
in the first act, actually to the point where I was
like concerned that I wasn't connecting at all
with the heroes, because it's all set up an
exposition and background for like a solid 30 to 40
minutes, I think, until the movie starts its
narrative flow and we settle into the actual story
right around the point that they venture into
space to confront Galactus. And that's when you
see the stakes beyond what's just being told to us.
And right after that, you know, we got the birth
scene and the press conference scene, and by then I
was like, okay, I'm in. And I really thought that
the second and third acts went a long way in saving
the film. Yet, narratively, the plotting of this
film is kind of strange because there's so much
that happens offscreen as it were. And then you
kind of get these cute little interludes in
between that with the family just kind of
reinforcing how much of a family they are. But
yeah, I would agree, the film definitely picked up
once they went to go seek Galactus. The first act to
montage was a much different way of introducing
audiences to this new universe than say the recent
Superman film, which began with like eight lines
of text on the screen and then dove right in. In the
end, I'm not sure what approach worked best
because Fantastic Four First Steps felt more
satisfying in terms of worldbuilding, but more
clunky in execution, where a Superman felt less
satisfying in terms of worldbuilding. But that
movie was able to get to the story right away. I
don't know what was the right approach, but either
way, I don't envy the writers of the film because
it's got to be so hard to get people to forget like
some of what they may know from previous franchise
versions of the characters, but still remember
some of the things like the origin. Reboots have
got to be so hard in terms of writing because it's
all just a delicate balancing act. Yeah, I mean, I
don't love the fact that we're kind of moving on
from origins because I personally love origin
stories. I would have loved to have seen them get
bombarded by cosmic radiation. I feel like that
whole thing was sorely missing from this film.
Well, I would have liked to have gotten a scene of
Superman being rocketed to earth from Krypton,
but we don't get origin stories anymore,
Jonathan. Fuck! Which, yeah, I agree. I don't like
that. But speaking of things that I did not like,
let's talk about Shalabal. If you've listened to
this podcast, you'll know that we were never
entirely sold on Shalabal, but like I held out hope
that this movie would actually have a good reason
for going with her instead of Norrin Rad, who is the
traditional silver surfer from the comic books.
And this movie never had a reason. The only reason
was to make Johnny Storm his kind of classic
playboy ladies man type character. And I don't
think that's a solid reason. No, I mean, because
they barely even touched upon that. Like she was a
real love interest for Johnny Storm. They should
have leaned more into that to make the gender swap
to Shalabal worth it. But then maybe they also
should have gone with Frankie Ray instead. You
know, the Herald known as Nova, who is
romantically tied to Johnny Storm in the comics.
And she still would have looked cool too, being
gold instead of silver. That's what I was thinking
the entire movie. I'm just going to imagine this is
Frankie. I mean, beyond the Johnny thing, it's
also possible that they were going for like a
motherly theme with the character of Shalabal to
draw a parallel between her sacrifice for Zenlau
and Sue's sacrifice. But I also think that you
could have played on that theme with Nora and Rad
just as well, just saying that, you know, as a
father, he sacrificed for his daughter and for his
planet. Right. So really, there was no good
reason. Marble definitely dropped the ball
there. And it doesn't really negatively affect
the movie so much as piss me off as a silver surfer
fan. I don't think fans are happy at all with the
fact that they went with Shalabal. And it sucks
because like as soon as Julia Garner was
announced, everybody was decrying the choice.
Like they knew better than to do this. And yeah,
Julia Garner was fine in the role, but it should
have been Nora and Rad. Because if and when we
finally do see him in Earth 616, he's going to feel
redundant, and his best story has already been
told. Yes, everything that we were afraid would
happen is going to. Right. And Julia Garner is a
good actress. I thought that was the main reason
why they wanted to work with her. Mm-hmm. But it's
not like she gave a fantastic performance here.
Like it was pretty by the book, I would say. It was
pretty hidden in the special effects, too.
Absolutely. Yeah, the best parts of the Silver
Surfer were seeing her surf different things,
whether it's like a wormhole or a lava wave. Yeah. I
loved seeing that. I loved what they did with the
special effects here. Just it could have been
Noren. Right. Imagine how cool it would have been
if it was. Well, I feel like I would have connected
with the character more just because I know him
from the comic books. You know, Shalabal was the
Silver Surfer for all of a few panels in the Earth-X
graphic novel. But you know, I don't think that's
enough precedent to give the character the
spotlight in a whole movie. But where they went
wrong with the Silver Surfer, I am happy to say that
they finally went right with Galactus. Like he's
not a cloud this time for sure, but we'll
definitely talk more about Galactus in our
character breakdown. So let's dive into that,
starting with Mr. Fantastic, aka Reed Richards,
played by Pedro Pascal. Prior to seeing the movie,
I was never fully sold on Pedro Pascal as Reed
Richards. Like, I knew he'd do fine because he's a
great actor with a general affability that makes
him likable in any role he's in. But mostly, I
thought John Krasinski, you know, who played Reed
Richards and Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of
Madness, and his wife Emily Blunt would have
crushed these roles without breaking a sweat. And
I really hope they're fucking kicking themselves
right now, because Fantastic Four first steps
gave Reed and Sue their greatest arcs yet as they
stepped into the world of parenthood. And yeah,
Pedro Pascal did great. You know, he's an
inoffensive actor who I think is mostly
believable as the world's greatest mind. But
where I think he really shined in this movie was in
his performance of parenthood anxiety. You know,
as he mentions in this film, his mind is constantly
running through worst-case scenarios in order to
be prepared to handle them. And when you're the
father of a potentially genetically altered
infant on the world stage where you have multiple
enemies and even more responsibilities, yeah,
there's a lot to worry about. And Pedro Pascal's
performance was full of subtleties. Like, it was
really easy to pick up on his internal struggles as
he dealt with the things around him. Yeah, I could
have said that better myself. And I think it wasn't
just parental anxiety. I think he's probably
suffered from that for a long time. It was almost
like an OCD level of intrusive thoughts of
worrying about the worst and just needing
obsessively to find a way to solve that. They
captured Reed in this film so much better than any
other films. It's embarrassing. And this is the
way the character should have always been. It's a
fantastic take. For sure. It was interesting,
like, as you could tell just by looking at him, that
he knew that the ethical action from, like, a
utilitarian perspective would be to hand over his
only child. But, like, what's great is that Reed is
too smart to be bound by such limitations. And I
love how he was always able to think of a solution
and adapt to the problem at hand. Whether it was
sucking Silver Surfer down a gravity well or
teleporting the earth or, you know, getting
Galactus to walk into a teleporter. He just always
had a solution and that felt very true to character
to me. Yeah, this is the first time I feel like we've
seen Mr. Fantastic as a genius over prior films,
because I never really got that sense. He was made
up like BS junk science, but like, oh, techie on
pulse and stupid stuff like that. But here he was
actually coming up with solutions to problems
that we understood. Yeah, they made sense. You
could see his thought process. He didn't try to
flash freeze Galactus by having Johnny goes
supernova and then break a fire hydrant and squirt
him with water like chemistry 101 stuff in the 2005
Fantastic Four movie. What happens when you super
cool molten metal? One thing that the 2005 movie
did get right, though, was the suits. I think I
don't love the suits in Fantastic Four first
steps. I don't love the color. I don't love the
material. I don't love the inconsistency in their
uniforms. I know that the film is set in the 1960s
and these outfits are like for sure better than
like Adam West's spandex that we saw superheroes
wear in the 1960s. But I do think that there was a
better solution to keep the outfits in the time
period and still not make them look like cotton
sweatsuits. Yeah, seeing Mr. Fantastic suit rip.
I was like, no, yeah, that shouldn't happen. No,
yeah, it's supposed to be unstable molecules. Why
is it ripping like a cotton sweater would? That was
definitely a gripe I had with the movie. And that
pertains to all the members of the Fantastic Four,
including Invisible Woman, a.k .a. Sue Storm
Richards, played by Vanessa Kirby. Dude, Vanessa
Kirby fucking cooked in this role and she ate. She
cooked and then she ate what she cooked. She was
such a good Sue Storm. I don't think I've ever seen
Vanessa Kirby in anything else. Like I knew her
name when she was cast and was generally pleased
with the casting. But I didn't like know that she
would fucking embody the character of Invisible
Woman as much as she did. Yeah, I'd seen her in The
Crown. The television series. And it was a
completely different performance. She's a
really talented actress. I thought she nailed the
emotional strength of Sue, who really is the glue
that binds the team together. I thought she
perfectly encapsulated the power and the grace
and the beauty, but also the vulnerability that
comes with being a new mother and how moms will
fucking pull up when they think their kid is in
danger. Yeah, she got pretty aggressive at times,
especially with Reed. Actually, I was sitting
next to a lady in the movie theater when I went to see
the movie and I heard her lean over to her partner
and say, wow, she's kind of a bitch. That lady could
fuck off because like Reed is pulled in a million
different directions, you know, with his
anxiety, you know, always thinking of the worst
case scenario, all these responsibilities. Sue
is the one that really is always focused on what
truly matters. And that's always been an
interesting dynamic in their relationship and
the comic books. You know, they don't have a
relationship where they never argue, but they do
have a perfect compliment in each other. Yeah,
that was clearly evident in this film. I love what
they did with her speech in front of the crowd
because I was with Reed. I was like, I mean, I think
you kind of should ethically give up the kid. And I
couldn't understand like where she was coming
from in regards to her not wanting to do that or
feeling like she just was refusing to do it. And I
was like, come on, be reasonable. But her speech
sold me in the same way that I think it sold
everyone. Yeah, I mean, like she didn't give a fuck
about utilitarian ethics. She knew that there was
no way she was even considering handing over her
son. And to the rest of the world, yeah, that may
have seemed selfish, but I do think she said it best
when she said, I will not sacrifice my son for this
world, but I will not sacrifice this world for my
son. You know, she had faith in her family that I
thought was on spiring. And, you know, her
willingness to sacrifice for that family was tear
jerking. Like I was just amazed by this
characterization of Sue. Yeah, ultimately, she
wasn't willing to sacrifice her child, but she was
willing to sacrifice herself. You know, there's
few things sadder in this world than seeing a baby
cry over his dead mom. And yeah, my eyeballs were
really leaking during that last scene,
especially with the wonderful acting
performance of Petra Pascal. Yeah, and Johnny.
Yeah. The thing I'm not so sure about because it was
hard to tell what his emotions were. But let's go
ahead and talk about the thing, a.k .a. Ben Grimm
played by Ebon Moss Bachrock. Ebon Moss Bachrock
was in this movie. Don't get me wrong, I like the
guy. I also thought he was a great micro in the
Punisher series as well. But his approach to Ben
Grimm in this movie was so low key that it bordered
on almost generic. Like the special effects, of
course, did a lot of the heavy lifting, but it was so
hard to see Ebon's performance behind the special
effects. Even in those quiet moments where you see
Ben's internal struggle in his eyes. I actually
think he needed to go a little bit bigger with his
acting to actually have it come through Ben's
rocky exterior. Yeah, he should have been more
what's the word I'm looking for? Gruff, I guess.
Yeah, I would agree that I did not see his
performance in the role in the same way that you see
Mark Ruffalo's performance in the Hulk or even saw
Michael Chickless's performance in his
interpretation of the thing. Yeah, I mean, the
character design was great. But as it was, you
would barely even know the guy had an arc. You know,
basically it was that he felt closed off from the
world. And as everything came under threat, he got
the push he needed to open up and reconnect with the
world around him, specifically through the
Jewish day school teacher, Natasha Leon's
character. And think is a deep character. You
know, this whole arc is a far cry from the this man,
this monster story in the comic books where he's
like in full self pity mode. And that just makes me
hope that Eben has more to do with the thing in
future installments. Yeah, this version of the
thing definitely feels like a psychologically
healed version of the thing. Yeah, like they
didn't really delve into the self pity that the
character is known for. Right. So you kind of lost
the tragedy of the thing, which I thought has
always been the most interesting thing about the
character. Yeah, I mean, they kind of touched upon
it. And like you saw more of Reed dealing with his
guilt regarding Ben's appearance, then you saw
Ben worry about his own appearance. You know, that
was a little bit weird. It was like Ben reassuring
Reed about the situation. Usually it's the other
way around. I said that the character design was
great, but I do have to ask what the fuck was up with
the thing's beard? Like, is that something I'm
just going to have to get used to now? Because fuck
that. It wasn't just the beard. He was growing hair
on his head. And I was like, why is this necessary? I
don't know. Like he grew it because of the world
energy conservation efforts for the
teleportation machines, but like those efforts
were just temporary. Right. Like, did he end up
keeping the beard just because Johnny said it
looked good? And like, was Johnny fucking with him
when he said that? And if so, where was the payoff
where he made fun of him for keeping the beard? I
have so many questions when it comes to the thing
manscaping and none of them are fun to ask. And all I
know is that the beard has got to fucking go. I was so
disappointed that he didn't have his classic look
for the film's climax or even by the film's end.
Yeah, I guess the beard is going to have to carry
over into Avengers Doomsday, which better not.
Yeah, it better not. I'm convinced that the thing
should never grow rock hair. Like that's just not a
thing that should happen. Weird choice for sure.
Let's go ahead and move on to the human torch, aka
Johnny Storm, played by Joseph Quinn. I thought
Joseph Quinn was a solid Johnny Storm, but more
than his performance, I appreciated the
characterization of Johnny here. Like, sure, it
wasn't as funny as Chris Evans' role, but it did
feel more real. Like Johnny is a ladies man in the
comic books, but I wouldn't say that's his
defining trait. Like to me, Johnny was always an
adventurous, immature, mechanic with his heart
always in the right place who could just never
really settle down. I think they captured most of
that in this movie. And Joseph Quinn seemed
entirely capable of taking on even more
substantial work in the future if the story calls
for it. They definitely made him smarter in this
film than he has been depicted in past films, and it
kind of makes sense because Reed was saying, you
know, I'm going up into space with the smartest
people I know. And if they didn't make him smart,
I'd be questioning why Johnny was a part of that
team. Yeah, they made him maybe a little bit too
smart because I could understand Johnny being a
skilled mechanic, but I can't understand him
being a skilled Xenolinguist. Right. That just
made no sense to me. But his attempt to connect with
the Silver Surfer did lead to a change of heart that
ultimately saved the day. And that was a good
culmination of his arc in that he was yearning for
adventure. You know, he was wanting to go back into
space, trying to get new spacesuits made and
looking into outer space transmission
recordings. I think the Silver Surfer really
filled that void that he had at the start. And maybe
that's why he was so motivated to get to know her
language. Right. Yeah. I think that was pretty
explicit that he wanted to get to learn her
language because he was attracted to her. You
know, it was just his driving force, I think. On a
small note, I'll say that Joseph Queen does look
more like Invisible Woman's brother more than any
of the previous film adaptations. I know like they
had Kate Mara be adopted in the Fantaphore stick
movie, but I didn't think Chris Evans looked
anything like Jessica Alba. I could kind of see
where Joseph Queen could resemble Vanessa Kirby.
I could kind of see where Joseph Queen resembles
Robert Danny, Jr. What? Yeah, I heard someone say
that he looked like the splitting image of Robert
Danny, Jr. when he was younger. And when I was
watching the film, I actually couldn't unsee it.
Like even with his mannerisms, it's pretty spot
on. Never say that out loud again. Like I don't want
to get stuck with that in my head. It's it's true.
Like if they were ever going to recast Tony Stark,
maybe like DHM, Joseph Queen would have made a good
one. You would have, but he can't know. Hey, it's
the multiverse. Anything is possible. Yeah,
which is not always a good thing. Let's go ahead and
move on to Galactus, who was played by Ralph
Inneson. There's not too much to discuss here
regarding Guinness's performance because it was
largely hidden under the special effects and that
helmet. But I got to say that the design of Galactus
was inspired. He looked so damn cool in this movie.
Like why did they ever make him a cloud in the Fox
films? Because the creative potential to render
this space God on the screen visually is such a
great opportunity and they totally seized on it in
this film. He looked badass like when his eyes
would light up and stuff like that. Oh, it was so
good. It was perfect. It was absolute sheer
perfection. And I really wish we would have seen
this version of Galactus before we saw like any
celestials. Yeah, that's interesting regarding
the celestials because, you know, this movie
never touched on why Galactus hungers for
planets. In the comic books, it's insinuated that
he eats planets as part of some universal balance.
And in Earth X, they explained that the celestials
would seed life on planets as a means to protect the
celestial embryo growing at the core and that
Galactus served as a sort of check on the celestial
population. And considering that they did
address that there was a celestial growing inside
of Earth 616 in the Eternals movie, I thought it
would have been interesting if they addressed
Galactus's cosmic purpose here. I'm honestly
really hoping that Reed accidentally teleported
Galactus to the 616 universe, although I guess
that would mean Silver Surfer went with him. Never
mind, I take it back. I just hope eventually we get
to see Galactus again one day. That would be cool
for sure. I do want to touch on one other character
real quick. I'm going to state it right off the bat.
I don't like Herbie. I thought he was annoying in
the movie. Is it because I said crypto was
annoying? Like every time he was not on screen, I
was really off. Herbie was a total scene stealer,
but like in the wrong way. You just got to get over
the fact that crypto sucks and that I hate him.
Don't take it out on Herbie. It's totally innocent
in this situation. I also hate Herbie. How does
that feel? No one does. No one does. It would feel
bad if I believed you, but I don't. Let's go ahead
and move into our story highlights. In a world
where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
Dynamite Podcast Network presents Consul
Combat, where video game legends brawl every
Monday. Dynamic Duel, where comic book titans
smash every Tuesday. Max Destruction, where TV
and action heroes battle every Wednesday. And
Sendro World, where anime champions clash every
Thursday. Join us as we speculate on the matches
and armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge
victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com where we
settle the debate and settle the score. In 1964, on
Earth 828, Reed Richards and Sue Storm learned
their pregnant on the fourth anniversary of the
day they were bombarded by cosmic rays while on a
mission in space. The world celebrates them and
Ben Grimm and Johnny Storm as superheroes and
recounts their efforts protecting the planet
from villains such as the Red Ghost, and their
diplomatic efforts such as garnering federal
rights for the Mole Man and Subterranean. That
night, during their weekly dinner, Reed and Sue
reveal the pregnancy to Ben and Johnny, and the
four begin preparing for the baby's arrival over
the next few months. Reed conducts tests on Sue to
determine if their cosmically altered DNA has
affected the baby. He also meets with Johnny
regarding their suit designs while testing a
teleportation machine and recording deep space
transmissions. The robot assistant Herbie
baby-proofs the house while Ben meets a friendly
teacher at a Jewish day school. One night before
dinner, the Silver Surfer arrives to herald the
coming of Galactus who will soon devour the Earth.
Reed tracks the Surfer's energy signature to the
disappearance of a half a dozen planets, and the
team decides to meet Galactus in space. Now that
was a lot, but that was all mostly told in montage.
Dude, yeah, that was way too much. That was like the
whole first third of this movie. There was a lot to
get through. Interestingly, a lot of little
tidbits and Easter eggs thrown into the montage,
like references to Red Ghost and Mole Man. We got to
see the team fight Giganto as their very first
villain, which was true to the comic books, as we
can all see on the very first cover to the very first
issue of The Fantastic Four. Which is a total
ripoff of Justice League of America number one. I
just want to say that. There were a lot of nice
touches here, I thought. Like the Future
Foundation, which is like their philanthropic
science foundation in the comic books, but here
they made it more like a diplomatic type
organization. So they were affecting the planet,
not just through their super heroics and their
inventions, but also through like politics. It
was all pretty interesting. Yeah, Sue was pretty
much a politician in this film the way it came
across. She was like a UN ambassador. Well, yeah,
that's what it seemed like the Future Foundation
was to me, was the UN. And it almost seemed like The
Fantastic Four were the head of the UN. Not the
head, because that one lady was the CEO, but they
definitely helped facilitate it. And like
apparently the country of Latveria never showed
up to their gatherings, which I thought was like a
funny little Easter egg too. Well, it just made me
wonder where Dr. Doom was during this whole thing.
Like, I don't think he would have been OK with The
Fantastic Four's actions in this film. Like, if
anyone would have had an issue with The Fantastic
Four willing to sacrifice, essentially, the
entire planet for their son, it would have been Dr.
Doom. Well, if I had to play devil's advocate,
knowing the character of Dr. Doom, he probably
would have been mostly focused on why Galactus
would want their baby, which was a question that
the rest of the world wasn't really asking. Yeah,
not even read and sue themselves. Well, they
didn't know. But Doom would have definitely put
his resources to work on figuring out why and then
probably just try to steal the kid for himself or
usurp his power. And I think that's exactly what's
going on in the midcredits scene of this movie.
That's fair. What did you think of the way they did
the Mole Man? Like, it wasn't really Mole
Creatures. It was like under grand construction
workers. Don't get me started on Mole Man. I hated
Mole Man in this movie. What really annoyed me was
that when he was on screen, a lot of people in the
theater were laughing, even though I didn't think
he was doing anything funny. Like, I always
thought the perfect Mole Man actor would be like
Danny DeVito or something. I always thought Mole
Man should be wearing rags and not really be well
dressed and wearing gold rings and stuff like
that. It was a very different take on the character
that I wasn't entirely pleased with. Yeah, I
suspected it as much. I don't really care too much
about the character, but I'm not surprised that
fans of the comic didn't care for the
interpretation. Some might. I don't know. To me,
Mole Man is just a very different character from
the books that I read him in. Red Ghost was in the
movie, though, for a little bit. Originally, he
was played by John Malkovich, but they cut him out
of the film and then they just got some random guy or
maybe he was a CGI creation. I don't know. I thought
that was a little weird. I knew that Natasha Leone
was going to be in this movie. I wasn't sure who she
was going to play. I thought maybe she was going to
be, I don't know, some kind of gender swapped
villain or something like that. But I was
surprised that she wasn't Alicia Masters. She was
like this random original character to the movie
who taught at a Jewish day school and seemed to be
romantically interested in the thing. I don't
know really what was behind her character. Yeah, I
don't really think any of that was needed in the
movie. It was really just a way to give more screen
time to the thing, I think. I think so. They needed
to give him something to do. So they had him like go
on these frequent walks through Yancy Street.
Back to the story. Venturing through a wormhole
device, the Fantastic Four followed the surfer's
energy signature to a distant planet and
witnessed its destruction. Pulled into
Galactus' ship via a tractor beam, the team learns
that Galactus is a cosmic being who feeds on the
life force of planets but is willing to spare Earth
in exchange for Reed and Sue's son, sensing
immense power within him and believing he can
transfer his hunger into the boy. He induces Sue to
go into labor as the team escapes back into the ship
with the silver surfer in pursuit. They
temporarily lose her in the gravity of a neutron
star as Sue gives birth to baby Franklin and they
return home. There are a lot of terrifying scenes
in the sequence, which was a fantastic sequence.
Like when the scanner was going across the ship and
then settled on Sue's belly, I was like, oh, crap.
Yeah. And then seeing the planet explode and stuff
like that. That was incredible. That was insane.
The scale of that planet exploding with this drill
coming out of it did such a good job of setting the
stakes of what could happen to Earth. The team lost
their minds. They were like, what the fuck? I
thought that was great. I also thought the silver
surfer was a really effective villain in this
scene when she was chasing their light speed ship.
You know, they thought they lost her by going into
the wormhole. But then all of a sudden she went into
the wormhole. I remember my wife was like, holy
shit. When she saw that because she doesn't really
know that the silver surfer can traverse the
galaxy at light speed. But yeah, that whole thing
was a lot of fun. Yeah, she was like Michael Myers.
There's just no stopping her, no escaping her. She
was like the terminator. She was like T1000. Oh,
yeah. Yeah, exactly. Although I have to say I was
really confused what happened near that black
hole because she was like chasing the ship and then
she like saw the ship get destroyed or something.
And then it turns out that wasn't true. How did that
happen? They turned the ship invisible and had her
follow the light speed engine portion to the point
where she got too close to the gravity well. So that
was all Sue's doing. OK, she saw the light speed
engine. Wait, didn't they need that to get back to
Earth? They were still able to approach near light
speed with their ship without the assistance of
the external engine. OK, makes sense. I guess so.
The scene where Sue gave birth to Franklin was so
tense. I don't know, it just felt very real. And it
kind of reminded me of like the tension that I felt
in the delivery room when my wife was giving birth
to our daughter. Yeah, I loved it when Sue was like,
Johnny, killer. Yeah, that was nuts. Back to the
story. After revealing the situation to the
press, the public turns against the team
believing they should give up their baby to
protect the planet. The Fantastic Four work on
finding a solution to stop Galactus and read in Sue
argue over potentially handing over their child.
Sue reinstills public trust by ensuring they will
move heaven and earth to protect the planet, which
inspires Reed to use his teleportation device to
relocate Earth and the team rallies the world to
build teleportation towers across the globe.
However, those towers are destroyed just upon
activation by the Silver Surfer who returns to the
planet. Johnny stops her from wrecking the final
tower in Times Square by playing for her the cries
of destroyed planets from Reed's deep space
transmission recordings, having deciphered the
Zen law language. Johnny reveals he knows of
Shalabal's sacrifice to protect her planet and
pleads for her help in stopping Galactus as she
flees in anguish. I was really surprised how
honest Reed was with the world. Like, he didn't
have to tell them everything that happened, like
how Galactus wanted their son. Yeah, I think it
would be entirely reasonable for someone to
withhold that information from the earth. Yeah,
and I don't know why he told the truth. I guess he's
just a really good guy or maybe it just slipped out.
I don't know. But yeah, I probably would have kept
that to myself. I'm no Reed Richards, though.
Moving back to the story, now planning to lure
Galactus into the final teleporter using
Franklin as bait, the team relocates Manhattan to
subterrania with help from the Mole Man. When
Galactus arrives, he avoids their trap and
snatches the baby from the Baxter building. Sue
uses her powers in an attempt to push Galactus into
the tower and succeeds with help from the thing
knocking down a building. Reed rescues the baby
from Galactus's grasp, though the cosmic being
proves too powerful to be held in the portal. As
Johnny prepares to sacrifice himself to push
Galactus back in, the Silver Surfer arrives and
knocks her master into the beam, teleporting them
both to the edge of the universe. Sue collapses and
dies from her efforts. However, baby Franklin
revives her with his awakened cosmic powers when
placed on her chest. I got to say, power scale wise,
I was a little miffed that Sue was so successful in
pushing Galactus, which I don't think she should
ever really be able to do. She's not that strong.
She definitely had like mom power going for her
within this climax. But I do think that the script
was able to rectify that situation by, you know,
having her die from her efforts. That kind of
seemed to make it a little bit more OK from a power
scaling perspective. I did question why everyone
needed to go to subterranean when they could have
just left the city like they did in Metropolis in
the Superman movie. I guess that's true. Yeah,
they could have just traveled to Jersey, you know,
Manhattan has a big population, but there's
plenty of bridges to go elsewhere. Boats, I don't
think they necessarily needed to go underground.
That almost seemed more dangerous. Like I'm
pretty sure Galactus is heavy enough to crush some
tunnels. I don't know that New York bedrock
supposedly pretty sturdy. I was actually shocked
when Sue died because I didn't see how they were
going to resurrect her and I was like, wait, what is
Sue actually going to die? For some reason, I
didn't make the connection to Franklin's reality
warping powers being given her back. Yeah, my
first thought was, oh, maybe they're going to have
a multiversal Sue join the team later. But then
once the baby entered the frame, I was like, OK,
yeah, he's going to bring his mom back. It was just a
beautiful moment. Yeah, great climax, great
stakes again. This film had so many surprises. I
was so happy with it by the end. Back to the story.
The team is celebrated for their victory and rides
off for another adventure in their fantastic car
with Franklin along with them in a car seat. Four
years later in 1968, Sue finds Dr. Doom holding
Franklin in an after credit scene. We see the
opening to the fantastic fours in universe
cartoon. I loved the kind of three man and a baby
approach they took to getting the car seat in the
fantastic car with Ben, Johnny and Reed all trying
to do it. I thought that was really funny. Those
things are not easy to get in. They are not. They are
complex pieces of engineering. Let me tell you
that. So I had a good chuckle at that. But like I felt
like the air leave my lungs during the mid credit
scene when Sue returned back to see Franklin and
there was this green hooded figure holding him.
There was such a good cliffhanger and tease for
what's to come. Yeah, it looks like Franklin got to
take a peek at Dr. Doom's real face. He's like, oh,
you look just like my uncle. No, he would never say
that. He would never say that. It wouldn't even
enter his mind. It is interesting to see how
Franklin would play into Dr. Dooms plans. I think
they're going to substitute the beyonders from
the comic books with Franklin Richards. I think
he's going to be the catalyst for Dr. Dooms
universal reality warping that ends the
incursions and forms battle world. That's my
theory. One nitpicky sticking point I had during
the mid credit scene, though, was that Herbie
offered the origin of species by Darwin as
potential reading for Franklin Richards. But
Franklin Richards has never been particularly
bright. You know, he's just a normal kid. It's his
sister, Valeria Richards. That's the prodigy.
And I immediately became concerned that they were
going to combine the characters of Franklin and
Valeria and make Franklin a prodigy like his
father. Well, hey, if Johnny could decipher alien
languages, Franklin can freaking read origin of
species. Whatever. All right. Everyone's a
genius. Did you like the end credit scene? No, I
mean, it was a waste of time. It was not more so than
like the Superman end credit scene. But the song
was OK. It wasn't anything special. The score as a
whole was special. Yeah, the music was good in this
film. I'm going to disagree with you about the
Superman end credits scene because you're
completely wrong. Hearing Superman saying, man,
I could be such a jerk sometimes. Just showed how
humble he was. No, that was stupid. Way to turn the
conversation towards Superman and your
Fantastic Four review. Yeah. And how it's
inferior is what I'm doing, because Fantastic
Four was definitely the better movie. It had
everything really that I ever wanted from a
Fantastic Four film, even beyond the retro
visuals and the cast chemistry. I thought the film
most importantly leaned into the emotional core
of the story, which is the team's familial bond,
and it did it with sincerity and real stakes. I'm
going to rate the film four and a half stars out of
five. A fresh rating on Rotten Tomatoes. Yeah,
I'll agree with that. I really enjoyed this film a
lot more than I wanted to. I went to this wanting to
really dislike this movie and just I just wanted to
trash on it and be like, oh, Superman is so much
better. I can't really say that. I enjoyed both of
the movies immensely. It is kind of refreshing to
have a series of superhero movies that really
focuses more on like hope and the lighthearted
nature of these stories. There's a lot of
parallels between the Fantastic Four and
Superman. And I think it's signaling that people
are kind of over the sort of cynical cloud that has
been permeating society, I feel like, for a good
long while now. Yeah, I wonder if we're maybe past
the whole dark era of superhero films. These two
films, Superman and Fantastic Four First Steps.
One of the things I like most about them is their
messages, like you mentioned, being kind, family
is paramount. Those are great messages to hear
from superheroes. And the Thunderbolts, too, you
know, they're like, don't do meth. Group hug,
everyone. Let's do it. Like everyone. I don't know
what Captain America Brave New World's message
was, but maybe that's why it's been the weakest out
of the superhero films released this year so far.
It's still a decent movie, though. Go listen to
that review if you haven't already. But that does
it for this review. AJ and IK help close us out.
Thanks for listening to Dynamic Jewel. Visit the
show's website at dynamicjewel.com and follow us
on Instagram at Dynamic Jewel podcast. You can
support the show on Patreon at patreon.com slash
dynamicjewel and joining a tier that works for you
or by rating and reviewing Dynamic Jewel on Apple
podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser or on our website.
Don't forget to listen to the other shows in the
Dynamite podcast network, including Max
Destruction, Senjo World and Console Combat. Our
next episode is going to be another review. We are
going to talk about Sandman Season 2. Now, Season 1
of Sandman was killer. Season 2, I'm almost
certain, will be uncomfortable to watch due to the
Neil Gaiman revelations that have come out
between the seasons. I'm not even thinking about
that as I'm watching it. I'm actually really
loving Season 2. I'm only halfway through it, but
damn, it is so good. I'm just taking the time to
relish each and every episode because I know I'm
going to be frigging heartbroken when it's over.
Yeah, I got to binge it. I'm just going to I'm just
going to speed watch it while also being on my
phone. I'll slap that phone out of your hands and
then slap you right in the face. But that does it for
this episode, guys. We want to give a big thanks to
our executive producers, John Straussky,
Zachary Hepburn, Destin Balcom, Miggy
Mathen-Geehan, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yatyn,
Austin Wazalowski, AJ Dunkerly, Nick Obanto,
Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Spees, Dean
Maleski, Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, Josh
Leiner, Mike Williams, Oscar Galvez and Paul
Graves for helping make this podcast possible.
And we'll talk to you guys next week. Up, up and
away. True believers. I'm going to run the stats on
a Gary versus Herbie fight.