This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi, welcome to
the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin
brother, Marvelous Joe. And in this episode, as a
tie-in to the upcoming Superman film that's
coming out in less than a month, we are pitting the
Green Lantern Guy Gardner against Gorr the God
Butcher. Now, you may remember Gorr from the
terrible movie, Thor, Love and Thunder, and
you'll be seeing Guy in the Superman movie, which
is why this is a tie-in. The equally terrible
Superman movie you forgot to say. Oh, it's going to
be amazing, dude. It's going to suck. I'm just
putting that out there. It's not even going to be
comparable to Thor, Love and Thunder. It's going
to be infinitely better because that was like the
worst thing Marvel's ever put out. One of the worst
things for sure. Christian Bale definitely
deserved better. But yeah, this will be an
interesting one. I kind of feel bad for Guy Gardner
because I think he's going to get the shit kicked
out of him by Gorr. I just don't see any other way
this fight's going to go down. I just realized this
is kind of a similar battle to what we did with our
White Lantern versus Null episode. Yeah, except
the characters of Null and White Lantern are much
more powerful than Guy Gardner and Gorr. Okay,
cool. It's a lesser episode of that then. Sweet.
Pretty much. Well, I'm still looking forward to
it. I know there's a lot of Guy Gardner fans out
there. I don't really think there's any Gorr fans,
but we're going to find out who's going to win
between the two characters later on in this
episode. I'm a Gorr fan. You would be gross. Before
we get into the battle, we're going to break down
the comic book movie news from the past week of
which we got quite a few news items. We learned that
John Berndtall's Punisher is going to join the
fourth Spider-Man movie, Brand New Day. Clayface
was cast in this film, and we got the official
trailer for Sandman Season 2. As always, we list
our segment times in our episode description, so
feel free to check out the show notes if you want to
skip ahead to a particular topic. Our
artificially intelligent dual simulator, AJ9K,
has a quick message for our listeners, though, so
listen up. The Dynamic 2.0 tier gives you access to
our Discord chat server, the Fantastic Four tier
gives you two bonus episodes each month, and the
X-Force tier makes you an executive producer of
this show. Lastly, the Diner Mike podcast network
tier lets you create your own podcast using this
Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe will help
you develop your show, provide graphic support
and consultation, and get you simulation
results. Pitch the twins your ideas via email at
dynamicdualpodcast at gmail.com. Check it out at
patreon.com. Thanks, AJ9K, and thanks to
everyone who supports the podcast. Guys, be sure
to tune in to the other shows and the Dynamite
podcast network this week, including the console
combat podcast, where hosts John and Dean
simulate battles between popular video game
characters. In yesterday's episode, they rebued
Kingsglaive Final Fantasy XV. Over on the Max
Destruction podcast, hosts Scotty and Gilly pit
your favorite action heroes from film and
television against each other. This week, the
brothers are pitting the White Ranger and his
Tiger's Orde against Servo from the Superhuman
Samurai Cyber Squad. And on the Send Joe World
podcast, host Zachary Hepburn speculates on
fights between fan favorite anime and manga
characters. In his next episode, Zach is going to
review K-pop demon hunters on Netflix. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our show
notes to listen to all of the shows in the Dynamite
podcast network. But with that out of the way,
click to the No Prize. A No Prize is an award that
Marvel used to give out to fans. Our version, the
Dynamic Dual No Prize, is a digital award we post on
Instagram for the person that we feel gave the best
answer to our question of the week. Last week, we
asked you guys, what has been your favorite
Superman moment from past films or television
series and why? We got five answers this week.
We're going to break down our three honorable
mentions before revealing the week's No Prize
winner. Our first honorable mention goes to
Travis Herndon, who said, What's up, dynamic
dudes? Travis here. Shout out to my evil twin. So my
choice would be from the movie Superman vs. the
Elite, the instant lobotomy. That scene was just
straight up badass because one, we never seen Heat
Vision use that small to go through somebody's eye
and like fuck up their powers and stuff to
eternally without them knowing. So to me, instant
lobotomy is the best Superman moment for me. Hands
down. Yeah, so Superman vs. the Elite was a
direct-to-video animated film based off of
Action Comics 775, which was titled What's So
Funny about Truth, Justice, and the American Way.
In which Superman goes up against a group of
anti-heroes known as the Elite, who kind of try and
make Superman seem like he's obsolete. And when he
turns their bad guy rules against them, he kind of
shows them that, hey, you're lucky I don't play in a
moral gray area like you guys do. One of the things
he did, of course, was take away the powers of the
leader, Manchester Black. And he did it in the most
like badass way. Yeah, it was kind of an ethically
shaky action on behalf of Superman, right? I
agree. Because what he did is he combined his X-ray
vision with his microscopic vision, slash
telescopic vision, I think, and his Heat Vision.
You think that he could do this all the time against
other villains. I'm not sure why he doesn't, I
guess because it's a morally shaky action. But
it's definitely an interesting feat for the
character. I remember reading one JLA comic book
issue where Marshall Manhunter linked the minds
of Superman and the Flash, and the Flash was
telepathically able to see through Superman's
X-ray vision. And then he phased into a guy's head
to do a similar effect where he messed with his
brain to remove his superpowers. And then, of
course, we also have the identity crisis arc,
which was all about the Justice League performing
brain surgery on villains to make him less evil.
It's such a bizarre use of superpowers that has
been kind of a recurring motif among DC
superheroes. Yeah, it's kind of like clockwork
orange in a way where it's like, can you force
people to be moral? And it is not ethically sound, I
would say. But of course, in the Justice League
versus the Elite storyline, the effects were
temporary. Like Superman made Manchester Black
think that he killed all of his allies when he
really didn't. So he was just kind of giving them a
taste of what it would be like if he was evil. It's a
great storyline, great movie. Definitely
recommend it to anyone who has not yet seen it,
though I just spoiled it all for you. Sorry, guys.
See it in action. Don't just take Jonathan's word
for it. Right, exactly. Great answer, Travis. Our
next honorable mention goes to Cyrus Moore. Who
said? Hey guys, Cyrus Moore here. I think the best
Superman moments happen to be in the movie The
Death of Superman. I think it's got some of the best
fight scenes with Doomsday. And I just, I think
it's the best Superman movie personally. It's
probably one of the saddest, but it was also great
to see Superman save Lois Lane in the Doomsday
fight. So yeah, we reviewed The Death of Superman
on this podcast when it came out. It was a fantastic
animated film. It was like part one of a two part
film that also included Reign of the Superman that
was also really good. Now this was not the first
time we had seen Superman fight Doomsday in
animation. Of course, there was the Superman
Doomsday film that came out like over a decade
prior to this film coming out. When this movie came
out, we had also just recently seen Batman vs
Superman where Superman dies at the hands of
Doomsday as well. Out of all the different
adaptations of The Death of Superman comic book
story arc, I think The Death of Superman animated
movie was the best. It was a real tear-jerker, but
with great action. Yeah, I would actually agree
with that. So great answer Cyrus. Our final
honorable mention goes to by DearBangora who
said, Hello dynamic duo. My favorite scene has to
be from the end of Superman and Lois. The fact that
they have this recap very similar to Six Feet Under
and they go through all the life of Superman and his
family and his kids. Just really embodied all of
what Superman is meant to be. Great Tyler Houghlin
scene, great scene in general, great way to end the
DC TV universe. Okay, so I will fully admit I was not
a big fan of the Superman and Lois television
series. Not for any reason that I didn't like the
story or anything like that. I just was always too
busy to watch it and by that point I was kind of done
with the CW. That said, by Dear's description of
the final scene of the show kind of really makes me
want to watch it. Yeah, I kept hearing that it was
really good among fans and on Reddit and stuff like
that. So I heard the show as a whole was just
amazing. And I think if you had watched it, maybe
this would actually get the no prize win. Who
knows? Yeah, that's actually very possible. My
apologies to everyone who enjoyed the show who
knows that this should probably get the win. But
alas, it does not. We want to give a quick shout out
to Alex Albro for calling in with his answer. But
the winner of this week's no prize is Lorenzo
Valdez. Who said? This is Lorenzo Valdez calling
in once again. My favorite Superman moment from a
film is the first flight scene for Man of Steel. My
favorite Superman moment from a television
series. Well, there are so many clonda moments
that I want to choose from Smallville. But the one
I'm going to go with because it feels most like what
you're soliciting, which is specifically a
Superman moment, because it's set at the top of the
daily planet. It's the clonda kiss from the end of
the season eight episode of Smallville power.
Clona forever and always. Bye bye. So I finally
realized what Lorenzo is saying when he mentions
clona. And I guess that's like shipping Clark and
Lana Lang, which no, I am anti-clona. He belongs
with Lois Lane. So I'm not really counting the
Smallville kiss scene. What I really love about
his answer is the Superman first flight scene from
Man of Steel, because that was intense. I still
remember watching that in theaters and just being
so moved by Hans Zimmer's sweeping score. It is
hands down. I think my favorite Superman moment
from the entirety of the Snyderverse. But who's
your favorite version of Lana Lang, though,
Jonathan? Oh, like favorite actress. Um, I would
say the one that I think is most close to the comics
was actually the Annette O'Toole version of the
character from Superman 3. She would later
actually be cast as Martha Kent in the Smallville
television series. So it's not the Kristen Crook
version from Smallville? No, she was fine. I just
think Annette O'Toole was more comics accurate.
I'm pretty sure Lorenzo Valdez is going to want to
fight you now. Come at me, bro. I thought I want to
make Clois a word, but Clois forever and always. I
think I've always been more of a, uh, clunder woman
type guy. But congrats to Lorenzo Valdez for
winning this week's snow prize. If you the
listener want a shot at winning your own no prize,
stay tuned to later on this episode when we'll be
asking another question of the week. And now that
that's done, on to the news. Alright, in a fairly
surprising bit of news from this past week, we
learned that John Bernthal, who plays the
character of Frank Castle the Punisher, will be
joining the cast of Spider-Man Brand New Day in a
move that makes me go, what is going on? I had no idea
what this film was going to be, but I think the
addition of John Bernthal to the cast gives us a
clearer picture. So previously you and I
conjectured that the film could be adapting the
Spider-Verse storyline because we thought maybe
Sadie Sink was going to play in Alternate Universe
Gwen Stacy. There are a ton of rumors going around
the internet right now, including rumors that the
story is going to involve symbiotes and the Hulk.
None of those rumors were substantiated, but we
did get confirmation from the Hollywood Reporter
that, yeah, the Punisher is going to be joining the
story, which really makes me rethink all my
previous notions in that they appear to be taking a
more grounded approach to this upcoming
Spider-Man film. Yeah, you would think that
someone from the Netflix shows, which were all
pretty street level and grounded, would make this
Spider-Man film somewhat like that, right?
Right. And it makes me think that Sadie Sink is more
likely going to be playing Felicia Hardy, the
black cat, because she's a more grounded street
level character, I think. And that the villain is
maybe going to be the kingpin, and maybe we'll see
Daredevil in addition to the Punisher. Or maybe
the rumors are true and the bad guy is going to be Mr.
Negative, who is another New York City crime boss
who has the power of the life force and the dark
force, which are abilities shared by the heroic
duo of Cloak and Dagger. So maybe those guys are
joining the story as well. And this really is
shaping up to be a more direct adaptation of the
brand new day story arc. Yeah, there's currently
rumors going around that Nicole Kidman is going to
play negative woman, essentially. Oh, I don't
know about that. I wouldn't like that. I was kind of
setting my hopes on Steven Yun as Mr. Negative
himself, Martin Lee, who's a pretty cool
character. He's kind of like Too Faced in the sense
that he's a crime boss who jumps between his light
side and his dark side, although in this case it's
very much literally his light side and his dark
side. When he's in his dark force form, he appears
as a photo negative kind of. And when he corrupts
other people or imbues objects with his dark
force, it appears as like a photo negative. It can
make for some pretty compelling visual effects, I
think, but I think the Punisher would make sense as
an ally going up against the Mr. Negative crime
boss. I'm seeing a visual motif with all of these
characters. You have Punisher, Black Cat, maybe
Cloak and Dagger, maybe Mr. Negative. It's all
black and white. And maybe even Black Suit
Spider-Man? I could see the movie posters now.
They'd have to introduce the symbiotes though if
we're going with Black Suit Spider-Man, but who
knows? Maybe Venom is in the movie too. At this
point, I feel like anything's possible, but I
gotta assume that the film is taking a much more
bare bones down to Earth approach to its story.
Maybe, maybe, maybe not, especially if there's
symbiotes involved. That being said, you know,
Berndthal's portrayal of Frank Castle the
Punisher is pretty damn rated R, both in his show
and in the Daredevil series. I'm wondering how
they're going to get away with that in a PG-13
Spider-Man movie. Like, what the hell is Peter
Parker going to do when he straight up sees the
Punisher rip a dude's throat out? Eh, it's
probably going to happen off camera. And then you
see Spider-Man puke in his mask or something like
that. Boom, there you go. Comedy gold. I just
remembered that the Punisher first appeared in a
Spider-Man comic. That's correct. He was a
conflicted Spider-Man bad guy who was trying to
kill him due to his misperception of Spider-Man
that he was a murderer at the time. It's really
interesting news that it'll be interesting to see
who else gets added to this Spider-Man forecast,
especially if they're coming from the Marvel
Netflix universe, which is, you know, now part of
the MCU. But there were a lot of characters there,
and that brings us to our question of the week.
Besides the Punisher and obviously Daredevil,
which of the former Marvel Netflix characters
would you want to see in the next Spider-Man film
and why? Now, we're excluding Daredevil here
because I think everyone will pick him, but if
Marvel were to include either Jessica Jones or
Iron Fist, Luke Cage, Electra, etc., we want to
know who you guys would most want to be in this film.
Recording answer at DynamicsDuel.com by
clicking on the red microphone button in the
bottom right hand corner of the screen, which will
prompt you to leave us a voicemail. Your message
could be up to 30 seconds long, and don't forget to
leave your name in case you include you on the
podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer and award
that person a Dynamic Duel No Prize that we'll post
to Instagram. Be sure to answer before June 28th.
Moving on to DC News, we learned last week that DC
Studios has cast its lead actor in the upcoming
Clayface live action film, and it looks like the
actor Tom Reese-Harris will be playing the
titular Batman villain. Now, I have no idea who
this guy is. I looked at his IMDb. I have not seen a
single one of his films. To me, he looks like the
white Rami Malek, but I'm okay with that because
they both kind of have these haunting looks with
the high cheekbones and sunken eyes. I'm sure the
guy is a fantastic actor, considering he's
British and they tend to play more technical
performances, which I think is perfect for
something like a Clayface film where he's an actor
and needs to be able to play different personas, I
guess you could say. I don't know much about the
actor either. I like the way that John Staroski put
a best on our Discord server regarding the actor's
appearance in that he looks like if David Bowie
fucked a scars guard, and I thought that was pretty
apt. Now, the film is going to be directed by James
Watkins, who also directed the horror film Speak
No Evil, and the original screenplay draft was
written by Mike Flanagan, although apparently
the Oscar-nominated writer Hussien Amini has
done rewrites. It's produced by Matt Reeves, who
also produced the Batman Caped Crusader animated
series, which did a fantastic rendition of
Clayface, and I'm really hoping that this film
takes some of the horror cues from that television
series. Yeah, I think we mentioned before on this
podcast that 2024 had like four or five different
renditions of Clayface on different television
shows and stuff, including Suicide Squad,
Isakai, Batman Caped Crusader, Creature
Commandos, and Harley Quinn. Yes, I just want an
amalgam of all those versions rolled into one.
Yeah, maybe not the Harley Quinn version, but
yeah, I love the rest of them. I don't believe
there's a release date for this yet, but it will
start filming fairly soon in the UK. In other DC
news, we got to our official trailer for Sandman
Season 2, which is being released in two parts this
year. If you listen to our review of Sandman Season
1, you'll know that I'm a huge Sandman fan, and I
loved that first season. Ever since then, I've
been stoked for the continuation of that series on
Netflix. Season 2 will be the final season, but it
does look like it's going to wrap up Sandman's
story nicely. We're going to be moving through a
lot of story here, everything from James Return to
Hell, to him finding his son Orpheus, to his
involvement with the Fairy Folk, to ultimately
the vengeance of Lita Hall and the Furies. It's
going to be an epic season, no doubt. Again, one of
the coolest aspects, I think, of this season in
particular, is that we get to see all seven members
of the Endless, including Destruction, who we
missed out on in the teaser trailer for this
season. Of course, we get Gwendolyn Christie
returning to her role as Lucifer. We get to see the
demon Azazel, who's like this shadowy, morphing
creature full of eyes and teeth. We get to see Nada,
who is James' true love in the series. And we get to
see Jack Gleason, the actor who played Prince
Joffrey, play Puck in the Sandman show, which I
think is perfect casting. That is, yeah. I was
surprised to see King Joffrey. I was like, what the
hell is he doing here? He just has such a weird,
sinister face, but as the character of Puck from
Midsummer Night's Dream, yeah, that's
perfection. Now, the story of Sandman has always
spanned centuries, and it looks like we're going
to see that as well, which is one of the more epic
aspects that I love about this story is that it's
not just confined to one setting, one timeframe,
one set of characters. It can really go anywhere,
and it does. For any of those unfamiliar with the
Sandman story, I definitely recommend watching
season one prior to the release of season two on
Netflix. The first part is coming out July 3rd,
just a couple of weeks here, and volume two is
coming out July 24th at the end of the month. I can't
fucking wait! And I just kind of want to sleep until
the show starts. I liked the trailer that much.
Actually, regarding the newcomer perspective,
that's one of the things I thought about while
watching this trailer was, if someone hasn't
watched season one or is completely unfamiliar
with the Sandman story or universe, I got to wonder
what they think about this trailer, because it
really goes all over the place. You said, you know,
the story spans centuries, but it's not a
straightforward fantasy series in the way that
most people think of fantasy series. And I got to
think that as a newcomer, if this trailer was the
first thing I saw, I would be so compelled to watch
it, because it looks so damn good. So damn good, so
damn expensive, still, which I love to see. Yeah,
the visual effects are on point. The
cinematography looks amazing. Yeah, again, wake
me up when it's July 3rd. But that does it for all of
the news for this episode, so now let's go ahead and
move on to the main event, where we pit the Green
Lantern Guy Gardner against the Thor villain,
Gore the God Butcher. Okay, the Green Lantern Guy
Gardner versus Gore the God Butcher. Now, I will be
totally honest and say that Guy Gardner is not my
favorite Green Lantern. In fact, he's probably
one of my least favorite Green Lanterns. But as I
mentioned earlier, he does have a lot of fans out
there. I feel like a lot of people just have like a
love-hate relationship with him, because he's
kind of a douchebag. But an endearing one in that he
frequently gets his ass kicked by Batman, like
punched in the face. Those one time. And kind of put
in his place, you know? He's kind of there to be a
punching bag for, I think, other heroes in a way. He
doesn't really take any guff from anyone except
when he does. And that's satisfying, I guess. I
guess also he does have a lot of heart in that while
he is kind of a dickbag, he is well-meaning and
legitimately heroic. Yes, as you will hear later
on in my backstory for Guy Gardner, he's
definitely very stubborn, doesn't know when to
give up, and because of that, yes, it does make him
very heroic. And he rises to the occasion. I think
Gore the God Butcher would also see himself as
heroic in his campaign against basically all
deities. We mentioned briefly Gore's inclusion
in the Thor 11 Thunder film. There's so much that
that movie got wrong from his appearance to his
powers. What about his origin? His origin is
incorrect. It's a shame that Marvel itself
screwed it up because who knows when we'll get to
see any more correct adaptation of Gore on the
screen. One of the many reasons that I'm still
pissed off to this day because of that film, and
hopefully I could do the character more justice in
this dual speculation. But to explain the
methodology behind our duels, let's go to our
sentient dual simulator Alfred Jarvis-9000.
AJ9K tell our listeners how you go about
determining a winner in our dual matchups. Yes, of
course, sir. The way I determine a winner between
the contestants is by running 1000 Monte Carlo
simulations using the characters statistics. A
Monte Carlo simulation is a probabilistic model
used to determine outcomes through random
sampling. In this case, I randomize the
statistics along a normal distribution as a way to
simulate the many variables that can occur during
battle. The stat parameters are based on the
official Marvel power grid from which the DC
characters statistics are extrapolated.
Additional stat categories are included such as
range, damage potential, versatility and
perception in order to create a more detailed and
accurate simulation. The results of the 1000
simulations provide a percentage of wins for each
character. The contestant with the higher
percentage is declared the victor as they have a
higher probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither character should win
100% of the matches. The comic book stories have
shown that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman, so the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks, AJ9K.
Before we run the simulations, though, we'd like
to break down each character's histories and
abilities before improvising a scenario on how we
imagine one of the 1000 simulations would play out
beat for beat. And I believe it's my turn to go first
with the Marvel characters backstory, so let me
tell you all about Gore the God Butcher. Gore was
born with a crippled leg on an unnamed desert world
whose twin sons scorched the ground and whose
knights were stalked by leathery predators. His
tribe taught that droughts, quakes, and famine
were divine tests and that prayer and sacrifice
would bring relief, yet no deliverance came. His
father died of sun fever, his mother was taken by
beasts, and every one of his children was claimed
by starvation or tremors. A violent quake crushed
his pregnant mate, Ara, leaving only their son,
Agar. When famine finally seized the boy during a
desperate march toward a rumored fertile land,
Gore buried the child, a forbidden act according
to his tribe, and renounced the gods. For
blasphemy, his people stoned him and left him to
die in the wasteland. Alone and dehydrated, Gore
saw two armored figures streak across the sky and
crash nearby. One shone gold, the other was a
living shadow wielding a black shifting sword.
The shadow was Null, an ancient evil you could
learn more about in his duel against White
Lantern. Null's weapon, all black, the Necro
Sword, was the first symbiote that the deity had
created, a thinking mass of liquid darkness that
bonds with hosts and feeds on rage. The gold god
begged Gore for help, but in realizing gods were
real and had ignored his family, Gore's sorrow
became fury. The Necro Sword slipped from Null,
wrapped around Gore's arm, and hardened into a
spear. With it, Gore slew the gold god, felt the
symbiote's darkness join with him, and swore to
butcher every deity in existence. While Null
could have pursued his weapon, he instead allowed
Gore to wield the all black, recognizing the
mortal's vengeful heart as a mirror of his own
hatred for the light. All black granted Gore
flight, super strength, and rapid healing. He
could mold the symbiote into armor or weapons at
will. He also shaped black berserkers, large
shadow creatures that obeyed him. For thousands
of years, Gore traveled from world to world,
murdering gods of war, harvest, song, and even
flowers. Convinced the universe would be kinder
without beings who demanded worship while
allowing suffering. During the Viking Age, Gore
reached Earth. Thor Odinson, then a brash young
god of thunder, found a dead North American deity
on an Icelandic beach and tracked the killer to
Russia, where the sl- Gorr ambushed Thor, chained
him inside a cave, and tortured him for 17 days,
demanding that Thor reveal the path to Asgard. A
band of vikings stormed the cave, distracting
Gorr long enough for Thor to sever his arm with his
own axe, yarn-borne, and strike Gorr with
lightning. Gorr survived and fled, determined
never to be weak again. You can learn more about
Thor in his duel against Wonder Woman. Seeking
greater power, Gorr attacked Kronix, a palace
guarded by the Time Gods. After killing its
defenders, he entered their pool of raw time to
travel through history. At the dawn of creation,
he slew one of the first Elder Gods and ripped out
its glowing heart. Far in a future timeline, he
captured gods from every pantheon he could reach.
Only an elderly King Thor, last ruler of Asgard,
remained free, caged yet unbroken. Gorr forced
his prisoners to mine star cores in order to build
the God Bomb, a device that would wipe out every god
in every era through time. Back in the present,
Thor noticed prayers going unanswered and
followed the trail to Gorr's fortress, where he
was caught and chained beside his older self.
Black berserkers then seized the Viking Age Thor
so the butcher could parade three versions of the
same deity before his ultimate victory. The Thors
escaped and hurled a fragment of a star at the God
Bomb, but Gorr survived. To supercharge all
black, he ordered his berserkers to slaughter his
enslaved gods, feeding their energy to the sword
and making himself unstoppable. Gorr used all
black to create copies of his former wife and kid,
Ara and Agar, for company. When the Ara construct
called him, my god, he vaporized her in rage. The
Agar construct horrified, freed Thor the
Avenger, and begged him to stop his father. Gorr
hurled the young Thor into space, activated the
God Bomb, and waited for Divinity to die. As the
Bomb detonated, the surviving gods of every
timeline prayed in unison. Their faith flooded
Thor the Avenger, and wielding both his own hammer
Mjolnir and King Thor's future Mjolnir, he
battled the butcher across a dying moon. The
youngest Thor struck the final blow, beheading
Gorr and ending a 3000 year crusade. Though dead,
the all black sword, carrying a copy of Gorr's
mind, endured. Years later, the spy Nick Fury
whispered a secret in Thor's ear learned from
their murdered watcher Uatu, telling Thor, Gorr
was right. You can learn more about the watcher in
his duel against the Monitor. Doubt washed over
Thor so much so that he became unworthy to lift
Mjolnir. During a war between the Norse realms,
the Dark Elf Malachith bonded with the blade and
called himself the Butcher of Thors until Thor
defeated him. You can learn more about Malachith
in his duel against Eclipso. Far in the future,
millions of years later, King Loki merged with all
black and rebuilt Gorr's body from living shadow,
setting him against an immortal all father Thor.
You can learn more about Loki in his duel against
Ares. Gorr crucified Loki and Thor on spires of
darkness and tried to spread the sword's darkness
across every star. Thor's granddaughters, Atle,
Elisive, and Frig, freed their grandfather and
rallied gods saved long ago by Thor. Atle severed
Gorr's head, but it was only a shell. All black's
darkness had woven itself into the very fabric of
space. Loki stalled Gorr by reciting every heroic
deed Thor had ever performed. The endless tale
bought time for Thor to release the god Tempest, a
cosmic storm trapped inside Mjolnir. The Tempest
shredded all black. Stripped of power, amnesiac
and raving, Gorr was left mortal. The Sky Lords of
Indigar, the same planet whose rescued gods had
once prayed for Thor, took Goren to live as a simple
farmer. Yet the Necro Swords residue had replaced
Gorr's heart. Memories crept back in and with them
his hatred, restoring him in the present day.
Fixating on Jean Grey, newly reborn as the
Phoenix, Gorr ambushed and killed her on the
barren planet Dogar. The Phoenix resurrected her
instantly, overwhelmed Gorr and ignited and
collapsed his dark heart, transforming it into a
newborn star so that at last, Gorr would give life
instead of taking it. You can learn more about the
Phoenix in her duel against Raven. And that's Gorr
the God Butcher's history. Powers-wise, Gorr is a
mortal alien whose heart was replaced with the
darkness of all black, the Necro Sword, a
primordial weapon composed of living abyss,
forged by the primordial entity Null using
celestial energy. Though the Necro Sword was
returned to Null's hands, Gorr can still use the
portion of living abyss that is now part of him. He
can shape this darkness to his will to form
constructs such as weapons like spears or a sword,
which is its preferred form. Gorr often uses it to
form a cloak that can create armor or wings or even
semi-sentient wolf lizard insectoid
hybrid-like creatures called black berserkers.
The living abyss grant Gorr strength enough to
lift over 100 tons in vulnerability, increased
speed, regenerative healing, and immortality.
Having lived for millennia, waging combat
against deities, he has become an adept
combatant. And that's Gorr. Gotcha. So you know,
like if it takes three different thorns to defeat
Gorr the God Butcher, Guy Gardner has his fucking
work cut out for him, doesn't he? I mean, not
really. One Green Lantern can easily take on three
thorns. What? Yeah, you heard me. I could have less
respect for you than I do right now. Just want to let
you know. I am okay with that. I'll get it back when I
win the duel, you know? Let me tell you about Green
Lantern Guy Gardner. Now Guy Gardner was born in
Baltimore, Maryland to a turbulent household
dominated by his abusive alcoholic father.
Frequently compared unfavorably to his older
brother, Mace, Guy developed a tough and
combative personality to shield himself from
constant ridicule and physical abuse. Despite
the toxic home environment, he showed potential
both intellectually and athletically earning a
scholarship to the University of Michigan. There
he studied education and psychology and played
football until a career ending knee injury forced
him to refocus on academics. He eventually became
a social worker and later a teacher working with
troubled youth, driven by a desire to help those in
need escape the kind of upbringing he endured.
Unbeknownst to him, Guy possessed the qualities
necessary to become a Green Lantern, willpower,
courage, and a strong sense of justice. When the
Green Lantern of sector 2814, Abin Sewer, crashed
on earth and lay dying, his ring identified two
worthy successors, Hal Jordan and Guy Gardner.
Jordan, being closer, was chosen. Gardner became
the backup Green Lantern, though he only learned
of this years later when the Guardians of the
Universe, the creators of the Green Lanterns,
informed him directly in an admission that
wounded his pride and fueled his lifelong rivalry
with Hal Jordan. You can learn more about how NRI
Green Lantern versus Nova dual episode. After
learning of his alternate selection, Guy trained
to serve as Hal's substitute in the event of his
incapacitation. He eventually received his own
Green Lantern ring and joined the Corps. Though
his attitude and temperament often clashed with
the more disciplined members, his effectiveness
in battle earned him a reluctant respect.
Initially assigned as Hal's backup, Guy took on
more responsibility following Hal's frequent
off-world duties. His first major outing came
when Hal was captured by Sinestro and taken to the
Anti-Matter Universe of Corde. The Guardians
activated Guy's ring and directed him to rescue
Hal, but he was intercepted and captured by
Sinestro's forces. Subjected to mental torture,
Guy was presumed dead when the Guardians lost
contact with him. Eventually rescued and
returned to earth, Guy suffered severe
psychological trauma and was placed in a comatose
state. He remained that way for several years
until the crisis on Infinite Earth's event when
the Guardians reactivated him as one of Earth's
Green Lanterns. Though he awoke, the mental
damage had altered his personality. He emerged
more arrogant, aggressive, and unpredictable.
The change was partially due to brain damage,
which affected his emotional regulation and
heightened his volatility, making him a wild card
among the Corps. When the Guardians later decided
to leave the Universe and choose successors, Guy
was given a ring and declared the official Green
Lantern of Earth. However, his bombastic
demeanor and combative style often put him at odds
with his peers, especially Hal Jordan, John
Stewart, and Batman. He joined the newly reformed
Justice League International, a more
politically driven version of the League, where
his brash personality acted as a constant source
of tension. Despite this, he became a core member
of the team and formed a unique rapport with heroes
like Booster Gold and Blue Beetle. You can learn
more about the Justice League in our team duel,
Justice League vs. Avengers. His time with the
League included several humiliations, most
famously being knocked out by a single punch from
Batman, but also triumphs, including
commissions to apocalypse, battles against
despair and defending Earth from alien
invasions. His overconfidence and crude sense of
humor masked a deep need for validation and a
fierce loyalty to his team. After Hal's
transformation into parallax, Guy lost his ring
during the destruction of the central power
battery. Refusing to stand idle, he saw
alternative means to remain a hero. He embarked on
a quest to acquire Sinestro's yellow power ring,
and when he was successful, he used it to continue
fighting crime, though the ring proved unstable
and more difficult to control. Seeking greater
power, Guy ventured into the alien realm of Kord
and later tapped into a mysterious inner energy
linked to his DNA. This transformation turned him
into Warrior, a being capable of morphing his body
into weapons and armor. The source of his power was
revealed to be his descent from an alien race
called the Vuldarians. Biologically engineered
shapeshifting warriors bred for combat.
Embracing his new identity, Guy became the
proprietor of a bar for heroes called Warriors.
Eventually his Vuldarian powers faded and Guy
returned to using the green lantern ring when the
core was restored. He served as a senior lantern
alongside Kyle Rainer, John Stewart and Hel
Jordan, operating out of Oa and protecting sector
2814. He also worked closely with the Honor Guard,
the elite leadership force of the core, and
participated in campaigns during the Rand
Thanagar war and the Sinestro core war, where he
fought valiantly against yellow lanterns and
other cosmic threats. In the post-flashpoint
timeline, Guy Gardner remained a green lantern
and continued to be depicted as one prone to acting
before thinking, but with unwavering courage and
a strong moral compass. He served with
distinction in the green lantern core and took
part in major battles, including defending Oa
from the invading red lantern core. During this
campaign, he was briefly possessed by a red
lantern ring drawn to the deep well of rage within
him. The experience left a lasting impression.
When Atrocidus, the founder of the red lanterns,
launched a new assault on earth, Guy volunteered
to infiltrate the red lantern core as a double
agent. You could learn more about red lanterns in
our Atrocidus vs Juggernaut dual episode. The
power of the red ring proved to be too seductive,
and Guy's infiltration turned into a reluctant
allegiance. Eventually, he embraced the
identity of a red lantern fully and became their
field leader, bearing their crimson sigil and
maintaining order among the volatile ranks.
Under Guy's leadership, the red lanterns
transformed from a brutal militia into a more
structured force focused on dispensing
vengeance and protecting the oppressed. He
developed a complex but mutual respect with
Atrocidus' rival, Gules, and established a red
lantern base of operations on earth, though he
struggled with controlling his rage-fueled
powers. After several adventures including
cosmic conflicts and battles against shadowy
manipulators like the Shadow Thief and the Shadow
Market, Guy relinquished his red ring and
returned to the green lantern core. He served on
Mojo, the sentient planet that for a time acted as
the core's HQ, helping train new recruits and
operating as a senior lantern within the honor
guard. When the green lantern core was merged with
the Sinestro core during a fragile alliance
brokered by Hal Jordan and Saurinik Natu, a yellow
lantern, Guy was among the few green lanterns who
attempted to make peace with the yellow lanterns.
His unlikely friendship with the reformed
Arquillo, a hulking brute and enforcer from the
Sinestro core, who's often compared to Kilowag,
became a standout moment during this period as the
two warriors bonded over their mutual love of
brawling and begrudging respect for one
another's strength. That's Guy Gardner's
backstory. Powers-wise, Guy Gardner wields a
green lantern power ring fueled by willpower,
granting him the ability to generate solid, light
constructs, fly, generate force fields, and
survive in space. His constructs often reflect
his brash personality, manifesting as blunt
force weapons like fists, bats, and hammers. For a
time, his Vulderian DNA allowed him to shape shift
parts of his body into weapons and armor, giving
him enhanced strength and durability. Even
without powers, Guy is a trained hand-to-hand
fighter. Wait, so does he have his Vulderian
powers or does he not? Technically, he still has
his Vulderian DNA, though he hasn't used it since
like the early 2000s. What you said he has the DNA
but that his powers like disappeared over time. It
was during the green lantern rebirth storyline
where like he went through like this tremendous
amount of pain where it seemed like his DNA was
rejecting his body or something like that, but
that was all quelled once a green lantern ring flew
onto his finger and he emerged once again as a green
lantern. So it didn't leave his body, it's still
there. Again, he just hasn't made use of it. And
will he have a red ring in this match or just the
green? I'm going with his traditional green ring,
although I loved the fact that he was a red lantern
for a time. I thought he made a fantastic red
lantern. I thought a red lantern ring couldn't be
removed from a red lantern without killing them.
There have been a few instances where they've been
able to circumvent that, particularly when
there's a, I think it's a blue lantern is present.
Interesting. Okay. Okay. I don't know why I'm
asking so many questions because I don't care
because this dude's going down. Oh, we'll see. In a
world where fantasies collide and heroes clash,
one podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
Dynamite Podcast Network presents Console
Combat, where video game legends brawl every
Monday. Dynamic Duel, where comic book titans
smash every Tuesday. Max Destruction, where TV
and action heroes battle every Wednesday. And
Sendro World, where anime champions clash every
Thursday. Join us as we speculate on the matches
and armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge
victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com, where we
settle the debate and settle the score. Now that
we've got their histories and abilities out of the
way, let's speculate on how one of the 1000
simulated matches will go. The winner is
determined by simulations, not the speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how the fight could play
out. AJ9K, what are the rules of our speculation?
Well, I should say there are no rules other than the
characters have no prior knowledge of the other
going into the fight. All they are aware of
starting out is that the other character is a
threat that needs to be eliminated. For the
speculation, the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the match
itself, as no environmental statistics are
considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. Alright,
then let's get into it. Green Lantern and Gore the
God Butcher meet on the battlefield. Who goes
first? I'm actually gonna say Guy starts off, and
he's gonna do so by undoing his belt buckle,
pulling down his pants. Moaning, Gore, while
giving him the middle finger. Gore is unamused.
Oh, but Guy is, so. Well, this amusement is gonna
turn into pure shock when all of a sudden he finds a
dark tendril up his pooper. But that's exactly
what Guy wanted to happen, because while Gore was
distracted by Guy's ass, Guy's gonna generate a
pit bull behind Gore that's gonna chomp down on his
ankle, while Guy, meanwhile, is gonna block that
black tendril with the green toilet that flushes
that tendril and that's plumbing just redirects
it right into the ground. Alright, I'm gonna say
first of all, Gore was not distracted by Guy's ass.
Sure, I will say that he does take a second to
straight up murder the pit bull construct. Oh,
shit. He's using his necrosaur to cleave it in half
from its jaws. Then Gore creates his own
creatures, a pair of black berserkers that chase
down Guy like a couple of rabid wolves that just
devour him alive. Okay, but I'm gonna say that
these creatures are gonna be blocked by a row of
giant sized football defensive linemen, and from
behind them, Guy's gonna generate a football and
hurl it straight towards Gore with perfect aim,
and it's gonna explode upon contact because it was
actually a bomb. And that's gonna send Gore flying
backward while Guy does a touchdown dance. A
football bomb? Sure. Sure. Yeah, sure. I'm not
sure what kind of football explosion would
actually even hurt Gore, but I know that he's
already fucking had it with Guy's shenanigans. So
Gore instantly recovers from this football bomb
and blitzes Guy sword first with enough force to
cut through a freaking sun. And he straight up
flies through any sort of defensive constructs
that Guy creates to protect himself, and Gore
slices right through Guy himself like a dark
bullet train. Oh no, Guy doesn't generate
anything to block this attack. Instead, he's
gonna hold up a green cape that hides his body, and
as Gore slices through it, Guy dodges to the side
like a matador, shouting, Toro! And Gore's gonna
fly right past him. But Guy, he's immediately
gonna hurl a lasso after him, catching Gore by the
ankles before proceeding to quickly hog tie him,
all while wearing a cowboy hat and bandana by the
way. Guy is annoying. But do you think that Gore is
just limited to his arms and legs? Even if Guy
manages to restrain Gore's limbs, Gore is just
gonna create a dozen more of them out of living
abyss. And all these extra limbs, they're like
scorpion tails, and they each simultaneously
reach out and impale Guy from all directions on
their stingers. Actually, two of them form blades
that free Gore from his bindings, but the rest of
them impale Guy. They like stab through him with
long stingers? Yeah. Okay, so Guy probably falls
to his knees, but before he can get stabbed again,
he's gonna generate a dozen chainsaws that are
gonna sever the scorpion tails. And just as Gore
frees himself from the lasso while Guy is still on
his knees, a giant green fist with brass knuckles
is gonna plow into Gore. Wait, wait, Guy should be
dead from getting impaled a dozen times. Well,
actually Guy has like weird organs due to his
Vulderian DNA, like he has two hearts, and he could
also heal rapidly because of his shapeshifting
nature. So yeah, he's hurt, but he'll be fine.
That's so weird. But you know what, it doesn't
matter because even if Gore gets punched by this
fist construct, the stingers that Gore stabbed
into Guy Gardener, they left this dark residue
within Guy's body. So it doesn't matter what the
hell Guy's organs look like on the inside, because
it's all just infested with shadowy maggots that
feast on his body in just like a matter of seconds.
And it looks like Guy gets covered in darkness, but
then he just dissolves into nothing. Well, again,
you know, Guy's Vulderian shapeshifting body
will just shift those maggots into a Gatling gun
that he transforms his other arm into that's not
armed with a ring, and he's going to fire those
maggots right back at Gore, which I don't know,
probably isn't gonna hurt him. Yeah, Gore would
just absorb them into the rest of his living
darkness. But once the maggots are done, he's
gonna transform his Gatling gun into a grenade
launcher, and he's gonna launch a nuclear level
implosive grenade that's just gonna leave Gore a
dark stain on the ground. What the fuck is an
implosive nuclear grenade? I guess the technical
term would be a Vulderian Fragmite bomb? I don't
know, it has like the destructive force of a nuke,
but it sucks things up like a mini black hole. It's
from the comics. Okay. Well, Gore blocks the bomb
with his cloak, so that when it goes off, when it
implodes, it just pulls in all of the living abyss,
like all of that gets sucked into the implosion.
But Gore himself is still left standing. And Guy,
in all of his cockiness, you know, he didn't
anticipate this. So as the living darkness
dissipates from the bomb, Guy is not paying
attention. He's assuming Gore was imploded to,
and then all of a sudden he gets fucking rocked
right in his nose by Gore, who is now mortal. And
since getting punched in the nose real hard is
apparently Guy's weakness, you know, he falls to
the ground, just completely knocked out, and he
loses the match. Fuck. You know, I can't even say
that wouldn't happen. I guess we'll leave it
there. Either Guy defeats Gore with some
Vulderian Fragmite bombs, or Gore just knocks Guy
out with a sucker punch to the face, apparently.
Well, let's find out which of these scenarios
happens by running the stats on these characters,
running the simulations, and coming back with a
winner. AG9K, hit it. Inputting data, running
calculations, processing results, simulations
complete. All right, this didn't turn out to be
quite the repeat of the White Lantern vs. Null dual
episode that I thought it was going to be. I think we
managed to do a pretty good job of differentiating
these two matches. Yeah, it wasn't hard,
honestly, with Guy. He's kind of different from
other Green Lanterns, not only in terms of his
brashness and attitude, but also in terms of his
physiology. You know, he's part Vulderian, and I
didn't want to play that up into the stats too much.
I still think his ring is his primary weapon. But he
has contingencies, we'll say. And that is what
gave him the edge in versatility over Gore the God
Butcher. You know, as versatile as Gore is with his
Necro sword. And he does some interesting things
with it, like he used it to create the God Bomb and
stuff like that. But largely he sticks with swords
and tendrils and dark creatures and stuff
compared to a Green Lantern ring, which Guy tends
to get a little bit more creative with, again, in
addition to his alien DNA. The two did share a lot of
similarities when it came to the stats, though we
both said they were equally fast, equally
evasive. When it came to strength and damage level
and range, they were also on par with each other. We
did give the fighting skill edge to Gore the God
Butcher just because he has millennia of fighting
experience. And we also said that longevity meant
he was smarter than Guy, who's kind of dumb. Yeah,
he's definitely done some really dumb stuff in the
comics. But we did give Guy the edge in perception
because Green Lantern rings can scan things and
give the bear added information. Yeah, there
weren't too many perception feats for Gore the God
Butcher. With all that said, Jonathan, who's
taken home the win here? I got to give it to Guy. I
think his versatility is going to give him the edge
here. And it looks like our Instagram poll takers
agree with me, just barely though, because 52% of
our poll takers voted in favor of Guy. That's one of
the closest polls I think we've put out there.
Yeah, really close. So it seems like this is a
pretty good match up in our followers' eyes. But
let's find out who actually won. AJ9K, the results
please. Hey, you are, sir. All right, the winner
between Green Lantern, Guy Gardner, and Gore the
God Butcher is... Gore the God Butcher. Damn it!
Looks like Guy Gardner got sucka punched right the
fuck out. As a matter of fact, Deadpool came out
when this match was over and told Guy Gardner that
he got knocked the fuck out. At a 1000 matches, Gore
the God Butcher won 571, whereas Green Lantern
only won 429. Really? Okay, I thought that was
going to be a little bit closer. I thought this was
essentially going to be a coin toss. And I am kind of
said that it again, Guy is not my favorite Green
Lantern, but I also just really hate Gore. Why?
What's wrong with Gore? He deserves this. Did you
see how they massacred my boy in Thor 11 Thunder?
Yeah, that's why I don't like him. That whole
movie, just everything about it is awful. Well,
maybe Superman will be bad and you'll hate Guy even
more too. Yeah, no, that's not going to happen. But
that does it for this duel. AJ9K, help close this
out. Max Destruction, Senjo World, and Console
Combat. In our next episode, as a tie-in to the 4th
of July holiday, we are doing a fireworks-related
duel with Jubilee versus Static. Yeah, I've been
dying to get a Jubilee duel in here at some point and
the executive producers kind of think of a better
time than around the 4th of July. And I agree. But
that does it for this episode. You want to give a big
thanks to our executive producers, John
Staroski, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Belcombe,
Mickey Muthengian, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi
Yatyn, Austin Wizelowski, AJ Dunkerly, Nick
Ibonto, Scott Kamacho, Gil Kamacho, Adam Spees,
Dean Maleski, Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, Josh
Schleiner, Mike Williams, Oscar Gabas, and Paul
Graves for helping make this podcast possible.
And we'll talk to you guys next week. Up, up, and
away, true believers. I thought a good tagline for
this episode would be The Gardener vs The Butcher.
But then I was like, nah, that's boring.