This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi and welcome
to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe and I'm his twin
brother Johnny DC. And just a heads up, we are
recording this episode, not even five days after
we recorded the last one when my voice was
completely shot. So I do expect my voice to falter
at some point during this episode because there's
a lot to say. I got a lot to talk about because we're
going to be reviewing Daredevil Born Again Season
one. And on top of that, we're going to go over the
latest comic book movie news this past week,
including the Thunderbolts Final Trailer, the
Fantastic Four Trailer. And we also got the
Sandman Season two date announcement. So my voice
is fucked. As always, we list our segment times in
our episode description. So feel free to check out
the show notes if you want to skip ahead to a
particular topic. Guys our artificially
intelligent duel simulator AJ9K has a quick
message for our listeners. So listen up. Why hello
there. Do you want even more from this podcast?
Then become a part of the dynamic duel community on
Patreon, where you can choose from three tiers,
the dynamic to a tier gives you access to our
discord chat server. The Fantastic Four tier
gives you two bonus episodes each month. And the
X-Force tier makes you an executive producer of
this show. Lastly, the Dyna Mic podcast network
tier lets you create your own podcast using this
Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe will help
you develop your show, provide graphic support
and consultation and get you simulation results.
Pitch the twins, your ideas via email at dynamic
Duel podcast at gmail.com. Check it out at
patreon.com / dynamic duel. Pip, Pip Cheerio.
Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast. Guys, be sure to tune into the other
shows and the DynaMic podcast network this
week, including the console combat podcast,
where hosts John and Dean simulate battles
between popular video game characters. In
yesterday's episode, they speculated on who
would win in a fight between so bad guy from Guilty
Gear and Ragnar the Blood Edge from Blazblue.
Blazblazblue? Something like that. Over on the
Max Destruction podcast, host Scotty and Gilly,
pet your favorite action heroes from film and
television against each other. This Wednesday,
the twins are reviewing the 1995 film Mortal
Kombat. On the Sanjo World podcast, host Zachary
Hepperin speculates on fights between fan
favorite anime and manga characters. On
Thursday, Zach is going to reveal who would win
between Sennaku from Shangri-La Frontier versus
Kirito from Sword Art Online. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our show
notes to listen to all of the shows in the DynaMic
podcast network. But with that out of the way,
quick to the no prize. A no prize is an award that
Marvel used to give out to fans. Our version, the
dynamic Duel no prize, is a digital award that we
post on Instagram for the person that we feel gave
the best answer to our question of the week. Last
week, in the absence of any news, we asked you guys,
what's your favorite Marvel or DC comic that
you're reading right now? And why? And we got one
answer. Apparently none of you guys are reading
comics. Well, we also didn't give him a whole lot of
time to respond either. So let's go ahead and
announce this week's no prize winner. Congrats to
Zozo. Who said? Hey there. So my favorite comic
series ever is the DC series. In my opinion, it is
just the perfect story. It's really cool having
Batman and Superman and Flash just, you know,
fight zombies being this zombie world and no one is
safe in it. And it's just very action packed,
violent, and it's just a perfect comic series. All
right, thank you. Now, I'm not sure if Zozo said DC
or DC's, but either answer is acceptable because,
yes, DC is an awesome series featuring Superman
and Batman, the Flash, and all of your favorite
superheroes. It's been going on since 1938. It's
freaking amazing. And DC's is one of its most
interesting stories, focusing on the anti-life
equation, infecting everyone and turning them
into zombies, which is just a really cool high
stakes story. We went over that story a few years
ago for Halloween during our DC's versus Marvel
Zombies episode, and that was a really fun episode
to do. Yeah, for sure. I recommend listening to
that episode if you have it already, because we had
a lot of fun with it. As Jonathan and I have noted
before on this podcast, we don't get a chance to
read a whole lot of the current comic books out
there because we're so busy reading the comic
books and research for this show, for the duels
that we're doing. So I was really looking forward
to getting answers from current Marvel readers.
But I know offhand that a lot of people recommend
the ultimate Spider-Man and the Ultimates and
Ultimate Wolverine lines that are coming out
right now. I heard X-Men is really good now that
they're out of the Krakowan era. Although I liked
the Krakowan era as well, less than I wanted to,
because I really love Jonathan Hickman as a
writer. But I kind of view his run on the X-Men as
kind of like Grant Morrison's run, who I also
respect as a writer. But it was kind of like a
contained sort of thing that I'm excited to move on
from and get into the more traditional feel of the
X-Men stories. Yeah, I keep hearing amazing
things about the absolute universe line that DC
has right now, like all of these articles are just
bombarding my news feeds about how much better the
absolute universe is than DC Prime. I haven't read
any absolute comics yet, but I 100% need to. I'm
just waiting for the trades to come out. I really
want to get my hands on One World Under Doom right
now, which I heard is pretty good. It's basically
the story about how Dr. Doom finally becomes the
world's dictator. You know, he becomes the one
ruler in charge of the world. And for some reason,
all the other country's leaders are going along
with it. So it sounds pretty interesting. If
anyone didn't get a chance to call in with their
answer, but they still want to share with their
reading, feel free to leave us a comment wherever
you're listening to this on, whether it's
Spotify, YouTube or shoot us an email. We'd love to
hear from you guys. But congrats to Zozo. You win
this week's No Prize. If you're the listener, want
to win your own No Prize, stay tuned to later on in
this episode when we'll be asking another
question of the week. And now that that's done, on
to the news. All right, this past week, we got two
trailers from Marvel Studios. We got the final
trailer for the Thunderbolts film, which comes
out on May 2nd, and we also got the first official
trailer for the Fantastic Four first steps movie,
which comes out on July 25th. Since the
Thunderbolts trailer came out first, we'll go
ahead and talk about that one first. And also, I
feel like I have less to say about it, because we've
seen so much from the marketing for this movie
already that I don't think there was a whole lot
else that they could show us without, like,
basically spoiling something. I think there's
quite a few surprises to be had in this film. But the
trailer took a more kind of sentimental approach
to the story. Like a lot of the previous marketing
has been about how this is a team of quirky outcasts
banding together. But this one was more about like
what it means to be a hero for these people,
especially Yelena, who feel like they've done so
much wrong in their past. And, you know, the
previous trailers have had cool songs like Possum
Kingdom by the Totes and Where's My Mind by the
Pixies. This one had Under Pressure by David Bowie
and Queen. And I have to say, it's probably one of
the worst renditions of the song that I've ever
heard, because it was just way too sentimental.
I'm wondering who they're trying to target with
this particular final trailer, because it's so
sappy. You have like Red Guardian telling Yelena
to like believe in herself. And she's like, but
I've done so much wrong. And she's crying and
stuff. I'm like, just go back to being the cool
outcasts. You know? Yeah, you mentioned that they
can't really show too much more without giving
spoilers, but I thought this trailer had major
spoilers in it. I mean, obviously when Yelena is in
that dark forest, when she's like looking at a
clone of herself or whatever, it's after she
stepped into the void's darkness, which we see at
the end of this trailer. She goes into some kind of
like trippy dimension where she's like facing her
inner most demons or some shit. I don't think it's
too revealing of a spoiler. It just means that like
she doesn't die when she walks into that dark
shroud. Well, we already knew she wasn't going to
die because she was announced for the Doomsday
movie. Dumb. I thought it was interesting at the
beginning of this trailer, how they showed a
flashback to Black Widow, which I thought was kind
of cheap a little bit. They're trying to play on
Marvel fans, I guess, nostalgia for the Black
Widow movie, which I don't think there's a whole
lot of. But I don't think it's a good look to try to
use Scarlett Johansson to help sell the movie when
she's probably not in it or not in a substantial
role. And the same for Chris Evans as Captain
America, when him and Bucky were, you know,
exchanging glances. Yeah. And all this doesn't
really feel like a new piece of marketing and so
much as kind of like a hash together, last pushed by
tickets of which I have. I have my tickets. I'm
going to go see it at the LMO on May 2nd, and I'm
really looking forward to it. I don't have my
tickets yet. Better fix that shit. Yeah. I'll
probably get them at the last minute. The film
isn't tracking too well, I think. So I expected to
do something like Brave New World numbers. I don't
think it'll be too hard to get tickets. Well, when
the movie turns out to be a masterpiece, since, you
know, a lot of the A24 film production people are on
this movie, I think you're going to be sorry when
you're not able to get tickets because everybody
else is so excited to see the film. Yeah, I'll take
my chances. All right. I mean, this trailer didn't
get me too excited to rush out and buy my tickets.
What was your favorite part of the trailer? I like
the shot where we see Yelena going into the void. I
think that seems like the climax of the film. Yeah,
I could see that. But again, you know, we know what
happens or at least you know, I think we're pretty
confident we know what happens after she goes into
there. You think Yelena appeals to the centuries
darker nature or something like that? Something
like that, exactly. She's like, hey, I'm dark,
too, but I follow the light. I hope that doesn't
happen. My favorite part of the trailer had to be
when Bucky was talking with some side piece on the
phone and she was like, oh, we're not going to come.
And he's like, we could be the ones that are coming.
And I was like, oh, that's a bold swing. I hope that
pays off for him. Rumors are that's Songbird on the
other line. Who is a major Thunderbolts character
from the comic books? We did a Duel episode with
Songbird against DC's Pied Piper. So if you're
interested in learning more about her,
definitely check that out. Nice. Yeah, she's a
traditional Thunderbolt. So I'm glad they found a
way to squeeze her into the film if that is her.
Yeah, for sure. Let's go ahead and move on to the
Fantastic Four trailer, though, because I think
there's a lot more to say about that one.
Considering it's the best look we've gotten at the
film since the teaser came out, you know, a few
months ago. The trailer starts off with the host of
the Ted Gilbert show. And now it's seeing the
Fantastic Four as a team of astronauts who got
superpowers and are now celebrities. It's kind of
like the Ed Sullivan show. It looks like back in the
60s. I got to say, I'm loving the production design
on this film. I think it's a bold, creative choice
to set this movie in the time period that it is.
Because not only is it new for Marvel Studios, it
also makes it feel very Jack Kirby-esque. You
know, the artist who worked with Stanley to create
the Fantastic Four. And it feels just plucked
right out of that timeline. Oh, yeah, I totally get
those vibes. The Jack Kirby retrofuturism.
Absolutely. Yeah, it kind of lends this innocent,
happy tone to the film that I don't think you
necessarily would get if the movie was set in the
main MCU in the modern day. Things like, you know,
the kids asking the thing to pick up the car seems so
wholesome, you know, back in the 60s. Whereas
today, you know, you have a bunch of cynical
assholes would probably be like, oh, that's
cheesy. Yeah, today you have heroes like the
Thunderbolts who are dripping with cynicism
compared to the Fantastic Four. Right. Yeah. So
it's kind of cool that we're going to get that
dichotomy this summer from Marvel in the
theaters. We get a scene of Fantastic Four during
dinnertime, during which Sue and Reed show up late
and the thing correctly deduces that she is
pregnant. And Johnny gets super excited. This is
our first real look at Joseph Quinn's portrayal of
the Johnny Storm character. And I got to say, I like
it. I think it's pretty well done. Yeah, Joseph
Quinn is a great actor. I really liked him in
Stranger Things. So I was pretty excited when he
was cast for Johnny. I'm actually really liking
the entire cast, except again for Ben Grimm's
voice. Still not loving that. But the other
performances seem great. Yeah, I still wish that
the thing's voice was a little bit deeper, a little
bit more gravelly. But we'll see. One thing that I
do hope changes between now and the release date is
the special effects on Silver Surfer. They
weren't terrible, but I was hoping for a little bit
more definition in the character. She's pretty
low res right now, I would say. I want to say she's
low res, but I will say she's low articulation, if
that makes sense. If we're talking about like
action figures, this is more of like a Barbie than
like a McFarland, you know? Yeah, absolutely. I
don't mind the look. I still really question why
they decided to go with the shawla ball version of
Silver Surfer, who was a female version of the
character as portrayed in the Earth X mini series,
which is one of my favorite stories of all time. And
I know that they're trying to establish this movie
as set in an alternate universe. But considering,
you know, Galactus seems to be portrayed as we
traditionally know him, this female server
server really stands out as like the only thing
other than the time period that is setting this
film apart as an alternate universe story. And
because of that, I think she stands out like a sore
thumb. She should have been Frankie Ray, Nova, the
other Herald of Galactus after Silver Surfer in
the comics. I completely agree. Frankie Ray was
the character from the comics who used to be Johnny
Storm's girlfriend. And she was actually the, I
want to say niece of Phineas Horton, who created
the original Android Human Torch. She was exposed
to those chemicals. And so she had flame powers and
she was turned into a Herald of Galactus and she was
given the golden skin as opposed to silver like the
Silver Surfer. It would have been a great
spectacle to see on the screen. And they still
could have treated this as an alternate universe
story. We still could have saved the Noran Red
Silver Surfer for the primary Marvel timeline.
It's just it's strange why they chose to go with
Shawla Ball. I also think that Julia Garner could
have made a great Frankie Ray. Oh, yeah, she would
have been perfect for the role. There was a shot
here that was a little bit too reminiscent of the
rise of the Silver Surfer film where we saw Johnny
Storm chase the Silver Surfer out into space and
then get knocked back down to earth. I really hope
this story doesn't hit too many of those same beats
that that 2007 movie did. I do have to say I love what
they're doing with the characters in this film. It
seems so much better than the past films. Like Reed
Richards, dramatic arc, his internal conflict is
very apparent in this trailer. I think Pedro
Pascal is going to do an amazing job in the role. The
guilt that he feels over possibly bringing
attention to earth and possibly leading to its
destruction from Galactus is a fantastic story
beat for the character. They seem to be making so
many cool choices, like with a fantastic car, the
way their powers are portrayed are pretty cool,
including Mr. Fantastic, who he's got to see
stretch for the first time here. And Galactus
looks like he's going to be phenomenal. Oh, yeah,
the invisibility powers that we got to see for a Sue
Storms character that looked so damn cool. Yeah,
it was like a prism, kind of like bending light
where you get that kind of rainbow aura at the edge.
Yeah, I liked how only parts of her were like
turning invisible. She was definitely strained,
but it looked like she was bending light. So cool.
I'm really looking forward to this, but I got to say
Marvel is not too late to just redo the special
effects around your Shala Ball Silver Surfer as
Frankie Ray, the Herald called Nova. It probably
is too late. It's not too late, but that brings us to
our question of the week. What do you think of the
Shala Ball Silver Surfer from the Fantastic Four
First Steps official trailer? So similar to how we
asked you guys about the most controversial
element of the latest Superman preview we saw,
where we asked you guys what you thought about
crypto. Now we're asking your thoughts about the
Silver Surfer. Record your answer at
dynamicdool.com by clicking on the red
microphone button in the bottom right hand corner
of the screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long and don't forget to leave your name in case we
include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a Dynamic
Duel No Prize that we'll post to Instagram. Be sure
to answer before April 26th. In DC News, we finally
got a release date for Sandman Season 2, which is
coming out later this year. In two parts. It came
with a brief teaser trailer. They're calling it a
date announcement in which we get to see all of the
members of the Endless, well, six of the seven at
least, which I've been dying to see. Like ever
since I started reading the Sandman comics and
dreamed of this being adapted on screen, like the
Endless are the coolest characters ever. And so to
see them all together kind of blew my mind and
totally has me pumped for this upcoming season.
Yeah, let me see if I can name them all real quick,
being someone who's never read the Sandman
series. I know there was Destiny at the beginning
of the trailer. Of course, there is his sister
Death and Dream. And of course, we saw Desire and
Despair from the previous season. I think the new
one that we're seeing here, step out of the
painting is Delirium, but I'm not clear who the
missing seventh member is. So the missing seventh
member is Destruction, and he is the embodiment of
change as a word, sort of in the same way that Shiva
is the embodiment of destruction and change and
Hinduism. OK, now Delirium is a fan favorite
character. She actually started off as Delight,
but over the eons, she morphed into Delirium
because she was kind of a cosmic afterthought, as
it were. So she's this very tragic figure, someone
who's all powerful, but also insane, though she
wasn't always. I'm really curious to see what they
do with her character and with all of the endless,
honestly. You know, we got to see characters like
Death and Despair and Desire in the first season,
but they get more heavily involved in Dream's
story in these subsequent volumes. So yeah,
things are going to get good. Now, this season is
going to be 11 episodes total, the first six of
which will be released July 3rd, and the second
volume or the second half will be premiering July
24th, and that's five episodes. Now, we know that
this series has been Warner Brothers' most
expensive television series to date. Oh, and you
could definitely tell. Yes. For sure. Everything
looks incredible from the costuming to the set
design. The visual effects are incredible.
Everything. Everything is incredible. I really
enjoyed the first season of the show with the
exception of a few acting performances. I'm
really hoping season two tops that. I imagine it
will just because of the story and all the
different characters that we'll get to meet,
including Kay, Thor. Did you see that? Oh, is that
who that guy was? Yeah. What a poser. Sandman Thor,
way better than Marvel Thor. You'll find out. I
immediately and strongly disagree with that
statement. I recently canceled my Netflix
subscription, but I'm definitely going to get
back for this series because it may just be my
favorite series of all time. OK, calm down. Calm
down. It might suck. You never know. Dude, did you
see the footage? Did you see the footage? I did. I
know that a good trailer does not make a good
series. Now, we should address the elephant in the
room. Has the news about author Neil Gaiman's
general shittiness affected your anticipation
of this season? No, I could give two shits about
Neil Gaiman. Not going to lie. To me, it's all about
the art, not the artist. I understand sometimes
that people don't want to engage with the art
because they feel like they're supporting the
artist. But at the end of the day, I grew up reading
this series and there's no way I'm skipping out on
this. Yeah, I think at some point you got to say,
fuck them. What they created belongs more now to
the fan base. Well, in the case of the Sandman
universe, almost that exactly because other
creators have picked up where he left off and
created an entire Sandman universe. This is why
you don't want to meet your heroes, kids, because
everyone sucks. DC High Volume, Batman, the Dark
Knight's definitive DC comic stories adapted
directly for audio for the very first time. Fear. I
have to make them afraid. He's got a motorcycle.
Get after him or have you shot? You mean blow up the
building? From this moment on, none of you are
safe. New episodes every Wednesday, wherever you
get your podcasts. But that does it for the news
portion of this episode. Now let's go ahead and
move on to the main event where we review the Disney
Plus and Marvel Studios television series
Daredevil, born again season one. OK, Daredevil,
Born Again is a nine episode Disney Plus
television series run by Dario Skardapane and
starring Charlie Cox and Vincent D'Onofrio. The
show is a direct continuation of the three season
Daredevil Netflix series, which is largely
considered one of the best, if not the best,
superhero television series of all time. I
personally rated each of the first three seasons
of the Netflix show as no less than four and a half
out of five stars, including season three, which I
gave a perfect five star rating. I think the big
question in fans minds was was this new show going
to compare to what came before? And there's a whole
lot to talk about in regards to that. So if you
haven't seen the show, I'm going to say I recommend
seeing it. Go ahead and watch it before listening
to our spoiler breakdown of this season. In fact,
go watch all three seasons of the Netflix show if
you haven't before and then watch Born Again.
Right, because we'll be discussing spoilers from
those seasons as well. And honestly, those
seasons are masterpieces for the most part.
They're worth it. I'm not going to say they're the
best superhero television series ever, but it's
definitely the best Marvel series ever. The best
superhero television series of all time. Yes, I
think we were all hoping after the Netflix deal
with Marvel ended that somehow, somewhere, some
way we'd get to see these characters again.
Thankfully, it wasn't too long before we got the
news that the series rights were coming back to
Marvel and that they were continuing the show. And
then, you know, they cameoed Charlie Cox as Matt
Murdock in projects like Spider-Man, No Way Home
and She-Hulk, Attorney at Law, Season One. And
then we also got to see Kingpin show up in shows like
Hawkeye and Echo. When they first announced the
new season as Daredevil Born Again, I understood
from a branding standpoint why they would call it
that, considering the show was being retooled
under a new streaming service. But at the time of
that announcement, I did object to that name
because, you know, we've already seen Daredevil
Born Again adapted masterfully in season three of
the Netflix show, born again being, you know, the
name of a story arc from the comic books. I was
concerned that the show runners were going to try
to retread old ground with the story of Matt
rebuilding himself from rock bottom. But despite
the season's subtitle, the show instead chose the
interesting angle of adapting the Mayor Fisk
storyline from the comics, which I thought was
fascinating, because in this take, both of the
main characters spend a majority of the season
trying to be something they're not. You know, Matt
tries to be just a lawyer, not a vigilante. Fisk
tries to go straight and just be a mayor, not some
crime boss. But each one over the course of the show
is fooling themselves. And as the episodes go on,
they slowly are reborn into their chur selves. So
Daredevil Born Again as the title works both in
terms of branding and in tailoring this
adaptation to that brand. Yeah, it's kind of like
Spider-Man Homecoming in that I think it was
Marvel Studios kind of claiming ownership of that
character and the story that they were going to
tell. Yeah, we know that the initial approach to
the show is to actually ignore the three seasons
that came before and treat it as its own thing. And
then during the actor and writer strikes, they
realized that that was the wrong way to go. Dario
Scarpina, who worked on the Punisher Netflix
show, came aboard and reworked the show so that
they retained the continuity from the Netflix
show, which all the fans loved. Yeah, the show kind
of went through development hell. They've been
going so far as to rewrite and reshoot the entire
season, scrap everything they had so far. I was
worried that that was going to be evident in this
season and it was. But that's not saying that I
thought the season was bad. I think the worst thing
you could say about the season is that it's the
worst season of Daredevil. But that's not saying a
lot just because the other three seasons were
amazing. And this one was still good. I would
agree. Yeah, the season overall had somewhat of a
tonal disparity that was definitely a product of
the production issues it had. But somehow, you
know, they still produced a show that was at the
very least comparable to the Netflix series,
right? Like it maybe didn't reach those heights,
but pretty damn close. And that's pretty
commendable, considering what they went through
while making it. I feel like if they had another
episode or two, it absolutely would have been even
more comparable to what we got with Netflix
because they definitely left me wanting more this
season. Yeah. Now, the Mayor Fisk storyline from
the comics was fascinating because Fisk becoming
the mayor essentially had Daredevil retreat from
his vigilante persona because Fisk owned the
police and the courts. In the comics, it forced
Matt as the then assistant and district attorney
to take a much more political approach to bringing
down the kingpin. It was a very political story
where after a failed assassination attempt on
Fisk, Matt used special constitutional
emergency powers to seize some control from the
kingpin and restore order to New York. And that
leads to the devil's rain storyline. Now, this
shows adaptation of that story took a much less
political approach to the mayor Fisk arc, which I
think is a good thing because the political
aspects of Daredevil board again, I think were
fairly slow and uninteresting. Like I really
couldn't care less about Fisk being labeled a
union buster in the press. And then like, you know,
the intern guy has to give a heartfelt apology for
it and stuff like that. I was like, let's keep
things moving. As decent an actor, I think James
Gandolfini's son, I can't remember his name was. I
just think his character was a little bit
unnecessary. I kind of saw him as being the son that
the kingpin never had. You know, we just got done
seeing kingpin in the Echo series where he tried to
mentor Echo and have that child that he never had.
But this young guy on his political team ended up
being much more of a natural surrogate. I guess it
was good to get the perspective of people who did
support Fisk, which is why I think it was also
important to include those like documentary
style shots of the people of New York, you know,
giving their say. That was really interesting.
That was something that they did here that they
didn't do in the Netflix show. And I thought it
brought a vital like New York element to the show. I
loved those moments from BB Yurick. Those were
really well crafted. They felt like they were
real, right, which kind of made the whole show feel
like it was a little bit more real. It's an
interesting technique that I've seen before in
films, like when Harry met Sally or something like
that, just real people telling real stories. I
thought it really nailed the New York aspect of the
show, which is important in a daredevil show. I
thought it was like a good analog for real life, you
know, when you see interviews and surveys with
people who vote differently from you, you know,
it's it's so hard to conceive of someone who has a
different perspective. And then, yeah, you see
that there are actually people who think this way.
There are actually people who would vote for
kingpin because of the security provides
against, you know, some of the superhero related
tragedies that have befallen the city of New York.
In this adaptation of the mayor Fisk storyline, I
think the show took the more interesting approach
of having Matt and Kingpin find themselves after
their own respective tragedies, foggy's death
and getting shot by echo, forcing them to
reevaluate their lives. It was a good launching
point for the story. And I thought it was
believable that Fisk might run for mayor after
taking some time to reevaluate. And that Matt
would abandon Daredevil for a time. That being
said, you know, it's a little bit disappointing
that it takes two thirds of the season to get Matt
back to being Daredevil again. I know that
Daredevil season three had a similar buildup to
getting him back in the suit. Right. But that
season executed its pacing flawlessly in my mind.
Not so much with this born again season. And apart
from some pretty fucking brutal book and
episodes, born again as a whole felt a little bit
tamer than the Netflix show, both thematically
and in terms of the violence. Though I'll say that
this season did have the most violence he never,
which was like bordering on fucking horror film
levels of violence when Kingpin crushed
Commissioner Gallo's head. That was, I don't
know, unnecessary. Yeah, it felt like out of
place, right? I was like, this isn't the fucking
terrifier. Like you could have gotten away with
the gruesomeness using sound effects alone. Kind
of like how they did when Kingpin decapitated a guy
in the car door in Daredevil season one. You know,
right? They didn't show it explicitly, but we
still got every ounce of the impact. Absolutely. I
don't need to see Kingpin literally pulling a
guy's jaw off and like, you know, all the sinew and
stuff that comes when you tear it away. Like you
would think that someone in there at that point
would have been like, fuck, I think we're working
for the bad guy here. Shit. It's like, I'm out. I'm
out. That was that was that was a lot, bro. Beyond
the time it took for the characters to get back to
their roles and the tonal inconsistencies. I
think the most disappointing thing about born
again was that due to time constraints during
their period of retooling the show, they have the
number of episodes for season one, because season
one was initially going to be 18 episodes. Oh, wow.
That's way too many episodes. But now it's two
seasons of nine episodes. And then season two is
going to be eight episodes. So the final episode
here, you know, if it felt more like a mid season
finale than a proper season finale, that's
because it is in a way. And it doesn't quite seem
entirely fair to judge a story based solely on its
first half, but since that's how they chose to
release it, that's what we're left to do. And I will
say that with the disappointing feeling that I
felt with this quote unquote season finale, that
disappointment will be reflected in my final
rating of this season. Well, as it should be, like I
mentioned earlier, I definitely noticed the
production problems that this season had. In part
with the sudden cliffhanger drop off in this final
episode of the season, that was totally coming by
surprise, by the way. Like I was just waiting for
the next episode and I was like, wait, what? What?
And I guess it's not bad to leave your audience
wanting more. But I would have appreciated some
more catharsis. This feels very much like
Infinity War or the Empire Strikes Back, but
definitely not at the caliber of those projects.
Right. My least favorite thing wasn't the ending.
It was, like you mentioned, just some of the filler
moments, like the bank episode, I felt it was like
an entire filler episode. I loved that episode,
though. It was standalone, but I thought it was
like a perfect standalone that felt almost right
out of the comics. I could see that. I would have
rather skipped it. I didn't need it. There
definitely was a filler episode here, but it
wasn't that episode. Really? Yeah. I'll be
interested in hearing this. Well, that'll be in
our episode highlights. But before that, let's
get into our character breakdown. Starting with
Daredevil, aka Matt Murdock, played by Charlie
Cox. We've talked about Charlie Cox before on this
podcast. He's a flawless Daredevil in my mind. The
guy not only embodies the role, but I think
transcends it with all the nuance he brings to his
performance. It's so great to have him back in the
role. You know, he had his cameos and other
projects, but I think where Matt Murdock really
shines is in the dichotomy between his charm as
Matt Murdock and his rage as Daredevil. And in
order to get that full character spread, you need
to see him on his own. As mentioned before, Matt was
on a journey back to being Daredevil after
retiring from the role because of the tragic loss
of his best friend, Foggy Nelson, and stepping
over his own personal ethical code in trying to
kill Bullseye for that. Over the course of the
episodes, we see him drift toward his vigilante
tendencies more and more, you know, starting with
a simple warning over a cup of coffee with a
kingpin. And then, you know, he ends up dusting off
his billy club and then he goes on to beat the shit
out of some people. And then eventually he dons the
suit once again. I think I've said multiple times
in this podcast's tenure that there's nothing
harder than sitting through a superhero project
watching the main character not want to be the hero
we know and love. I know I said that with the first
half of Luke Cage, season one, and I think I
definitely said it for She-Hulk, Attorney at Law.
And I'll say it again here, it was hard to get
through those episodes wanting to see him be
Daredevil again. Yeah, I definitely felt like
this was somewhat retread of season three. Like
you mentioned, where it kind of takes the whole
season for him to get back into costume. I agree. I
don't love that. I don't think it was as well done as
season three, but it would be really hard to match
that. They tried at least. Yeah, at least they
showed us that Matt really did want to be Daredevil
again and did a good job of putting him in
situations like the Bank Heist where he still got
to show off his powers, you know, just outside of
his Daredevil outfit. And I liked the Daredevil
outfit for this season. I thought it was a cool
texture upgrade. And I liked the new Billy Club,
although it seems infinitely more dangerous than
the other Billy... I mean, Daredevil is good like
that. He's a marksman. He has his radar sense. I
don't think that's going to happen, but it does
seem needlessly lethal for a character who never
really goes that far. That said, his radar sense
this season seemed different than in past
seasons. Like, he had a harder time focusing on
multiple things at once. Like he'd be focusing on
one thing and miss something else entirely. That
happened multiple times this season. I think that
was more of a product of his rage, such as the Muse
fight or something like that, than his actual
powers going funky. No, I don't think it was his
powers going funky. I just think it was a choice on
behalf of the creative team. Like he would be
focusing on someone's footsteps so much that he
would almost get run over in the street and it's
like, oh, that's not the Daredevil I know. The
Daredevil I know has like a very keen spatial
awareness. It's his radar sense. I really did like
how the show, especially in the first episode, I
noticed used aspect ratio to try to portray what he
was focusing on. So like the letterbox format
would shift to almost full screen on some parts
where the audience got to hone in on exactly what
Matt was focusing on. It was very artistic and it's
not something that they did too much outside of
that first episode, unfortunately. It just
seemed to me more like they were focusing on his
senses rather than this sixth radar sense that he
typically has. Well, I always kind of interpreted
his radar sense as the internal image he gets from
all the sensory data that comes into him. Yes, like
echolocation. Yeah. And in season one of
Daredevil, they portrayed it very much like a city
on fire type thing, which I thought was really
cool. I really want them to go back to that. Yeah,
that'd be cool to see again for sure. Let's go ahead
and move on to the kingpin, AKA Wilson Fisk played
by Vincent D'Onofrio. Just like Charlie Cox, it is
so nice to see Vincent D'Onofrio back in the role in
this main show and not just in cameos anymore. Like
his appearance in Hawkeye was lackluster and his
role in Echo was fine. And he was like the best thing
about Echo season one. But only in the Daredevil
show do you truly get a feel for how sadistic and
terrifying the character is, I think. And really,
I think this is the most terrifying we've probably
ever seen him, especially in the last episode of
this season, when he had the whole face ripoff
thing and then his smile to Vanessa at the end when
they were having dinner together. It was like some
Hannibal Lecter type stuff. Like D'Onofrio was
really pulling from some of his creepier roles
that he's had in like the cell or something like
that. Oh, dude, like making Vanessa shoot her
former lover that she had when she thought he was
gone and dead. Yeah, that was trippy. Yeah, their
whole relationship got a lot more focused here
than I thought it would. But I was definitely along
for the ride. I like where they took it. Yeah, he had
a phenomenal arc this season, I thought. There was
an interesting note that they made this season. It
was really kind of almost a throwaway line that
Vanessa said in the final episode, episode nine,
that served to bridge the gap between the Netflix
show and Hawkeye. At the end of Daredevil Season
Three, I think we all assumed that Kingpin was
going to be locked up forever. But in this season,
we learned that he was acquitted by his defense
attorneys who painted the FBI, including people
like Agent Nadine, as corrupt. And if you go back
and watch Daredevil Season Three, it's just so
fucking tragic. Considering how cathartic the
end of that show was and how it really felt like Matt
and Agent Nadine got justice there. And it turns
out, yeah, they did it. No, Kingpin was acquitted
just like he always is. It was kind of bullshit.
Yeah, I could see that. But I also don't see any
other way around it, really. Well, yeah, the bad
guys always got to come back, right? And, you know,
they already established the fact that Kingpin
was not in jail from shows like Hawkeye and shows
like Echo. Right. So I figured something went
wrong somewhere. I did think it was cool how
Vincent DeNafio bulked up over the episodes. I
don't know if he bulked up like physically or if it
was just the tailoring of his suits. But I did
notice upon his first reveal, I was like, oh, he's
skinnier. And they even mentioned that in the
show. Matt comments, you've lost weight and
everything. But by the end, dude was fucking
massive. So that was a really believable
transformation that I thought was pretty dope.
Apparently he was bulking up down in that secret
dungeon that he had. He definitely looked a lot
better and more dapper here than he had in shows
like Hawkeye and Echo. I loved DeNafio as Kingpin.
He's perfect in the role. Let's go ahead and move on
to the Punisher, a.k .a. Frank Castle, played by
John Berndthal. It was nice to see the Punisher
back. I still think that Berndthal is the most
compelling actor to play the character. I'm not
quite sure that they used Frank Castle as well as
they could have during this season. No. I was a
little underwhelmed by Matt and Frank's initial
meetup. I don't think it held a candle to any of
their interactions in Daredevil season two,
which were like Shakespearean in quality. I don't
know if I would go that far, but it was so much better
than what they did here. Yes, Shakespearean.
Okay. I was so glad that Punisher showed up again in
the final episode. That way we could see him get in
action scene with Daredevil. And we saw him
address the issue of the Punisher copycats, which
I was hoping was a thread that they wouldn't leave
dangling. Yeah, it's so relevant to the real
world. Would you have some cops and some authority
figures touting a Punisher logo as a symbol that
they aspire to? It's not great. No, I don't love
that. I've been wanting to get a Punisher tattoo
for the longest time. I have a Captain America
shield on one shoulder. I wanted to get a Punisher
skull on the other. It's kind of like that
dichotomy, the angel-devil shoulder kind of
motif. And I won't get a Punisher tattoo now
because I think it's been co-opted by people who
shouldn't be using it necessarily. I don't mind
gun enthusiasts using the Punisher logo, but I do
have a problem with law enforcement using it
because it's a symbol of a person who deals out
lethal justice because in part they've gone
insane and I just don't think it's a good look. I
hate when I see the Punisher skull with the thin
blue line. Yeah, I don't think anyone should be
using the Punisher logo, honestly. Some
positions in society should be held to a higher
standard, I would say personally. And that
standard should not be the Punisher. Right, yeah.
He's an interesting character, one of Marvel's
most interesting characters in fact, but I don't
think he's necessarily an inspiring character.
Peacemaker! They should just get Peacemaker
logos. So much better. The irony of that
statement. I wonder if we'll see Punisher again in
Daredevil Season 2 or if we'll only see him again in
the special presentation that Marvel's working
on. Either way, I hope we see what he does once he
escapes his cell as we saw him do in the
post-credits scene of the show. Dude, that was so
obvious. The cop who went to shake his hand is a
freaking idiot. Anthony was a big dum-dum for
sure. I kind of hope that we don't see the Punisher
in the following season of Born Again, just
because like you, I don't think he was really well
used here, which is surprising considering that
the Punisher showrunner came on board to the
writing team for this series. Yeah, well, I also
hope that he doesn't show up again in Season 2, not
because I don't want to see the character, but
because he's not really a team player. And so if you
have him teaming up with, you know, whether it be
the defenders or New York City's finest, I think it
would just be strange to see him be that kind of
person. He's more of a loner, you know? He was a
member of the Thunderbolts for a while in the
comics. He should have been in that movie. Yeah,
that was weird too, though. Let's go ahead and move
on to the character of Muse, aka Bastion Cooper,
who was played by Hunter Doohon. I'll say that I'm a
little bit conflicted with the characterization
of Muse in this series. On one hand, he ended up
being so much less mysterious than his comic book
counterpart, because in the comics, who he is
really isn't even human. Like, he has powers.
Like, he can absorb the sensory data in his close
proximity, which makes him hard to pinpoint. On
the other hand, I'll admit that adapting him as
this sort of Banksy artist serial killer, who
drains and paints with the blood of his victims was
pretty damn interesting. I didn't know anything
about the character of Muse from the comics. I
thought this character was pretty interesting in
this show, even though I felt like he kind of came
too little too late and then was gone by the time
things got interesting. Well, according to the
rumors, Muse was originally going to be the main
bad guy of the season. And then the show got
retooled and he was kind of sidelined. And I really
think that the show could have used him in a couple
more episodes than they had him in, just to build up
that mystery, you know? The actor who played him, I
thought did a decent job, even though it was very
obvious that he was Muse. I don't know if you saw the
show Wednesday, but it was the same bad guy actor.
So right away when I saw him, I was like, okay, he's
the bad guy. Honestly, he didn't even register to
me at the book signing when we first saw the
character, until the recap of the previous
episodes at the start of each episode, I realized,
oh, it's this guy. I thought the element of
painting with your victim's blood after draining
it was a really interesting modus operandi that we
haven't seen or I personally haven't seen in a lot
of like thriller material like shows and movies,
conceptually evil Banksy. It just felt kind of
neat. Yeah, I wonder what Banksy thinks of this
series. He probably hates it. I did think that the
revelation that he was like a Taekwondo expert was
a little bit convenient. That's right. It was a
little bit ridiculous. Like they needed to give
some kind of rationale for why he could hold his own
in a fight against Daredevil, but just kind of like
shoehorn again. Oh, I'm a Taekwondo champion was
silly at best. It's like, sure you are, pal. Sure
you are. Let's move on to Bullseye, aka Benjamin
Pointexter, played by Wilson Bethel. I really
like Wilson Bethel. I thought he was a force of
nature in Daredevil Season 3, and I was so glad that
they brought him back for board again. I think he
was a little underutilized, just like Muse here,
but he absolutely gave us the best action scene of
the season, which ironically was in Episode 1.
Yeah, it was the action scene that kicked off the
series, basically. Wilson Bethel's Bullseye is
still, I think, one of the most terrifying
villains we've probably ever seen in a superhero
television series. Seeing him come back just
brought me chills. I didn't know he was going to be
in the series. And when he was, I kind of thought he
was dispatched a little too quickly. I'm glad they
brought him back and it was cool to see some of the
things he did. But yeah, I definitely needed more
Bullseye this season. Yeah, I think newcomers to
the Daredevil show who hadn't seen the Netflix
previous seasons, I don't think we're
adequately, probably convinced of how scary this
character is based just on his showings in this
show. I mean, that first episode was incredible,
but I think you really have to see Daredevil Season
3 to get a grasp of the depth that has gone into this
character. I hope he comes back. I don't know where
the hell he went to in that last episode. Right? He
just disappeared. Yeah, I don't think he had any
reason to. He was trying to kill the kingpin for
putting him into general population, but he
probably would have been fine killing Matt and
Kingpin and Vanessa all in one go. But instead, he
missed a shot and then took off. It was strange.
Yeah, seeing Kingpin go to Windows to look outside
after an assassination attempt from Bullseye, I
was like, yeah, that's not a smart move. Like
Bullseye will always hunt you down. Exactly. And
also, I don't think putting Bullseye in general
population was actually a threat to him. I feel
like he could have killed every other prisoner
that was there, considering he can turn anything
into a weapon pretty much. Yeah, absolutely. I'm
wondering why he didn't. I don't know. But that's
it for the characters. Let's go ahead and move into
our episode highlights. In a world where
fantasies collide and heroes clash, one podcast
network rises above the rest. Prepare yourself
for the ultimate showdowns in comic books, video
games, movies, and anime. The Dynamite Podcast
Network presents Console Combat, where video
game legends brawl every Monday. Dynamic Duel,
where comic book titans smash every Tuesday. Max
Destruction, where TV and action heroes battle
every Wednesday. And Sendro World, where anime
champions clash every Thursday. Join us as we
speculate on the matches and armed with the power
of mathematical simulations, discover who will
emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com,
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
Episode 1 was called Heaven's Half Hour. While
celebrating the retirement of their NYPD
associate, Cherry, Matt Murdock, and his friends
are attacked by Bullseye, who shoots and kills
Foggy Nelson. In retaliation, Daredevil drops
the villain off a roof, an act seen by Cherry, who
learns that Matt is Daredevil. One year later,
Matt has retired as the hero and works at a new law
firm started with former DEA Kirsten McDuffie,
who sets him up with her friend Heather Glenn, a
therapist. Kingpin returns to New York after
spending time away recovering from being shot and
nearly killed. He has his wife Vanessa step away
from leading New York's crime in his stead and
announces his candidacy for mayor, running on an
anti-crime and anti-vigilante platform. Matt
and Fisk meet at a diner, warning each other to stay
in line. Seen as a tough and capable candidate by
the people of New York, Fisk wins the election for
mayor. He admits to Vanessa that he knows of the
affair she had with a man named Adam during his
absence. As the city celebrates, a graffiti
artist paints a mural of Fisk. To me, this was the
best episode. I always hate when that happens,
when the first episode was the best, but I don't
regret this one because I had such a good time
watching it. It really felt cathartic, you know,
getting the show that you know and love back and
just as good as you remember it. By the time those
opening credits rolled, after we saw Daredevil
throw Bullseye off the building after hearing
Foggy's heart stop and he tossed his helmet down
with all those blades sticking out of him, I was
floored. My jaw was on the ground and I was just able
to just like absorb that new opening credit scene
with a riff on the classic Daredevil theme, you
know, it was fantastic. I really wish the internet
wasn't so quick to spoil things for people. Like
right after the episode dropped, I learned that
Foggy Nielsen was going to die in the first
episode. And so it kind of ruined the whole opening
kind of bit for me. That's horrible. Well, you
still said you didn't know Bullseye was going to
show up, so you were surprised by that. That's
fair. Yeah, I was surprised by Bullseye, not by the
outcome of what happened, though. It was a cool
fight, though. I love how it was that, you know,
single tracking shot that the Daredevil series is
known for, where we got to see Daredevil and
Bullseye fight outside of Josie's Bar, come into
Josie's Bar, go up the stairwell, and then onto the
roof. The fight choreography was just
phenomenal. And seeing Bullseye like murder so
many people in the course of that fight, yeah, it
was horrifying. And also seeing Bullseye like
smack the pavement the way he did, I totally
thought they killed off the character. Me too. In
regards to some of the side characters, I don't
think Kirsten McDuffie was nearly as compelling
in the show as she is in the comics. She's a more fun
character in the comics, I think, a little more
witty. But I've never liked Heather Glenn,
whether it was in the comic books or in the show,
especially in the show, though, that she was a
waste of a character. You know, she actually
showed up in the 2003 Daredevil movie with Ben
Affleck. She was the one that left the voicemail on
his phone, breaking up with him, saying he was too
distant. That was Heather. Same character.
Interesting. In the book, she was like a socialite
heiress, if I remember correctly. Episode two was
called Optics. Hector Eliyat comes across two men
beating up another on a subway platform and tries
to stop them when one of the aggressors is hit by a
train and the other reveals themselves as a cop.
Matt overhears Hector's story and volunteers to
defend him against his murder charge. Charyon
covers that Hector is the vigilante known as White
Tiger. Information which Matt requests be held
from the trial, believing that a history of
violence would bias the jury. Fisk Blackmail's
New York Police Commissioner Gallo to prevent him
from resigning in protest of his election.
Heather begins counseling Kingpin and Vanessa's
marriage. Matt tracks down the subway platform
victim named Torres to get him to testify against
the cops, but he's interrupted by officers with
Punisher Skull Tattoos who attempt to attack him.
Matt savagely beats them in response when that's
the end of the episode. What did you think of White
Tiger in this series? I thought it was cool. I
thought his costume could use some work, although
he's kind of depicted as a homegrown type of
superhero. I thought it was canonically supposed
to be made out of jade. I don't know what it was made
out of here. It looked like silver, but I wish I
could have seen more of White Tiger in action in his
costume. Like we saw some like footage of it on the
BB Eurek report, but you know his ability is to be
three times the martial artist, three times the
strength, you know, three times the skill due to
the three pieces of the jade amulets. I think it
would have been cool to see that in action. Yeah,
that's what I was going to say. I would have loved to
have seen White Tiger in action. It was kind of
weird to hear Matt Murdock and everyone talking
about this amulet that he had that gives him like
superhuman powers. I was like, this is kind of
different from the more grounded Netflix shows
when they're talking about superpowers. Right.
Yeah. I mean, the fact that they're setting it more
in the MCU kind of got to give him a little bit more of
that leeway. But the fact that like the amulet
wasn't taken by the Department of Damage Control
or something like that, like his positions were
returned to his next of kin. You know, his niece,
Angela was in the show and she becomes his
successor as the White Tiger. This whole
storyline almost played exactly like how it did in
the comic books where he was framed for a murder of a
cop and Matt defends him, gets him acquitted, and
then White Tiger is shot and killed right after
leading to Angela taking up the mantle. Although
in this show, Angela is a lot younger. Yeah, I was
about to say she was way too short to be a superhero.
Yeah. She's not my favorite version of the White
Tiger, though. That's Eva Hector's sister. You
can learn more about White Tiger in our Dula
episode where we pit her against Bronze Tiger. I
want to say RIP to Kamar Dulos Reyes, the actor who
played White Tiger. He died in December 2023 from
cancer. Oh, no way. What? Yeah. He dedicated a few
episodes to him. I didn't make that connection. So
we've on to episode three, the hollow of his hand
with Kingpin stepping away from crime, the gang
leaders Victor and Luca start turning on each
other. Vanessa frustrated that her work is being
undone as Kingpin's right hand man Cashman
ordered Luca to pay Victor 1.8 million in
restitution. In court, the victim Taurus
declines to testify on Hector's behalf at a fear of
police retaliation, causing Matt to reveal his
client's White Tiger identity, focusing on
testimony from the people he saved over the years.
The jury finds Hector not guilty, which angers
Fisk due to his anti-vigilante stance. Despite
Matt warning him to lay low after being
exonerated, Hector dons his White Tiger costume
and is shot dead by a man wearing the Punisher
symbol. I thought this was a great legal episode. I
always like seeing the legal cases that Matt takes
on play out in the courts. It's one of the unique
aspects of the Daredevil comic and these
Daredevil shows. And also, you know, the She-Hulk
shows, which you know how I felt about that show in
our review. But I always like a good legal drama.
And I thought that played out pretty well here.
Yeah, it played out as one of the better trials that
have been in the entire series. I agree. And the
ending was sufficiently tragic. When I saw the
Punisher skull, I was like, that wasn't Frank. So I
knew that they were kind of going to address the
police idolatry of the character of Punisher,
that whole theme within the course of this show,
which I was really looking forward to. I actually
thought the mystery of who shot White Tiger was
going to be the main focus of the show. It was kind of
weird when they were deviating with subplots
after that. Yeah, it was kind of pushed off to the
side, which is unfortunate, especially for the
character of White Tiger. And I wasn't thrilled by
the reveal that it was Cole North, who in this show
was a member of the anti-vigilante task force. But
in the comic books, he's actually a police
detective. It's more like the character of Cherry
within this show, except more of a badass because
he can fight. It was very against the type of
character that he is in the comic books. In the
comic books, he's more of a hero. Yeah, the reveal
that he was the killer was so anti-cli-backed. I
was like, come on, it was one of the things that kind
of made me feel that there was trouble going on
behind the scenes story-wise. Yeah, maybe.
Episode 4 was called Six Semper Systema. Matt
comforts Hector's niece Angela, who believes the
cops killed her uncle. Kingpin and Vanessa
discuss her affair with Adam in therapy. Matt
represents a man arrested for stealing caramel
corn. Fisk announces his plan to rebuild the
city's Red Hook port, which some suspect is a cover
to build up his future criminal endeavors. Matt
tracks the bullet casing used to kill Hector and
sees the Punisher skull on it. He tracks down
Punisher to ask if he's Hector's killer and if not
to take responsibility for those misusing his
symbol. Frank calls Matt out on his anger and his
failure to avenge Foggy. Matt contemplates the
Daredevil mantle while pulling his billy club out
of storage as Fisk has dinner in a secret dungeon
where he's keeping Adam. I thought this was the
filler episode. A lot of it was just kind of
unimportant. You know, the biggest thing about
this episode was the Matt and Frank meetup, but
that was weak as hell. I just really didn't like how
that played out, because the way it ended, it
almost played like a scene from Good Will Hunting,
where Frank was like, you're angry about Foggy's
death, ain't ya? Well, it's not your fault, Red.
It's not your fault. And Matt's like, don't fuck
with me, man. And then, you know, they share a cry.
And I'm sitting over here like, what the fuck is
going on? Right, 100%. I was like, well, that's
unusually intuitive for Frank Castle. Right. The
whole caramel corn thing. What the fuck was that
about? It was supposed to be a commentary on
society, you know? It really hit home when the guy
was like, you know, the city's willing to pay five
times as much to have me incarcerated than to help
me eat. You know, it was really tragic hearing
about him, you know, digging through trash and
stuff like that. And a lot of people are in this
vicious cycle. But, you know, that whole plot
thread really never went anywhere. I don't know if
they were trying to go for like Stiltman in the
Netflix shows here. I think it would have been
better if they would have, because at least I would
have cared a little bit more. Oh, you're talking
about Turk Barrett? Yes. Yeah, in the comic books,
he's Stiltman, but they never showed him in his
Stilts. They only referenced him in the old
Netflix show. They should have made Turk come
back. I really like Turk. I thought he was a great
character in the old show. Moving on to episode
five, which was called With Interest. On St.
Patrick's Day, Matt visits New York Mutual Bank to
seek out a loan for his firm, where he speaks with
assistant bank manager Yusuf Khan, the father of
Kamala Khan, the hero known as Ms. Marvel. During
their meeting, a group of bank robbers working for
Luca take everyone in the bank hostage, seeking
access to the vault to get the $1.8 million he needs
for his debt. The lead robber, Devlin, negotiates
with Detective Kim while Yusuf is taken to open the
vault. Matt subdues two of the robbers and opens
the vault where they find a rare diamond the
robbers were trying to get. Matt pretends to hand
over the diamond right as the police storm the bank
and rescue the hostages. Devlin disguises
himself as a cop and escapes, believing he's in the
clear, but he's followed by Matt who beats the
ever-loving shit out of him. Matt secretly
returns the diamond to Yusuf at the bank. Like I
said earlier, I liked this episode. I don't know if
you liked it as much as I did, but it felt like a story
that you'd get in between arcs in the comics, you
know? And I really like how cleverly it played out
where one of the hostages was on the inside with the
criminals and stuff like that. I thought it was
pretty well done and well executed. I just hated
how it really didn't play into the rest of the show.
One shots are cool. I don't think they're cool in
television series though. Yeah, I mean, like
there was the major side plot between Victor and
Luca, the crime bosses, but they didn't really
focus on that too much. So it was weird to see it get
an entire episode dedicated to that subplot here.
You're right. But we got a really cool cameo from
Yusuf Khan, the father of Kamala Khan, which I
think was totally in keeping with the types of
cameos that you would see in the books. Yeah,
that's true. I thought the best part of this
episode though was the Irish joke. I mean, it was
good. I think that was to pad the runtime a little
bit. 100%, but it was actually funny. Let's go to
move on to episode six, Excessive Force. After her
body is discovered with its eyes gouged out, Luca
visits Fisk, who tells him that he has a week to pay
his debt. A sanitation worker tells Fisk that the
murals around the city are painted by the
mysterious artist Muse using human blood. Angela
Diltoro visits Matt at his firm informing him that
her late uncle, White Tiger, was looking into
finding a serial killer who was hiding in the
subway tunnels. Fisk meets with New York's elite
edda fundraiser, including Jack Duquesne, who
rejects his plans to build the Red Hook port. Fisk
puts together a vigilante task force of crooked
cops and grants them impunity to go after Muse.
Angela investigates Muse's location herself and
is taken as his next victim. Her family contacts
Matt to report her missing, and he finally
redaunts his Daredevil suit to rescue her. He
fights and nearly kills Muse, but the villain
escapes as Daredevil tries to save Angela from
bleeding out. Meanwhile, Fisk beats Adam in a
secret dungeon. I was not expecting to see
swordsmen come back from the Hawkeye show. It was
really cool to see him here, and I hope that he joins
Daredevil's team in season two of Daredevil Born
Again. Yeah, I'm really curious to see who they
will put on that team. I was hoping they would kind
of hint at it, maybe with the cameo from the
defenders or something like that. But yeah, it
would be cool if he was a part of that team. He was
captured with a punisher, maybe the punisher set
some free, I don't know. That'd be cool. Episode
seven is called Art for Art's Sake. Inna Angela
recovers in the hospital and tells authorities
the location of Muse's lair. Detective Kim tells
Fisk that the primary suspect of the Muse's
identity is an artist and taekwondo expert,
Bastion Cooper, who happens to be one of Heather's
therapy patients. Luka meets with Vanessa, who
asks her to take back control of the mob behind
Fisk's back. Daredevil finds paintings of
Heather in Muse's lair and goes to her office where
Muse has her restrained and plans to kill her.
Daredevil rescues her and fights Muse, ending
with Heather shooting and killing the villain
before fainting from blood loss. Fisk has his task
force take credit for taking down Muse and
rescuing Heather. Cashman kills Luka in a trap set
by Vanessa. I liked this episode. I thought the
fight between Muse and Daredevil was like hella
violent. A lot of blood spray, especially when
Daredevil shoots his billy club through him and
stuff like that. I thought it was an action packed
hero versus a villain fight. It was nice to see
those two kind of clash together again after their
initial bout in the previous episode. Yeah, it was
a great superhero versus super villain battle. I
do really wish that the Muse arc was not just like a
two episode thing and that they really would have
established him more in earlier episodes. I did
think it was kind of convenient that he was
obsessed with Daredevil's girlfriend. But I also
think that the whole therapy sessions between
Wilson Fisk, his wife and Daredevil's girlfriend
was also very convenient, considering the fact
that I'm not entirely certain Wilson Fisk was
going to her to learn about Matt, like Matt
suspected. No, I think they were legitimately
trying to work on their marriage. But by the end of
this, when you know she becomes one of his cabinet
members, I totally think it's going to be to get
information on Matt. Yeah, probably. Episode
eight was called Isle of Joy. In prison, Bullseye
gets moved from solitary to the general
population. Kingpin reveals Adam's secret
prison to Vanessa who kills Adam to reconcile
their marriage. At Josie's bar, Matt deduces that
Foggy's death was an orchestrated hit by
Bullseye, not out of some vendetta. Matt visits
Bullseye in prison for information, but Bullseye
only agrees to talk on condition of his release,
resulting in Matt smashing his face into the
table. At a fundraiser ball, Kingpin begins
consolidating his power over the elites who
rejected his Red Hook Port Restoration. Bullseye
uses his broken tooth to escape prison and break
into the ball. Matt deduces that it was Vanessa who
ordered the hit on Foggy, not Kingpin. Matt then
hears Bullseye's rifle about to shoot at Kingpin
and takes the bullet through the chest. I gotta say
Heather annoyed the shit out of me this episode. I
normally wouldn't comment on this, but I was that
annoyed. She tells Matt like, Daredevil didn't
save me. I saved me. Muse and Daredevil were there
for themselves. It's like Chica. You were getting
sliced into with a scalpel when Daredevil
arrived. He literally had Muse impaled when you
shot him. You didn't save shit, okay? Yeah, that
was pretty ridiculous. I actually really liked
this episode. These last two episodes, I felt
like, were what the show should have been from the
beginning. I thought they were really good. And I
think a lot of it has to do with Bullseye. Again, the
character is just really cool and a great
Daredevil villain. Even though the end of this
episode was kind of ridiculous, I thought,
considering we already know that Wilson Fisk
wears bulletproof suits. And I'm pretty sure Matt
knew that as well. I don't know if Bullseye knew
that though, because he obviously wasn't going
for a headshot for Kingpin. But if Matt knew that,
why did he take the bullet? Great question. Maybe
he somehow knew that Fisk wasn't wearing a
bulletproof suit at this time. I guess maybe.
Let's go ahead and move on to the final episode
called Straight to Hell. In a flashback to one year
earlier, Vanessa frees Bullseye from his
psychiatric facility in exchange for killing
Foggy, who's working on a case involving the Red
Hook Port, where she launders her money. Back in
the present, Matt wakes up in hospital,
critically injured, but alive. Kingpin orders
New York City to be shut down in an effort to hunt
down his enemies, causing a city-wide power
outage, and orders Cashman to kill Matt in the
hospital. Matt escapes during the blackout and
heads home where he finds the Punisher ready to
assist him. Together, they fight off the
anti-vigilante task force who break into Matt's
apartment, and they learn that one of the cops was
White Tiger's murderer. The pair argue about
Frank's lethal force, but jump out of the window to
avoid a grenade. The pair are picked up by Karen
Page, who, along with Matt, learn in Foggy's files
that the Red Hook Port is a historical free port
exempt from state and national jurisdiction, and
that the Fisks are trying to create their own
city-state there. Punisher is captured after
single-handedly trying to take down the
anti-vigilante task force cops, and denies their
offer to join them. Kingpin learns of
Commissioner Gallo's attempt to undermine him,
and smashes and tears his face apart with his bare
hands in front of his force. He declares martial
law in New York, and Daredevil begins recruiting a
contingent of honest police and other dissidents
to save the city. In a post-credits scene,
Punisher breaks the guards' arm to escape his
cell. I thought there were some great fanboy
moments here. Seeing Daredevil and Punisher team
up again, this time both of them in costume, was so
cool to see as a fan. Because they've teamed up
before in the Netflix shows, but never with them in
their outfits. There's just something really
exciting about that as a fan. And it was so
well-written too. After they jump out of the
building to avoid the explosion, they land on the
car, and they get off, and Matt's like, you're an
asshole, Frank. And Punisher's just like, I know.
It was just great fan service. Yeah, I was
wondering who was the friend that called Frank to
go help Matt. And when it was revealed to be Karen
Page, I was like, oh, that's right. She was a big
part of Punisher Season 1. I totally forgot about
that connection. I'm so glad that they brought the
actors for Foggy Nelson and Karen Page back,
because that would have been really weird to even
have the Punisher in the Daredevil show again
without that connection. Yeah, Deborah N. Wall is
fantastic. She was great in the Daredevil show.
She was great in the Punisher show. It was nice that
she served as the bridge between those two
characters. And it just felt right that she would
be the one to kind of facilitate that team up. And I
really hope that she sticks around for Daredevil
Season 2, because I think she plays an important
role that I think was kind of missed in the course of
this season. There was a great emotional moment
between her and Matt at the end of this episode,
where Matt admits to Karen that after Foggy died,
he didn't know who he was anymore. And her
reassuring him that no matter what Foggy always
believed in him, I thought was just a great
springboard for this renewed sense of self going
into Season 2 and taking the fight to the kingpin.
Right. Foggy would not have wanted him to give up
pursuing justice the way he does. But that's the
end of the show. Overall, I think there was a lot to
enjoy here, especially as a fan of the Netflix
series. And while it didn't necessarily quite
reach the heights of the Netflix series, when you
consider that the first episode and the last two
episodes were the best of the season, I'm even more
hyped going into Daredevil Born Again Season 2,
which will come out next March. Like its namesake
character, the show rediscovers itself as it
goes, resulting in an uneven, yes, but ultimately
comparable season to the Netflix series before
it. And I think that's the best thing you could say
about it. I'm giving it four out of five stars, a
fresh rating on Rotten Tomatoes. Although you'll
note that it is a lower rating than any of the other
Daredevil seasons that we've rated. Yeah, I said
it was the worst Daredevil season, but the other
ones were just so damn good. I feel like there was
inevitable, you know. The show started off really
strong and it ended really strong. And while I
didn't love a lot of the stuff in the middle, I'd
still recommend it to anyone who is a fan of the
Netflix shows. And I'm definitely looking
forward to seeing what they bring next year.
Absolutely. My voice made it. I can't believe it
for the most part. I think I'm definitely
struggling more than it was at the start of this
recording. So that does it for this review. AJ and
IK, help close this out. Thanks for listening to
Dynamic Jewel. Visit the show's website at
dynamicjewel.com and follow us on Instagram at
Dynamic Jewel podcast. You can support the show on
Patreon at patreon.com slash dynamic jewel and
joining a tier that works for you or by rating and
reviewing Dynamic Jewel on Apple podcasts,
Spotify, Podchaser, or on our website. Don't
forget to listen to the other shows in the Dynamite
podcast network, including Max Destruction,
Senjo World, and Console Combat. Our next episode
is going to be a really big one. It's going to be a
team duel between Watchmen and Thunderbolts. And
it looks like our Thunderbolts team is going to
skew pretty closely to the roster that's in the
movie. So you definitely want to check that out
before the movie hits theaters. That does it for
this episode. We want to give a big thanks to our
executive producers, John Starosky, Zachary
Hepburn, Dustin Belcom, Mickey Muthigan,
Brandon Estregard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yatn,
Osso Waslosky, AJ Dunkerly, Nick Obanto, Scott
Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Spees, Dean Maleski,
Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, Josh Leiner, Mike
Williams, and Oscar Galvez for helping make this
podcast possible. We'll talk to you guys next
week. Up up and away, true believers. Fun fact,
Daredevil gets all the ladies using his signature
pickup line, me so horny, and then pointing at his
horns. Look it up.