This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. I'm Marvelous
Joe and I'm his twin brother Johnny DC. And in this
episode we are going to review the latest DC
animated direct video release Batman Ninja vs.
Yakuza League. It is the sequel to the 2018 Batman
Ninja film, which was phenomenal. Does the sequel
hold up? We will let you know later on this episode.
Yes it does. I said later on this episode. Come on
man, now they have no reason to listen to the rest.
They will. Especially since this is an all DC
episode because before the review we're going to
break down the latest comic book movie news that
came out this past week, of which there was just one
news item and that was the report on Colin Farrell
being in talks to play Sergeant Rock in that movie.
Yeah we're going to talk about that later. As
always we list our segment times in our episode
description so feel free to check out the show
notes if you want to skip ahead to a particular
topic. Guys our artificially intelligent dual
simulator AJ9K has a quick message for our
listeners, so listen up. Why hello there. Do you
want even more from this podcast? Then become a
part of the dynamic dual community on Patreon
where you can choose from three tiers. The dynamic
2.0 tier gives you access to our discord chat
server. The fantastic 4 tier gives you two bonus
episodes each month and the X-Force tier makes you
an executive producer of this show. Lastly the
Dynomic podcast network tier lets you create your
own podcast using this Monte Carlo simulator.
Johnny and Joe will help you develop your show,
provide graphic support and consultation and get
you simulation results. Pitch the twins your
ideas via email at dynamicdualpodcast at
gmail.com. Check it out at patreon.com slash
dynamicdual. Pip pip cheerio. Thanks AJ9K and
thanks to everyone who supports the podcast. Guys
be sure to tune in to the other shows on the Dynomic
podcast network this week including Max
Destruction which pits your favorite action
heroes from film and television against each
other. This Wednesday hosts Scotty and Gilly are
finding out who would win in a fight between
Parzival from Ready Player One and Blue Shirt Guy
from Free Guy. On the Cendro World podcast hosts
Zachary Hepburn speculates on fights between fan
favorite anime and mage characters. In Zach's
next episode he is going to discuss who would win
between Vasto Lorde Ichigo from Bleach versus Six
Tail QB Naruto. On the console combat podcast
hosts John and Dean simulate battles between
popular video game characters. In yesterday's
episode they determined who would win between VV
Ornis here, Final Fantasy 9, I don't know if I
pronounced that correctly, and Gail Decarios
from Baldur's Gate 3. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com
or click the link in our show notes to listen to all
of the shows in the Dynomic podcast network. But
with that out of the way. Quick to the No Prize! A No
Prize is an award Marvel used to give out to fans.
Our version, the Dynamic Dual No Prize, is a
digital award that we post on Instagram for the
person that we feel gave the best answer to our
question of the week. Last week we asked you guys,
what character do you think Sadie Sink will be
playing in the upcoming fourth Spider-Man film
from Marvel Studios? That was coming off of the
news that Sadie Sink has been cast in a role in the
fourth Spider-Man movie though no one knows what
that role is. So we asked you guys what your
thoughts were. We got three honorable mentions to
get through as well as one No Prize winner. Our
first honorable mention goes to Christopher
Manati, who said, Hi guys, Christopher Manati. So
I don't know that much about Sadie Sink, I haven't
seen Stranger Things or anything so my answer is
more based on a character I want to show up and that
would be Black Cat. I really like Black Cat as a
character and I've wanted her to show up in a
Spider-Man movie for a little while and I think it
could lead to some very funny scenes, especially
with Tom Holland's Spider-Man and with how
awkward he is. So yeah, that's my answer. Yeah, I
think that thematically introducing Black Cat
into Spider-Man 4 would make sense, considering,
you know, at the end of Spider-Man 3, Peter Parker
was resigned to kind of move on with his life with MJ
and Ned for getting all about him. And so it would be
interesting to see how he copes with moving on from
that relationship with this new superhero chick
who's really into him and maybe there's a romantic
connection between them. Yeah, it would be a test
of his love, whether he has moved on from MJ as she
has or not. I agree, I think thematically it would
work. Now, whether or not Sadie Sink could
actually play the character of Black Cat in the way
I would envision the character of Black Cat to
appear on the silver screen, I don't know about
that. But it's an interesting idea nonetheless.
Well, who could play Black Cat in the way that you
envision, do you think? I don't know, like Sidney
Sweeney, I know that's a really kind of obvious
answer and it can't really happen since she played
Julia Carpenter in Madame Web, but that's kind of
who I was thinking would make an ideal Black Cat.
No, because I have dibs on her for Power Girl. I
guess that would make more sense than showing up in
Spider-Man 4 as a different character within the
Spider-Man universe. That's right. Great
answer, Christopher. Our next honorable mention
goes to Travis Herndon, who said, What's up,
dynamic dudes? Travis here. Shout out to my evil
twin. So my answer has to be Gene Gray, since the MCU
is following the ultimate Spider-Man
interpretation of the character who was the first
X-Man he met in the comics. Gene Gray. And if I could
say that X-Man characters would be popping in and
out of future MCU projects, so it would make sense
to introduce Gene right now so we can get a look at
her. Yeah, I can see this making sense too. In the
initial Ultimate comics, which came out in the
early aughts, Ultimate Spider-Man had a
crossover with the Ultimate X-Man. And while I
wouldn't say that the MCU is a direct adaptation of
the Ultimate line of comics, it's really a mixture
of both Ultimate Universe and the 616 Universe. I
think it would be totally cool for the heroes to
meet up with each other while they're still early
in their respective careers. And actually have
X-Man springboard as a wear off of the Spider-Man
franchise. Yeah, I would not hate that. I think she
would be a fantastic Gene Gray. And whether she
makes her first appearance in the Spider-Man
movie or any other Marvel movie, I don't think it
matters, because I actually think she's perfect
casting for a younger version of that character.
Yeah, and then she grows with the role. Boom. Great
answer, Travis. Our final honorable mention goes
to by Dear Bangura, who said, Hello, dynamic duo. I
think that Sadie Sink should play Kitty Pride. I
think there in the Ultimate comics, she was a
redhead that was dating Peter Parker. So I think
that would be a great combination and it would be a
great red herring. Thank you. Yeah, so similar to
the Gene Gray answer, I think I actually like this
idea more where she's potentially playing Kitty
Pride, because in the Ultimate comic books, Kitty
Pride and Peter Parker were an item in the same way
like Black Cat and Peter Parker were an item. But
Kitty Pride is a member of the X-Men as Shadow Cat.
So you can still have that X-Men crossover there,
but with also a potential love interest, as
opposed to Gene Gray, who was not a love interest
for Peter Parker. So I think Kitty Pride kind of
serves the best of both worlds in terms of the X-Men
with Gene Gray and in terms of a romantic interest
angle with Black Cat, because she is both of those
things. Oh, I had no idea that Kitty Pride dated
Peter Parker in the Ultimate universe. Yeah, I
still think Sadie would make a better Gene Gray,
though I do like the idea of introducing Kitty
Pride as a love interest in a Spider-Man movie.
Now, is that just due to the red hair? Oh, 100% yes.
Okay, okay. Great answer by dear. We want to give a
quick shout out to Mason Thompson and Lee Tapscott
for calling in with their answers. But the winner
of this week's No Prize is Harrison Fox, who said,
Hey guys, Harrison Fox. So initially I was
thinking that Sadie would be playing Black Cat,
but the more I think about it, the more I feel that
maybe it's going to be Gwen Stacy. And this version
of Gwen Stacy, instead of being killed off in a very
dramatic way, will become our Spider-Gwen. And
then we can have a Spider-Woman character do
something, unlike the three that were introduced
in Madam Web. I think that would be a great idea. I
really like this idea. Now, we all know that Gwen
Stacy's fate is to die at the hands of Green Goblin,
but we've seen that done in the amazing Spider-Man
films with Andrew Garfield. And I think that fans
are clamoring for a live action version of
Spider-Gwen. So it's entirely possible that
Sadie Sink is playing Gwen Stacy, and they'll be
riffing on the character's history by
incorporating a little bit of Spider-Gwen story
from her respective universe. You can totally see
this happening, especially since Spider-Man 4 is
supposed to take place between the two Avengers
movies, and therefore you could introduce some
multiversal elements into it. I don't know, Sadie
Sink would look like Blonde? Well, I mean, Bryce
Dallas Howard played Gwen Stacy in Spider-Man 3,
and she was given a wig or dyed her hair blonde. So
there's precedent there in terms of the hair
color. What I like most about this answer, though,
is that it didn't deal with the X-Men. It dealt more
with the Spider-Verse, which is really where I
think the franchise should be going. And also, you
know, Spider-Gwen could be a potential love
interest as well. Because I don't think we've seen
that in the comics. I don't think we've seen
Spider-Gwen be a love interest for 616
Spider-Man. So great answer, Harrison Fox. You
win this week's No Prize. If you the listener want a
shot at winning your own No Prize, stay tuned to
later on this episode when we'll be asking another
question of the week. And now that that's done, on
to the news! Okay, so not too long ago, we learned
that Luca Guadagnino, the director of films such
as Challengers and Suspiria, pitched James Gunn
and Peter Saffron, the heads of DC Studios, on a
Sergeant Rock film written by his longtime
writing collaborator, Justin Karitsky. Now,
initially, the rumors were that Daniel Craig was
interested in playing the title role of Sergeant
Rock, considering he had just come off of working
with Luca Guadagnino in the film Queer. But it
looks like Daniel Craig has moved on from the
Sergeant Rock role, and currently Colin Farrell
is in talks to star as Sergeant Rock. Thank God,
man. All right, I was getting really scared there
that DC was going to nab up another James Bond
actor, and just can't have that. Just cannot have
that. Now Daniel Craig can come over to Marvel
where he belongs. Yeah, it's never going to
happen. Now, this is interesting because Colin
Farrell is famously, and to much acclaim, already
playing Oswald Cobb, the Penguin in Matt Reeves,
The Batman Universe. Of course, he plays that role
under heavy makeup, and he's basically
unrecognizable in both voice and demeanor. So I
could actually see this working. Oh, absolutely.
Colin Farrell is one of the more dynamic actors of
his generation. The guys at Chameleon, he could do
anything, and you would never even know that the
actors were the same. Yeah, I mean, an actor of his
caliber can clearly pull off anything. I am
concerned, though, about the physicality of the
role. Like, Colin Farrell doesn't strike me as
being, like, as physical as a soldier would need to
be. What are you talking about? He was super
physical in Daredevil as the character Bullseye.
Ugh, don't remind me. But no, like, in the past, a
Sergeant Rock film has been attempted by actors
such as Bruce Willis and Arnold Schwarzenegger.
Like, they've tried to make this film before, but
they just never came to pass. And what I think of
Colin Farrell, I don't necessarily think action
star in the same way that I do actors like Willis and
Schwarzenegger. I think Colin Farrell could
totally pull that off too, though, the 80s action
era. The only way I see this working is if it's more
like a saving private Ryan-type film, as opposed
to something like, I don't know, Rambo. So you're
thinking he's more Tom Hanks than Ben Affleck in
Pearl Harbor? Yeah, which doesn't surprise me
considering the director. He hasn't really done a
big war movie like this, or like too much action in
general, outside of a tennis match. So yeah, I can
see this definitely being more cerebral than
action, which is fine by me, honestly. I mean, if
his pitch was good enough for James Gunn and Peter
Saffron, it's good enough for me, and I can't wait
to see if Colin Farrell's cast. Someone needs to be
cast relatively soon because they want to start
shooting this movie this summer. Who would be your
ideal actor if it wasn't Colin Farrell? Oh,
interesting question. Yeah, who's a big name
action star right now? Uh, Chris Hemsworth? Thor,
really? Yeah, he's done with Marvel. After Love
and Thunder, just let him move on, poor guy. The
hell is wrong with you? I regret asking this
question because you just gave the absolutely
worst answer of all time. Or, or the best answer.
No. Speaking of Colin Farrell playing both the
penguin and potentially Sergeant Rock, that
brings us to our question of the week. What Marvel
or DC actor whose performance was hidden by
practical or special effects would you like to see
play another character? And which one? We've seen
this before with actors like Gemma Chan, who
played in Captain Marvel and The Eternals, and Jai
Minhatsu, who played in Aquaman and the Shazam
movies. But besides those two, what actor would
you choose? Record your answer at
dynamicdool.com by clicking on the red
microphone button in the bottom right hand corner
of the screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long and don't forget to leave your name in case we
include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a dynamic
duel no prize that we'll post to Instagram. Be sure
to answer before March 29th. But that does it for
all the news for this episode, so let's go ahead and
move into our main event, where we review the
latest DC animated film to hit home video, Batman
Ninja vs Yakuza League. Batman Ninja vs Yakuza
League Okay, Batman Ninja vs Yakuza League. It's
the direct sequel to 2018's direct-to-video
anime feature, Batman Ninja. Both films were
written by Kazuki Nakashima and directed by
Junpei Mizusaki, with Shinji Takaji
co-directing the sequel. I loved the first film. I
love most anime I see honestly, especially if it's
DC related projects like my adventures with
Superman or Suicide Squad Isakai. They're some of
DC's greatest animated projects. But Batman
Ninja is a project that I've rewatched numerous
times since its release, and I love it every time I
watch it. I've had nothing but high expectations
for this sequel, which usually leads to some
disappointment, but not here. Batman Ninja vs
Yakuza League is a worthwhile successor to the
first film that amps up the action, the stakes, the
badass design, and the absurdism from the first
film to a whole other level. And I recommend it to
any Batman or anime fan out there. Yeah, I really
enjoyed this film. It also surpassed my
expectations. I was not expecting this to be as
good as the original Ninja Batman, which was
fantastic. You know, I had my criticisms of it, but
it still kind of held up in my mind, and now so does
the sequel. Absolutely. If you haven't seen this
movie yet, please make sure you do so before
listening to this spoiler review. The film is
available now on digital platforms, though
physical copies won't be available until
mid-April. Now, while I recommend the film, just
be aware that the original Japanese language
version was not available upon the film's early
digital release, but I'm hoping that it will be
available by the time the physical version comes
out. Yeah, that was fucking stupid. And really,
that's the only way I watched the original Batman
Ninja was the Japanese audio. That's right. And so
I was like, I don't want to watch this now. I don't
really prefer dubs over subs. No, I 100% prefer
subs. I was pissed when I first realized the audio
issue with the digital release because I vastly
preferred the original Japanese language
version to the English dubs in the first film. But
to my surprise, you know, this English voice cast
for the sequel did a pretty decent job with the
film. I guess the dubbing was done by a company
called Sentai Filmworks, who does a lot of English
dubbing on anime projects, like My Hero Academia,
Sword Art Online, Food Wars, just a ton of anime.
I've seen some hate online saying Warner Brothers
cheaped out on getting the original voice cast
back. But honestly, good riddance, because in my
opinion, the dubbing in this film is way better
this go around. I mentioned earlier I didn't want
to watch the movie because they didn't have the
original Japanese audio. And I was kind of
resigned to watching the film for this review with
the English language dubs. But I also was
surprised with the quality of the voice cast. It
takes a certain kind of special voice acting to
sell the kind of melodrama of a lot of anime
reactions and things like that. And a lot of
standard American voice actors just can't pull
off that kind of drama in a believable way. So you
can't just like hire a celebrity voice actor like
Tony Hale or something like that. You got to have a
qualified anime English voice actor to do this
stuff right. Absolutely. Like, I think I could do
some voice acting not well, but I could do it. I
could absolutely not do anime voice acting
because my voice would crack as soon as I try to get
overly emotional. I'm telling you right now, you
wouldn't be able to do any voice acting. Okay. Wow.
I have a podcast, bro. That doesn't mean anything.
Have you listened to this podcast? That's fair. My
voice sucks. Why are you even listening right now?
I wonder that every week. Anyway, moving on. In the
first film, Batman, his allies and his villains
were all transported back in time to feudal Japan
where Batman, unable to rely on much of his high
tech equipment, had to learn ancient techniques
of the ninja to stop an all out war between his
villains, while also finding a way to return
everyone to the proper time. That film began
fairly serious in tone, though by the end we were
watching giant mechazoid fortresses battle
monkeys stacked on top of each other in the shape of
Batman. Shit got weird, but I still loved it so much
so that I was convinced that it deserved a five star
review in my initial reaction. You talked me down
from that, Joseph. I think in part because of just
how absurd it became. But in this film, the sequel,
Yakuza League, they start with the absurdity
already ratcheted to 10. So you don't have that
jarring tonal shift to contend with like you did in
the first film. When you have jetpack wearing
katana wielding Yakuza gangsters raining down
from the sky within the first 10 minutes of the
movie, there's pretty much nothing you can't get
away with in this film. And though the story gets
pretty ambitious and the level of absurdity it can
get away with, where like even several of the
characters say that the story elements are dumb
during the course of the movie, the film subverts
expectations for Western audiences in
particular in such a way that is not only funny, but
just fun in general. And it captures your
attention in the way good art tends to. Yeah, what I
really appreciated about this movie was just how
self aware it was. You know, the first film did go
off the rails and I did take issue with that. But
this movie, like you said, starts off the rails,
and it comments on it like it knowingly does so. But
also it you know, it takes its time to explain the
absurdity behind everything going on for every
weird thing you see. There is a rational
explanation for it. And I do appreciate that, even
though it does lead to the film being 90%
exposition. Oh, I know. So so much dialogue in this
movie is them just explaining things, which
surprisingly worked. I don't know how they pulled
that off, but they did somehow. Maybe it had
something to do with the visuals, because this
film looks gorgeous. We've seen examples of
computer generated anime before, like in the
first Batman Ninja movie, or Batman and Superman
Battle of the Supersons. But this is hands down the
best example to date of that style, partly because
I believe they didn't try to overdo the shading and
lighting like the Japanese characters in this
film are fairly flatly colored and you know, are
identifiable by their sketchy contour lines, as
if to imply they are a sketch or like experimental
result of Russell Gould playing with reality. The
designs like the first film are admirably
complex, yet quintessentially Japanese like
everything in the film. Yeah, computer animated
anime is not my favorite thing. It's rarely done
well in the anime that I've seen, and you know,
myself not being an avid anime consumer. I didn't
really like the computer animation that was in the
first Batman Ninja movie. I thought everybody
walked a little bit too stiff. They look like
robots to me, you know, their faces were soulless
abominations. But here, actually, the film
completely reversed my opinion on computer
generated anime animation, because I thought it
was really well done. The movements looked
believable. The expressions had more life to
them. Everything just looked better, not
counting, you know, the hand drawn interlude that
was in the first Batman Ninja movie, because that
was beautifully done. Oh yeah, absolutely.
Besides that scene, I would definitely say though
that this film looks better than the first and the
story of this film is better than the first. You
know, we described the first film as being
narratively simple. And while this film still
follows that style over substance narrative
approach, this time the story has much more
complexity and is actually quite successful in
building an entirely new world with fascinating
characters whose stories may be glossed over, but
are brimming with possibility. Rather than
seeing how familiar characters adapt to a strange
new environment like the first film, here we see
how familiar characters are affected by exposure
to a strange new environment from the get go, from
birth, which brings a sense of Eltsworld intrigue
to the mix akin to something like Red Sun. Yeah,
that was really cool. I mean, what I liked probably
more about Batman's story in the first movie was
that he was a fish out of water and he had to become
something new. He had to become a ninja and study
the ninja way in order to survive in feudal Japan.
And feudal Japan as a setting was just phenomenal.
I liked it more than the setting of modern day Japan
being taken over by these Yakuza gangs. But I'll
still say that there was a lot of interest there and
that Batman was still a fish out of water with these
other characters that had changed into these
unique Japanese personas. Yeah, did you notice
the Easter egg around the Yakuza League's names?
It was their given names. Yeah, it was the Japanese
pronunciation of their first name. So Arthur
became Asa, Barry became Barry, Clark becomes
Koraku, and Jessica becomes Zeshika, so on and so
forth. I thought that was kind of cool. I didn't
realize that until I was writing my review. But
even beyond that, words like Hage-ne, the name of
the Yakuza family that Clark was the leader of,
means steel. Really? Yeah. Now, speaking of
Superman, his Japanese counterpart, Koraku, is
the only character in the film who actually gets a
real character arc. Batman has a mission, Diana
has a code, they grow to appreciate each other's
ways, but beyond that, they're static. Superman,
on the other hand, begins the film as an enforcer
for Russell Gull and the leader of the Hagen-E
crime family who views the world through the lens
of power. There's those who wield it, and there's
those who are subjugated by it. He compares Yakuza
to demons and believes they, like all of humanity,
are irredeemable without control from a
stronger, more violent, more controlling force.
But after battling Batman, who tells him his
Superman wasn't powerful because he dominated
others, but because he uplifted them and
realizing Ross lied to him about the people of
Batman's world, Koraku starts to question
everything. His whole identity, which was built
on strength, is fractured upon his defeat at the
hands of Batman. And in the end, Koraku doesn't
just fight for power, he fights to protect others.
He becomes a true Superman, embracing the Ninkyo
Code and helping save Gotham. Yeah, it was a great
arc. Allegedly, the rest of the Justice League
went through the same arc. It would have been nice
to actually see that happen, as opposed to just
being told that it happened. Yeah, that's fair. I
do think Superman is an inspiring enough figure,
though, whether he's good or evil, to have changed
the minds of the other League members with an
inspiring speech or something like that. Just
something we didn't see. It was cool to see the way
that this movie grafted your standard anime arc
types onto these Justice League characters. You
had Wonder Woman with her Lady Snowblood type arc
type. Oh yeah, and Zesha Ko is kind of like a gothic
Lolita type figure. Yeah, Lolita fashion. And
Barry was this crazy loose cannon who had
boundless energy, just that crazy anime
archetype. Whereas Aquaman was more of your
traditional gangster, but he was a badass. Yeah,
their looks totally fit them as well. I really
liked the look of Aquaman and Wonder Woman. The
only character I really didn't like the look of was
the Flash. I get that they were trying to go for this
raiding, lightning style design, but I think they
should have done more with what was under his coat,
because essentially it was just the Flash suit.
Yeah, they relied too much on his headgear selling
his new design. Yeah, exactly. Although I did love
the fact that his tornadoes were able to transport
people across the dimensional space time rift,
because not only does Flash do things like create
whirlwind tornadoes, but he also travels through
time. So for him to be that medium through which
they traveled was genius, I thought. For sure.
Although he was pretty slow in this movie, yeah. I
don't think so. I thought he was pretty fast. He
could barely keep up with the Batmobiles that Red
Hood and Red Robin were driving. Well, that's
fair. And actually, you know, they even said
themselves, like if this was the real Flash, we
would not have been able to defeat him. So yeah,
these versions do seem a little bit depowered in
general, I would say. Except for Aquaman. Holy
shit. He was awesome in this movie. They always got
to give Aquaman hydrokinesis when they can't
figure out what to do with him, because otherwise
he wouldn't have had much to do in this movie, I
think. They just need to give him hydrokinesis in
the comics. Like large scale hydrokinesis like
that, not like Mera, but where he's like shifting
tidal waves and stuff. So cool. I agree. What did
you think of the look of Superman? It caught me off
guard. I think I was expecting something a little
bit more traditional. I guess he was wearing a
robe, but the sunglasses were a little strange.
That was a unique choice. I actually thought they
were really cool. I'm glad that he kind of stuck
with a traditional Japanese robe type look with
like a coat over his shoulders that kind of acted
like a cape. But the sunglasses for me just like
tipped the whole thing over the edge into Yakuza
badass territory. I thought it evoked Superboy a
little bit. Well, I actually thought it evoked
Eradicator, just like an evil version of Superman
of sorts. That makes sense. I also really liked the
look of Batman in this movie. We didn't really get
the Ninja Batman or Samurai Batman looks that we
got in the first movie. But here we did get to see the
full-on advanced tech version of Batman with the
holographic displays and transforming vehicles
and armored suits. It's awesome. I think this is my
favorite version of Batman, the high-tech
version, I should say, because we saw in the first
movie, you know, he had the Batplane that
transformed into the Batmobile, which
transformed into the Batbike, which transformed
into a battle suit. Right? That all makes sense to
me. I think the most fascinating version of Batman
is not like the Gothic Neo-Norah version, but the
one that's most like Iron Man, the one with the vast
amount of resources. Because it makes more sense
to me that he would operate in that sort of sci-fi
almost capacity as a billionaire crime fighter
who can stand toe-to-toe with the rest of the
Justice League. This is, I think, the most capable
version of Batman that we've probably ever seen.
Yeah, you might be right. I definitely think this
version makes sense in the context of the other
Justice League characters, because otherwise,
you know, he can't really contribute as much as the
others. It's cool to see things like the Batmobile
and the Batplane operating as this sort of Voltron
type character. You know, they went with like
Giant Mechaz in the first movie. I'm glad they
avoided that here and decided to go for more of like
a separating battle station type approach for the
Bat family. That was great. Yeah, Alfred's
animated video that he made of the Bat Phoenix was
one of my favorite things about the movie. Not
gonna lie. It just evoked old classic anime
cartoons like Gundam or Voltron. It was awesome.
And there were neat little touches to like the 60s
television show too. Like in the beginning when
Batman and Robin slid down their pole into the
Batplane. I loved that. They need to bring things
like that back into, you know, the modern mythos. I
want to see like an adaptation of the Bat pole in
James Gunn's DCU and maybe even introduce it in
like the Batman. Just as an homage, just because
it's like an iconic part of the character that
people know and love so much. Absolutely. And it
doesn't even need to be cheesy. Right. Like it
wasn't here. Yeah, exactly. Another thing I
really liked about this version of the Justice
League were the names and origins of each of them.
So you have Zeshaqa the Emerald Ray. She was this
gambler who found herself in trouble and while on
the run she stumbled upon the Power Ring. It was
reminiscent almost of like Alan Scott's origin,
which I think worked well for this version of the
character. Yeah, I like how a lot of her energy
constructs were like gambling themed. Yeah, it
was either like gambling themed or like teddy
bears. It was cute. Now Aquaman was Asa the awkward
dragon, which is super cool because dragons of
course are aquatic creatures in eastern
folklore. Now he came from a species of aquatic
people living at the bottom of Lake Inokashira,
which is a real lake in Tokyo. And his mother, the
queen, fell in love with a yuck as a gangster. I
thought that was awesome. Yeah, that was a great
play on his standard origin. My favorite use of
Aquaman's powers in this movie was when he sent the
sea turtle out to send a message to Wonder Woman.
And then like she responded and like the sea turtle
literally like spun away back to the lake. I
thought that was great. It almost reminded me of
something like out of a Miyazaki film, just how
surreal it was. Yeah, exactly. Of course, Wonder
Woman in this film was Diana the Eagle Goddess. She
was raised in Yoga Gashima, an island of women in
Lake Inokashira. And she was a descendant of the
gods apparently, bestowed with a portion of
Benzaiten's power in order to protect Japan and
the Ninkyo spirit. And Benzaiten is like an
eastern goddess. Oh, you know the seven drunk gods
like that Kung Fu martial art style? Yeah.
Benzaiten is the Japanese name of the girl god.
Okay. She's like a warrior. Bodhi, the fleet of
foot was a low level Yakuza thug that was struck by
lightning. Well, in a hot spring. That's kind of
funny. So good. And the coolest one I thought,
Kuraku, the man of steel, who instead of landing in
America, landed in Japan and was raised by a Yakuza
family. Very reminiscent of Red Sun. To touch on
the final character, Russell Ghoul, I am glad that
he was the primary antagonist in this film. I
forgot that he was going to be because I forgot that
he was in the trailers for this movie. With his
resources and his League of Assassins, he's
always kind of been Batman's most formidable foe,
in my opinion, and even more so in this film. And
that he has a Yakuza League of Assassins. And I kind
of like the play upon the different League
versions. And he's one of Batman's only rogues, I
would say, that like wants to destroy all of
humanity as opposed to just causing chaos in
Gotham City. Oh, absolutely. Yeah. He's an eco
terrorist, right? So he's always trying to end the
human race. And this was a pretty wild plan to do
just that, even though I'm left wondering, like,
why he couldn't simply just use the engine that he
rebuilt to create a world he had always wanted to
see. Like, why not create that instead of create a
Yakuza world to conquer his native world? That
seems like an extra step that's unnecessary.
Well, well, you know, you can only fold a piece of
paper in half seven times. So maybe a world without
humans was just too far removed from standard
reality. Interesting. OK. Not sure if I buy it, but
it is in fact an explanation. I also liked how they
made it so that like Batman's past time adventure
didn't have cascading ripples through time, like
what I thought was going to be the case. But, you
know, instead, Ross simply improved upon Gorilla
God's Quake engine to create a machine capable of
warping space time and therefore reality. That's
an awesome, dangerous power for Ross to have. To
all the movies and anime, the Dynamite Podcast
Network presents Console Combat, where video
game legends brawl every Monday, Dynamic Duel,
where comic book titans smash every Tuesday, Max
Destruction, where TV and action heroes battle
every Wednesday, and Sendro World, where anime
champions clash every Thursday. Join us as we
speculate on the matches and armed with the power
of mathematical simulations to discover who will
emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
Moving on to the story highlights, Bruce Wayne and
his son Damien and Alfred notice something is
amiss with the world when they realize, among
other things, that the islands of Japan and the
Justice League are missing after their time
traveling adventure to feudal Japan. When they
receive a warning of a Yakuza hurricane
approaching Gotham City, they suit up as Batman
and Robin to take on the mysterious Japanese
mobsters who've fallen from the sky. An
occurrence they learn has been going on for some
time. Surmising that he and his allies must be time
displaced with counterparts from a different
timeline, Batman spots an inverted version of
Japan peeking through a fissure in space-time in
the sky above Gotham and travels with Robin in the
Batplane to investigate, leaving Nightwing and
Red Robin to handle the remaining Yakuza. Now, I
absolutely loved the James Bond-esque opening
credits scene that also served as a recap to the
first film in this movie. It was great. Yeah, they
were kind of going for a Adele kind of vibe with the
song. I think didn't quite pull it off. I didn't
love the song, but I do appreciate the effort they
put into the opening credits for sure. I figured
you would like that as a James Bond fan. Yeah, I
totally did. Now, recognizing that the fissure
has an energy signature similar to that of the
Quake engine that sent them through time in the
first film, Batman flies through it to an inverted
Tokyo where they're immediately attacked by
Zesuka, the Emerald Ray. That world's version of
the Green Lantern Jessica Cruz and, as of the Aqua
Dragon, a version of Aquaman, both of who work as
enforcers for the Hagenet crime family. With
their plane damaged, Batman and Robin are rescued
by Diana, the Eagle Goddess, a version of Wonder
Woman who leads the Amazonia Yakuza family and
claims Batman and Robin are under her protection
while in Kichijoji, Tokyo. Harley Quinn, as
Harren the Wild Jester, aids Diana and Asa and
Zesuka leave. Meanwhile, Nightwing, Red Robin,
and Red Hood manage to defeat Barry, the fleet of
foot, a version of Flash, who generated a tornado
that allowed him to travel to Gotham. Now, the way
they defeated Flash was kind of bizarre and that
Red Hood was able to fire off these smelly
canisters that reminded him of smells of like meat
and beer and stuff like that and rice. So he just got
like really hungry because apparently, body is
hungry all the time. Yeah, I didn't love that. It
was funny. Did you find it kind of convenient that
Batman and Robin had an ally on the Yakuza side of
things? Like if Wonder Woman wasn't this like
honorable character, would they have even stood a
chance, I wonder, in defeating the Yakuza League?
Oh, interesting. Probably, probably. Because
Batman still had the contingency plans to defeat
each member of the Justice League, so why not use
Diana's against her? Although that would have
eventually required him getting back to his
reality, but I still think he could have done that
without Diana. If anything, all he needed was
Joker's help. Which was bullshit. We will get to
that. Now Diana informs Batman of the Yakuza War,
known as Yakuza Geden, that has overtaken Japan,
forcing its citizens to pick family allegiances.
With the death of Dayo, the leader of the Dumuzu
family, a version of Doomsday, at the hands of the
Hagenae family leader, Kuraku, the Man of Steel,
the Hagenae family is currently the dominant mob,
and one that does not subscribe to the honor system
among Yakuza known as the Ninkyo Way, as Diana and
her Amazonae family does. The real world, or
Amatsukuni as Japan knows it, appeared in their
sky a month ago, and the Hagenae family wants to
rule it. While beginning repairs on the Bat Plane,
Batman learns that Harin is his world's Harley
Quinn, who came to the inverted Japan just before
he did along with the Joker. Thanks to Harley,
Diana believes Batman is an Oya-Boon, or leader of
a Bat Cartel. Now I thought it was totally baller
that this version of Superman killed his Doomsday
and not the other way around. Yeah, I thought that
was a little bullshit. Like, why is Doomsday
leading a family? I feel like the character is not
smart enough to do that, so I thought it was an
interesting choice of character, for sure. Yeah,
a badass choice, like I said. Okay. Hardcore. Now
as Batman attempts to fly back to Gotham, Kuraku
appears and captures the Bat Plane, as the Hagenae
Oya-Boon, Ras Al Ghul, ordered him to bring Damien
to him. After flinging Robin toward Ras' Yakuza
Tower, Kuraku nearly kills Batman until Joker and
Harley Quinn interfere on a makeshift plane.
While Harley distracts Kuraku, Joker straps his
high-powered ejector seat to the Bat Plane and
shoots him into Gotham, claiming he doesn't want
Kuraku to kill Batman. While Diana rescues Harley
from Kuraku, Batman reunites with Nightwing, Red
Hood, and Red Robin. And you're right, the Joker
moment was bullshit. It was dumb, and even Batman
admitted it. I was also really glad though that
Joker didn't reappear back in the story, because I
guess I was anticipating that, and I thought it
would have been unnecessary. So while I
appreciate that they didn't bring the Joker back,
it did leave a bit of a plot hole. Yeah, honestly, I
thought the Joker was going to return, and I
thought that Batman is going to use the villains
from the first movie to help defeat the Yakuza
League. I don't know why I got that impression
initially. That would have been cool. Yeah, it
didn't end up happening. It turns out all he needed
was his own Bat Family to take him on. Now Robin is
taken before his grandfather, Ras Al Ghul, who
explains that he's improved upon Gorilla Grodd's
time-traveling Quake engine, creating what he
calls a four-dimensional origami system capable
of reshaping space-time itself. Ras reveals that
he used it to create new realities by folding
space-time like origami to create a new world of
Yakuza assassins under his control, capable of
wiping out humanity on a Metsukuni and allowing
Robin, his desired successor, to rebuild it to his
liking. Robin refuses and becomes trapped in a
sushi claw machine. So random. Pretty random. I
thought it was funny how he just ordered
California rolls because that was the sushi he was
most familiar with, and Ras Al Ghul called him out
for that. I thought that was almost kind of an
insult to Damien. I feel like Damien has better
taste than that. I could be wrong. Well, he's
young. Who knows? That's fair. Now in the Batcave,
Batman explains that bringing down the Yakuza
League should be simple as they know their
weaknesses, and thanks to being exposed to a
space-time pulse from the Quake engine in their
prior adventure into the past, they can see and
travel to the inverted Japan through the fissure
and space-time with whatever tech they possess.
Before Batman and his allies prepare for their
trip back to Japan, Alfred shows them a video he
made for them using a new batship known as the Bat
Phoenix that can separate into smaller ships that
each of them can control individually. Meanwhile
in Japan, Ras and Kuraku discuss bringing down
Diana and the Amazon family before conquering a
Metsukuni, which Ras has led Kuraku to believe is
full of Yakuza. While Diana nurses Harley back to
health, she is visited by a giant turtle messenger
from Asa, challenging her to a duel. After
accepting the challenge, Diana begins to sing
about her feelings, karaoke style, awakening
Harley, who is invited to sing but is quickly
stopped when she sings horribly. Again, another
random absurdist moment, but honestly, I was
laughing. I laughed too. It was strange in that a
lot of the story elements to this movie seem to try
to cram as many Japanese customs as possible, kind
of randomly, like the sushi thing, like the claw
game, like this karaoke part. Yeah, I always
wonder if the Japanese creators of these films is
just trying to expose Western audiences to as many
Japanese things as possible. Yeah, that's what it
felt like. One thing I didn't like about this movie
was how easy it was for Batman to defeat the Justice
League. Yeah. Saying to the others that, oh, it's
going to be easy to bring these guys down, and then
as you watch the film progress, yeah, he was right.
It kind of ruins the whole versus aspect of this
movie to me. Now, granted, the stakes are still
huge because of what happens later on with the
potential destruction of Gotham, but that threat
wasn't because of the Justice League, and I
thought it would be. Yeah, Batman should never say
that it's going to be easy to take down the Justice
League. It should always be difficult. We've seen
him do it before in stories like Tower of Babel,
which was adapted into Justice League Doom, but
that felt earned. It's never fun to see Batman go
into, like, God Bode, you know, where he could just
defeat all these other characters. Actually, I
mean, it probably is fun to see that. It actually is
really cool. But yeah, it just, it was different
from what I thought it was going to be. That doesn't
mean it was bad, but the title of the film sets up a
premise that wasn't as satisfying as maybe it
could have been. Now, Asa and Diana meet on Lake
Inokishira, where it's revealed that they used to
play together as children. As the two battle,
Zeshika intervenes, holding members of the
Amazon family hostage. Harley joins the fight,
battling Zeshika, who is suddenly rammed by the
Bat Phoenix. The ship separates with Nightwing
taking on Zeshika, Batman helping Diana against
Asa, and Red Robin and Red Hood assigned to Rasa's
Yakuza Tower, where Kuraku rallies Yakuza troops
to conquer a Masukuni. Nightwing brings down
Zeshika with the science ninja technique, Decoy
Body, tricking her into thinking he was inside a
Sentai-esque suit of armor before shooting her
with a sleeping dirt. Which was bizarre. Like, I
don't know when he switched out of the suit. It
might have been when, like, she caused a whole
bunch of smoke to come up. I've seen this film
twice, and that has to be the moment, but still, it
was unexpected. I mean, that Decoy Body was pretty
down powerful to be just a technological creation
of Batman. You know, if he can create drones as
smart and powerful as this, Batman should be
creating these guys all the time. Maybe it's a
resources issue. We'll go with that. Now, as Baty
generates a storm to shoot Yakuza into Gotham,
Diana helps Batman bring down Asa with the science
ninja technique, Electrolisis, in which Batman
trapped him in an electric current underwater,
then uses that electricity to create a chemical
reaction that exploded the water around Asa.
After Batman and Nightwing explain to Diana their
plan to blow up Rasa's quake engine to dissolve the
dimensional fissure joining their worlds, Robin
and Red Hood use the science ninja technique,
Tornado Canceller, using their ship to reverse
the direction of Flash's tornado, then blowing up
the giant Yakuza Gatling cannon. Red Robin
activates the Bat Phoenix's cloaking mode before
he and Red Hood detach from it and take to the Tokyo
streets, where they're chased by body. They
eventually lure him into a trap they set up in an
underground parking garage involving a
treadmill and a holographic projector before Red
Hood takes body down using science ninja
technique, Vending Machine, which he hides in a
holographic vending machine and shoots body in
the head with a sleeping dart when he tries to buy a
drink. Again, they played on his desire for food in
order to defeat him. I know it's really hard to take
down a character like the Flash, but I feel like
they didn't have to go quite so ridiculous with it.
Well, I think other Flash projects like the Flash
movie established that Barry is always hungry, so
maybe they were just borrowing from that. Who
knows? This was the most bizarre take down, I feel
like. Because as Flash was having trouble
catching up with these Bat Phoenix cars, I was
like, what is going on? And then for it to be a
hologram, I was like, okay, well, when did that
happen? Kuraku destroys the parking garage, and
though Red Hood and Red Robin try to blow him up,
Kuraku nearly kills them before he's plowed into
by Batman's tank car. And Diana saves the boys, all
of whom go with Nightwing to Yakuza Tower to find
the Quake engine and Robin, while Batman takes on
Kuraku and robotic armor transformed from his
tank. As the two fight within a crater in the
street, Kuraku dismantles Batman's armor,
though Batman uses science ninja technique
spectral conversion to depower Superman by using
crystals within his dismantled armor to filter
the sunlight above them into red solar rays. While
suffering a beatdown from Batman, Kuraku learns
that Ross has been lying to him about Amatsukuni
being full of Yakuza and that he's a weak version of
the Superman that Batman is familiar with. Though
Kuraku manages to disrupt the spectral
conversion filter, Batman knocks him out with a
Kryptonite knuckle duster before leaving to
Yakuza Tower to go after Ross. This did serve to
highlight how lame Superman's weaknesses are.
What? They're always exploited. It's so easy to
defeat Superman if you have the right tool,
otherwise it's impossible. But we've seen this
time and time again where he's either taken out by
Red Sun radiation or Kryptonite and I'm just over
it. I was hoping that they would go a different
route for this film. It did not bother me at all, I'm
going to be honest. Everything from the battle
between Diana and Asa leading up to this battle
between Kuraku and Batman was just balls to the
wall action. I loved these fights. I thought they
were really hyperkinetic and really cool. I
thought it was pretty absurd that Batman's
dismantled armor just managed to create this net
filter of light because it had crystals in it. But
it was also very satisfying to see Batman just beat
the shit out of this evil version of Superman. The
dialogue was satisfying and the action was cool,
but it was so obvious and therefore there was no
tension because you knew that of course Batman was
going to pull out Kryptonite. Well, not
initially. I didn't think he was going to at first,
but then once he did, the fireball that was around
his hand, I've never seen it depicted that way. The
design again just kind of I feel like saved it.
Yeah, Kryptonite radiation as green flame is
pretty badass. At Yakuza Tower, Robin breaks free
from his claw machine. Easily, I add, and joins
Diana and Batman in confronting Ross. Ross
removes a space-time converter from his quake
engine, sending its four-dimensional origami
system out of control and causing the inverted
Tokyo to breach the dimensional fissure and fall
into a collision course with Gotham. Unable to
return the converter back to the engine as it
phases into other dimensions, Batman deduces
that the energy from the space-time pulse their
bodies were exposed to can anchor the engine back
in Tokyo, and his crew works to focus their energy
on the machine while Diana prevents Ross from
interfering. Meanwhile, as Tokyo emerges with
Amatsukuni, the Yakuza League members become
disoriented by the awareness of their alternate
heroic selves across other realities, and Ross
knocks Diana from the tower. There's a little bit
of like flux capacitor mumbo jumbo going on here,
but I didn't mind it as much because conceptually
it made sense, which I thought was the most
important thing. Yeah, I can't tell you how long it
took me to sort of write out this plot structure and
just make sense of everything everyone was
saying. It was not easy. But as I was watching the
film for the first time, I wouldn't say that
bothered me because yeah, they do eventually get
around to explaining everything that's going on.
Now, as gravity inverts itself around them,
Batman chases Ross to get the converter. Ross
blows up the base of Yakuza Tower, detaching it
from Tokyo so it alone can still fall onto Gotham as
a contingency for Batman successfully closing
the fissure. As Ross escapes via airplane and as
Tokyo debris plummets toward Gotham, Kuraku,
Diana, and the rest of the Yakuza League appear,
holding up the tower and protecting Gotham in an
adoption of the Ninkyo spirit, freeing up Batman
to go after Ross upon the cloaked Bat Phoenix.
After defeating Ross and recapturing the
converter, Batman races back to the tower and with
help from Harley, restores the converter to the
engine. As Tokyo begins returning to its own
reality, Batman tells the Yakuza League to return
the tower to their world and destroy the engine
there to close the fissure and sever the link
between their worlds. Using the Hagoni
technique, rising dragon of valor, the Yakuza
raise the tower and depart Gotham. With the
Justice League and Robin's Japanese hairstyle
back, Batman and his allies confirm that their
timeline has been restored. In a mid-credits
scene, Robin rejects the Alfred suggestion of
wearing a wig. My favorite part about this end
scene is that when the Justice League characters
became their composite selves, their reformed
versions, and they got their new updated
costumes, the tattoos that were underneath the
costumes glowed. They're Yakuza tattoos. And
they all had this really awesome look because of
that. Yeah, tattoos are synonymous with Yakuza
and crime in East Asian culture. I remember when I
went to Korea, they had to check my entire body for
tattoos when I lived there for a time. So yeah, it's
kind of a big deal, maybe not so much anymore, but I
loved that the Justice League had those tattoos.
They were pretty sick tattoos too. They were.
Yeah, they were really cool. Now, the end credits
for this film, they showcased these real like
paper dioramas of like the different origins of
the Yakuza League. I didn't realize those were
real when they were showing them throughout the
movie. Really? But yeah, someone actually made
those and they're awesome to see on display. Holy
shit. You didn't see that in the end credits? The
camera moves around them. Yeah, I thought it was
still animated. No, it's real. Okay. All right,
I'll take your word for it. I want them. I would buy
those out of my so much merch from this movie. Oh my
gosh. But that brings us to the end of the film. I
really liked it. I know it's not perfect. I know
it's probably too absurd for a lot of viewers, but
because it's loaded with absurdist anime fun and
hyperkinetic action. And with the sequel
showcasing gorgeous Japanese inspired designs
and new takes on fan favorite characters. I think
this is an improvement upon the first film, which
we gave three and a half stars. So I'm bumping this
one up to four out of five stars, a fresh rating on
Rotten Tomatoes. I think that's a solid rating. I
think the key thing that you mentioned here is that
it's fun. It's a fun movie just like the first film.
And I don't think you even need to really see the
first film in order to appreciate the sequel.
Though I do think the first film is worth watching
too, because it has a lot more traditional, you
know, feudal Japanese elements. But this one is
worth watching for the cool twist on the Justice
League characters. Yeah, that's a great
description of this whole movie, I think it's just
cool. Like a lot of Japanese things are. But that
does it for this review. AJ9K help close this out.
That does it for this episode, guys. We want to give
a big thanks to our executive producers, John
Strausky, Zachary Hepburn, Mickey Bathegan,
Brandon Essargard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi
Yatyn, Austin Wosalowski, AJ Dunkerly, Nick
Obonto, Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Spees,
Dean Molesky, Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, Josh
Leiner, Mike Williams, and Oscar Galvez for
helping make this podcast possible. We'll talk to
you guys next week. Up up and away, true believers.
So, that's it for this episode.