This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi and welcome
to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe, and I'm his twin
brother Johnny DC. And today you're going to hear
Bloodsport get an ass whooping by Killmonger, the
Black Panther villain, because this is gonna be
embarrassing, I think, for DC. Actually, you're
here today to witness a murder of Killmonger by
Bloodsport. T'Challa, but also the other way
around. Yeah, that's right, we are going to find
out who'd win in a fight between Bloodsport, the
Superman villain, I think he's mostly Superman
villain, against Killmonger, the Black Panther
villain. And who would win in a fight between
Superman and Black Panther? Superman. Easily
Black Panther, because Vibranium, obviously.
What? That's not the answer for everything,
Joseph. We're gonna plug in these character
stats, run simulations, and find out who'd win the
most out of 1,000 matches before that, though
we're gonna break down the latest comic book movie
news to come out this past week, of which we did get
some decent news. Finally, we got some
announcements. Yeah. We were hoping for a last
episode, specifically that the Superman movie
that came out this year will be releasing a sequel
in 2027, titled Man of Tomorrow. And there was also
a Marvel Zombies trailer that came out this past
week that was a whole lot of fun, definitely want to
talk about it. But as always, we list our segment
times in our episode description, so feel free to
check out the show notes if you want to skip ahead to
a particular topic. Guys, our artificially
intelligent dual simulator, AJ9K, has a quick
message for our listeners, so listen up. Thanks,
AJ9K, and thanks to everyone who supports the
show. Including our executive producer, Devin
Davis, who we forgot to wish a happy birthday last
episode because we suck, but we're gonna make that
right. Devin, happy birthday, man. Happy
birthday. If I could give you a gift of anything
from Marvel, I would grant you a holographic image
inducer, specifically the type that X-Men like
Nightcrawler used to use, because I know that
sometimes you cosplay. I feel like that would help
out with that. I'm gonna get you something way
cooler, Devin. I'm gonna get you Madame Zanadu's
Tarot Deck, because I know you're into the magic
side of both Marvel and DC, and I think you would
really like that. That is a good one. That's a good
one. It's not the better gift, but it is a good one.
I'll let Devin decide that. Guys, be sure to tune
into the other shows and the Dynamite Podcast
Network this week, including console, combat,
where hosts John and Dean simulate battles
between popular video game characters. In
yesterday's episode, the two determined who
would win between Heishiro Bitsuguri from Soul
Calibur and Hao Maru from Samurai Showdown. Over
on the Max Destruction Podcast hosts Scotty and
Gilly, pet your favorite action heroes from film
and television against each other. On Wednesday,
they're going to find out who would win in a fight
between Chase Walker from Never Back Down and Yuri
Boyka from Undisputed. On the Central World
Podcast hosts Zachary Hepburn speculates on
fights between fan favorite anime and manga
characters. In this next episode, Zach's going to
reveal who would win between Trafalgar D.
Waterlaw from One Piece and Tanjiro Karinji from
Bleach. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or click the
link in our show notes to listen to all of the shows
in the Dynamite Podcast Network. But with that out
of the way, quick to the no prize. A no prize is an
award that Marvel used to give out to fans. Our
version, the Dynamic Dual No Prize, is a digital
award we post on Instagram for the person that we
feel gave the best answer to our question of the
week. Last week we asked who would be your number
one quarterback running back, wide receiver,
tight end, safety and kicker on your Marvel or DC
fantasy football team? Yeah, we asked that
because it's fantasy football season, the
football season is starting and there was no news
from last week. And my team sucks right now. Oh my
gosh, I lost my first game so bad. I won mine
actually, I got like the second highest score in
the league this week. Oh, okay. I'm happy for you,
Trafalgar. Aside of things to come in regards to
Bloodsport vs Killmonger perhaps. We got a few
answers. Let's go ahead and give our first
honorable mention to Lorenzo Valdez who said, My
team would of course be the Smallville Crows with
Whitney Fordman as quarterback, Clark Kent as
running back, Victor Stone as wide receiver,
Jason Teague as tight end, Michael John Carter as
safety and Pete Ross as kicker. Clona forever and
always, buh-bye. Okay, no surprise Lorenzo gave a
Smallville answer seemingly this is a high school
team. I guess considering it features a lot of high
school characters from the Smallville
television series. We've got Whitney, Lana's
boyfriend from early seasons as quarterback. You
got Clark himself as a running back. You've got
Cyborg on the team. You've got Jason Teague,
another romantic interest for Lana on there.
Michael John Carter is probably an older member of
the team, but you know, maybe he got held back a
couple of years. And of course, Pete Ross is the
kicker. Not a bad Smallville high school team. I
was going to say that they'd get their asses kicked
considering they are a high school team, but given
that they have Superman and Cyborg and Booster
Gold on there, they might be able to hold their own.
They're going to state. Great answer Lorenzo. Our
next honorable mention goes to Alex Albro who
said, Hey guys, Dr. Strange with my quarterback.
He's going to put the ball where it needs to be sling
ring that thing. Wolverine's my running back
because he's small, compact and doesn't mind head
trauma. Spider-Man's got sticky fingers. You saw
him in Endgame with the gauntlet. He's my wide
receiver. Hawkeye, older liable is my tight end.
Ironman with his iron legion is going to lock it
down on defense and Batrock is my kicker because
he's got that leg. My cheer captain's either dead
pull or black bolt. My team name is the one liners
because they're all good at quips and
catchphrases or because that's all black bolt
needs. One liners is a great name for that team, but
I thought you were going to call it sling ring that
thing because that was a great catchphrase. Dr.
Strange is an interesting choice for your
quarterback, but a valid one. I think he'd put all
kinds of magic spells on the ball or something like
that. I really like Batrock as the kicker. I'm
surprised he went with Hawkeye for the tight end. I
thought maybe he might make a good quarterback as
well. I know we didn't ask for cheer captain, but
the fact that you went with either dead pull or
black bolt was interesting. I definitely would go
dead pull in that case because I wouldn't want
black bolt to destroy the entire stadium. I also
thought Spider-Man as a wide receiver was
brilliant. Yeah, that's really good. Great
answer, Alex. Our final honorable mention goes to
Noah Terry, who said... So for my Marchman is DC
themed team, I got Superman as the quarterback,
obviously. You got Wonder Woman as the kicker, got
Martian Manhunter as the safety. You got Shazam as
the tight end. You got the Flash as the running
back. And you got Green Lantern Hell Jordan as the
wide receiver. That's my answer. And that is a
solid DC All-Star lineup. Definitely going to the
Super Bowl. Definitely probably winning the
Super Bowl, if I'm being honest. It's basically
the Justice League as a football team. That being
said, Jonathan, Noah did forget to name the team.
What do you think is a good name for this team? The
Justice League. All right. Great answer, Noah. We
want to give a quick shout out to Travis Herndon,
who called in with his answer, but forgot to name
one of the positions. He did have a great team
lineup, though. That was called the NYC Chumps.
But the winner of this week's No Prize is Colby
Hentges, who said... My fantasy football team
would be called the Executioners. My quarterback
would be the grizzled vet with telekinesis,
Nathan Summers. My running back, the unstoppable
Kane Marco. Wide receiver, the fastest mutant on
the planet, Jean-Paul Boubert. Tied end, 9
vulnerable when he's blasted in Sam Guthrie. My
safety would be defensive coverage master Kurt
Wagner. And my kicker would be the British girl who
loves her footy Betsy Braddock. Man did this guy
nail the assignment. I love each and every one of
these options. If you don't know the characters by
their given names, his quarterback is Cable. His
running back is Juggernaut. His wide receiver is
North Star. Who's a speedster in Alpha Flight. His
tight end is Cannonball. His safety is
Nightcrawler. And his kicker, of course, is
Psylocke. Or Captain Britain, as she's known
currently. The Betsy Braddock version. Who's
British. Of course, the Brits love soccer. Not
only did he nail each position, I think, with
characters that have traits that suit the
position, but he also stood with a theme with
regards to the world of X-Men and adequately named
the team as the Executioners. I just thought it
worked on every level. I mean, I don't know if they
would beat the Justice League team, but it is a damn
good team. That Justice League team is like the
Patriots. No one wants to root for them. They're
probably cheating as well. That's fair. So great
answer, Colby. You win this week's No Prize. If
you, the listener, want to shout out winning your
own No Prize, stay tuned to later on this episode
when we'll be asking another question of the week.
And now that that's done, on to the news. So
Superman, the first film in James Gunn's DCU hit
theaters in July. And it's been an amazing success
doing incredibly well, especially at the
domestic box office. So much so that last week,
James Gunn announced another Superman film is
coming July 9th, 2027, titled Man of Tomorrow. Of
course, David Cornswet is returning as Superman,
as is Nicholas Holt, both of whom teased Man of
Tomorrow on their social media accounts with
images of Superman and Lex Luthor side by side.
With Lex being in his classic green war suit, which
is pretty awesome. I'm hoping that means we'll get
to see it in this upcoming film. I don't know if the
two characters are going to join forces against a
larger threat or what is going on, but I am
interested to see how their antagonistic
relationship continues to develop as this
universe progresses. Now, it seems like it's a
Superman sequel, but James Gunn is not claiming it
as a Superman sequel, correct? Well, he's
claiming it's not a direct sequel to the first
Superman movie. So I don't know if that means he's
not just continuing that story or what exactly
that means. I think he's the long clear as to what
direct sequel means as well. In fact, he said that
Superman 2 is a sequel to Peacemaker season 2.
Regardless, yeah, this is a sequel to the first
Superman movie, but I think it's going to feature a
lot more characters, or at least that's the rumor,
sort of like how Civil War was a Captain American
movie that featured a ton of other cast members. Or
the first Superman movie. Yeah, true, like the
Injustice Gang. Right now, the rumors are that
John Stuart and Hawk Girl are going to play a role in
this film, but personally, I'm hoping for Batman
and Wonder Woman. There's not too much more to say
about this other than the release date, which is
pretty exciting, because we'll be getting a
Batman and Superman film in the same year of 2027.
I'm really excited to learn more about the movie as
more information comes out, including the
villain, and that brings us to our question of the
week. Who do you want the villain for Man of
Tomorrow to be? And why? Record your answer at
DynamicDuel.com by clicking on the red
microphone button in the bottom right hand corner
of the screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message can be up to 30 seconds
long, and don't forget to leave your name in case we
include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person at Dynamic
Duel No Prize that we'll post to Instagram. Be sure
to answer before September 13th. In Marvel News,
we got perhaps one of the greatest trailers that
Marvel Studios has ever put out, or Marvel
Television I guess in this case, and that is the
trailer for the upcoming Marvel Zombies animated
series. If you guys have not seen this yet,
definitely go on YouTube, check out the Marvel
Zombies official trailer. It's the one that
starts off by saying that the following is rated
TVMA before an arrow goes through the head of a
zombie. It's worth watching if you're into this
kind of stuff. It looks like it's going to be such a
good time. It looks so much cooler than I thought it
would. Marvel Zombies, that's a cool project. But
it really looks like they're going all out with the
violence. Like way more than they did in What If.
Right. And I don't know if it was the song choice
that they chose for the trailer, because I'm a big
fan of Baby Metal. It's a Japanese metal band. The
song choice was top notch. It was so good. We got to
see all kinds of characters kicking all kinds of
ass just spotting from the trailer. We know that
among the survivors of the zombie outbreak from
the What If episode is going to be Shang-Chi. I
think I saw Kate Bishop, Hawkeye. There was
definitely Yelena Bolova, Black Panther, and
Ant-Man. And Ms. Marvel was on there. Kamala Khan.
That was really interesting. We also saw
Spider-Man pull off one of the most epic zombie
decapitation movies of all time. And of course,
Blade. Blade was really interesting. He's not
going to be voiced by Mahershala Ali, but it's
really cool to see him in one of these Marvel
Studios properties. He's wearing Moon Knight's
outfit for some reason. That's really
interesting. Yeah, I didn't even realize it was
Blade initially because of the voice, I think. And
it wasn't until the very end when he was doing the
sickest swordsmanship against Ghost that I
realized, oh shit, this is Blade. Yeah, even more
than the survivors, I'm looking forward to seeing
the Zobified Heroes, the ones that were turned.
And of course, we saw Scarlet Witch as one of the
zombies that's a carryover from The What If Show.
We saw Captain America, Clint Barton's Hawkeye.
Saw the Abomination. That's fucking crazy as a
zombie. Namor looked really cool. They even made a
point to call him out as a zombie. And he sliced some
chick like right in half. That was nuts. Overall,
this thing is just turning out to be like a Marvel
fan and a zombies fan and even a Marvel Zombies
comic book fans dream. And while we won't be
reviewing the four episode mini series coming out
in a month, I will definitely be watching the hell
out of it and will most likely be giving my thoughts
here on this podcast. Right, we're not going to
dedicate an entire episode to the review, but I am
curious to hear what you think about it. Yeah, the
show starts in just a few weeks on September 24th
and then it's going to run each week after that.
Which is perfect and lead up to Halloween. I cannot
wait if anything this trailer shows just how cool
Marvel can be, especially when compared to the
very not cool DC Universe. Wait, what? How? Has DC
ever put out anything like this? The answer is no.
Case closed. I mean, there was like Constantine.
Yeah, no, sorry. Did Constantine have a baby metal
soundtrack? I rest my case. No, but it had perfect
circle. We're talking about metal, not new metal.
Okay. But that does overall the news for this
episode, so let's go ahead and move into our main
event where we find out who would win in a fight
between the Superman villain Bloodsport and the
Black Panther villain Kilmonger. Alright,
Bloodsport versus Kilmonger. I think mainly
we're doing this duel because the characters
stood out so much in their respective films that
they started from a few years ago. Of course,
Kilmonger was played by Michael B. Jordan in the
2018 Black Panther movie, really stood out as a
tremendous villain, probably cooler than he ever
was in the comics. So, you know, he's been pretty
badass in the comic books. He was just really well
adapted to screen. As was Bloodsport played by
Idris Elba in the Suicide Squad film directed by
James Gunn. The character is a little bit
different than that in the comics, but that was
still a really good adaptation of the character, I
would say. Yeah, in the Suicide Squad film, the
character was known for having like all these
different gadgets on his person on his body suit
that could transform into weapons. Right. And
they also drastically altered the look of the
character from what he had in the comics at the
time, though the comics have adopted the look from
the film because it was just so cool. Like it is my
go-to skin in Fortnite. Do you have a Kilmonger
skin in Fortnite, Joseph? I don't, but I have a
Black Panther skin. Fake fan. Alright. Yeah, the
character of Kilmonger in the comic books has also
taken a lot of cues from the film version just
because it was done so successfully on the big
screen, I think. Of course, we're talking about
two characters who are heavily armed and highly
tactical. I'm really just didn't hear in how this
one turns out. But to explain the methodology
behind our duels, let's go to our sentient duel
simulator, Alfred Jarvis 9000. AJ9K tell our
listeners how you go about determining a winner in
our duel matchups. Yes, of course, sir. The way I
determine a winner between the contestants is by
running 1000 Monte Carlo simulations using the
character's statistics. A Monte Carlo
simulation is a probabilistic model used to
determine outcomes through random sampling. In
this case, I randomize the statistics along a
normal distribution as a way to simulate the many
variables that can occur during battle. The stat
parameters are based on the official Marvel power
grid from which the DC characters' statistics are
extrapolated. Additional stat categories are
included such as range, damage potential,
versatility and perception in order to create a
more detailed and accurate simulation. The
results of the 1000 simulations provide a
percentage of wins for each character. The
contestant with the higher percentage is
declared the victor as they have a higher
probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither character should win
100% of the matches. The comic book stories have
shown that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman, so the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks, AJ9K.
Before we run the simulations, though, we'd like
to break down each character's histories and
abilities before improvising a scenario on how we
imagine one of the 1000 simulations would play out
beat for beat. And I believe it's my turn to go first
with the DC characters' comic book backstory, so
let me tell you all about Bloodsport. Now, Robert
Dubois was a young man when he was drafted into the
Vietnam War. Panicked and fearing for his life,
Robert fled to Canada, leaving his younger
brother Michael, who believed in the war effort,
to assume Robert's identity at a report for duty in
his stead, intent on maintaining his brother's
integrity and clean record. Michael was deployed
to Vietnam, where he lost all four limbs in an
explosion. Overwhelmed by guilt upon hearing
what happened to Michael, Robert suffered a
mental breakdown and was institutionalized in
Canadian psychiatric facilities. Over the
years, he developed vivid combat delusions,
mentally rewriting his own cowardice into a false
past of battlefield trauma. A perfect target for
manipulation, Robert caught the attention of Lex
Luthor, who used a handler named Kimberly to
recruit and outfit Robert with a prototype
teleportation device linked directly to his
nervous system. This surgically implanted rig
allowed him to summon weapons from a hidden,
off-site arsenal instantaneously, including an
experimental rifle that fired
kryptonite-tipped projectiles. With his mind
warped and his arsenal loaded, Robert adopted the
codename Bloodsport and set his sights on
Superman, the symbol of the American values that
he had come to despise. You can learn more about
Superman and Lex Luthor and their respective dual
episodes against Dr. Doom and Baron Zemo. Robert
orchestrated a mass shooting in Metropolis to
lure Superman into battle. Disguised as a
decorated Vietnam war veteran, he opened fire in a
packed cafe, killing dozens. When Superman
intervened, Robert shot him with a
kryptonite-laced needle, forcing Superman to
retreat. The attack sent shockwaves across the
city, prompting even Lex Luthor to distance
himself from the carnage. Robert later
threatened to detonate the power source of his
teleportation rig, an act that would level 10
square miles of the city. As panic spread, Jimmy
Olsen uncovered Bloodsport's true identity and
tracked down his brother Michael in a veterans
hospital. Michael was brought to the scene, where
his presence triggered a complete emotional
collapse in Robert. Realizing the damage he'd
caused, Robert surrendered and was incarcerated
as Stryker's Island Penitentiary for the
criminally insane. While in prison, Robert
encountered a new inmate, Alexander Trent, a
white supremacist who had appropriated the
Bloodsport identity to promote his extremist
agenda, and to spite Robert due to his race. Their
feud escalated until the Warden sanctioned a
boxing match between the two, overseen by
Superman. The event erupted into a prison riot,
during which time Robert seized one of Trent's
smuggled weapons and attempted to escape. He was
shot by guards and presumed dead. Trent continued
operating under the Bloodsport name, committing
racially motivated terror attacks in Metropolis
and other cities, though he was eventually
defeated during a violent confrontation with
Superman and Black Lightning. During the
Salvation Run initiative when criminals were
exiled to a distant planet, a third unidentified
version of Bloodsport, who shared Robert's
teleportation-based weaponry with military
training, was shown to be trapped along with other
villains on an alien world. This Bloodsport
fought for Lex Luthor's side, though upon
returning to Earth with the other villains, he
joined Intergang before eventually being caught
by Superman. After the Flashpoint resets of DC's
continuity, Robert Devois was reimagined with a
revised history. In this continuity, he and his
brother Mickey dreamed of serving in the
military. When Mickey enlisted and was killed in
combat, Robert blamed the government, the war,
and the American system itself. Adopting the
Bloodsport moniker, he sought calculated
vengeance, targeting symbols of state power,
particularly Superman. Using stolen Lex Corp
technology, Robert reverse engineered a
personal teleportation rig that enabled him to
summon a high-tech arsenal mid-combat. Armed
with Kryptonite-based ammunition and
multi-dimensional weapon caches, he attacked
Superman in Metropolis and nearly defeated him
before being subdued. Robert's precision and
battlefield control made him one of Superman's
most dangerous human adversaries. After being
incarcerated at Stryker's Island, he continued
to operate as a mercenary and weapons expert. In
one mission, he joined a crew hired to capture
Solomon Grundy, resulting in a clash with
Superman and Batman. In another, he was hunted by
the Metropolis Police Department and
intercepted by speedsters Barry Allen and Wally
West during a shootout in Hub City and was soon
imprisoned once again. Amanda Waller eventually
recruited him into the Suicide Squad after seeing
potential in his teleportation tech and ruthless
efficiency, outfitting him with upgraded armor
and access to an expanded arsenal. His missions
escalated from standard infiltration to
multi-versal reconnaissance. On a mission to
Earth 3, Robert was captured and tortured by
Ultraman. After Waller dispatched the Suicide
Squad to recover him, she ensured his continued
compliance by revealing that she had embedded
explosives in every multi-versal variant of his
brother Mickey as leverage. Furious at Waller's
manipulation, Robert joined Rick Flag's rogue
squad to dismantle Waller's operation. You can
learn more about Rick Flag in our Rick Flag vs. Nick
Fury Duel episode. Flag's rebellion culminated
in a direct assault on the crime syndicate of Earth
3, in which Bloodsport served as Field Commander.
Under his orders, the squad ambushed Earth 3's
watchtower, disabling syndicate surveillance
and neutralizing dozens of Owlman's enforcers in
a coordinated strike. After Bloodsport
assassinated one of Waller's top aides during the
conflict, Waller countered by transporting
multiple versions of Mickey into the battlefield
as human shields, and Robert surrendered.
Despite the setback, he played a vital role in
subduing Ultraman and was returned to Earth 1
alongside the surviving multi-versal Mickey.
Following the destruction of Balrive,
Bloodsport stayed with Flag's independent
Suicide Squad. He led a covert heist against
Lexcorp and later competed in a deadly
underground tournament hosted by Roulette,
unknowingly facing a disguised Bruce Wayne in the
final round. During the battle, Wayne sabotaged
Bloodsport's teleportation link, causing
Robert to be pulled into his own weapons vault and
captured. And that's his history. Powers-wise,
Bloodsport possesses no innate superpowers, but
his combat training and tactics combined with his
teleportation... His cybernetic teleportation
rig is connected to an extra-dimensional weapon
cache, allowing him to summon a wide array of
firearms like energy rifles and heavy ordnance,
explosives, and specialized tools such as
shields and jetpacks in the middle of combat.
Robert is a master marksman and ambidextrous
shooter capable of switching weapons or hands
without compromising accuracy. His suit
provides ballistic protection and
modifications to with sand hostile alien
environments. And that's Bloodsport. So
Superman oversaw a boxing match between two
prisoners, one of them being a black man and the
other being a white supremacist? How is that okay?
You know, I don't have an answer. Jesus. That was
one of the weirdest things I think I've ever heard
in these backstories. I know, right? I didn't know
that he could teleport. So he can't teleport, like
physically, his whole body, he could just
teleport weapons. I mean, he can teleport, but
it's only to like retreat back to his weapons
vault. He can't teleport to like various
locations in the battlefield. Oh, okay. All
right, that's good to know. So it's like an
instantaneous teleportation to his cache and
then back to the very spot that he left from. Uh, no,
no, he teleports the weapons themselves. He
doesn't teleport. Oh, I thought you just said that
he could teleport to his weapons cache. You asked
me if he could teleport and I'm saying if he did, it
would just be to his cache. He wouldn't be able to
teleport back to the battlefield. Oh, I see. I see.
So if I understand this correctly, the
teleportation technology he has does not
actually move his physical body unless he's
retreating, but instead teleports the weapons
that he employs in battle. Exactly. It teleports
the weapons to him. So what if he doesn't have
anything in his weapons cache? What if he just has
like a pea shooter? Oh, he's got a ton of stuff in his
weapons cache, like multi-dimensional scary
stuff. Killmonger's dead. That is a scared
Killmonger. Not yet. If Black Panther doesn't
scare him, nothing will. Okay, let me tell you
about Killmonger, whose real name is Njeraka.
Njeraka was born in the African country of Wakanda
to Njobu, a warrior of royal descent. His early
life was marked by tragedy when a fellow Wakandan
named Ndemue betrayed the nation to the mercenary
Ulysses Kla, whom you can learn more about in our
LifeWire vs. Kla duel episode. During Kla's
incursion into Wakanda to steal vibranium,
Njeraka's parents were killed and the boy was
taken captive. Ndemue acted as his custodian
while serving as Kla's accomplice, but treated
the child cruelly and convinced him that Wakanda
had abandoned him. Kla forced Njeraka to renounce
his name and take on the identity of Eric, claiming
the world had no place for him. For years, Eric was
raised in servitude, building devices for Kla's
band of raiders while being told he had no home. His
resentment grew until he finally killed Ndemue
and severed ties with his captors. Reluctant to
return to Wakanda, he settled in Harlem, New York.
There, he pursued education, proving himself a
gifted intellect. He excelled academically,
earning degrees in business, engineering a PhD in
Neural Science, and a master's degree from MIT.
Despite his accomplishments, his hatred
remained fixed on Kla and Wakanda's monarchy,
whom he believed responsible for his parents'
deaths and his abandonment. In New York, Eric
attempted to assassinate Kla, but the mercenary
was protected by Wilson Fisk, the kingpin of
crime, whom you can learn more about in his duel
against the penguin. Killmonger infiltrated the
kingpin's crime ring, however his defiance and
obsession with vengeance against Kla alienated
him from others in the crew. When kingpin betrayed
the group by sending bullseye after them to
eliminate loose ends, the crew disbanded. During
this time, Eric began hearing the voice of a
goddess. He first believed it was Bast, the
Wakandan panther god, but it was later revealed to
be another deity that spoke to him, Kyliluna, the
goddess of war, and a fallen sister of Bast who was
long ago banished from Wakandan worship.
Kyliluna encouraged him to embrace rage and
bloodshed and to take on the name Killmonger.
Killmonger's bitterness deepened. He secretly
obtained intelligence on Wakanda through the
International Espionage Organization Shield
and vanished, determined to bite his time until he
could exact vengeance on his homeland. Years
later, when T'Challa announced that Wakanda
would open itself to the outside world,
Killmonger used the opportunity to return. He
presented himself as a grateful exile, eager to
come home, but inwardly he still seethed with
anger. Secretly, he began plotting to overthrow
the throne. You can learn more about T'Challa, the
Black Panther, in his duel against Black Manta.
Killmonger's schemes centered around a
vibranium shock bomb meant as a deterrent against
colonizers. He murdered fellow Wakandan
refugees using their deaths as experiments with
neuropsychic weaponry while preparing to frame
Wakanda as aggressors. His plan was to drop the
bomb on a shield helicarrier, forcing Wakanda
into global war and destabilizing Black
Panther's rule. T'Challa confronted him, and
with his sister Shuri's aid, the Black Panther was
able to foil the plan. You can learn more about
Shuri in her duel against Aqualath. Rather than be
captured, Killmonger leapt from a plane into a
lake, disappearing once again. He resurfaced
later in Wakanda, taking advantage of Black
Panther's absences with the Avengers to stage
rebellions. He gathered lieutenants such as
Baron Makob, King Kedavre, and Salamander Krule,
building an army known as the Death Regiment. He
manipulated unrest among Wakandans who were
dissatisfied with their king's global focus.
With this army, he attacked the royal palace and
battled Black Panther at warrior falls. He nearly
won, hoisting T'Challa's body over the
precipice, but he was pushed to his death by a boy
whose father had been slain by Killmonger's men.
His dead body was found by a mysterious Wakandan
woman who helped preserve it with herbs. Later,
the villain known as the Mandarin resurrected
Killmonger using Wakanda's resurrection altar
and one of his mystical rings. You can learn more
about the Mandarin in his duel against
Abracadabra. Killmonger allied with the
Mandarin in a plan to transmute Wakanda's
vibranium into Antarctic vibranium, which
vibrates at a frequency capable of dissolving
other metals. Black Panther and Iron Man foiled
the scheme, and when the Mandarin withdrew his
power, Killmonger's body crumbled into a
skeleton. Yet this was not the end. Killmonger's
loyal followers later sacrificed themselves at
the resurrection altar to restore him again.
Reborn, Killmonger attempted to undermine
Wakanda's economy by destroying T'Challa's
reputation abroad. He recruited allies
including Hydroman and Nightshade while
manipulating N'Kia, a former Dora Milaje, into
becoming the villain, Malice. When economic
sabotage failed, Killmonger challenged
T'Challa in a ritual combat for the throne. This
time, he triumphed, becoming King of Wakanda and
assuming the mantle of Black Panther. He even
attempted to join the Avengers into T'Challa's
place, but when he consumed the sacred
heart-shaped herb that gave the Black Panther his
abilities, his body reacted violently. The
herb's properties were poisonous to those
outside the royal bloodline, leaving him
comatose. And a quick side note, I know that I said
that his father was of royal descent, but the only
thing that I could think of is that the writer of
that story forgot, and maybe Killmonger was just
outside where he needed to be on the royal family
tree. Marvel. Shut up. Though T'Challa could have
left Killmonger to die, he kept him alive.
Eventually, Eric awakened and left Wakanda,
traveling to New York where he encountered Casper
Kohl, a police officer who donned an old Black
Panther suit to fight crime. Kohl offered him a
synthetic version of the heart-shaped herb,
hoping to bind Kohl to him as an ally in the Panther
cult. Kohl accepted the herb but chose
independence, and instead of owing Killmonger
allegiance, he took up the identity of the White
Tiger. A mantle that has passed through several
heroes that you can learn more about in our Bronze
Tiger vs White Tiger duel episode. Killmonger
later allied with the US government, who saw him as
a potential means of destabilizing Wakanda. With
their backing, Killmonger conquered Wakanda's
neighbor, Nyganda, and proclaimed himself as its
ruler. He captured Shuri and Monaco Rambo, aka
Photon, or Spectrum I like to call her Photon,
forcing Wakanda into conflict. In battle, he
fought Black Panther once again, with both of them
wearing advanced suits of armor. Killmonger
gained the upper hand, but Photon freed herself
and struck him at light speed, killing him. His son
witnessed the event and swore vengeance against
T'Challa. However, even this death was not the end
for Killmonger. While dead, Wakanda began
exploring the stars, searching for the source of
the meteor that struck Earth millennia ago and
formed the Great Mound Vibranium deposit that
Wakanda was built upon. The explorers traveled
through a temporal anomaly that brought them back
in time to the vast reaches of space, and they began
settling on habitable planets, making Wakanda
the first large-scale human intergalactic
empire. From one of the colonies came a new
Injadaka, named after Killmonger's birth name.
He rose to power and became a tyrant over the
colonies, becoming a host to a Klingtar symbiote.
You can learn more about the parasitic Klingtar
symbiotes in our Clayface vs. Venom duel episode.
Eventually, this Injadaka and the intergalactic
empire traveled to Earth in an attempt to invade
and overthrow what they called Wakanda Prime in
Africa. When they were stopped by the Black
Panther and Injadaka was killed, his symbiote was
placed on Killmonger's corpse on their
resurrection altar. The ritual succeeded in
reviving Killmonger but created a struggle
between his soul and that of the intergalactic
tyrant for control of their shared body.
Together, they returned to space and commanded
immense armies in symbiotic power, waging war
across galaxies. Yet their internal conflict
weakened them. When confronted by T'Challa in a
final battle, he was able to strike a killing blow,
ending Killmonger's threat once more. And that's
Killmonger's backstory. Powers-wise, I'm not
going with the recent symbiote-enhanced Eric
Killmonger. I'll be going with the traditional
mercenary slash warlord Killmonger,
specifically the one wearing the suit from the
Back to Africa story arc from Black Panther Volume
4. Though the heart-shaped herb was poisonous to
him, it did also enhance its natural physicality
in the same way it affected T'Challa and his royal
ancestors. This means he is in peak human physical
condition, including his speed, stamina,
strength, reflexes, agility, and durability. He
has enhanced senses, is a master martial artist,
and expert strategist. Killmonger is an expert in
neural science, having engineered electrode
gadgets that can extract information from or
paralyze the human brain, as well as devices that
can command animal life, including a pair of
trained leopards. He is also a gifted chemist,
having developed a non-poisonous synthetic
version of the heart-shaped herb and various
toxins. He has worn body armor, not a full suit like
the Black Panther habit, but a vibranium chest
plate with pauldrons on the shoulders and face
mask. He also wears vibranium bracers with
poisonous spikes, hidden blades, concussive
energy blasters, and communication devices. For
this matchup, he'll also have a vibranium
Wakandan spear and short sword. But does he have an
entire arsenal cash at his disposal? He has an
entire arsenal on his person. Not enough. It's not
going to be enough. It will be enough because while
Bloodsport's running around, being all
ineffective, he's just going to get got. Get gatt.
We'll see. Apparently, this guy dies all the time.
So, damn it. But now that we've got their histories
and abilities out of the way, let's speculate on
how one of the 1000 simulated matches will go. The
winner is determined by simulations, not this
speculation, but it's fun to imagine how the fight
could play out. AG9K, what are the rules of our
speculation? Well, I should say there are no
rules, other than the characters have no prior
knowledge of the other going into the fight. All
they are aware of starting out is that the other
character is a threat that needs to be eliminated.
For the speculation, the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the match
itself, as no environmental statistics are
considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. Alright,
then let's get into it. Bloodsport and Killmonger
meet on the battlefield? Who goes first?
Bloodsport is pretty calculating, so I'll say he
starts off by summoning a sniper rifle with an
X-ray scope and he's gonna target Killmonger's
heart, just dead center and fire around. I mean,
Bloodsport is not more calculating than
Killmonger, but we'll give you this first shot.
The bullet hits Killmonger in the chest, but the
funny thing about a vibranium chest plate is that
it's gonna absorb any force directed against it,
so that bullet just felt like a cotton ball to
Killmonger, who's probably like surprised that
the guy got a shot off, but he's gonna retaliate by
firing two concussive force blasts from his
Wakandan spear at Bloodsport. One of the blasts is
to knock the rifle out of his hand, and the other
blast is to knock him on his ass. Okay, I mean, the
funny thing about an extra-dimensional,
multiversal weapons cache, though, is that you
never quite know what Bloodsport is going to
summon from it, and this rifle actually fired a
spider drone onto Killmonger, not an actual
round. So while Bloodsport is dodging
Killmonger's force blasts, that spider drone is
gonna crawl down Killmonger's arm onto his spear,
at which point it's gonna explode. Just detonate
this powerful explosion, and that's gonna send
his spear flying far away from him. Wait, so you're
telling me that this spider drone that Bloodsport
shot onto Killmonger could have detonated on
Killmonger's head, but instead why did it choose
to blow up the spear? Fuck. What a dunce. That
spider's stupid. I'm gonna say that the spider
drone didn't even make it to the spear, because it
got impaled on one of Killmonger's spikes that he
has on his arm bracers. Okay, but Killmonger's
going to quickly recognize that Bloodsport is
like a marksman, so he's gonna be strategic and try
to close the distance between the two. So he's
gonna sprint, he's gonna blitz Bloodsport, and
hurl his Wakandan warblade at him, which is like
this machete weapon, and it takes off one of
Bloodsport's hands. Okay, well, I'm assuming
this warblade is vibranium? Fuck yeah it is. Of
course it's vibranium. Okay, so while Killmonger
is charging towards Bloodsport, Bloodsport has
seen the metallic armor and weaponry that
Killmonger has, so he's gonna summon a magnetic
mine launcher, and he's gonna fire a mine between
him and Killmonger, and that mine's gonna attract
Killmonger's sword just straight down onto it, as
well as Killmonger himself as he nears it, and he's
just gonna plant face first straight onto that
mine, which Bloodsport is then gonna detonate. So
there's your face explosion. You happy? No,
because if Bloodsport activated this magnetic
mine, then the sword that Killmonger threw would
have been pulled into it first, and it would have
just sliced right through it and disabled it. So
that did nothing. Killmonger picks up the blade as
he continues sprinting toward Bloodsport, and he
closes the distance and just straight up spears
and impales Bloodsport right through the chest.
Except blam! Electrified net launcher, just as
Killmonger reaches Bloodsport. So now
Killmonger's trapped on the ground, being
electrocuted, and that's when Bloodsport
summons a 44 magnum revolver and just gives
Killmonger a fatal dose of lead poisoning right
there on the ground. I mean, with how fast
Killmonger closed the distance while sprinting,
I don't think Bloodsport would have had time to
summon and fire a net launcher, but say grant you
that Bloodsport fired the net. Like how's it gonna
get past the spear that Killmonger is swiping at
him, right? The net's just gonna get all caught and
twisted in the spear, so Killmonger discards it,
tossing it to the ground, and without missing a
beat, crouches, knee slides past Bloodsport and
slashes his Achilles tendons on his ankles, which
drops him to his knees. Okay, except Bloodsport
just fucking hopped into the air as Killmonger
slides past him, and while in mid-air, he's gonna
summon a Thunderbuster 2000X, which fires around
every millisecond. No way Killmonger can dodge
that, even sliding on the ground, so he just gets
riddled with bullets from behind. I mean, the gun
may shoot fast, but it doesn't make Bloodsport
fast. Like recognizing that Bloodsport left over
his slash attack and is now drawing a gun on him,
Killmonger's gonna slash with his Wakandan
Warblade at the gun's barrel, which is just gonna
cleave it in two. So yeah, this gun fires around
every millisecond, more like backfires every
millisecond, which is gonna destroy that gun, and
probably Bloodsport's hands when it explodes in
his grasp. And at that point, Killmonger is gonna
press the advantage, he's gonna slap a neural
device on Bloodsport's head that's gonna
infiltrate his mask. I don't know how, but it did
infiltrate Black Panther's mask, okay? And it
paralyzes him with this searing pain, and while
Bloodsport's like struggling, Killmonger does a
neural extraction using the device and gets
Bloodsport to tell him where these weapons are
coming from. And once he finds out it's through
teleportation, Killmonger ganks his teleporter
and then just fries Bloodsport's brain with the
neural device. So the match is over. Okay, way too
many moves. I mean, if a gun explodes in your hand
and then you get paralyzed with a neural
electrode, I'd say Killmonger gets all the moves
he wants. First of all, Bloodsport is
ambidextrous and was holding the Thunderbuster
with one hand, so he still has his other one, you
know? Second, Bloodsport wears a fucking helmet,
not a mask. So even if the neural device manages to
connect with his neural network, it's a weak
connection. So the pain isn't as strong as you
think. And that's gonna give Bloodsport enough
leeway to summon a giant fucking laser cannon
while Killmonger is asking him dumb questions. So
Bloodsport blasts Killmonger apart, leaving
nothing but bones and some vibranium armor and
weapons, which are now gonna go on Bloodsport's
weapons cache. So match is really over now. No,
Killmonger has enhanced senses. Like if he sees
Bloodsport is reaching for a gun during his
interrogation, he's just gonna straight up blast
the dude's head off with one of his wrist mounted
force blasters. What do you mean reaching for a
gun? Bloodsport doesn't reach for guns. They
materialize in his hands. I said raising his gun.
If he sees him raising his gun. If he sees him
raising a gun, it's already too late. Yeah, for
Bloodsport, because Killmonger blasts his head
off. No, no. Killmonger is disintegrated. That's
how it ends. Well, let's see which of those cases is
true by running the simulations. It's a quick draw
situation, I guess. Either Bloodsport manages to
blast Killmonger with this energy cannon, or he's
too paralyzed from the neural device to move
quickly enough and Killmonger notices and blasts
him before he gets blasted. Let's go ahead and
input the stats, run the sims, and come back with a
winner. AG9K, hit it! Inputting data, running
calculations, processing results, simulations
complete. Alright, this is a damn good matchup.
These guys went back and forth on a lot of the stats,
but they were like close on a lot of the stats too.
Yeah, I'm kind of getting a flashback to last week
where they kind of played a tit for a tat with each of
these stats. We said that they were equal when it
came to movement speed and evasiveness, but we
also said that Bloodsport was more durable, he
could inflict more damage, he had a greater range
and was more versatile. Yeah, whereas Killmonger
is stronger than Bloodsport having ingested the
heart-shaped herb, we also said he's a better
fighter, barely, is definitely smarter though,
and has enhanced perception due to his increased
senses. Yeah, the intelligence stat was actually
the greatest discrepancy between the two. Right,
because not only has Killmonger overthrown an
entire nation, he's also like a master engineer,
neuroscientist, and chemist. Whereas
Bloodsport's crazy. Yeah, and most iterations of
the character Bloodsport is mentally unstable.
But taking all of these stats into consideration,
Joseph, who do you think came out on top? This is
going to be close, actually. So the Bloodsport's
better than Killmonger in a lot of places where it
counts. I do think Killmonger would be able to
outsmart Bloodsport, but yeah, I think it's going
to be close. I'm going to root for Killmonger
though. Instagram is siding with DC. Again, as
always, 56% of the poll takers are siding with
Bloodsport. They sided with Marvel last week, did
they? Yeah. Oh, I don't know, it hurts more when
they side with DC, so it feels like they're always
against me. Well, let's see if they chose
correctly this time. AJ9K, the results, please.
Hey, you are, sir. The winner of the matchup
between Bloodsport and Killmonger is
Killmonger. Hell yeah, hell yeah. Finally.
Finally. Which, damn it. Killmonger won 524 of the
1000 matches or 52.4% compared to Bloodsport who
won 47.6% of the time. So it was a close, close
match. I mean, Bloodsport has better gadgets and
gear, right? But Killmonger's no slouch in that
department. He has a lot of gadgets and gear
himself, but he also has the enhanced physicals
and the smarts, I think, that overpowered
Bloodsport. And that's pretty much exactly why he
won. In the areas where Bloodsport was better, he
was just barely better. And in the areas where
Killmonger was better, it was by a little bit more
like intelligent. Close match, though. Yeah,
yeah, really close. I'm kind of sad I lost this one.
Bloodsport's powers are pretty damn cool. Like if
I could have a superpower, I think Bloodsport's
would be pretty awesome. That is a cool power, sir.
Yeah, I like it more than what they did in the
Suicide Squad movie, where every weapon of his was
just kind of part of his suit. I mean, that was a
great way to ground his ability in the movie. But
the idea of him being able to teleport any weapon
from his cash into his hand, I think, is even
niftier. Well, Bloodsport had a suit similar to
that, a different design. It was created for him by
Lex Luthor, where he could pull different nano
weapons off of his armor. Interesting. He used it
against Superboy, but yeah, I prefer the
teleportation. What would be an interesting
fight is the movie versions of these characters
where we have Killmonger wearing the Black
Panther habit, going against Bloodsport wearing
his nanotech suit. We didn't end up doing that for
this matchup because we're going with the comic
book versions, as always, but maybe that might be a
good option for the Max Destruction podcast down
the line. Oh yeah, I'm down for that. That'd be
really cool. Maybe Bloodsport could get his
revenge. Or Marvel could win twice, which is twice
as nice. Honestly, I don't see Marvel losing
another duel matchup after this one. I think we're
going to go on a streak for the rest of the year,
leading up to January and the end of this podcast,
and it feels good feeling that confident right
now. Are you just saying that because I said that?
No, but it's easy to say things like that when
you're riding high off of a win. Pride comeeth
before the fall, my friend. Trust me, I speak from
experience. But that does it for this duel. AJ9K
help close us out. Our next episode is going to be a
team duel where we find out who would win in a fight
between the Legion of Superheros and the new
mutants. It's going to be a good one. I kind of think
it's lopsided, but I guess we'll find out. But that
does it for this episode. We want to give a big
thanks to our executive producers, John
Staroski, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Belcom,
Mickey Muthangian, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi
Yatyn, Austin Wizolowski, Aji Dunkerley,
Nikobanto, Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam
Speese, Dean Maleski, Devin Davis, Joseph
Kirsting, Josh Schleiner, Mike Williams, and
Paul Graves for helping make this podcast
possible. We'll talk to you guys next week. Up, up
and away, true believers.