This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. I'm Marvellous
Joe and I'm his twin brother Johnny DC. And in this
episode, after taking a quick detour into the
Mortal Kombat vs. Street Fighter realm, we're
coming back to Marvel vs. DC and finding out who
would win in a fight between the rodent themed
characters of Ratcatcher and Squirrel Girl. And I
should note right off the bat that her name is the
unbeatable Squirrel Girl. So Jonathan, if you
think you're winning this episode, you're going
to get beat. What do you mean, like in real life or in
the match? I mean, in real life. Oh, no. For having
such a bad opinion. Yeah, Ratcatcher is probably
most famous for being in the Suicide Squad film
directed by James Gunn. But in the comics, the
character actually hasn't been around that long.
Like he doesn't have too many appearances. Same
with Squirrel Girl, actually. She debuted in the
90s and then had a few appearances, didn't appear
for like 10 years until Great Lakes Avengers and
then really came to the forefront in the recent
Marvel Rivals video game. So we're going to get all
into her history and Ratcatcher's history later
on this episode. But before that, we're going to
break down the latest comic book movie news to come
out this past week, of which we got two news items.
First one being the Superman sneak peek and the
other one being the new title reveal for the
Spiderman four film. Yeah, both of these news
items came out of CinemaCon, which is like Comic
Con, but for movies. As always, we list our segment
times in our episode description, so feel free to
check out the show notes if you want to skip ahead to
a particular topic. Guys, our artificially
intelligent dual simulator, AJ9K, has a quick
message for our listeners. So listen up. Why hello
there. Do you want even more from this podcast?
Then become a part of the Dynamic Jewel community
on Patreon, where you can choose from three tiers.
The Dynamic 2.0 tier gives you access to our
Discord chat server. The Fantastic Four tier
gives you two bonus episodes each month. And the
X-Force tier makes you an executive producer of
this show. Lastly, the Diner Mike podcast network
tier lets you create your own podcast using this
Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe will help
you develop your show, provide graphic support
and consultation and get you simulation results.
Pitch the twins your ideas via email at
dynamicjewelpodcast at gmail.com. Check it out
at patreon.com slash dynamicjewel. Pip pip
cheerio. Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone who
supports the podcast. Be sure to tune into the
other shows and the Dynamite podcast network this
week, including the console combat podcast,
where hosts John and Dean simulate battles
between popular video game characters. In
yesterday's episode, they speculated who would
win in a fight between Little Mac from Punch Out
against Balrog from Street Fighter, who's a
boxing episode. And over on the Max Destruction
podcast, hosts Scotty and Gilly pit your favorite
action heroes from film and television against
each other. This Wednesday, the twins are
carrying on the Street Fighter theme by reviewing
the 1994 film Street Fighter the Movie. And on the
Senjo World podcast, host Zachary Hepburn
speculates on fights between fan favorite anime
and manga characters. On Thursday, Zach's going
to reveal who would win in a fight between Dante
from Devil May Cry versus Bash the Stampede from
Trigun. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or click the
link in our show notes to listen to all of the shows
in the Dynamite podcast network. But with that out
of the way, quick to the no prize. A no prize is an
award that Marvel used to give out to fans. Our
version, the Dynamic Dual No Prize, is a digital
award we post on Instagram for the person that we
feel gave the best answer to our question of the
week. Last week, we asked you guys which character
not announced for Avengers Doomsday, which you
most like to have seen and why. And of course, this
is coming off of the cast reveal for Avengers
Doomsday that came out a few weeks ago. We got a few
answers, just three it looks like. So we have two
honorable mentions and one no prize winner. Our
first honorable mention goes to Mike Williams.
Who said? Hi guys. Mike Williams here. The person
that was not announced. I would like to say Michael
fast vendor, the younger Magneto. I can't see Dr.
Dooms pulling off all this mayhem against all
these heroes that I will help. And then maybe the
younger Magneto turn on them at the end of the movie
as always make my model. Check out. Yeah, we got to
reveal that some of the X-Men characters from the
original Fox franchise are going to be in Avengers
Doomsday, including Patrick Stewart as
Professor X in McKellen as Magneto. James Marsden
as Cyclops, etc. We did not receive word that any of
the new cast of characters from the rebooted
timeline, starting with X-Men first class, is
going to show up. So characters like James
McAvoy's Professor X or Michael fast benders,
Magneto, are not going to appear. Possibly,
allegedly. We'll see if they end up showing up on
the cast list. But those actors will be sorely
missed, especially Michael fastbender as
Magneto, who really came to define the character
on his own, apart from Ian McKellen's version.
Yeah, what duo did it better, Patrick Stewart and
Ian McKellen or James McAvoy and Michael
fastbender? I can't choose. They were both great.
Gun to your head, gun to your balls. I guess I would
go with James McAvoy and Michael fastbender, just
because I think they brought just as much gravitas
to the roles as the elder actors. But they brought
this cool factor that wasn't quite as prevalent.
That's probably blasphemy. I don't feel good
about that answer. It's a fucked up question. It's
a fucked up question. Yeah, I mean, you gave the
wrong answer to because there really is no right
answer to that question. Right, right. Great
answer, Michael Williams. Our next honorable
mention goes to Travis Bailey. Who said? Travis
from that town. What's up there, twin? All right,
so we spoke about it. Give me Haley Stanfield's
Potter Twin. I know this dove, Cameron. I can see
the vision there. I'm cool with that. I see the
vision. Or give me Dallas Dupre Young and Cobra Kai
as Miles Morales. Now, you got something there. He
laying hands on cats like here, Reverend, like he
like he under the revival tent. Man, because we
don't have that iconic spider-man fighting scene
like we got from Derrick Devil and Vassal. Yeah,
Travis gave two answers here. He said either Haley
Stanfield as Gwen Stacy. Of course, she voices the
character of Gwen Stacy in the Spider-Verse
animated films or Dallas Dupre Young as Miles
Morales. And I agree with both of those answers.
Haley Stanfield, I think is a little bit older than
Dallas Dupre Young. And, you know, of course,
Dallas doesn't voice Miles in the Spider-Verse
films. That's Shamique Moore. I also think you'd
be a great Miles Morales. But I think you do want to
cast pretty dang young like teenager aged for
Miles and Spider-Gwen if they were to show up.
Yeah, honestly, if you could get Haley Stanfield
to cameo as Gwen Stacy and Shamique Moore to cameo
as Miles Morales, that would be perfection. But
Dallas Dupre Young as Miles Morales is something
I'd never considered. I think if you're going to
get him as Miles Morales, though, you shouldn't do
Haley Stanfield as Gwen Stacy. You should cast
another Cobra Kai actress, maybe Peyton List to be
her, because I think she would be great in that role
as well. Yeah, that'd be awesome. But I'm also
hoping that they save the Spider-Verse
characters for the Spider-Man films. Great
answer, Travis. But the winner of this week's No
Prize is Gil Camacho. Who said? Hey, guys, Gil
Lee-Macho here. You know, all jokes aside, my
answer would have been Mark Ruffalo, but I think we
should give that guy a break. So my answer is going
to be Edward Norton, Bruce Banner, aka The Hulk. I
think we need a more serious, more savage version
of The Hulk, and he could be a variant of Bruce
Banner. And I think I would get a kick out of him
interacting with the thing. So that's my answer,
Edward Norton. Yeah, it was a huge disappointment
that The Hulk was not mentioned as one of the cast
members for the upcoming Avengers Doomsday film.
It seems more like the character is going to be
saved for the sequel Avengers Secret Wars. That
being said, considering we're getting like all of
the old Fox X-Men characters in Doomsday, it would
also be interesting to see how a variant of Mark
Ruffalo's Bruce Banner, Edward Norton, would
interact with everybody else if he were to show up
in Avengers Doomsday. And it would be even more
interesting if Mark Ruffalo actually was in the
film when we got to see his Bruce Banner's
interaction with Edward Norton's Bruce Banner
and also maybe get some interaction between the
thing and one of the Hulk's. I just think there's a
lot of potential to kind of get some closure with
the character of Edward Norton's Bruce Banner if
you were included in this film. I mean,
technically Edward Norton is not a variant,
though, but it would be cool if this film cleared
that up and bring back Terrence Howard as well.
Yeah, just everybody who is recast in any of these
films, just have them show up in Avengers Doomsday
as variants. And then we could just, you know, all
understand how the recasting happens and
continuity and stuff like that. Although, I guess
you couldn't do that with William Hurt. Just CGI
him. Just do a Princess Leia. Yeah, that'll work.
That'll work. But no, I love this answer. I think if
you guys listen to our review of the Incredible
Hulk, you're aware of just how big a fan I was of
Edward Norton as Bruce Banner. It's kind of a shame
that, you know, he wasn't able to retain the role,
but I'm still really glad that we got Mark Ruffalo
as the character now. It would just be nice for him
to actually show up in this movie. Great answer,
Gilly. You win this week's No Prize if you're the
listener who won a shot at winning your own No
Prize. Stay tuned to later on in this episode when
we'll be asking another question of the week.
Another that's done. On to the news. OK, last week
during CinemaCon, the Warner Brothers panel
unveiled what they're calling a sneak peek. It's
really an extended trailer of Superman. There's
not too much new footage from the previous
trailer, except for an extended opening
involving crypto and Superman by the fortress of
solitude. Now, this was initially only supposed
to be played in theaters as a theatrical exclusive
for the first time in a while. For anyone who went to
go see the Minecraft movie, you know, CinemaCon is
for movies, but it's specifically for theaters.
Like theaters go there and see what new films the
studios are going to bring out. So I'm not
surprised that Warner Brothers was trying to
throw theaters a bone by not releasing this
online. That said, it eventually was rumors are
because it was leaked, but I don't remember seeing
it leaked anywhere. Thank you, goodness. They did
release this online, though, because I am not
interested in the Minecraft movie. I know people
like that. Never played it as a kid. It kind of was
too old to play it by the time it became popular. But
yeah, I'm glad I got to see this trailer. Yeah, but
did it really drum up any hype for the Superman film
that wasn't already there? Probably not, I'll be
honest. In fact, it probably hurt the film because
there's been a lot of criticism specifically
regarding crypto. Now, when the trailer starts
off, Superman, of course, lands near the North
Pole as he did in the previous trailer. And he
whistles for crypto, who comes and immediately
just starts jumping all over him. It's like a
really bad dog. And the first time I saw this
trailer, I was like, what the heck? Is crypto
really hurting Superman that much? Like is crypto
stronger than Superman? I was just confused. But
after watching it like 50 times, I was like, OK,
Superman's hurt. His dog's being a bad dog and just
jumping all over him. It didn't bother me as much.
No, it didn't bother me the first time I saw it. I
just figured that it was a scene that's being
played for laughs, which was a little bit strange
to me because seeing the shot of Superman in the
snow injured like that seemed very serious in its
tone from the first trailer. And then we see that
the tone is actually more comedic when crypto
shows up and then starts essentially beating the
shit out of Superman. So we're having this tonal
disparity that's something more akin to a Marvel
film, I think, than anything we've seen come out of
DC, you know, with Peacemaker. And the Suicide
Squad accepted. Yeah, I'm still trying to figure
out if this would be considered bathos or. Sure, of
course it would. Maybe because I think one of the
big recurring themes of the movie is how bad of a dog
crypto is. So maybe not. I'm not sure. I mean, that
being said, I don't mind crypto being portrayed as
like this problem dog because I think it's
endearing. You know, I think most people who have
had a dog who needed to undergo training or just had
some behavioral issues knows where this is coming
from and can kind of relate to it and find it
endearing and stuff like that. And I think it'll be
an interesting story element to explore for
Superman dealing with this all powerful dog,
basically. I don't think that's going to be the
main plot of the movie, but I think it's an
interesting subplot. I was confused, though, as
to the state of crypto's training, because on one
hand you have him jumping all over Superman
wanting to play with him and, you know, injuring
him. And then on the other hand, you have him
actually listening to Superman and carrying him
directly to the fortress of solitude. So like,
does he obey orders or does he not obey orders?
Like, make up your mind. I think he was just really
excited to see his owner. But then when he realized
that, oh, hey, things are pretty serious. I should
probably listen to him. That's the vibe that I got.
OK, so he is trained then. Ish, probably not well.
OK, like, don't make him a service dog is what
you're saying. Definitely not. Now crypto drags
Superman to the fortress of solitude, which holy
shit was incredible. Like the whole opening scene
that we have here for this trailer looks gorgeous.
That was not expected for how cool the fortress of
solitude was going to look in this film. It's by far
the best realized version of the fortress of
solitude that I think I've ever seen. The
cinematography of this movie, I think, is going to
be incredible. I mean, based off these trailers,
yeah, it's it's going to look phenomenal. I also
love the fact that the fortress is able to hide
itself because, you know, considering we have
Google Maps and satellite technology, it would
not be difficult for people in governments to spot
superman fortress. So the fact that it's able to
grow out of the ground, I thought was fascinating.
The robots were a surprise, kind of. It was a
surprise that there were so many of them. And one of
them was voiced by friggin Alan Tudyk, who is
apparently doing like all the voice roles in the DC
universe. He also does Dr. Phosphorus. He did
Clayface. It's like, holy cow, how many more are
you going to do? The design of the robots struck me
as particularly odd because they were kind of
retro futuristic, which concerns me because we
know that the entire style of the Fantastic Four
movie that's coming out just two weeks after
Superman is also retro futuristic. So I'm
concerned that the two films are going to have a
very similar aesthetic that I think audiences
aren't going to appreciate them being so similar.
I did not even think about that, but that is
completely valid. I'm just glad that Superman
comes out first. I mean, the design of Kirby is
different from these Kryptonian robots, but I
would say that they have the same style. Yeah, and
actually, now that you mentioned it, the
cinematography of both films is not too far off
either. Right. Right. Like the color palette is
kind of similar. The one thing that threw me off the
most in this trailer, even more than Krypto's
behavior, was the sunlight magnification tool
that the robots used to heal Superman from his
injuries. I've never seen Superman react that way
to sunlight. It almost seemed like he was in pain. I
was like, stop it, you're killing him. It was just
bizarre. And some people on a discard were saying
that maybe it was like a pleasure reaction, just
like pleasure overload, which I'm like, yeah. I
said that, actually. But no, I think he's having a
reaction to the intense accelerated healing
process. You know, it's painful, even though he's
being healed. What did you think of the robots
humor, by the way? There wasn't much humor there.
Like one of them was like, don't thank us. We want to
appreciate it. And then the girl robot was like, he
looked at me. He isn't that contradictory. Like,
do they have emotions or don't they? That's a great
question. I have no idea. Are you concerned about
the writing and the tone of this movie based off of
this extent of sneak peek? The tone is jarring. I'm
not going to lie. This is a very different tone from
what we've been used to with the character of
Superman. That said, I'm not really concerned
about the writing because I know James Gunn is a
good writer. He's a really good writer, actually.
I'm just not sure how to take some of these comedic
beats out of context. Well, I guess we'll see how
the film turns out when it comes out in just a few
months. That's right. The film is coming out July
11th. Hopefully we get a new trailer before then
and just this extended one of the previous trailer
that we got. Yeah, I think we're going to get a new
trailer soon. And I think it needs to be fucking
incredible because I think a lot of people are on
the fence about this movie and they just need to be
wowed. They need to be convinced. So James Gunn
better pull out all the stops on this next trailer.
100 percent. I want to know who the villain is. I
want to know what the stakes are. Visually, it just
needs to be breathtaking, which I'm not too
worried about. But yeah, it's it's got to be good.
Maybe less crypto. I don't know. It depends on how
lovable you can make him. But speaking of crypto,
that brings us to our question of the week. What do
you think of crypto, the super dog from the
Superman sneak peek? Yeah, did you love him? Did
you hate him? Did you think he was funny? Did you
relate to that dog in some way from personal
experience with your own pets? Let us know. Record
your answer at dynamic dual dot com by clicking on
the red microphone button in the bottom right hand
corner of the screen, which will prompt you to
leave us a voicemail. Your message could be up to 30
seconds long and don't forget to leave your name in
case we include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a dynamic
dual no prize that will post to Instagram. Be sure
to answer before April 12th. In Marvel News,
coming out of CinemaCon, we got the title for the
upcoming Spider-Man 4 film, which was revealed to
be Spider-Man Brand New Day. Now, the previous
trilogy of Spider-Man films all included home in
the title for some reason. None of those movies
were named after a comic book arc or anything like
that. You know, you had homecoming, you had far
from home and you had no way home. I'm really glad to
move on from those. I think if you've listened to
this podcast for a while, you'll know that
Jonathan and I didn't love any of the home titles.
I'm really glad to see them now referencing the
comic books with their subtitle, Brand New Day. Of
course, those who read the comics will recognize
this as a dance slot run back in the early 2010s that
came after the one more day story arc, where
basically Peter Parker's marriage and life was
erased from reality. And he was rebooted in that he
was no longer married to Mary Jane and he was living
with Aunt May again, kind of down on his luck. The
one more day arc really brought the character back
to basics and introduced some pretty cool
characters like Mr. Negative and Anti-Venom and
paved the way for future great stories like the
superior Spider-Man. Will any of that be
addressed within this film? I don't know, but I
like the idea of Spider-Man kind of starting fresh
with this new Spider-Man 4 film, especially
considering how the No Way Home film ended. Now,
Brand New Day has nothing to do with the
multiverse, correct? Correct, because rumors
are that Brand New Day, you know, taking place
between Doomsday and Seeker Wars is going to
heavily involve the multiverse. So I'm wondering
how they're going to adapt that storyline, if they
are at all, for a multiverse soul entry? That's a
good question. I don't think they're actually
going to adapt anything from the comic books
regarding the Brand New Day arc. What I really want
to see, and I think what a lot of fans want to see, are
either a Spider-Man vs. Venom storyline with
Eddie Brock or like a Spider-Verse movie where
they introduce Miles Morales and Spider Gwyn.
Marvel has, you know, borrowed arc titles from the
books and not adapted them one for one. Look at
things like Thor Ragnarok or even Civil War, which
had the same premise as the arc in the books, but the
execution was entirely different. That's fair,
like Secret Invasion even? Exactly. Yeah, that
was too different if you ask me. But I think, you
know, this title gives Spider-Man fans a lot to
look forward to. I think at least a lot to hope for.
And, you know, the Spider-Man franchise has
always been good ever since the production of them
was taken over by Marvel Studios. So, yeah, lots to
look forward to, especially considering, again,
that it's being directed by Dustin Daniel Cretan,
of course, who helmed the Shang-Chi and the legend
of the Ten Rings film. Yeah, I'm still sad that he's
not moving forward with the Shang-Chi sequel, but
he's definitely deserving of directing a
Spider-Man film. But that does it for all the news
for this episode. So let's go ahead and move into
our main event, where we find out who would win in a
fight between DC's Ratcatcher and Marvel's
Squirrel Girl. All right, Ratcatcher versus
Squirrel Girl. These are two fairly well-known
characters, I think. They both have rodent-based
powers in that they can each control the animals of
their namesake. Ratcatcher controls rats,
Squirrel Girl controls squirrels. There's
really not too much more to it than that. Now, we
have actually had the idea for this tool for quite
some time. And I'm actually pretty excited to
finally be getting around to it, because I am aware
of Squirrel Girl's legend, and I will be glad to
knock her down a peg, because I'm just going to say,
I think she's overhyped because she beat people
like Dr. Doom. Exactly. What? There's no way she's
that powerful. Apparently she is. For people who
may be unaware of the character, Squirrel Girl is
notorious for being one of the more ridiculously
themed heroes who just so happened to defeat Dr.
Doom in canon in the comic books by basically
overwhelming him with a vast legion of squirrels.
It's pretty ridiculous to say the least, but the
character does have her charms. She's kind of a gag
character, though, in just the people that she's
been able to beat in the comic books, which also
includes Thanos and Galactus. It's pretty funny.
If you go onto the official Marvel power grid on the
marvel.com website and look at her stats, she's
actually maxed out at sevens across the board. So I
think you have a hard time ahead of you, Jonathan.
There's no way she's going to be maxed out on all of
her stats. That's dumb. Now, Squirrel Girl has not
appeared in a film like Ratcatcher has, although
in the Suicide Squad film, there's actually
Ratcatcher's daughter who kind of took up his
mantle. But Squirrel Girl was almost in a
television series played by Milana Vayntrob. And
I'm actually kind of sad that that show never came
out, because I thought she would have been great
for that role. Oh, she's a perfect Squirrel Girl,
but she did get to voice the character of Squirrel
Girl in several of the Marvel Rising cartoon
movies. Oh, I didn't know that. I'm glad Kevin
Faggy threw her a bone after the show was canceled.
Oh, for sure. And of course, Ratcatcher was played
by Daniela Melchior in the Suicide Squad film,
who, as you said, was the daughter of the original
Ratcatcher, who was played by Tycho Waititi.
Can't wait to find out who will win. But to explain
the methodology behind our duels, let's go to our
sentient dual simulator, Alfred Jarvis 9000.
AJ9K tell our listeners how you go about
determining a winner in our dual matchups. Yes, of
course, sir. The way I determine a winner between
the contestants is by running 1000 Monte Carlo
simulations using the characters statistics. A
Monte Carlo simulation is a probabilistic model
used to determine outcomes through random
sampling. In this case, I randomize the
statistics along a normal distribution as a way to
simulate the many variables that can occur during
battle. The stat parameters are based on the
official Marvel power grid from which the DC
characters statistics are extrapolated.
Additional stat categories are included such as
range, damage potential, versatility and
perception in order to create a more detailed and
accurate simulation. The results of the 1000
simulations provide a percentage of wins for each
character. The contestant with the higher
percentage is declared the victor as they have a
higher probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither character should win
100% of the matches. The comic book stories have
shown that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman. So the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks, AJ9K!
Before we run the simulations though, we'd like to
break down each character's histories and
abilities before improvising a scenario on how we
imagine one of the 1000 simulations would play out
beat for beat. And I believe it's my turn to go first
with the DC characters backstory, so let me tell
you all about Ratcatcher. Born and raised in
Gotham City, Otis Flanagan worked as a municipal
exterminator for the Gotham City Sanitation
Department. As a Ratcatcher, he developed an
uncanny connection with Verman, frequently
claiming he could train them to respond to his
commands. Those who worked with him dismissed the
claim as delusional, pointing to his solitary
demeanor and increasingly erratic behavior.
Viewed as eccentric and untrustworthy, Otis's
reputation deteriorated further after he was
arrested for stabbing and killing a man during a
street fight. Convicted of manslaughter, he was
sentenced to 10 years in Black Gate Penitentiary.
During his incarceration, Otis became
increasingly bitter and reclusive. Feeling
betrayed by the very city he had spent his life
serving, he reevaluated his role in Gotham's
ecosystem. In his eyes, the true infestation was
not the rats he once exterminated, but the
citizens and officials who had turned against
him. Embracing the company of rodents, he began
forming a bond with the prison's vermin
population, feeding them, studying them,
training them, and eventually commanding them.
His affinity for rats grew into an obsession,
where others saw filth, Otis saw loyalty. He came
to believe the rats, like himself, were
misunderstood and mistreated. When he was
released for good behavior, Otis adopted a new
identity, Ratcatcher. Returning to Gotham, Otis
sought revenge on the four officials who had
played key roles in his conviction. One by one, he
abducted them, luring or ambushing each one into
the city's underground sewer system, which he now
called home. With his deep knowledge of the
subterranean tunnels, he eluded law enforcement
and concealed his victims in a hidden underground
lair. There, aided by an ever-growing swarm of
rats, he subjected the officials to years of
psychological and physical torment. Bowed in
darkness, the prisoners endured the constant
gnawing presence of vermin, while Otis preached
to them about his vision of a future where rats
inherited the earth. His captives remained
hidden for five years, presumed dead, while Otis
refined his control over rats using whistles,
high-frequency tones, and other methods of
animal training. Eventually, one of Otis'
prisoners, Judge Wyatt Hogan, managed to
successfully escape captivity and nearly made it
to the surface until he was killed by a swarm of
rats. His body was found by Batman, however, who
followed the trail of vermin back through the
sewers. The Dark Knight confronted Ratcatcher in
his lair, quickly dispersing the rats with
ultrasonic emitters before defeating Otis and
delivering him to the authorities. While
incarcerated once more, Otis used his abilities
to build a reputation inside of Blackgate. With
rats acting as messengers and couriers, he
developed a barter system among inmates,
smuggling contraband through ventilation ducts
and sewer lines. His network proved invaluable to
other criminals, including Bane, who used
Ratcatcher's rodent couriers to help him
orchestrate an escape. Despite being locked
away, Otis' influence spread across the prison.
The vermin he trained became his eyes and ears
throughout Blackgate, allowing him to
communicate with allies and track prison
movement unnoticed. He later escaped during a
parole hearing, using a flute he had secretly
carved to emit high-pitched frequencies that
summoned rats. Overrunning the courtroom with
rodents, he fled back to the depths of Gotham's
sewers, where he attempted to orchestrate a
scheme to take over the city with rats, but his plan
was stopped by Nightwing, who at the time was
temporarily operating as Batman, and Otis was
sent to prison once again. You can learn more about
Nightwing in his duel against Daredevil. When a
devastating earthquake struck Gotham, turning
it into a no-man's land, Ratcatcher was among the
many inmates who escaped the ruined prison. He
resurfaced briefly, joining a group of villains
attempting to exploit the city's chaos, but was
recaptured shortly afterward. Though his role in
the criminal underworld was often secondary, his
knowledge of the city's subterranean network
made him a recurring nuisance for authorities and
an asset to fellow rogues. In the wake of Gotham's
reconstruction, Otis took refuge among the
city's homeless population. Sympathetic to his
cause, some of Gotham's vagrants saw Ratcatcher
as a kind of folk figure, an enemy of the elite who
lived among societies forgotten. He was
eventually discovered by authorities and
confronted by police. One of the homeless
individuals who attempted to protect him was
secretly an Omak sleeper agent. When the man was
struck by police, the Omak programming activated
and identified Ratcatcher as a gamma-level
threat. Before Otis could escape, he was
vaporized on the spot. In post-Flashpoint
continuity, Otis was presumed dead until he was
once again seen navigating the city's sewers and
subterranean ruins, where he resumed his
criminal activities and was discovered working
alongside Menace, a known adversary of Batwing.
You can learn more about in our Batwing vs. Miles
Morales episode. Otis' skills brought him into
contact with a wide range of Gotham's criminal
underworld. At one point, he aligned himself with
the Gotham vigilante mother panic, operating not
as an enemy, but as a reluctant ally. Eventually
returning to crime, however, Otis clashed with
Batman again after being tracked to a sewer base,
fortified by tunnels, booby traps, and swarms of
defensive vermin, though Batman was able to
overcome all of Otis' obstacles and capture him
once again. Powers-wise, Ratcatcher has no
superhuman abilities outside of his talent to
train and control rats, seemingly via a staff and
lantern that he carries. He uses the rats to attack
enemies and swarms, send messages, and smuggle
contraband. Ratcatcher also uses a gas gun and gas
grenades capable of emitting cyanide or other
noxious chemicals, which he's protected from
thanks to his gas mask. And that's Ratcatcher.
Okay, so he does employ some gadgets in addition to
the rats that he controls. Yes. Well, he's gonna
need them because Squirrel Girl is about to eat
some nuts and kick some butts. Let me tell you about
her backstory. Doreen Green was born in Canada to
Dorian and Maureen Green. A genetic modification
of unknown origin granted her squirrel-like
traits, which began to manifest when she was 10
years old. These included a large,
semi-prehensile tail and the ability to
communicate with squirrels. After rescuing a
squirrel from a dog, she befriended it and named it
Monkey Joe. The two became partners and Monkey Joe
encouraged Doreen to use her powers to help
people. Although Doreen initially believed she
was a mutant, a doctor confirmed otherwise. At age
14, Doreen adopted the alias Squirrel Girl, an
ambushed Iron Man in a forest near Stark
Enterprises, hoping to prove herself as a worthy
sidekick. Iron Man declined, but when Dr. Doom
appeared and captured him, Doreen summoned a
horde of squirrels, including Monkey Joe, to
overwhelm Doom's ship and free Iron Man. The
squirrels disabled Doom's systems and forced him
to flee, marking Doreen's first major victory.
Following this, she continued to train and hone
her skills. Around her 15th birthday, she aided
the Hulk in a fight against the Abomination,
directing the blinded Hulk while her squirrels
helped subdue the enemy. Later, Doreen relocated
to New York City and began fighting crime in
Central Park, where she saved the Great Lakes
Avengers, Flatman and Dorman from Muggers.
Impressed, they invited her and Monkey Joe to join
the team. As a member of the Great Lakes Avengers,
Doreen battled threats like Batrox Brigade and
witnessed the death of the team's newest member,
Grasshopper. Tragedy struck again when Monkey
Joe was killed by a leather boy, a rejected member
of the team disguised as Dr. Doom. After mourning
her squirrels loss, Doreen helped the team defeat
Maelstrom with an army of squirrels, of which only
one survived. She named the survivor Tippi Toe,
who became her new companion and remained at her
side, moving forward. During this period, Doreen
and Tippi Toe independently defeated Modak,
Tarix, and even Thanos, off panel, but his defeat
was verified by Uwatu the Watcher. Despite being
offered a position by Shield, Doreen declined,
preferring to stay with the Great Lakes Avengers.
She later joined the Thing in a battle against
Bibeast in Central Park, after which she and the
team attended a superhero poker tournament.
There, Flatman won with a straight flush, and the
group adopted the name Great Lakes Champions.
When the Superhuman Registration Act went into
effect, the team registered and joined the
initiative as Wisconsin's official superhero
team. During this period, Deadpool mistakenly
attacked them under the belief they were
unregistered, and Doreen defeated Deadpool with
ease. Squirrel Girl later helped rescue the god
Dionysus from Advanced Idea Mechanics, or AIM for
short, returning him to Olympus after their
victory. Around this time, she revealed her
admiration for the new warriors, especially
Speedball, who you can learn more about in his duel
against Wally West the Flash. After Speedball's
transformation into the guilt-ridden Vigilante
Penance, Doreen attempted to change his fate by
using a time machine borrowed from Dr. Doom.
Instead, she traveled to the year 2099, where she
met alternate versions of Speedball and Mr.
Immortal, though she was convinced by him to
return to her own time. During the Alien Squirrel
secret invasion of Earth, the team discovered a
scroll posing as their newest recruit. After the
initiative reorganized under Norman Osborn,
Doreen left the group after defeating Fin Feng Fum
on her own and returned to New York. You can learn
more about Fin Feng Fum in his duel against Star-O
the Conqueror. In New York, Doreen became the
nanny for Danielle Cage, who was the daughter of
Luke Cage and Jessica Jones. She cared for the
child through several crises, including the
attacks from the Thule Society, the Revengers,
and the Organization Hammer. She remained with
the family even after they departed the Avengers,
continuing to protect Danielle. You can learn
more about Luke Cage and Jessica Jones in their
respective duels against Thunder and Huntress.
After leaving the cages, Doreen enrolled at
Empire State University to study computer
science. On her first day, she met Nancy
Whitehead, who would become her best friend. She
also confronted Craven the Hunter and persuaded
him to redirect his energy toward hunting sea
monsters instead of squirrels. Not long after,
Doreen intercepted Galactus on route to Earth,
wearing Iron Man's armor she traveled to the moon
and persuaded the cosmic being to feed on a
different planet rich in nuts. This encounter
ended peacefully and Galactus left Earth
unharmed. You can learn more about Galactus in his
duel against the Spectre and more about Craven in
his duel against Vixen. Upon Doreen's return,
Nancy revealed that she had figured out Squirrel
Girl's secret identity but promised to keep it a
secret, and the two formed a close friendship.
Doreen also met Chipmunk Hunk and Koi Boy, fellow
students with animal-based powers. Together
with Tipito, the group battled threats like
Mysterion and the Asgardian Squirrel God,
Ratatosker, with aid from Loki and Thor. Doreen
and Nancy also rehabilitated the villain
Braindrain, updating his outdated systems and
encouraging him to pursue education at Empire
State University. Although romance wasn't a
major focus for Squirrel Girl, Doreen's interest
in Chipmunk Hunk was complicated when he began
dating someone else. Encouraged by her friends to
try online dating, she endured a series of
unsuccessful experiences. Mole Man, angered by
her earlier interference in his domain, began
demanding her attention. After a confrontation
including Tricephalus, who was in love with Mole
Man, Doreen allowed herself to be defeated to end
his pursuit, and she stepped away from dating. A
separate version of Doreen created through a
cloning device became her antagonist. The clone,
Aline, lacked Doreen's empathy and sought to
build a squirrel dominated utopia. She
imprisoned heroes in the negative zone, a hostile
alternate dimension, and banished Doreen to the
moon. There, Doreen summoned Mjolnir and became
Squirrel Thor. After liberating the heroes,
Doreen made one last appeal to Aline's humanity.
Aline willingly stayed behind and reshaped the
negative zone into Squirrel Topia 5000, the
society that she had envisioned. Doreen and her
friends later visited there with mutual respect.
During Doreen's second year at ESU, she joined the
US Avengers. She also encountered Melissa
Morbeck, a villain who posed as a benefactor for
the Avengers and gifted Squirrel Girl a flying
squirrel suit. Morbeck later used technology to
control animals and attacked the city, but Doreen
and her allies defeated her with the help of Nancy
and Mary, who disabled the controlled tech.
Later, Loki summoned Doreen to help repel a frost
giant invasion of North America. She reunited
with Ratatoskir, and together they sparked a
political revolution in Jotunheim that forced
the giants to retreat. Soon after, Morbeck
returned with an alliance of villains, including
Dr. Doom, Modok Superior, and Leader to exact
revenge. She leaked Doreen's identity to the
public and attacked her apartment using stolen
Iron Man armor. In the final confrontation,
several former foes turned to allies including
Kraven, Moleman, and the godlike entity Galactus
came to Doreen's defense. Galactus teleported
the villains away and restored Stark's armor,
while Iron Man publicly honored Doreen's
achievements. Following these events, Doreen
retired from superheroics and launched the
Inbeatable Squirrel Girl Radio Show, an A.M.
radio calling program where she answered
questions about being a hero. Her co-hosts
included Tippi Toe, Nancy, Koi Boy, Chipmunk
Hunk, and Braindrain. And that's her backstory.
Powers-wise, Squirrel Girl has the enhanced
proportionate physicality of a squirrel. This
grants her increased strength, able to lift
around 10 tons, increased durability, and
increased reflexes and leaping distance. She has
a 3-foot-long, bushy tail and small claws on her
hands and feet that help her climb. Her front and
sides teeth are abnormally large, like a rodents,
giving her superior biting strength. In
addition, Squirrel Girl has a small knuckle spike
she can retract from the back of each hand that is
sharp enough to carve into wood. She is fluent in
Squirrel Chatter, which she can use to speak with
and command vast legions of squirrels, either to
assist her in battle, serve as a distraction, or
chew through electronic components. However,
Squirrel Girl's most valuable skill is the
ability to reason, negotiate, and draw empathy
from others through verbal communication, which
has allowed her to most commonly defeat villains
through reasoning rather than physical
confrontation. She also has a utility belt with
pouches that she calls her nut sacks, which she
uses to carry a variety of nuts as snacks for
herself and her squirrel friends. Wow! And that's
Squirrel Girl. She is the most frustrating
character for me as a hater of all things Marvel,
because you know she's a joke and it's ridiculous
the feats she's been able to accomplish, like
defeating Thanos and Galactus as well. What? Is
Squirrel Girl a joke or is it your face? We're
twins. Yeah, but like you know we don't look that
similar. We're identical twins! We're video game
legends brawl every Monday. Dynamic duel where
comic book tyens smash every Tuesday. Max
destruction where TV and action heroes battle
every Wednesday. And Sendro World where anime
champions clash every Thursday. Join us as we
speculate on the matches and armed with the power
of mathematical simulations to discover who will
emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
Now that we've got their histories and abilities
out of the way let's speculate on how one of the 1000
simulated matches will go. The winner is
determined by simulations, not the speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how the fight could play
out. AJ9K, what are the rules of our speculation?
Well I should say there are no rules other than the
characters have no prior knowledge of the other
going into the fight. All they are aware of
starting out is that the other character is a
threat that needs to be eliminated. For the
speculation the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the match
itself as no environmental statistics are
considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. Alright then
let's get into it. Ratcatcher and Squirrel Girl
meet on the battlefield who goes first. I'm going
to say that since there are way more rats on the
planet than there are squirrels, that Ratcatcher
is going to go first because just of you know how
more accessible rats would be to summon for him and
so he's going to start by sending a swarm or rather a
mischief of rats to attack Squirrel Girl. A group
of rats is called a mischief? Yep. Okay I learned
something today. I don't know what a group of
squirrels is called. One sec. Okay they're called
a scurry. So Squirrel Girl sees Ratcatcher summon
this rat army and she's like okay you want to get
nuts? Come on let's get nuts. Squirrel Stampede
and she summons this scurry of squirrels to match
the size of Ratcatcher's rat army. Okay these rats
are way meaner than squirrels though. We're
talking like roided out New York City subway pizza
rats here. They will fuck these squirrels up and
that's what they're gonna do. You know just
zooming in on this mini battle we're gonna see
squirrels getting slashed open, limbs not off,
eyeballs tail whipped right out of their sockets.
It's gonna be a scene like right out of Watership
Down just squirrel carnage everywhere. Oh man
okay first of all you're sick bastard. Second of
all like rats are mean and big or whatever but
squirrels are way more agile than these fat ass
rats. So like maybe a few squirrels go down but a
majority of them are just gonna leap over the rats
including Squirrel Girl. She and the squirrels
are gonna like long jump over the rat army over to
where Ratcatcher is and she's gonna break the
staff and the lantern that he uses to control the
rats with some well executed knuckle spike
punches. She punches the staff? Yeah with her
knuckle spike it breaks it and the lantern. Okay I
mean he doesn't actually need those things to
direct rats. I think he just uses the lantern to see
in the sewers. He could verbally command them but
now that Squirrel Girl is in close Ratcatcher is
just gonna point blank blaster right in the face
with the cyanide capsule from his gas gun and she's
gonna breathe that in and die. No no she doesn't
breathe in the cyanide gas because she
immediately covers her face with her long pushy
tail and it functions as like a gas mask of sorts. At
least long enough for some squirrels to bite
through the firing mechanism on Ratcatcher's gas
gun and just render it completely useless and
actually they also chew off his trigger finger
too. Geez and then Squirrel Girl is gonna use her
tail to fan the gas away from her. Okay well I'm
gonna say surprise there were actually rats
hiding in Squirrel Girl's tail so when she uses it
to cover her face she already has like a rat chewing
on her nose and as she's using her tail to fan the gas
away she's also just flinging more rats onto
herself and they all begin to chew through her I
guess. Okay well Squirrel Girl stops these rats
from chewing through her by summoning a suit of
squirrel armor. You know she has all her furry
friends come over and cover and protect her body
and these squirrels are gonna repel the rats that
are crawling on her and then Squirrel Girl points
her arm at Ratcatcher and kind of like one of Iron
Man's repulsor blasts she's gonna fire a squirrel
pulsor blast from her squirrel armor which is just
really just sending a bunch of squirrels right at
Ratcatcher right at his nuts and these squirrels
straight up castrate him. She's like get those
nuts! Geez! Okay well to get the squirrels away
from him right away Ratcatcher he's gonna slam
down a gas grenade right at his feet and the
squirrels they're just gonna fall off of him and
that's when he's gonna unleash this barrage of rat
traps that are gonna land on Squirrel Girl's armor
snapping and killing enough squirrels to expose
an opening in her armor that his rats can penetrate
and dismantle that armor. You know it's not real
armor right it's just a bunch of squirrels on her
body that she calls her squirrel armor. I
understand the joke. Okay okay okay Squirrel Girl
loses her squirrel armor then but then she's gonna
tell some squirrels to hold their breath you know
and their little squirrel cheeks in order to avoid
Ratcatcher's poison cloud and they're gonna leap
over onto Ratcatcher's face and chew through his
gas mask which falls off and therefore he ends up
poisoning himself and dying. No because he has a
swarm of rats sacrifice themselves to cover and
protect him from the poison and then just shuffle
him away like carrying him through this massive
wave of rats that surround Squirrel Girl and
before she realizes it Ratcatcher is gonna reach
out from the wave and grab her by the ankles and just
pull her right into the rat avalanche and by the
time it dissipates all that's gonna be left of
Squirrel Girl is a bucktooth skeleton. Match over
it. Actually this whole time Squirrel Girl had her
squirrels talking with the rats and convincing
them that listening to this Ratcatcher guy isn't
all that it's cracked up to be like he's a huge
asshole and the squirrels convinced the rats to
ignore his commands and attack him instead. So
this rat avalanche that you're talking about that
you say devour Squirrel Girl actually they just
devour Ratcatcher instead and like as
Ratcatcher's like what the hell and he like cries
out in agony Squirrel Girl is gonna seal the deal by
expertly chucking over a couple of acorns into his
mouth and he dies choking on her nuts. Match over.
Of course. I say that these squirrels don't
convince the rats of anything because the
squirrels have rabies and they just give the
squirrels rabies so actually the squirrels turn
on Squirrel Girl. Well let's go ahead and leave the
match there. Either the squirrels convince the
rats to turn on Ratcatcher or the rats give the
squirrels rabies causing Squirrel Girl to get
devoured by an avalanche of rodents. That's
right. Let's go ahead and put the character stats,
run the simulations and find out which scenario
happens when we come back with a winner. AG9K hit
it. Inputting data, running calculations,
processing results, simulations complete. Okay
I did not know going into this match that Squirrel
Girl has the proportionate speed and strength and
overall physicality of a squirrel. Well I didn't
know going into this match that Ratcatcher had a
gas pellet gun and gas grenades. Though that
didn't really quite help him in the stats. I mean it
gave him the leg up in versatility but not much
else. The only other stat that Ratcatcher came
ahead in was intelligence though they did tie in a
few stat categories. We definitely did not max out
Squirrel Girl stats as suggested by the Marvel
Power Grid. No I mean like a joke character
bullshit aside we the podcast don't consider
Squirrel Girl imbedable. We tried to approach her
statistics as fairly as possible. That being said
she's quite impressive statistically. She's
fast, she's evasive, she's durable, she's
strong, she's pretty smart and she actually has
fighting experience unlike Ratcatcher. No he is
not a good fighter at all. So taking the stats into
account Joseph who would you say came out on top in
this match? Obviously Squirrel Girl she is the
unbeatable Squirrel Girl that's just how it is
that's that's reality and I don't know anybody who
would disagree with that. Instagram certainly
agrees with me because 73% of our followers cited
with Squirrel Girl in this match. I really really
don't want Squirrel Girl to win but I'm scared not
gonna lie. Let's see who came out on top AJ9K the
results please. Hey you are sir. The winner of the
matchup between Ratcatcher and Squirrel Girl is
Squirrel Girl. Buy a lot. She won 784 of the 1000
matches or 78.4% of the time. Are you sure that's
not 99.9% of the time? It is not but might as well be.
Ratcatcher only won 21.6% of his matches less than
a quarter. It's kind of embarrassing. Is this one
of the biggest wind spreads that we've ever had on
the podcast? It is. Does that mean this is a
mismatch or does it just mean that Squirrel Girl is
that fucking awesome? I will admit to nothing. I
don't think this was a mismatch but I will also not
admit that Squirrel Girl is awesome because I have
my pride. Well I think it stands to reason that if
Ratcatcher can single-handedly defeat Star of
the Conqueror as we saw in the Suicide Squad film
and Squirrel Girl beats Ratcatcher then Squirrel
Girl also probably beats Star of the Conqueror and
probably most of DC if we think about it. Again
there are way more rats in the world than there are
squirrels. It's not about quantity it's about
quality and everybody knows the squirrels are
better than rats. No one fucking likes rats
everybody loves squirrels. This match played out
exactly how it was supposed to so DC can see these
nuts. Can we just end this episode already? Gosh!
That does it for this duel AJ9K. Close us out.
Thanks for listening to Dynamic Jewel. Visit the
show's website at dynamicjewel.com and follow us
on Instagram at Dynamic Jewel podcast. You can
support the show on Patreon at patreon.com slash
dynamicjewel and joining a tier that works for you
or by rating and reviewing Dynamic Jewel on Apple
podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser or on our website.
Don't forget to listen to the other shows in the
Dynamite podcast network including Max
Destruction, Senjo World and Console Combat. All
right in our next episode we're going to find out
who would win in a fight between Blue Beetle the Ted
Kord version versus Prowler the Spider-Man
villain slash sometimes ally. Yeah that should be
another interesting one. Two gadgeteers going
against each other. Can't wait to see who's gonna
win but that does it for this episode. We want to
give a big thanks to our executive producers John
Staroski, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Belcom, Miki
Matangian, Brandon Esthergard, Nathaniel
Wagner, Levi Yatn, Austin Wyselowski, AJ
Dunkerly, Nick Obanto, Scott Kamacho, Adam
Spees, Dean Moleski, Devin Davis, Joseph
Kirsting, Josh Leiner, Mike Williams and Oscar
Galvez for helping make this podcast possible.
We'll talk to you guys next week up up and away true
believers. I'm more of a kick nuts eat butts kind of
guy.