This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi, welcome to
the DynaMic Dual Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin
brother, Marvelous Joe. And in this episode, we
are doing another team duel, this time between the
Legion of Superheroes and the New Mutants. Yeah,
my guys have actually had a movie. Hey, my guys have
had a movie? What? Yeah, it was animated. Oh, yeah,
it was called the Legion of Superheroes starring
Supergirl. That's right. And? Yeah, but it didn't
have most of the Prime Legionaries, at least like,
you know, not the main ones like Cosmic Boy and
Saturn Girl and Lightning Lad. You know what the
New Mutants movie did I have? What? An audience.
You're not wrong. But I thought it was a pretty
decent film. You could listen to our review of
that. It's a great set of characters, the New
Mutants, and a lot of them, as they've gone older,
have like powered up from their original power
limitations. So I think this is going to be a good
match. Yeah, it's actually the same for the Legion
of Superheroes. Both teams started off as
teenagers, but they have had some growth in the
comics, or at least Legion would have if they
wouldn't keep rebooting themselves. Their
background is very convoluted. But we'll get more
to that later on in this episode. Before that,
we're going to break down the comic book movie news
from the past week, of which we have two news items.
One is a report that was done by Variety talking
about the current state of film franchises,
including Marvel and DC. That was pretty
interesting to read. And we also got another
trailer for Marvel Zombies. As always, we list our
segment times in our episode description, so feel
free to check out the show notes if you want to skip
ahead to a particular topic. Guys, our
artificially intelligent dual simulator, AJ9K,
has a quick message for our listeners. So listen
up. Why hello there. Do you want even more from this
podcast? Then become a part of the Dynamic Jewel
community on Patreon, where you can choose from
three tiers. The Dynamic 2.0 tier gives you access
to our Discord chat server. The Fantastic Four
tier gives you two bonus episodes each month, and
the X-Force tier makes you an executive producer
of this show. Lastly, the Diner Mike podcast
network tier lets you create your own podcast
using this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe
will help you develop your show, provide graphic
support and consultation, and get you simulation
results. Pitch the twins your ideas via email at
dynamicjewelpodcast at gmail.com. Check it out
at patreon.com slash dynamicjewel. Pip pip
cheerio. Thanks AJ9K, and thanks to everyone who
supports the podcast. Be sure to tune into the
other shows on the Dynamic podcast network this
week, including the console combat podcast,
where hosts John and Dean simulate battles
between popular video game characters. In
yesterday's episode, the two determined who
would win in a rematch episode between Samono Suke
Akechi from Onimusha and Ryu Hayabusa from Ninja
Gaiden. Over on the Max Destruction podcast,
hosts Scotty and Gilly pit your favorite action
heroes from film and television against each
other. On Wednesday, they're going to find out
who'd win in a fight between Adonis Creed, Apollo
Sun, and Rocky, both from the Rocky franchise. I
don't know if I want to know the answer to that. On
the Cinger World podcast, hosts Zachary Hepburn
speculates on fights between fan favorite anime
and manga characters. Next episode, Zach is
reviewing the series to be hero X. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our show
notes to listen to all the shows in the Dynamic
podcast network. But with that out of the way,
quick to the No Prize. A No Prize is an award that
Marvel used to give out to fans. Our version, the
Dynamic Dual No Prize, is a digital award we post on
Instagram for the person that we feel gave the best
answer to our question of the week. Last week, we
asked you guys, who do you want the villain for Man
of Tomorrow to be and why? And of course, this is
coming off the news that the Superman movie is
getting a sequel in 2027 titled Man of Tomorrow. We
get quite a few answers. Let's go ahead and run down
our honorable mentions as well as the No Prize
winner. Our first honorable mention goes to
Travis Herndon. Who said? Well, so the name of the
dude Travis here, shout out to my able twin. So my
pick would be Matalo. I think he'd be a nice,
grounded villain for Superman's sequel. We've
never seen him before in a live action movie. And
you could have the story be that Lex created him and
only for him to go overboard forcing Lex and
Superman to have a very shaky alliance to take
Matalo down. He's a very interesting bad-ass
villain, and he can be a threat to both Lex and
Superman. So James Gunn did confirm in an
interview with Howard Stern last week that in the
Man of Tomorrow film, Superman and Lex Luthor
would be teaming up to stop a greater threat. And I
could see that being Matalo, especially if you go
the route that Travis mentioned, where Lex Luthor
is responsible for his creation. But he kind of
goes against his creator and now him and Superman
have to team up to stop what he created. Yeah, it
could be like the age of Ultron of the Superman
franchise, right? And Matalo isn't that
powerful, but he is to Superman because he has the
kryptonite and he can be, you know, a formidable
foe against a human like Lex Luthor. So yeah, I
could see this and I like the idea of it. It's also
cool because we haven't seen Matalo as a villain on
the big screen yet. So why not? Great answer,
Travis. Our next honorable mention goes to We
Don't Know because they didn't submit their name.
But, uh, yeah, let's give it a listen. Joe, John,
Joe, how's it going, guys? Man of Tomorrow, I
think, should have Brainiac as the villain. We've
never really seen him in live action, at least not
done, you know, not really in a proper way. And
given that there's going to be multiple other
superheroes, I think it's a great opportunity to
bring in a bigger villain like that. I think it's
too early for Darkseid. But I would also like to see
Parasite or Matalo, someone who's not just going
to be a big brute fight for Superman. Now,
actually, Brainiac was the most common answer
that we received. And he's honestly the villain
that I have most wanted to see Superman face. On the
big screen in like forever. Like, it still
surprises me that we haven't seen him fight
Brainiac yet in a movie. He's such a great villain.
Yeah, and he definitely raises the stakes enough
to warrant a Superman Lex Luthor team up. So good
answer. Whoever you are, whoever answered, be
sure, guys, to leave your name when you leave an
answer, either in the field to the asks for your
name or in the call itself. Our final honorable
mention goes to Dylan DeWitt, who said, Hey, guys,
Dylan DeWitt here, big fan of the show. Thanks for
what you guys do. Right to the chase. Man of
Tomorrow should have Brainiac as the villain. We
haven't really had a big screen adaption of the
character. And I think that if they're going to
have multiple characters in Lex and Superman
teaming up, then Brainiac would be the most
obvious choice for that. I could also see Cyborg
Superman or Parasite, somebody like that. Now,
Dylan mentioned Brainiac, but he also mentioned
Cyborg Superman, who, of course, is a villain that
tied into Superman's death and the whole reign of
the Superman saga in the comics that I am still
waiting to see adapted in live action. I think that
would be a fantastic film, probably not for Man of
Tomorrow. Considering it seems like the premise
of that is that Superman and Lex are timming up. But
maybe for the film after that, we could explore
characters like Steel, like the Eradicator, like
Superboy and Cyborg Superman. What do you think
about Parasite as an option? I think that could be a
good one, especially if it's like a version of
Parasite that grows big, like a Kaiju, like
Godzilla or something like that, like how he did in
Superman, Man of Tomorrow, the animated movie.
And Lex and Superman teamed up to stop him in that
film as well. That's true. Who knows? Maybe that's
why the film is called Man of Tomorrow. Because
it's this straight adaptation of the animated
film. I hope not. I did not love that film. But great
answer, Dylan. We want to give a quick shout out to
Noah Terry and Lorenzo Valdes. But the winner of
this week's No Prize is Alex Albro, who said, Hey
guys, this chapter really is about gods and
monsters. I think this film would be a good one to
start to introduce villain like Perpetual and
Barbados and people like that. You know, it could
lead eventually to a crisis storyline if you
wanted it to. But also, I think it could just get
into the greater origin of the multiverse and make
this DC a bit more whimsical and fantastical in
previous iterations. May not be punk rock, but it
could be metal. Is that an allusion to Dark
Knight's Metal? Yes, of course, the characters of
Perpetua and Barbados were introduced in the Dark
Knight's Metal comics storyline, along with the
introduction of the Dark Multiverse, which I feel
like you can't really explain until you get into
the multiverse. Perpetua is a character that
definitely falls within the gods and monsters
theme that James Gunn has set up for the kickoff of
the DCU. But I do feel like it's a lot to get to. Like
the Dark Multiverse is a deep cut, as cool as it is. I
feel like you would need a lot of setup going into
it. And James Gunn will just cover it through a
bunch of text in the first minute of his movie.
That's all the exposition you need. Honestly, I
kind of believe it. Now, Alex gets the win because
he gave an original answer, but also because he was
bold enough to suggest something like Perpetua,
the creator of the DC universe itself in the
comics. Yeah, that would be a wild battle for sure.
But congrats, Alex. You win this week's No Prize.
If you, the listener, want a shot at winning your
own No Prize, stay tuned to later on this episode
when we'll be asking another question of the week.
And now that that's done, on to the news. All right,
this past week, Variety, a Hollywood news outlet,
released a report that commented on Hollywood's
biggest franchises and where they currently
stand in comparison to the past 10 years. Marvel
and DC were highlighted in this report, as well as
other popular franchises like James Bond and Star
Wars, the Jurassic Park movies, Mission
Impossible, Hunger Games and Star Trek. It was
interesting to see how specifically the MCU and
the DC franchises currently compare to how they
have in the 20 teens. They have a lot of
infographics up on there, so I'm going to try to do
my best to explain it, but overall, the state of
Marvel is that while the Marvel franchise
currently has the biggest share of market
saturation out of all the franchises, just
because of all the content that Disney is putting
out there with Marvel. Marvel is actually
slipping compared to the 20 teens in that their box
offices are going down. However, fortunately,
the report says that because Marvel's budgets are
also going down, that the return on Marvel's films
is staying relatively level. Yeah, they don't
have to pay Robert Downey Jr. anymore. Oh, wait.
Yeah. But the report comments that the Avengers
movie is basically bulletproof. It's going to
make a load of money, but they could also signal to
moviegoers that they can afford to skip the
in-between films and just stick around for the
Avengers movies. Right. Especially this go
around because it doesn't seem like there was too
much setup for the Avengers, at least compared to
the films in the last decade. Right. Now, whereas
Marvel had more commercial potential, DC had more
creative health, in surprise to no one. Of course,
that has a lot to do with James Gunn, who jumped ship
from Marvel to DC. And we're going to see just how
much influence apparently James Gunn had on
Marvel now that he's gone and is ramping up the DC
universe on screen. His Superman movie did
fantastic out the gate. Not only was it a critical
success, but it was also a commercial success, at
least domestically. But then again, DC is also
making inroads in the global box office as well,
according to this report. Yeah. When you compare
the box office return of the Superman movie that
came out this year to the past 10 years of DC films,
yet DC's box office is up currently, as well as
their return on budget, because Superman was made
for a little bit less than what they were making the
previous DC movies. So everything is looking
great for DC right now. The state of the franchise
is in good shape. And Marvel is looking a little bit
shaky. But then again, we all know that the
Avengers is going to make a billion dollars and
Marvel is going to take back its crown at the
movies. I feel like I heard that exact same thing
when you were talking about Fantastic Four, which
you owe me money, motherfucker. You don't know
that yet. Fantastic Four has not exited theaters
yet. So we'll talk then. We know. We know there's no
way it's going to catch up. Anyway, on the topic of
film franchises, that brings us to our question of
the week. Besides Marvel and DC, what is your
favorite film franchise of all time? And why?
Record your answer at dynamicdool.com by
clicking on the red microphone button in the
bottom right hand corner of the screen, which will
prompt you to leave us a voicemail. Your message
could be up to 30 seconds long. And don't forget to
leave your name in case we include you on the
podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer and award
that person a dynamic dual no prize that will post
to Instagram. Be sure to answer before September
20th. In other Marvel news, we got the second
trailer for the upcoming Marvel Zombies animated
series. It's actually a mini series. It's only
four episodes that's going to start streaming on
September 24th. The last trailer we got was Off the
Wall bonkers, insane and so damn cool with the
soundtrack and everything like that. This second
trailer takes things a little bit more epic and
serious. A lot of the first episode looks like it's
going to play out exactly like the World War Z movie
where we see Shang-Chi and Katie in the streets of
San Francisco fleeing from the zombie outbreak.
And you have like a bunch of zombies like leaping
off buildings and shit to try to eat people. It
looks like absolute madness. And I'm totally here
for it because they didn't really show too many of
those scenes in the what if Marvel Zombies
episode. You know, it was more of like a slow build,
more of like a night of the living dead as opposed to
a World War Z. And I really like the apocalyptic
approach that World War Z took to the start of its
zombie apocalypse. It does look like some of these
zombies gain sentience and can talk, which of
course is true to the Marvel Zombies comic book
series where the zombies could reason and talk.
And that's really what made them so dangerous. And
eventually the Marvel Zombies ended up taking
over the whole universe and spreading into the
multiverse. Yeah, that's interesting. I like the
way that this trailer kind of sets up a little bit of
who the good guys are and who the bad guys are. We
definitely know some of the good guys are going to
probably be zombified, but it's going to be
interesting to see which one survive. Yeah, it
looks like an all out war between the last
remaining survivors and the legions of undead
that come after them, which is not a common
approach in zombie films. You don't usually see
like battle fronts of zombies against survivors.
I think it's going to be pretty interesting,
though. Really looking forward to seeing how this
plays out. It's going to be a great time this
Halloween season, which is quickly approaching
us. And as we said last time, we won't be reviewing
the miniseries, but we will definitely be
discussing our thoughts on it in this show. But
that does it for all of the news for this episode. So
let's go ahead and move on to our main event, which
is the team duel between DC's Legion of
Superheroes from the 31st century and the new
mutants from the 21st century. All right, Legion
of Superheroes versus the new mutants, as we
explained earlier, these are both super teams of
young heroes who are kind of fulfilling a legacy.
In regards to the Legion, who exist in the 31st
century, it's the legacy of the superheroes of the
21st century. And for the new mutants, it's the
legacy of the X-Men. Yeah, they have that theme in
common, I guess, the same way that young justice
and the young Avengers do. That was a previous duel
episode that we did. But the new mutants are
decades older than the young Avengers team. Same
with the Legion of Superheroes. I think these
teams first debuted like back in the 80s and 70s, if
I'm not mistaken. It was actually the 1950s for the
Legion. Whoa, OK, yeah, well, the new mutants were
the 80s. I thought the Legion just went back to the
70s, but I was wrong. The 50s, that is an old team,
and they've probably been rebooted once per
decade since their inception. Too many times, way
too many times. I try to make sense of it for my write
up on their history. But yeah, they've gone
through more reboots than the DC universe has for
sure. Well, the future is always changing, right?
So maybe that makes sense. I think that's how they
justify it. Well, let's get into these teams' back
stories. First, to explain the methodology
behind our duels, let's go to our sentient duel
simulator, Alfred Jarvis 9000, AJ9K tell our
listeners how you go about determining a winner in
our duel matchups. Yes, of course, sir. The way I
determine a winner between the two teams is by
running one thousand Monte Carlo simulations
between every character on each team using their
statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation is a
probabilistic model used to determine outcomes
through random sampling. In this case, I
randomize the statistics along a normal
distribution as a way to simulate the many
variables that can occur during battle. The stat
parameters are based on the official Marvel power
grid from which the DC characters statistics are
extrapolated. Additional stat categories are
included such as range, damage potential,
versatility and perception in order to create a
more detailed and accurate simulation. The
results of the 49,000 simulations provide a
percentage of wins for each character on both
teams. The team with the higher average win rate is
declared the victor as they have a higher
probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither team should win 100%
of the matches. The comic book stories have shown
that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman, so the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks, AJ9K.
Before we run the simulations, though, we'd like
to break down each team's histories and rosters
before improvising a scenario on how we imagine
one of the thousands of simulations would play out
beat for beat. And I believe it's my turn to go first
with the Marvel team backstory. So let me tell you
all about the new mutants. The new mutants were
assembled when Professor Charles Xavier
believed his X-Men had died battling the alien
brood. You can learn more about the X-Men in our
Titans vs. X-Men duel episode. Though despondent
and unwilling to endanger more children, Xavier
was persuaded by Dr. Moira MacTagger to train
young mutants so they would not face threats
alone. He first recruited John Coyman, aka Karma,
a Vietnamese refugee who could possess others'
minds. She was soon joined by Reigns and Claire,
aka Wolfsbane, recruited from a mob in Scotland,
and Danielle Moonstar, a Cheyenne girl with the
ability to project illusions of people's fears
and desires. From Brazil, they brought in Roberto
D'Acasda, aka Sunspot, who could draw power from
sunlight, while in Kentucky, they encountered
Sam Guthrie, aka Cannonball, who could propel
himself in an impenetrable shield. At Xavier's
School for Gifted Youngsters, the new mutants
trained in the use of their newfound abilities
while adjusting to life as students and young
heroes. They battled government agents from
Project Wide awake in their sentinels and
confronted Xavier himself after his infection by
a brood embryo compelled him to manipulate the new
mutants into becoming hosts. With the X-Men's
return from space, both teams fought together to
save Xavier, ultimately restoring his mind to a
new body. The new mutants then continued their
training alongside their X-Men mentors. You can
learn more about Professor X and his duel against
the Doom Patrol's chief. The new mutants faced
personal and supernatural challenges. Karma
went missing during a battle against Viper and
Silver Samurai, leaving the others to press on
under Moonstar's reluctant leadership. They
encountered Cloak and Dagger, fought criminals
in Brazil, and traveled to Nova Roma in the Amazon,
where they met Amara Akila. After awakening her
ability to control molten rock, she became Magma
and joined the team. Around this time, Ileana
Rasputin, aka Magic, the younger sister of
Colossus, reappeared from the dimension of Limbo
as a sorceress now armed with the Soul Sword. She
also became a full member of the new mutants, now
wielding dark magical powers in addition to her
teleportation abilities. The new mutants' first
rivalry emerged with the creation of the Helians,
a separate mutant school trained by Emma Frost at
the Massachusetts Academy. You can learn more
about Emma Frost in our Poison Ivy vs. White Queen
duel episode. During an attempt to rescue Kitty
Pryde and Doug Ramsey, both of whom were captured
by Emma Frost, the new mutants discovered Doug was
a mutant with the ability to decipher any
language. Taking the code name Cypher, he joined
the team. Soon after, the techno-organic alien
Warlock arrived on Earth, fleeing his father.
Warlock was accepted into the team, bonding
closely with Cypher, who was able to use his power
to communicate with the alien. Together, the
team's growing roster faced mystical menaces
such as the Demon Bear, which hospitalized
Moonstar until Magic slew it with her Soul Sword.
They also fought and defeated the
human-slash-alien villain known as Hybrid,
alongside Rom the Space Knight. Karma eventually
resurfaced after being possessed by the Shadow
King, and the new mutants fought to free her from
his control. Their lives became increasingly
tied to supernatural realms when the Enchantress
captured them in Asgard. Scattered across that
realm, the members endured personal trials.
Wolf's Pain fell for the Wolf Prince, Krimhari.
Magma was enchanted by fairies. Cannonball
labored among dwarves. Sunspot joined the
Warriors 3, and Moonstar bonded with the steed,
Brightwind, becoming a Valkyrie. Eventually
reunited, the new mutants returned to Earth with
lasting changes, particularly Moonstar's new
role. You can learn more about the Enchantress and
Asgard in our Enchantress vs Enchantress duel
episode. When Xavier departed for space with
Flaundra, the leader of the Shiar alien race,
Magneto assumed leadership of the school. The new
mutants were wary of being taught by their former
enemy, but gradually gave him a chance. Magneto
proved effective, even harsh, but tragedy struck
when the beyonder erased and resurrected the team
as emotionless slaves, leaving the students with
deep trauma. Ammafrost exploited this despair by
manipulating Magneto into sending them to her
academy, where they underwent therapy and
returned to Xavier's school more resilient. As
tensions grew under Magneto's leadership, the
team disobeyed him to investigate Birdbrain, an
experimental creature tied to the villain
Animator. In the battle that followed, Doug
Ramsey, Cypher, was shot and killed while saving
Wolf's Pain. His loss devastated the new mutants
profoundly, with Warlock not understanding
human death, actually trying to bring Cypher back
by using his shapeshifting ability to animate his
corpse. Ultimately, Cypher was buried and his
friends said goodbye. Magics struggle with her
demonic nature worsened as Limbo became
corrupted by the demon Sim, culminating in her
transformation into the Dark Child during a
demonic invasion of New York. To end the crisis,
she sacrificed herself by erasing her older self
from existence, reverting to childhood and
leaving the team without her. The new mutants'
relationship with Magneto deteriorated further
as he aligned with the Hellfire Club, a secretive
and influential society of wealthy elites who
manipulate political and economic power while
secretly advancing their own mutant-dominated
agenda. Seeking independence from Magneto, the
students attempted to function without him.
During the X-Men's apparent death and battle with
the adversary, the new mutants drifted into
darker paths. They were drawn toward the nation of
Genosha, where Cameron Hodge, a mutant bigot and
leader of an organization called the Right, was
dedicated to exterminating mutants with
advanced technology. In the conflict, Warlock
was killed and his and Cypher's remnants were
absorbed into one of Hodge's technological
creations. When freed, the two were merged into
one being, which called itself Duglock. Will
Spain left the new mutants after being
genetically altered by the Right, and Sunspot
inherited his father's multinational company.
With their ranks depleted, the team was reforged
under the leadership of Cable, a time-traveling
soldier who trained them for war. Alongside Boom
Boom, Domino, Shatterstar, Warpath, and Feral,
the new mutants evolved into X-Force, abandoning
their old team identity. You can learn more about
X-Force in their duel against the outsiders.
Years later, the new mutants' concept returned at
Xavier School. Danielle Moonstar recruited new
students including Wind Dancer, Wither,
Prodigy, Elixir, Wallflower, and Surge. Karma
and Wolfsbane served as faculty. This second new
mutant squad trained alongside their rival
Helians, clashing during competitions and
crises. Relationships among them grew
complicated and following the elimination of
most of the mutant population's powers by the
Scarlet Witch, the squads were disbanded. Only a
handful retained their powers, joining a single
junior X-Men team. You can learn more about the
Scarlet Witch in her duel against Zatana. The
original new mutants eventually reunited as an
independent team of X-Men. They faced the
Hellfire Club's Black Queen, Selene, and her
resurrected Legion of Undead Mutants. They
defended the X-Men's San Franciscan base against
Bastion's human council and dealt with Norman
Osborn's regime. You can learn more about Bastion
and Norman Osborn in their respective duels
against Amazo and the Joker. Internal divisions
reflected the greater schism within the X-Men, as
Cannonball and Karma sided with Wolverine at the
Jean Grey School in New York while the majority of
the new mutants remained with Cyclops in San
Francisco. They took on new members including
Blink, X-Man, and Fawc villains such as Sugarman
and the Elder Gods of Limbo. When the mutants
established a nation on the Sentient Island of
Cracow, the new mutants joined with the rest of
their kind. Many of the new mutants who had
previously perished such as Cipher and Warlock
were revived using the island's resurrection
protocols. Reunited, the new mutants lived on the
Academos habitat, taking on roles as teachers and
mentors. Sunspot and Moonstar recruited Magic,
Karma, Wolfsbane, Cipher, Chamber, and Mondo for
a mission to Shiar space to retrieve Cannonball.
Their involvement led them to interstellar
intrigue battling the Shiar. Back on Cracow, they
guided students such as Armor, Glob Herman,
Maxime, and Manon who dubbed themselves the Lost
Club. Under Magic and Moonstar, the new team
served as a training squad for younger mutants, a
reminder of the legacy of Xavier's youngest
heroes. And that's the new mutant's backstory.
For the seven-member duel, I'll be starting with
Mirage, Sunspot, and Magic, all of whom we've done
duels with against Arrowette, Starfire, and
Deadband respectively. Filling out the other
four spots will be the new mutants members,
Wolfsbane, who can transform into a large wolf
with increased strength, speed, and healing
factor, enhanced senses, and sharp fangs and
claws. Next is Cannonball, who can surround
himself with a propulsive thermochemical energy
called a blast field that makes him
indestructible while flying. He could also emit
this energy from his body as shockwaves or
directional blasts. Next is Magma, who can
mentally control molten rock beneath the Earth's
surface to create volcanic or seismic activity.
She could also transform her body into lava and
project molten rock and harden it to stone. My last
member is Cypher, but merged with Warlock. Cypher
has the ability to communicate and translate any
language, including body language, which he can
use to anticipate opponents' attacks. He could
also shapeshift given Warlock's techno-organic
nanophysiology and can also control and absorb
technology and can convert organic tissue on
contact into technology that he can then control.
And that's my roster to reiterate its mirage,
sunspot, magic, wolf spane, cannonball, magma,
and Cypher merged with Warlock. Okay, so to
clarify, Warlock is inside of Cypher? Yeah, due to
Cypher's ability to communicate with Warlock,
they are able to merge together to combine their
powers essentially. It gives Cypher an actual
offensive ability besides just, you know,
translating languages. Traditionally, when
they're merged, they've been called Douglock,
but that was actually when Warlock was taking on
Cypher's form. And Warlock didn't have any memory
of who he was as an alien. But in the modern era, when
Cypher was revived, the two kind of teamed up,
where it's Cypher's body with Warlock's added
powers. So I'm not calling the character
Douglock, I'm just calling him Cypher. So what I'm
hearing is that you're trying to cheat by
introducing an eighth member by having one be
inside of the other. No, what I'm trying to do is
make Cypher, who was one of the early New Mutants
characters, able to stand up to Brainiac Five, who
is his counterpart on the Legion of Superheroes
team. Gotcha. We'll get more to the counterparts
once I reveal my roster. Before that, let me go over
the Legion of Superheroes backstory. In the 30th
century, a united interstellar government known
as the United Planets was formed to preserve peace
across the galaxy. During a political summit,
three superpowered teenagers, Rock Crinn of
Braal, Garth Rands of Winneth, and Irma Ardine of
Titan thwarted an assassination attempt on
industrialist RJ Brand, a vocal proponent of
intergalactic cooperation. Inspired by the
legendary superheroes of Earth's past, Brand
encouraged the trio to form a team of young
champions who would promote unity and defend the
United Planets. Taking the codename's Cosmic
Boy, Lightning Lad, and Saturn Girl, the three
founded the Legion of Superheroes. The team's
earliest missions were coordinated from a
rocket-shaped clubhouse on Earth with strict
membership requirements. Each hero had to
possess one unique superpower. They quickly
recruited other youths from across the galaxy,
including Brainiac Five, Chameleon Boy,
Triplicate Girl, Phantom Girl, Colossal Boy, and
more. Through time travel, they saved Superboy in
the 20th century and he joined the Legion as an
honorary member, followed later by Supergirl and
Monal of Daxam, a former sister planet of Krypton.
You can learn more about Supergirl in our
Supergirl vs Captain Marvel duel episode. As the
team grew in reputation and size, they became
official peacekeepers of the United Planets,
operating with support from the science police.
Their base of operations evolved into a
technologically advanced headquarters in
Metropolis and leadership responsibilities
began rotating among members. Subteams emerged,
including the Legion Espionage Squad and the
Legion of Substitute Heroes. They faced enemies
such as the Fatal Five, the Dark Circle, and the
Sorcerer Mordru, and suffered tragedy with the
death of founding member Lightning Lad and the
sacrifice of... The Legion endured numerous
galactic conflicts including the Earth War with
the Coons and the Great Darkness Saga, which saw
them battle the God-like Dark Side. Though they
ultimately repelled his invasion, they lost many
members doing so. In the aftermath, the Legion
restructured internally, held elections for
leadership, and began recruiting non-humanoid
members such as Telus and Quistlet. After the
crisis on Infinite Earths altered the time
stream, the original history of Superboy was
erased. It was revealed that the Superboy who had
joined the Legion came from a pocket dimension
created by the Time Trapper to preserve their
continuity. After this Superboy died in battle,
Manel was retconned into the role of the Legion's
inspirational figure, and the team continued its
mission. Following the Magic Wars, the United
Planets descended into disarray. Earth was
covertly conquered by the Dominators, prompting
the disbandment of the Legion. Years later,
Chameleon Boy secretly assembled a new, more
pragmatic version of the team to resist. The
clandestine operation confronted covert
threats and political machinations, including a
battle between the Sorcerers Mordru and Glorath
over control of the time stream. During this
period, a hidden chamber beneath the Time
Institute was discovered, containing Batch SW6,
teenage duplicates of the Legion who believed
themselves to be the originals. These younger
heroes formed their own version of the Legion, as
the older team fought to prevent the collapse of
their reality. The Legion's fate was sealed
during the Zero Hour Crisis when the Time Trapper
revealed that the SW6 Legionnaires were not
clones, but younger versions pulled from a
divergent timeline, as reality destabilized
both the original Legion and their younger
counterparts merged in an attempt to preserve the
time stream, effectively ending their
continuity. In a rebooted timeline, the Legion
was reimagined once more. Still inspired by the
trio's rescue of RJ Brand, this incarnation
emphasized diplomacy and unity among worlds. The
founding members, Livewire, Cosmic Boy, and
Saturn Girl built a team that included updated
versions of familiar faces like apparition,
invisible kid, excess, and Andromeda. They
earned the trust of the United Planets through key
missions against white triangle Daxomite
supremacists, the terrorist network Tangleweb,
and corrupt political figures such as President
Chu. After a devastating encounter with the alien
collective known as the Blight, a spatial rift
opened during a mission pulling half of the Legion
into an unknown universe. Presumed dead by those
who remained, the missing members found
themselves trapped by a deranged god called the
Progenitor, later revealed to be Element Lad,
driven mad by isolation and unchecked power over
centuries. Livewire ultimately gave his life to
prevent the cosmic entity Omni-Phaegos from
invading their home. The surviving Legionnaires
eventually returned to their universe only to
discover Earth in ruins, the Legion disbanded,
and their reputation shattered. Undeterred,
they reassembled and established a new orbital
headquarters known as Legion World. From there,
the team fought off invasions from Robotica, who
sought to impose forced evolution through a
process called hypertaxis, and defended the
galaxy from threats like a mind-controlled
warworld. Brainiac 5 ultimately defeated
Robotica's leader, Computo, by allowing him to
evolve beyond conquest. The Legion continued to
grow, launching the Legion core and contending
with threats like Universo and Ra-Sel Ghul, the
latter of whom impersonated President Leland
Macaulay in an effort to accelerate humanity's
evolution. The team narrowly averted
catastrophe when Darkseid attempted to merge
with his younger self to dominate time itself, and
later faced the fatal 500, an army of villains from
across the universe. Following the Flashpoint
event, Legion members Wildfire, Dawnstar,
Tyrock, Timberwolf, Telus, Gates, and Chameleon
Girl were stranded in the Nile 8 their own
timeline. While working to contain the virus,
they encountered the Black Razors and Martian
Manhunter, who warned them they could never
return home. You can learn more about Martian
Manhunter in our Martian Manhunter vs. Vision
episode. Meanwhile, in the 31st century, the rest
of the Legion carried on until a devastating
battle with the Fatal 5 forced the United Planets
to disband the team. Scattered, many
Legionnaires returned to their home worlds, some
joining the Science Police, while others
retired. A few, like Brainiac 5, continued their
work in secret. The team reunited when a cosmic
entity named Infinitus threatened the
multiverse. Brainiac 5 resumed leadership, and
the lost Legionnaires were reintegrated into the
team. They were joined by Legionnaires from
alternate timelines, including Xs and Gates from
Earth 247. After defeating Infinitus, the Legion
reestablished itself as an intergalactic,
peacekeeping force aware of the multiverse. In a
newly converged future, the Legion was born anew
in the 31st century of Earth Prime. In this world,
society had grown sterile and repressive,
discouraging physical contact, individual
thought, and free expression. Children were
tracked, monitored, and trained to conform.
Against this backdrop, a small group of teen
heroes defied cultural norms and formed a new
Legion of Superheroes, inspired by the long lost
example of Superman. This new Legion expanded its
mission beyond defense into cultural
revolution. Thousands of young idealists
rallied to their cause as Legionnaires, while the
core team, featuring Cosmic Boy, Lightning Glad,
Saturn Girl, Brainiac 5, Ultra Boy, Shadow Lasts,
and Timberwolf, fought authoritarian
governments like Terror of Ferma and subversive
figures like Lemnos. Supergirl briefly joined
them due to a temporal displacement, while
Dreamgirl became a martyr whose cryptic visions
had guided the team's broader purpose. After a
brutal war with the Dominators, the Legion used a
massive Phantom Zone projector to exile an entire
planet in order to save the galaxy. When Cosmic Boy
mysteriously vanished, Supergirl and later
Lightning Glad stepped up to lead the Legion. The
team endured internal rifts, external sabotage,
and future-born invasions. Eventually, they
discovered that the United Planets had been
infiltrated by Rosal Ghul and his army of
genetically engineered teleporters. Ros sought
to trigger Max hypertaxis on Earth by using the
Moon as a catalyst. The Legion and allies defeated
him and restored the Moon to its rightful orbit.
The most recent incarnation of the team formed
when the Legion traveled back to the 21st century
to recruit John Kent, Superman's son, into their
ranks. This roster introduced new members like
Gold Lantern, Dr. Fate, and Monster Boy, while
reinventing similar characters with fresh
origins and updated abilities. And that's their
history so far. Now when choosing who would
represent the Legion of Superheroes for this
roster, I decided to start my 7-member roster with
the team's 3 founders. Cosmic Boy, the team's
magnetic field manipulator and founding leader
who can control metal, produce force fields, and
generate EMP blasts. Saturn Girl, a powerful
telepath from Titan, able to read and influence
minds. And Lightning Glad, who wields
devastating electrical power. Other prominent
members across the Legion's history on my team are
Brainiac 5, the 12th level intellect who provides
unparalleled strategy and advanced tech,
primarily a force field generator. And Chameleon
Boy, a shapeshifting master of infiltration,
deception, and surprise attacks. To represent
the diverse and sometimes outright bonkers
Legionnaires that make the Legion unique amongst
other DC teams, I decided to add Bouncing Boy to my
roster who can inflate his rubberized body,
allowing him to ricochet at high speeds and
turning his body into a human wrecking ball.
Finally, to represent the team's history with
Superman and his family, I'm adding Supergirl,
who of course possesses all of the powers of her
cousin. All Legionnaires wear Legion Flight
Rings, which grant them high speed flights,
environmental protection, such as in space, and
instant communication across fast distances.
And that's the Legion. To reiterate, my team
consists of Cosmic Boy, Saturn Girl, Lightning
Glad, Brainiac 5, Chameleon Boy, Bouncing Boy,
and Supergirl. Yeah, I like that team. I like its
diverse roster. What is the deal with all of the
Legionnaires' names either ending in Boy, Girl,
Lad, or Lass? That was only really during the first
wave of Legionnaires, I feel, because later on you
get characters like Excess and Dramata. Should be
called Excess Boy and Dramata Girl, I feel like.
Otherwise it doesn't feel like a Legionnaire
name. Is this why Livewire changed his name to
Lightning Glad? Well, it was Lightning Glad, then
it was Livewire, then I believe his sister took on
the name Livewire, then he was back to being
Lightning Glad and in another reboot, it's
complicated. I think Brainiac 5 should change his
name to Brainiac 5 Boy. I think you should change
your name to Marvelous Boy. Wait, that's weird. So
as we've mentioned earlier, whenever we're
coming up with these team battles, we don't really
know too much about the other team. So to make this
as fair a battle as we can make it, we like to match up
individual characters on each roster who have a
comparable power level that we're aware of. Yeah,
in this instance for this team duel, we're pairing
up the characters of Supergirl and Magic, who are
badass warrior types, Cosmic Boy and Sunspot, who
wield spectral energies, Saturn Girl and Mirage,
the resident psychics of the group, Bouncing Boy
and Cannonball, who can launch themselves and
slam into other characters, Chameleon Boy and
Wolfsbane, who can transform their bodies,
Brainiac 5 and Cipher, the resident tech smart
guys, and Lightning Glad and Magma, who wield
elemental energies. Notice that none of the
members on my team have the words boy or lass or lad
in them. No, but they would be so much cooler they
did like Magic class, Sunspot boy, Mirage girl,
heck yeah. Dynamic duel, where comic book titans
smash every Tuesday, Max Destruction, where TV
and action heroes battle every Wednesday, and
Sendro World, where anime champions clash every
Thursday. Join us as we speculate on the matches
and armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge
victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com where we
settle the debate and settle the score. But now
that we've got their histories and rosters out of
the way, let's speculate on how one of the
thousands of simulated matches will go. The
winner is determined by simulations, not the
speculation, but it's fun to imagine how a fight
could play out. Ajin and Kei, what are the rules of
our speculation? Well, I should say there are no
rules, other than the teams have no prior
knowledge of the other going into the fight. All
they are aware of starting out is that the other
side is a threat that needs to be eliminated. For
the speculation, the groups will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the match
itself, as no environmental statistics are
considered in my simulations. The teams must earn
victory on their own merit. All right, then let's
get into it. The Legion of Superheroes and the new
mutants meet on the battlefield. Who goes first?
I'm going to say that cannonball starts this off by
blasting right into the air and then slamming down
right in the middle of where the Legionnaires are.
And he slams right on top of Cosmic Boy actually and
scatters the rest of the team when he lands and
creates this like massive shockwave. Not first
field, cannonball slams right into a force field
generated by Brainiac 5 who could extend his
personal force field. He's just going to quickly
envelop his team right from the get go when
cannonball shoots into the sky. You know,
Brainiac is going to be doing all of these
instantaneous calculations determining his
power and trajectory and stuff like that. So when
cannonball bounces off of the force field,
Brainiac, he's going to collapse his force field
back to around him personally, and that's going to
allow lightning glad to unleash this really
intense lightning bolt at magic that's going to
then arc to every other member of the new mutants
electrocuting all of them. Now, because magic can
just block the lightning bolt with her soul sword.
And that's when she teleports over to the
Legionnaires in the middle of the group. And then
she does this magic spin slash kind of like link
from the Legend of Zelda games. She's like, ah, and
all the Legionnaires get blasted away from her
from this magic slash, they get blasted away.
Yeah, with magic energy. Okay. All right. So the
Legionnaires, they all get blasted backward. But
bouncing boy, he just bounces right back like
literally slamming right into magic, bouncing
off of her and then bouncing into Wolf's Spain. And
the rest of the new mutants just like a pinball
knocking their asses over. Okay. All right. So
bouncing boy bounces everyone, except magma, who
protects herself by erupting it like this geyser
of lava from the ground right in front of her. And
bouncing boy crashes into the geyser and like
lifts him into the air like a fountain. And he just
gets third degree burns all over his body and dies.
Oh snap. Okay. Actually, Supergirl, she's going
to use her freeze breath to ice over that geyser
pretty quickly. So while bouncing boy probably
looks like Freddy Krueger about now, his burns
aren't fatal. And Supergirl, she's going to carry
him to safety while Saturn girl, meanwhile, she's
going to take mental control of magma and cause her
to open a geyser beneath Sunspot. That's not going
to do anything. Sunspot not only is he highly
durable, like pretty much almost invulnerable,
especially to heat, but like all the heat
radiation from the magma would power him up
actually. Like after a quick dip in this lava
shooting out of the ground, Sunspot's going to fly
out and blast a solar blast at cosmic boy and just
fry cosmic boy like French fry. Except cosmic boy
would block that blast by transforming these
metallic bobbles that he has on his outfit into a
large flat metal shield, which he's then going to
push towards Sunspot and casing the metal around
his head so you can't see or even breathe. That also
doesn't matter to Sunspot because he doesn't need
oxygen when he's in his solar mode because he's
sustained by the photosynthesis. But if the
metals covering his face, he will be blinded. So
while he's dealing with that, I'm going to say
meanwhile, Wolf's Bane in full on beast mode, like
werewolf mode, she straight slashes off
chameleon boy's antenna off of his head. So
quickly he doesn't have time to react. Well
chameleon boy will just form new ones, you know? Ah
shit. And then he's going to transform into a eight
foot Cthulhu type monster and his tentacles are
going to stretch around and bind Wolf's Bane while
his claws pierce into her abdomen, killing her. So
she's out. No, because all of a sudden, he gets a
neural arrow straight into his head area, which
stuns him. And that arrow came from Mirage who
fired it because she's always been protective of
her friend Wolf's Bane. And chameleon boy
stunned, which causes him to melt into a puddle.
Okay. And Wolf's Bane escapes. And then Cypher
rides over on this like techno organic motorcycle
that Warlock transformed into. And he reaches
down and transmutes the chameleon boy puddle into
like these techno organic nanites that he just
absorbs into himself. Interesting. Okay. I'm
going to say before Cypher gets to chameleon boy
though, lightning glad is going to intervene and
he's going to destroy Warlock's motorcycle with a
lightning blast that's going to send nanite
pieces flying everywhere. And that's going to
allow chameleon boy to slither away as a puddle and
recover. Meanwhile, Saturn girl, she's taken
mental control of cannonball and she's going to
force him to plow straight into Wolf's Bane at full
speed, just breaking her body completely. I don't
know how Wolf's Bane would actually get out of
that. So she's probably out of the match, but magic
will create a portal to limbo that cannonball
flies into and that will cut off Saturn girl's
telepathic hold over him. And then he's going to
fly back into the match through another one of
magic's portals. And while that's happening, all
of a sudden Wolf's Bane, who was thought dead on the
ground, rises up and now she's like a zombie
werewolf. Okay. And she runs over to Saturn girl
and she's immune to Saturn girl's psychic probes.
And she straight bites into Saturn girl's face and
just like chomps down on her, swallowing her whole
and digesting her. I'm sorry. What the fuck is
going on here? It's an illusion that Saturn girl
sees as a fear of hers, which is caused by Mirage, of
course. So Mirage gets Saturn girl to see Wolf's
Bane rise up from the dead and eat her. So Saturn
girl's freaking the fuck out thinking she's being
eaten. Of course she's not really, but as she's
freaking out Mirage stabs a neural spear into
Saturn girl's back, which is going to paralyze her
mind and shut it down. So Saturn girl is now out of
the match. No, dude, Saturn girl would not fall for
a mental illusion like that. She's an insanely
powerful telepath. Actually she would because
Mirage's powers are empathic in nature, not
telepathic. So it's like a sort of different
psychic attack. And it totally works on telepaths
because it manipulates their emotions, not
necessarily their brain. Well, that's stupid.
But whatever, sure, Saturn girl's out.
Meanwhile, Super girl, she is probably chasing
down cannonball since she can match his speed. And
when she grabs him, she's going to steer both of
them into the ground causing this deep impact
crater. And with cannonball pinned in the ground
unable to move, he stops blasting. And that's when
Super girl sends a quick beam of heat vision right
through his head, ending him and taking him out of
She's going to turn into her magma form and she's
going to melt the metal off of Sunspot's face that
Cosmic Boy had put there. And Sunspot's then going
to fly over to bouncing boy and just finish burning
him alive. Like whatever magma started, he just
finishes and then Sunspot kicks him like a charred
soccer ball. And he kicks him so hard that like
bouncing boy bounces to the other side of whatever
country they're in. That's fucked up. Yeah, I
guess that wasn't necessary, but I tried to get a
soccer element in there with bouncing boy because
Sunspot's really good at soccer. Anyway, Cypher
at this point has transformed himself into a
Nanite cloud using Warlock's power. And he swarms
over to chameleon boy and like he avoids his whole
motion sensor and tannethink by translating
their movement and determining their function.
So like he stealthily gets around chameleon boy
and then reforms and stabs chameleon boy with an
arm sword, which infects chameleon boy with a
techno organic virus and converts him into
technology. So chameleon boy is now a techno
organic being under Cypher's control. And he
commands chameleon boy to take the form of a
missile that Cypher then loads into his new arm
cannon and fires at lightning lad, just
obliterating both chameleon boy and lightning
lad for a twofer explosion. Now, except Cosmic Boy
saw chameleon boy being infected by the tiny metal
Nanites and Cosmic Boy he's generating this EMP
blast that's going to shut down all of Cypher's
Nanites, which just dropped to the floor like
sand. So chameleon boy is gone, but so is Cypher and
lightning lad, meanwhile he has Mirage in his grip
and he's overloading her with electricity until
she's fried. So she's out. Okay, Mirage is out, but
Magma shoots a lava wave at lightning lad that
hardens into stone on contact. So she encases
lightning lad in obsidian and he's trapped inside
the stone and he just suffocates to death. Okay,
well guess what? You're done messed up because
lightning lad was Cosmic Boy's friend. So now
Cosmic Boy, he's going to pull down a meteor from
space like the size of a fridge and it's going to
slam right down on Magma, sending her Magma form
just splattering everywhere. Yeah, that would
work if Magma couldn't control rock. She's just
gonna break this meteor apart before it even
touches her. No, you said she controls like earth
rock, not space rock. Like this meteor is like an
alien Xenomineral. Okay. All right. You may have
got me there. Okay, so Magma's out then. She gets
crushed by this meteor, right? But then all of a
sudden, magic drops from a portal above Cosmic
Boy. She lands on him and she stunts him with her
soul sword and then she snaps his neck with her
Eldritch armor arm. Oh, you mean her metal arm? No,
no, no, it's Eldritch armors, magic. It's not
metal. Like some artists may render it metal, but
like sometimes they also render it just black,
like black demon armor. Like her soul sword is made
out of her soul, even though some artists draw like
metal and some make her sword look more like a
lightsaber, right? But either way, none of its
metal, even if it looked like it and Cosmic Boy
tried to manipulate it, he wouldn't be able to.
It's magic and he'll still be out of this match.
Well, that's dumb. So I have Supergirl and I have
Brainiac Five left and you have magic and Sunspot.
So with so few people left, I'm gonna say Sunspot
blasts Supergirl with solar energy, like what? An
idiot? And her Kryptonian cells are just gonna
absorb the attack. And when Sunspot is like, oh,
that's when Supergirl is gonna snatch him, drain
him of the rest of his solar energy and just hurl his
ass right up into outer space powerless. Oh, damn.
Would he do that? What else is he gonna do? Sure, I
guess he wouldn't know that Supergirl absorbs
solar energy. That's on him, I guess. So now I just
have magic left and you have Brainiac and
Supergirl. So magic's gonna take this fight to
limbo, okay? Because there she's the sorceress
supreme. She's the ruler. So she creates
teleportation portals and just sends everyone to
limbo. And while there, this big King Ghidorah
Hydra looking demon just burns Supergirl alive
with Hellfire. And I don't care how powered up
Supergirl is, she's vulnerable to magic like the
rest of the super family. So Supergirl's out. And
now it's just magic and Brainiac. And magic
telekinetically pulls off Brainiac's
Legionnaire flight ring so that he can't fly. And
then she sets up two portals suspended in midair
that cause Brainiac 5 to just fall forever for all
eternity in a portal loop in limbo. And that is how
the new mutants win this match. Okay, that was a
good move. But I'm gonna say while Brainiac is
falling in this portal loop, he's going to unleash
a Nanite grenade that he built from repurposed
warlock Nanites. And when these Nanites explode,
they infect the demons in limbo, converting them
into tech under Brainiac's control. So Brainiac
causes limbo's demons to turn on magic and devour
her, ending that endless portal loop. So the
Legion ends up winning actually. How did Brainiac
repurpose these warlock Nanites if they were
rendered inert by cosmic boys EMP? Oh, he just
rebooted them and re-energized them using his own
tech. I don't know what a techno organic infested
demon would look like, but I think magic would be
able to purge the virus using her magic. Cause
magic trumps tech. Now you would think that, but
you would be wrong because tech in fact trumps
magic. And I think Iron Man would agree with me.
Well, I think Dr. Strange would agree with me.
Well, let's go ahead and leave the match there.
Either magic beats tech and she's able to purge the
demons of the techno organic virus and defeat
Brainiac, or tech beats magic and the infected
demons eat magic. That is correct. But either way,
I don't know how Brainiac 5 is getting out of this
infinite portal loop. Well, once magic is dead, it
just ceases to exist. And you know, he'll find his
way out of limbo eventually, or he'll just
freaking take over the whole dimension. Alright,
well, let's go ahead and leave the match there.
We'll enter the stats and see what end scenario
happens when we run the simulations. AG9K, hit it.
Inputting data, running calculations,
processing results, simulations complete. This
was a fun match. Both teams are awesome. And
they're pretty similar in that Legionnaires are
kind of like mutants in a way, and that a lot of them
really only have one power. I mean, except for
Supergirl, but for the others, that was
definitely reflected in the stats. Yeah,
Supergirl was the most powerful member out of
either team. But just barely more than magic.
Yeah, the weakest member out of either team was
Wolfsbane, which sucks, because I really like the
character of Reince and Claire. But
statistically, she wasn't all that great. You
know, she's fast and can fuck you up with her claws
and fangs. But the fact that, you know, she goes
into her wool form, that she's not very versatile
or anything like that, she just didn't hold up.
Your weakest guy, though, was Bouncing Boy. Yeah,
not surprising. Definitely did not hold his own
against Cannonball. His counterpart, as it were,
he basically got obliterated by him in the stats.
You know what sucks, though, is that all of the
Legionnaires have their flight ring, which
grants them like interstellar flight speed. So
the Legionnaires just wiped the floor with new
mutants when it came to the speed stat. That was the
greatest disparity between the two teams, was
that the Legionnaires were much faster overall
because of their rings. Yeah, and the biggest
advantage that the new mutants had was that they
were much more durable. Some of my guys have force
fields and stuff like that, but without those,
they just didn't have the physicality that your
guys did. Yeah, I mean, like Supergirl's
invulnerable, but so is Cannonball when he's
blasting, Sunspots highly durable, and so is
Cipher when he's merged with Warlock. Most of the
new mutants team did pretty well. Like Magic won
about three fourths of all of her matches against
the Legionnaires, Cannonball won about half, and
then you have Wolfsbane who only won 14% of her
matches in total. Supergirl was definitely my
highest winner, also winning about three fourths
of her matches. My next most successful character
was actually Cosmic Boy, and no surprise,
Bouncing Boy lost a majority of his matches. So
Jonathan, who do you think is winning this one, and
why is it the new mutants? Uh, why is it not the new
mutants? Because I'm voting for the Legion 100%,
and I'm not the only one who did. According to our
Instagram poll, 67% of those who voted voted in
favor of the Legion, even though the new mutants
had a movie. That's terrible. What does that make a
difference? I'm just saying popularity wise, you
think people would have gone for the new mutants,
but people are smart. You know, they know how
powerful the Legion is. Well, let's see if they're
right. AJ9K, the results please. All right, the
winner in the team duel matchup between the Legion
of Superheroes and the new mutants is... the
Legion of Superheroes. I'm sorry, what was that?
Legion of Superheroes one. I can't understand
you. One more time. I said the punk ass Legion of
Superheroes. Who are they? Out of the thousands of
simulated matches between the two teams, the
Legion of Superheroes won 51.7% of the time,
whereas the new mutants only won 48.3% of the time.
That is close. I thought the Legion was going to
stop much more than that. Like I figured the Legion
was going to win this because the Legion is just
powerful. I'm legitimately surprised how much of
a good fight the new mutants put up. I'm not. I
thought they were going to win because you're
dumb. But the fact that they barely lost is
something to be proud of. I think I would have
preferred that they won. You know, if the
Legionnaires didn't have their flight rings, I
think the new mutants would have actually taken
this. Well, too bad for you. They do. So better luck
next time. I'm not going to need luck for our next
matchup. I got skills. You got Skittles and that's
it. I also have Skittles. What of it? Well, that
does it for this duel. AJ9K helped close us out.
Forget to listen to the other shows in the Dynamite
podcast network, including Max Destruction,
Senjo World, and Console Combat. In our next
matchup, where Joseph thinks he will need no luck,
but will in fact need all the luck in the world, we
will pit Bizarro versus Abomination, the evil
counterparts to Superman and the Hulk
respectively. That'll be a good one. I'm really
looking forward to that one. But that does it for
this episode. We want to give a big thanks to our
executive producers, John Staroski, Zachary
Hepburn, Destin Belcom, Mickey Mataengian,
Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yatyn, Austin
Wieselowski, AJ Dunkerley, Nick Ibonto, Scott
Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Spies, Dean Maleski,
Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, Josh Leiner, Mike
Williams, and Paul Graves for helping make this
podcast possible. We'll talk to you guys next
week. Up up and away, true believers. Shrinking
Heroin Small Lass