This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi and welcome
to the Dynamic Dual Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe and I'm his twin
brother Johnny DC. And in this episode we're going
to find out who'd win in a fight between Jubilee of
the X-Men and Static of the Milestone Comic
Imprint from DC. Right, both of these characters
had hit shows in the late 90s and early 2000s. They
both wear jackets, they both sport eye gear, they
both shoot sparkly things from their fingers.
Well, I mean Static does a lot more than that, which
is probably why he's going to win. Now Jubilee
shoots fireworks, okay? And no little sparkly
little lightning things are going to compete with
the power of fireworks as everyone should know
this 4th of July season. Like you go outside during
the 4th of July and you hear all those explosions?
Yeah, it's because they're fucking explosions,
they're loud, they rattle your windows, it's
really annoying. If you're a grown ass adult like
me, your dog probably gets pissed off. But yeah,
it's potent stuff. Oh yeah, it's almost like, you
know, when lightning strikes and there's
thunder? No, that doesn't happen. Okay, well this
is going to be an interesting matchup I think.
We'll find out who's going to win later on in this
episode. But before that we're going to break down
the latest comic book movie news to come out this
past week, of which we just have one news item and
that is the Fantastic Four First Steps Final
Trailer. As always we list our segment times in our
episode description so feel free to check out the
show notes if you want to skip ahead to a particular
topic. Guys, our artificially intelligent dual
simulator AJ9K has a quick message for our
listeners, so listen up. The X-Force tier makes
you an executive producer of this show. Lastly,
the Dynamite podcast network tier lets you create
your own podcast using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and
consultation, and get you simulation results.
Pitch the twins your ideas via email at
dynamicdualpodcastatgmail.com. Check it out at
patreon.com slash dynamicdual. Pip pip cheerio.
Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast. Be sure to tune in to the other shows in
the Dynamite podcast network this week,
including the console combat podcast where hosts
John and Dean simulate battles between popular
video game characters. In yesterday's episode
they determined who would win between Sora from
Kingdom Hearts and Shulk from Xenoblade
Chronicles. Over on the Max Destruction podcast
hosts Scotty and Gilly pit your favorite action
heroes from film and television against each
other. This week the brothers are pitting John
Wick against the equalizer. Over on the Sinjo
World podcast hosts Zachary Hepburn speculates
on fights between fan favorite anime and manga
characters. In his next episode, Zach is going to
reveal who would win between Aoi Toto of Jujutsu
Kaizen and Ryo Shimizaki of Mob Psycho 100. Visit
dynamicpodcast.com or click the link in our show
notes to listen to all the shows in the Dynamite
podcast network. But with that out of the way,
quick to the no prize. A no prize is an award that
Marvel used to give out to fans. Our version, the
dynamic duel no prize, is a digital award that we
post on Instagram for the person that we feel gave
the best answer to our question of the week. Last
week we asked you guys, besides the Punisher and
obviously Daredevil, which of the former Marvel
Netflix characters would you most want to see in
the next Spider-Man film? And this is coming off
the news that it has been confirmed that the
Punisher is going to be in the next Spider-Man
brand new day movie. We got five answers total, so
let's go down our three honorable mentions and the
no prize winner. Our first honorable mention goes
to Alex Albro, who said, I think Nuke should be the
one from the Netflix universe to be in the
Spider-Man movie. He's a really grounded
character who could be an Act One villain, or he
could be on the Punisher side and they're going
crazy throughout New York, and then either the
Punisher kind of sees the evil of his ways and stops
Nuke, or Spider-Man stops them before they all go
crazy, or maybe Spider-Man just gets a symbiote
and everybody's crazy in a really allegedly
grounded movie. Thanks. Yeah, I thought this was a
pretty good answer because Nuke was in the first
two seasons of Jessica Jones. I guess the one issue
with this answer is that Nuke died in Jessica
Jones, but he was played by Will Travel and I
thought he was actually really good in the role.
Kind of a bizarro take on Captain America in a
different way that John Walker was. For those who
may not know who Nuke is, he's like a super soldier,
but he takes these pills to get his physical
enhancements. He played a big part of the born
again Daredevil comic book storyline, but I can
see how elements of that could be incorporated
into the Spider-Man movie. Yeah, great answer,
Alex. Our next honorable mention goes to Lorenzo
Valdez. Who said? This is Lorenzo Valdez calling
in once again. The Netflix character that I think
is perhaps most likely to appear in Spider-Man
Brand New Day would be Karen, given that we already
know that the Punisher is now going to be in the
movie. But I also will say that I think we would
really be missing out if we never got to see a
confrontation between Kingpin and Spider-Man in
the MCU. Clona forever and always, buh-bye. Yeah,
Karen Page has been a big part of the storylines for
both Daredevil and Punisher. So if Punisher is
making an appearance in the Spider-Man movie, it
would not surprise me if Karen was also there.
Yeah, she's kind of the supporting character that
bridges a lot of the gaps between the Daredevil and
Punisher series. And I think she's Frank
Strongest supporting, consistent supporting
character throughout all of his appearances. So
great answer, Lorenzo. Our next honorable
mention goes to Cyrus Moore. Who said? Hey guys,
Cyrus Moore. So what I really want to see is I don't
want to see the Punisher Daredevil in this new
Spider-Man movie. I want to see Iron Fist because
with Iron Fist, we could bring over Luke Cage in the
same movie, maybe introduce Nova, recast Flash
Thompson that way we can get an agent Venom, have
White Tiger that way we can have an ultimate
Spider-Man movie, and introduce a bunch of
characters and have an amazing team up. And that
would just be awesome. Yeah, this is kind of going
along the lines of why we asked this question of the
week to begin with, because incorporating the
Punisher into the Spider-Man series kind of makes
it seem like the story is going to take a more
grounded street level approach, and that would be
a good opportunity to bring in other defenders
characters from the Netflix series. And yeah, I
think Iron Fist is a strong candidate, especially
if they give the guy some good fight choreography
this time, and he follows through with it, I think
Danny Rand would be a good addition, and then also
bring in Luke Cage and other characters like Agent
Venom. Although Cyrus mentioned recasting Flash
Thompson for the role of Agent Venom, and I think
Tony Revelore could pull it off. Yeah, he's kind of
on the smaller end, but that doesn't really bother
me because he's a good actor. Tom Hardy himself is a
little bit on the smaller end, you know? He's only
like three inches taller than Tony Revelore, so.
Oh, I did not know that. Well, great answer, Cyrus.
We want to give a quick shout out to Sheldon Moore
for taking the time to visit our website and record
an answer. But the winner of this week's No Prize is
Lee Tapscott, who said, Which character from the
Netflix Marvel series I would like to see in
Spider-Man movie? The character of Kingpin. I
mean, he was originally a Spider-Man enemy, and
with him being like the mayor of New York right now,
he could be going after Spider-Man for, you know,
being an unregistered superhero or whatever he's
after. Yeah, I guess this all really depends on how
Daredevil born again season two kind of shapes up
with Daredevil's battle going up against Mayor
Kingpin. But yeah, I think it would be fantastic to
have Vincent D'Narvio as the Kingpin be the
primary antagonist for the Spider-Man brand new
day film, especially if you have like the Punisher
and maybe even Daredevil show up and they all team
up to go up against him. Oh yeah, totally. When we
asked this question, I really wasn't looking for
the Defenders characters. I was looking for
Kingpin. And since Lee Tapscott gave only that
answer and no one else, that's why he gets this
week's No Prize win. Yeah, I think it would just
feel right considering he's right in that the
Kingpin was originally a Spider-Man villain
before he was a Daredevil villain. And you know,
with the Punisher making his first appearance in
the Spider-Man comic books too, everything just
seems to dovetail nicely in regards to a
Spider-Man street level crime story. So great
answer, Lee. You win this week's No Prize. If you,
the listener, want a shot at winning your own No
Prize, stay tuned to later on in this episode when
we'll be asking another question of the week.
Another That's Done. On to the news! Alright, this
past week we got the final trailer for the
Fantastic Four First Steps film, which comes out
in just a few weeks here on July 25th. It's our final
good look at the movie before it comes out, and I
gotta say it's the best trailer that's come out
yet. I think it has a lot of scenes and moments that I
think will get a lot of people excited, what they
were probably looking for in the trailer since the
beginning. Because we get a good introduction and
good look at the heroes and the costumes. We get to
see a lot of action of them going up against
Galactus. We get to see everybody's powers
including Reed stretching and Sue creating
current visible force fields. The thing smashing
through stuff and the human torch flying, the
Fantastic Car flying. I'm not surprised that they
waited until the final trailer to really showcase
the special effects considering the film is very
CG heavy. I gotta say the special effects look
amazing in this film. I love the feel and visual
tone of the movie. Galactus looks like he's gonna
be freaking awesome. The more I see this
character, because in the previous trailer we
just got a shot of his legs as he was walking through
the city. And in the trailer before that we just got
a shot of his shadow looking over Manhattan. But
here, while we don't get to see his face, we get to
see pretty much the rest of his body. And I think
it's gonna look incredible on the big screen with
all the intricate details that they actually have
on his suit. The scale of him is gonna be pretty awe
inspiring when we finally get to see him. We got
another look at Shalabal's Silver Surfer played
by Julia Garner who has a little bit more dialogue
in this trailer as she heralds the coming of
Galactus. I thought her voice treatment was
pretty good. Again, still not thrilled about this
not being Gnor and Rad, but we've talked about that
on this podcast before. Actually didn't love her
delivery. Now Julia Garner is a good actress, so I
was kind of surprised. It sounded like to me she was
asking questions. I herald your end maybe? That
wasn't a question mark, it was a comma. The whole
thing was question marks. She's an alien, maybe
that's their style of diction. You don't know. Do
you speak alien? Are you from another planet?
Sounds like fucking English to me. It's English,
but it's alien English, okay? Okay. It's totally
fine. It looks like at some point in the movie the
Fantastic Four fly up to Galactus' spaceship,
which I think is gonna be a cool scene. And that's
where they, like, I don't know, they almost die in
the process coming back down to Earth. There's a
really nice acting moment with Petro Pascal when
reporters ask him if everything's gonna be okay
and he gives the honest answer of I don't know,
which is a big deal for Reed Richards considering
he's regarded as the smartest man in the world and
he should have the answers. We get a few shots of
baby Franklin Richards and his appearance makes
me think that maybe he's gonna be used as a McGuffin
of sorts. I hope they don't do some kind of deus ex
machina where the baby ends up saving the day
because he's, you know, he's an all powerful
reality warper in the comic books. Yeah, it was
interesting to see him as a baby. I don't think I've
ever really seen him as an infant in the comics.
Usually he's a little boy, right? Right. So I
thought it was interesting that in the previous
trailer we have Sue and Reed finding out that
they're pregnant. But then in this trailer, like,
the baby is already here. So it makes me wonder
about, like, how long of a timeframe this film
takes place in. Yeah, definitely over the course
of a year, right? Considering the kid looks about,
like, eight to ten months old within these shots.
Maybe the Silver Surfer comes and warns
everybody, tells them they have, like, a year
before Galactus comes or something like that. Who
knows. Interesting. There's a running gag
throughout the trailer where people are trying to
get Ben Grimm the thing to say it's clobbering
time, which is his catchphrase in the in-universe
cartoon that they have about the Fantastic Four.
And it's pretty funny. Johnny tries multiple
times to try to get him to say it, including an
interesting scene where he's, like, carrying the
thing while flying. But the thing has a beard. He
has a full-on mustache and beard combo made out of
rock that I've never seen anything like that
before in the comic books. I've seen the Hulk with a
beard, but I don't think I've ever seen the thing
with a beard. I didn't even think that he could grow
a beard. And I feel like it raises all sorts of
questions regarding Ben Grimm's body hair. Like,
does he have pubes? Or armpit hair? Like, does it
crystallize out of his armpits? And he has to,
like, shave all this stuff? It's really bizarre. I
don't like it. I don't like things with a beard. I
hope he loses it. I hope he doesn't have it for, you
know, the climax of the film. And it's like, why
doesn't he have hair on top of his head? Yeah,
that's a great question. Great question. Does he
not shave his eyebrows? And so, like, is that why
they're so bulky and big? Oh, that's interesting.
Are the beetle brows hair, rock hair? Wow. I think
it's just a kind of an uncomfortable subject. And I
don't want to think about Ben Grimm's pubes. So I'd
rather just stop discussing it. Yeah, and he's
like ass hair. I don't want to think about that. All
in all, I was really pleased by this trailer and I am
really hoping that it provides the level of
excitement that the film needs in order to do well
at the box office. Again, it's only coming out two
weeks after the Superman film. Hopefully
Fantastic Four just bites a huge chunk out of the
Superman final box office. That way I can gloat in
front of Jonathan. But speaking of the DC Marvel
summer blockwesters that come out in July, that
brings us to our question of the week. What movie do
you think will be making more at the worldwide box
office? Superman or the Fantastic Four first
steps and why? And this includes the entire
duration of their theatrical runs worldwide. By
the end, what's your best guess as to who's coming
out on top and will ultimately be the more popular
film? Yes, and why is it Superman? Record your
answer at dynamicduel.com by clicking on the red
microphone button in the bottom right hand corner
of the screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long and don't forget to leave your name in case we
include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a Dynamic
Duel No Prize that we'll post to Instagram. Be sure
to answer before July 5th. But that does it for all
the news for this episode, so let's go ahead and
move into our main event where we find out who would
win in a fight between the teen heroes of Static and
Jubilee. Static vs Jubilee Static vs Jubilee,
this particular matchup was an idea by the
executive producers. We've been trying to get
Static in a duel matchup forever, basically,
since the start of this podcast. So I'm surprised
that we're just getting to him now because we
really enjoyed his cartoon Static Shock on the WB
as kids. And we also loved the 90s X-Men cartoon of
which Jubilee played a major role, especially
within, you know, that first season. Right,
exactly. We have these two young teen heroes who
are encountering new worlds filled with
superpowers for the first time from their
respective cartoons that were popular when we
were kids. We watched the heck out of those shows,
but we're really doing this episode now in lead up
to the 4th of July holiday since Jubilee has
fireworks powers, essentially. We thought this
would be a fun episode to do. Yeah, so when you go out
there and see all of the fireworks displays this
holiday, you can just think about, dang, like
Jubilee really shoots those out of her
fingertips. She really did fuck Static up that
episode. Yeah, or maybe during your 4th of July
weekend there happens to be a thunderstorm and
you're seeing all of the crazy lightning and
thunder and you're like, whoa, that's way more
scary than fireworks. I'm so glad Static won
because he should have. We will see what happens.
But to explain the methodology behind our duels,
let's go to our sentient duel simulator Alfred
Jarvis-9000. AJ9K tell our listeners how you go
about determining a winner in our duel matchups.
Yes, of course, sir. The way I determine a winner
between the contestants is by running 1000 Monte
Carlo simulations using the characters
statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation is a
probabilistic model used to determine outcomes
through random sampling. In this case, I
randomize the statistics along a normal
distribution as a way to simulate the many
variables that can occur during battle. The stat
parameters are based on the official Marvel power
grid from which the DC characters statistics are
extrapolated. Additional stat categories are
included such as range, damage potential,
versatility and perception in order to create a
more detailed and accurate simulation. The
results of the 1000 simulations provide a
percentage of wins for each character. The
contestant with the higher percentage is
declared the victor as they have a higher
probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither character should win
100% of the matches. The comic book stories have
shown that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman, so the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks, AJ9K.
Before we run the simulations though, we like to
break down each character's histories and
abilities before improvising a scenario on how we
imagine one of the 1000 simulations would play out
beat for beat. And it is my turn to go first with the
DC characters backstory, so let me tell you all
about static. Now within the Dakotaverse, also
known as Earth M, Virgil Ovid Hawkins grew up in
Dakota City, a fictional Midwestern city plagued
by crime, poverty and social tension. Virgil was a
bright, science-loving teenager who adored
comic books, video games, and all things pop
culture. His intelligence and interests often
made him a target for bullies at Ernest Hemingway
High School, especially Martin Bizmoney B
Skoponi. Despite the harassment, Virgil
maintained strong friendships with classmates
like Frida Gorin and Larry Wade. Quietly, he
harbored feelings for Frida, not realizing she
was dating Larry. One night, after enduring yet
another beating at the hands of Martin and his
friends, Virgil reached his breaking point.
Pressured by Larry, he went to Paris Island with a
gun, intent on confronting his tormentor. In the
end, he could not bring himself to commit an act of
violence, and he tossed the weapon into a river,
choosing to walk away instead. At that moment,
however, the police arrived to break up a massive
gang brawl nearby, which would later be known as
the Big Bang. The police unleashed experimental
tear gas infused with a mutagenic agent known as
quantum juice. The gas was originally designed as
a radioactive tracing agent to track criminals,
but instead caused horrifying mutations,
transferring many who survived into
superpowered beings known as Bang Babies. Virgil
survived the event and discovered he had
developed electromagnetic powers. Inspired by
his love of superheroes and driven by a sense of
justice, he crafted a homemade costume and
adopted the name Static, determined to protect
his city. As Static, Virgil quickly realized that
being a hero was far more challenging than he had
ever imagined. His first major battle was against
Hotstrike, the pyrokinetic form of his former
bully, Martin Scarponi. Initially overpowered,
Static rallied to defend Frida, who discovered
his identity and became his closest confidant.
She supported his mission, but also reminded him
of the importance of balance, as his dual life
strained his friendships, academics, and family
responsibilities. Virgil struggled to keep jobs
and saw his great slip, discovering that heroism
demanded countless personal sacrifices. Over
time, his enemies grew more dangerous. Static
fought criminals like Commando X, who sought to
divide the city through fearing chaos and
holocaust, a ruthless energy-wielding villain
and former member of the Blood Syndicate, which
was a powerful gang of metihumans trying to impose
their own control on Dakota City. He faced
unpredictable metihumans like Tarmac, Rubber
Bandman, and Puff, and even reality-bending
threats such as Riff. Despite these challenges,
Virgil continued to push forward, using his
intelligence and scientific mind to outwit foes
as much as overpowered them. His analytical
nature allowed him to develop creative tactics,
including using electromagnetic fields to
deflect bullets and mobilize enemies and hack
into communication systems. He built his iconic
flying disc, known as the Static Saucer, which
allowed him to soar through the city and pursue
criminals with speed and precision. Virgil's
personal life, however, became increasingly
complicated. His brief romance with the
mysterious metihuman Dusk offered him hope and
escape, but it ended in tragedy when she
sacrificed herself to save civilians from a fire.
This loss, combined with the death of his close
friend Larry during a failed drug operation,
pushed Virgil to the brink of giving up his heroic
identity altogether. Grieving and questioning
whether his actions truly made a difference, he
stepped away from the mantle of Static to try and
reclaim a normal life. Dakota, however, could not
be left unprotected. When bank babies began
mysteriously disappearing, Virgil discovered
the culprit was John Tower, a once heroic figure
turned power-hungry villain. Timmy Gupp with
other heroes, Virgil led a mission to confront
Tower, free the captives, and restore hope to his
city. Through this ordeal, he reaffirmed his
commitment to heroism, but vowed to approach it
with more balance, choosing to protect Dakota on
his own terms rather than being consumed by guilt
or duty. Following the merging of the Dakotaverse
and the main DC universe, Static joined the Teen
Titans. Initially haunted by trauma from his time
as a captive fighter in the Dark Side Club's
underground tournaments, he struggled to fit in.
However, he eventually found camaraderie and
purpose with his new teammates forming bonds with
Acogirl, Blue Beetle, and Wondergirl. His
brilliance as a scientist and inventor shone
through when he designed a special stabilizing
suit for Kid Flash, saving him from a potentially
fatal molecular breakdown. You, of course, can
learn more about the Teen Titans in our Titans vs
X-Men dual episode. His time with the Titans
provided Virgil with something he had long
craved, a surrogate family who understood his
struggles and stood by him. He proved himself as
both a capable fighter and a supportive friend
earning the respect and affection of the team.
Eventually, Virgil returned to Dakota after
hearing that a deadly virus was sweeping through
the city, infecting many residents including his
sister Sharon. Investigating its origin, he
confronted Holocaust, who had orchestrated the
plague as part of a power scheme. In the ensuing
conflict, Static was captured and imprisoned in a
containment unit designed to neutralize his
abilities. Ultimately, the Teen Titans arrived
to rescue him and together they defeated
Holocaust. After reuniting with his family in
Frida, Virgil decided to return to San Francisco
with the Titans, telling his parents he had been
accepted into a quantum physics fellowship to
protect his secret life. Although his ties to home
remained strained, he carried with him a renewed
sense of resolve and community. In the
post-Flashpoint timeline, Virgil and his family
moved to New York City following a traumatic event
that left his sister Sharon split into two
identical versions of herself. Virgil began
working as an intern at Star Labs under the
guidance of Hardware, a brilliant technological
hero. There he received advanced equipment,
including a new high-tech suit and an upgraded
versatile flying disc. In New York, Virgil faced
new adversaries, including the powerful
sunspots and viral, a living virus entity.
Despite these challenges, he continued to
support his fellow heroes, even helping Red Robin
redesign his cape and glider apparatus,
showcasing his technical genius. When the Dakota
verse was later rebooted, Virgil's origin was
revised so that he gained his powers during a
violent clash at a Black Lives Matter protest,
confronting Cotstreek shortly after. Once he
stepped into the hero role, he exposed government
corruption and rescued kidnapped bang babies,
solidifying his reputation as Dakota's
guardian. And that's Static's backstory.
Power-wise, Static can generate, absorb, and
manipulate electromagnetic energy, enabling
him to produce powerful electrical attacks,
magnetize objects, and create static cling
fields to immobilize opponents or anchor
objects. You can generate electromagnetic force
fields, which act as protective barriers against
projectiles and energy blasts. Using magnetic
levitation, he flies on a metal disc, the Static
saucer, which also doubles as a weapon and shield
in combat. His scientific intellect rivals some
of the DC Universe's greatest minds, allowing him
to build custom gear and analyze complex threats.
His powers, however, are ineffective against
insulators such as wood and rubber, and that
remains among his few physical limitations. I
didn't know that the Milestone Universe got
rebooted. Yeah, it did. I think around the rebirth
era, they took a new crack at the Dakota verse. That
was pretty interesting how they decided to
contemporize it by making it part of tear gas used
during a protest or something like that. That's
definitely a more interesting way to modernize
origin from the original gang violence kind of
angle that they went with during the character's
conception. Yeah, I think the creators of
Milestone Comics always want their characters to
remain relevant in a modern day setting and
context. So what they did, I thought, was an
interesting approach. For sure. Yeah. Also, I
forgot that Esthetic is pretty smart, too. He's
like a smart kid, inventor kid. Yeah, really
smart. That may come to hurt Jubilee because she's
notoriously not good at math. She has something
called discalculia, I think, which is not like a
measure of intelligence or anything like that,
but it just means that she has difficulty
processing numbers in her head, kind of similar to
like how a dyslexic has trouble reading.
Interesting. OK. But who cares? Because math's
not going to probably show up in this speculation
at all. Let me go ahead and tell you more about
Jubilee. Jubilee Lee was born in Beverly Hills,
California, to two Chinese American doctors who
had built a comfortable life after immigrating
from Hong Kong. She loved arcade games and
excelled at gymnastics with coaches whispering
about the Olympics. Her world ended, however,
when hired gunmen murdered her parents outside
their home. Orphaned at 13, Jubilee ran from
foster care and turned the giant Hollywood mall
into a secret hideout. She stole food and earned
spare change by shooting bright, sparkling
fireworks from her hands, her newly awakened
mutant power. Mall managers hired the M Squad, a
group of paid to capture mutants. During a chase
through the food court, Jubilee's panic set off a
blinding blast. At the same moment for X-Men,
Storm, Rogue, Silak and Dazzler happened to be
shopping. They drove the hunters off and Jubilee
saw that they were heroes. Their ally, Gateway, a
silent teleporter, opened a portal for the team.
Before it closed, Jubilee secretly slipped
through and found herself at the X-Men's
temporary base in the Australian desert. You can
learn more about the X-Men and their duel against
the Titans. Unsure the famous mutants would trust
a runaway. She hid in tunnels for weeks, sewing
together a bright yellow jacket from Dazzler's
spare clothes. Trouble hit when the Reavers,
brutal cyborg outlaws, stormed the base and
nailed Wolverine to a metal X. Jubilee refused to
leave him. She freed him and stayed by his side,
scavenging water and supplies while his healing
factor did the rest, a rescue that forged the
father and daughter bond that would shape her
life. The Reavers kept hunting so the pair fled to
Madropore, a crime-ridden island in Southeast
Asia. There they battled the Mandarin, who ruled
local gangs with help from the hand, a deadly ninja
clan. Jubilee's fireworks blew a hole in the
Mandarin's fortress and helped free Sylocke from
brainwashing. You can learn more about Wolverine
in his duel against Hawkman and more about Sylocke
in her duel against Gorilla Grodd. News of mutant
slavery pulled the trio to Genosha, an island
nation that forced mutants into hard labor.
Jubilee guided depowered mutants boom-boom and
rictured through patrols until other X-teams
toppled the government. Professor Charles
Xavier, impressed by her courage, invited her to a
school in West Chester, New York. Joining
Cyclops, Beast and Rogue on the X-Men Blue team,
Jubilee helped them fight villains such as
Sauron, the Sentinels, and the Brood. She even
escaped Mojo, a tyrant from another dimension who
showed her an enslaved future version of herself
named Epsissa, a future she swore to avoid. A time
portal later let Jubilee witness the night her
parents died. Armed with the killer's faces, she
tracked them but chose jail over revenge after
Wolverine's advice. Her grief continued though
when her young friend Magic died of the legacy
virus, Magneto ripped metal from Wolverine's
bones, and Sabertooth broke free inside the
mansion. Shaking off the terror, Jubilee fired a
neutralizer gun and knocked Sabertooth out when
the mansion's defenses failed. You can learn more
about Sabertooth in his duel against Killer Croc.
Not long after, Techno Organic Aliens called the
Phalanx captured many senior X-Men. Jubilee
teamed with Banshee, Emma Frost, and even
Sabertooth to rescue the captives and several
young mutants. Realizing she needed peers her own
age, she moved to the Massachusetts Academy to
help form a new school and team called Generation X
under the teachers Banshee and Emma Frost. Her
classmates were Husk, Sink, Monet, Chamber, and
Skin, and their school days mixed Algebra with
combat drills. They fought foes such as
Juggernaut, Omega Red, and Implate, her
classmate Monet's vampiric brother. During the
nationwide Operation Zero Tolerance
Initiative, government agents kidnapped
Jubilee to steal X-Men's secrets. She blasted the
guards while escaping, stopped to give one guard
CPR, was recaptured, and then was freed by a
sympathetic aide. Wolverine brought her home,
but soon after, hacked security codes to let the
enemy raid the X-Mansion. Soon after, she learned
that a businessman named Hunter Braun had
arranged for her parents' death. Jubilee and her
friends tracked him down and she destroyed his
warehouse before police arrested him, finally
giving her closure. Generation X broke apart
after teammate Sink died diffusing a bomb and the
school closed. Jubilee and Skin tried acting in
Los Angeles, but found only stereotypical roles.
Her former teacher Banshee then formed X-Cor, a
mutant police force unit which Jubilee, Husk, and
Monet joined. They stopped riots in Paris,
blinded the giant blob, and stopped a plot by
mystique before the group fell apart. Hate
preachers called the Church of Humanity soon
kidnapped Jubilee, Skin, and others and
crucified them on the X-Men lawn. Angel's healing
blood saved her, but Skin died, deepening her
grief. She moved in with her long-glossed witch
aunt named Hope in Los Angeles, only to learn that
Hope was a secret assassin. A clash with her former
boss leveled the house and Jubilee returned to the
X-Men. Later, the Scarlet Witch warped reality in
an act that erased most of mutant kinds powers,
including Jubilee's. She opened a halfway house
in Queens for depowered mutants, but was badly
hurt when Omega Red attacked it. After healing,
she joined Night Thrasher's tech-based new
warriors. Wearing anti-gravity gauntlets, she
took the name Wundra and helped train her fellow
teammates. Trust broke, though, when Night
Thrasher hid a risky time machine plan. After
casualties and chaos, the new warriors
disbanded. You can learn more about that team in
their duel against Infinity Inc. While leading
friends in San Francisco, Jubilee was turned into
a vampire by Zaris, the son of Dracula, whom you can
learn more about in his duel against Andrew
Bennett. Wolverine rescued her and the X-Men
toppled Zaris, but Jubilee remained undead. She
relied on Wolverine's blood and a mystic pendant
to endure weak sunlight. She trained with a group
of Daywalker vampires who taught her how to
control her vampiric impulses. Teaming with
Wolverine's clone, a former brainwashed killer
called X-23, helped both women manage their
darker urges. You can learn more about X-23 in her
duel against Cassandra Cain Bagrell. On a later
trip to Budapest, Jubilee found an abandoned baby
boy. She named him Shogo and took him to the rebuilt
Jean Grey School for higher learning. Storm
helped Jubilee complete the adoption process.
Headmistress Kitty Pryde, seeing Jubilee's
growth, asked her to mentor a class of misfit
students, Quentin Choir, Bling, Eyeboy, Nature
Girl, Morph, and Tynesite. Her old friend
Chambered co-taught alongside her and their
friendship became romance. Trouble struck when
Monet, merged with her vampire brother and plate,
invaded the school and stole Jubilee's sunlight
pendant. Quentin sacrificed a shard that he had of
the powerful Phoenix Force to save his teacher,
curing Jubilee's vampirism and restoring her
mutant abilities. Professor Xavier then
announced Cracoa, a living island where mutants
could live free. Jubilee and Shogo moved there and
joined Betsy Braddock, Rogue, Gambit, Richter,
and even Apocalypse on a new team called
Excalibur. While exploring other worlds, a magic
realm linked by a portal, fairy energy
temporarily turned Shogo into a dragon. When he
was hurt by enemy soldiers, Jubilee's fireworks
scattered the attackers and she calmed her son as
he healed. You can learn more about other worlds
and the Excalibur team in our Uncle Sam vs. Captain
Britain dual episode. The mutants of Cracoa later
held their first Hellfire Gala, a grand party
meant to show mutant progress. The anti-mutant
group Orcus and the war robot Nimrod attacked them
and Jubilee was killed in the fight. However,
within days she was restored to life on Cracoa via a
combination of other mutants' powers. And that's
Jubilee's history. Powers-wise, Jubilee is a
mutant with the ability to produce explosive
light blasts in the form of multi-colored energy
plasmoids that she refers to and highly resemble
fireworks. She can control their intensity in
terms of brightness and explosive potential,
meaning she can generate the energy bright enough
to blind opponents, which is why she wears big
sunglasses, or powerful enough to blast your face
off at close proximity, just like a firework. And
that's a reminder to be safe out there this year,
kids. Taken to her utmost limit, Jubilee can
manifest a light blast so powerful that it turns
her whole body sparkly and can obliterate a
starship. In addition, for some reason, she has
natural psionic shields that make her slippery to
telepathic detection, possibly developed as a
safeguard from her powers manifesting as a
runaway, but I'm not sure what that has to do with
energy plasmoids. Maybe she has like little
plasmoids running around her brain, distorting
the electrical fields that make her difficult to
detect. But yeah, telepaths have trouble finding
her. Finally, Jubilee is an Olympic-level
gymnast and is an adept hand combatant, having
undergone some fight training with Wolverine.
That's really interesting because Static
actually has telepathic resistance as well, and I
have no idea why. I didn't list it in his power set
because I didn't really think it would factor into
this match, but it's weird that both characters
have that. Yeah, I wasn't even going to mention the
telepathic resistance thing, but she does have
like a number of feats regarding those psionic
shields. Weird. It's something that I actually
learned about the character during the process of
my research for this bio. Well, not that it
matters. Yeah, there's not going to be any
telepathy or math. Maybe some math, maybe a little
bit of math. In a world where fantasies collide and
heroes clash, one podcast network rises above the
rest. Prepare yourself for the ultimate
showdowns in comic books, video games, movies,
and anime. The Dynamite Podcast Network presents
Consol Combat, where video game legends brawl
every Monday. Dynamic Duel, where comic book
titans smash every Tuesday. Max Destruction,
where TV and action heroes battle every
Wednesday. And Sendro World, where anime
champions clash every Thursday. Join us as we
speculate on the matches and armed with the power
of mathematical simulations, discover who will
emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
Now that we've got their histories and abilities
out of the way, let's speculate on how one of the
1000 simulated matches will go. The winner is
determined by simulations, not the speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how this fight could play
out. AJ9K, what are the rules of our speculation?
Well, I should say there are no rules, other than
the characters have no prior knowledge of the
other going into the fight. All they are aware of
starting out is that the other character is a
threat that needs to be eliminated. For the
speculation, the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the match
itself, as no environmental statistics are
considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. Alright
then, let's get into it. Static and Jubilee meet on
the battlefield, who goes first. I'm gonna say
that Static goes first and he'll start off by
hopping onto his saucer and zipping right over
Jubilee, blasting her with electric bolts as he
flies circles around her. Okay, but Jubilee,
she's gonna dodge these blasts, because she's
super agile, so she's doing backhand springs and
flips and stuff to evade his blasts, and while in
midair, she's gonna shoot out a plasmoid blast
that has the light intensity of like a flash bank,
and that's gonna blind Static, and so he can't see
where he's flying on his saucer, and he ends up
crashing it into the ground and just fucking his
shit up. I'm calling BS on dodging electricity,
alright? But sure, let's say she gets lucky and
manages to dodge all of these electric strikes,
but she's definitely not blinding him, because he
wears sunglasses as part of his costume, so he does
crash, actually, but intentionally, into her
real hard. Well, I mean, like, Jubilee's right up
there with like Nightwing and Daredevil in terms
of agility, so like if Nightwing and like Batman
can dodge a hail of bullets, I think it's
reasonable to say that she can dodge Static's
blasts. It's more about anticipating where the
blast is gonna go than, you know, being able to move
faster than a bullet or lightning or something
like that, and in fact, she's so agile when Static
tries to crash into her, Jubilee flips over him,
and she clotheslines him off of his saucer,
knocking him to the ground, and then she unloads a
plasmoid blast at his saucer that's powerful
enough to destroy it, so he can't fly around
anymore. Actually, his saucer is so agile and thin
that it can just dodge her plasmoid blasts, all
right, because even though Static's not on it, he
could still control it via electromagnetism.
It's like a video game for him, and he's gonna zip
that thing all around her fireworks and right into
her, knocking her to the ground as well. Well, I
mean, if it's coming at her, you know, if she missed
blasting it earlier, she's not gonna miss as it's
approaching her, because she's gonna throw her
hands up and unload a fireworks display all around
in like a 15 foot radius, and that is definitely
gonna destroy the saucer. Sure, fine, but Static
himself is protected from the fireworks since
he's gonna throw up this electromagnetic force
field around him, and once the fireworks are over,
that's when Static puts on his own show with this
rapid fire homing chain lightning that there's no
way Jubilee is going to dodge. So she gets shocked
real hard and repeatedly. She doesn't need to
dodge it because she can still fight energy with
energy, so she just blocks the lightning with
counter blasts from her plasmoids, because
essentially lightning energy is plasma anyway,
so yeah, counter. That's fair. Does Jubilee need
her hands to emit plasmoids? Like, does it come
from her hands? No, not strictly. Like, she can
fire plasmoids from her hands, or she could do
things like create fireworks around herself
without hand direction. Okay, well, you know,
Static can create static fields that make things
like magnetically attract and stick to each
other, so I was gonna have him stick her hands to her
sides, but we'll say instead that he causes her
head to magnetically attract to the floor, so she
just drops straight down and that's going to
interrupt her counter blasts to his electricity,
and so she for sure gets zapped. How does he
magnetize something like a head, which is
non-magnetic, and make it attract to the ground,
which is also non-magnetic? Like, that doesn't
make any sense. He basically just has a sticky
power. Sort of. Well, anything with electrons can
be magnetized, and that's one of his powers. He can
magnetize things that can't typically be
magnetized. Like, he wants magnetized a guy's
head so that all these guns were attracted to it,
essentially. But yeah, so it's like a sticky,
attractive power, and Jubilee just eats the
floor. Okay, so she may be stuck and trapped on the
ground, but that's not going to matter because
Jubilee can approach nuclear level with her
blasts. Okay, so from the ground, she's just going
to emit this fireworks show blasts that has like
the energy of like 10 combined firework finales,
like at a firework show. Just, it's just
explosions and colors everywhere that
completely engulf static, just vaporizing him
with all that destructive might. Now, I'm
guessing this is like 10 combined, like, little
league firework shows, right? No, this is like 10
combined, like, Disneyland level finale
firework shows. Okay. Well, I mean, as this is
going on, though, Static's just going to surround
himself with the force field once again. And he's
going to run up to her really quick as she's pinned
to the ground. And he's going to Taser touch her,
which is going to overload her nervous system with
electricity that's going to cause her to stop with
the fireworks and just become paralyzed instead.
So the match is over. No, no, no, if he gets close
enough for a Taser touch, that means he's like,
well within proximity for Jubilee to just
manifest an explosive plasmoid inside his force
field. There doesn't have to be a direct line of
sight there. Like, Wolverine once told her that
she could blow up people's heads from the inside if
she wanted to. And in this instance, yeah, she
wants to. So she pops off Static's head in the final
fireworks display and then it like manifests into
the sparkly design that says, I beat you in
fireworks letters. What? Okay, so you're telling
me that Jubilee can get through Magneto's force
field? Is that what you're telling me? Like this
whole time, all the X-Men needed to defeat Magneto
was fucking Jubilee? No, I would say that Static is
not at the level of Magneto. So no, she couldn't get
through Magneto's force field, but she could get
through Static's for sure. That's dumb. That's
dumb. Let's end it here. Let's take it to the stats.
Either Jubilee gets tased to the point of
paralysis or Jubilee essentially turns Static's
head into a firework. Let's go ahead and input the
character stats, run the simulations and find out
which of those two scenarios is more likely to
happen. A.J .9K, hit it! Inputting data, running
calculations, processing results, simulations
complete. All right, well, hopefully
everybody's Fourth of July is just as spectacular
and colorful as this speculation was. And ours
impressive as Static's stats were, because he
dominated Jubilee in so many categories,
including speed, evasiveness, strength since he
could lift things with electromagnetism,
intellect, and versatility. Don't forget
perception, because he can listen to radio waves
with his powers. Right. Yeah, we said he was more
evasive because he has his force field, he's
faster because he can fly, but we did say that
Jubilee has greater damage potential than Static
does. And she's a better fighter, having received
more training. Is that going to be enough to take
this match? Maybe not, but also, yes. That makes
literally no sense. Well, according to our
Instagram followers, 72% of them also disagree
with me, saying that Static would win. Well, let's
find out if that's the case. Adj9k, the results,
please. Hey, you are, sir. The winner of the
matchup between Static and Jubilee is Static. Of
course, Static. This was not even close. He won
83.8% of the 1000 matches or 838 of the 1000
battles, with Jubilee only winning 162 or 16.2%.
This was a terrible match. Well, the real question
is who could win in a fight between these two
characters in a video game battle? Like if they
picked up their controllers, I'm guessing
Jubilee would kick Static's ass. No, Static has a
degree of technopathy, so she would still lose.
No, powers aren't allowed in this video game
tournament. Says who? Says me. I'm saying who's
objectively better at video games. Jubilee is. I
mean, personality-wise, I think the two are
fairly similar when it comes to how geeky they are.
So a video game tournament would probably be
closer than the results of this match were. And
that's what matters. And that's what matters.
Hey, whatever helps you sleep at night. But that
does it for this duel. Adj9k help close us out.
Thanks for listening to Dynamic Joule. Visit the
show's website at dynamicjoule.com and follow us
on Instagram at Dynamic Joule podcast. You can
support the show on Patreon at patreon.com slash
dynamicjoule and joining a tier that works for
you, or by rating and reviewing Dynamic Joule on
Apple Podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser, or on our
website. Don't forget to listen to the other shows
in the Dynamite podcast network, including Max
Destruction, Senjo World, and Console Combat. In
our next episode, we will be reviewing season one
of the Iron Heart Marvel television series. I
watched the first three episodes already. I'm
really looking forward to the last three
episodes, though. Yeah, I haven't started the
show yet. I have been rewatching Sandman season
one and lead up to Sandman season two, which starts
this week. But yeah, I'll eventually get to Iron
Heart. That does it for this episode. We want to
give a big thanks to our executive producers, John
Sturrosky, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Belcom,
Mickey Muthagian, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yatyn,
Austin Wizalowski, Andrew Dunkerly, Nick
Obanto, Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Spees,
Dean Molesky, Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, Josh
Schleiner, Mike Williams, Oscar Galvez, and Paul
Graves for helping make this podcast possible.
We'll talk to you guys next week. Up, up, and away,
true believers. Do you ever feel like a plastic bag
drifting through the wind, wanting to start
again? You just got to ignite the light and let it
shine. Just own the night like the fourth of July.
Cause baby, you're a firework. Come on, let your
colors burst. Make them go, oh, oh, oh, you're
going to leave them all in awe. Oh, oh.