This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi and welcome
to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters and stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe and I'm his twin
brother Johnny DC. And guys, there are only three
episodes left of this podcast in its weekly
format. We're semi-retiring in mid-January as we
turn 40. We've been doing this podcast for 10 years
now and we're coming up to the end here. This will be
our last Brothers Award episode as well as the last
episode of 2025, which is wild. This year went by so
quick. It's ridiculous. I remember the 2024
Brothers Award episode like it was yesterday.
It's getting crazy. If you guys have never
listened to a Brothers Award episode before, it's
basically the best of what Marvel and DC put out in
terms of television and film over the year. The
Brothers Awards are named after the cosmic DC and
Marvel entities that were in the 1996 DC versus
Marvel crossover series. Right. In fact, those
figures are on our award images that we post to
Instagram as like Oscar statues. This is our
Oscars, but it's better than the Oscars. It's way
better than the Oscars, man. First of all, our
awards actually mean something. It's not just a
popularity contest. I haven't trusted the Oscars
since they snubbed the Dark Knight. Never forgive
them for that. I never forgive the Oscars for not
giving Black Panther the award for best picture.
Anyway, we're not going to be going over the comic
book movie news this episode because Jonathan and
I are recording this episode earlier, so we don't
have a good handle on what the current news is. But
also, I'm hoping that Marvel is going to release
the full set of Doomsday trailers online so that
everybody can watch them as they're meant to be
seen and not just like the leaked versions. Who
knows? Maybe by the time this episode drops, that
will be the case. But if it is, we're not talking
about it until 2026. Right. This episode is just
going to be All Brothers Awards. But before that,
our artificially intelligent duel simulator,
AJ9K, has a quick message for our listeners. So
listen up. Hello. These are the final episodes of
Dynamic Duel's weekly podcast, leading up to our
grand finale on January 20th. We hope you've
enjoyed the past 10 years of Marvel and DC duels and
reviews, and we'd love for you to stick with us as we
count down these last episodes. We're inviting
you, the listener, to help us close out the show by
visiting dynamicjule.com over the next few weeks
and clicking the red microphone button in the
bottom right corner to leave us a voicemail that
we'll play during the final episode. Tell us what
first got you into DC or Marvel, how long you've
been listening, a favorite episode or moment, or
anything else you want to share about what the
podcast has meant to you. Your messages will be
aired and responded to on the January 20th finale.
Again, head to dynamicduel.com and leave your
final message. We would love to hear from you. Pip
pip cheerio. Thanks AJ9K, and thanks to everyone
who takes the time to call in and leave us a
voicemail. Be sure to tune in to the other shows in
the DynaMic Podcast Network this week, including
the Konsole Kombat podcast where hosts John and
Dean simulate battles between popular video game
characters. In yesterday's episode, they
reviewed with Matt, Halo Legends. Over on the Max
Destruction podcast, hosts Scotty and Gilly pay
your favorite action heroes from film and
television against each other. The Macho Twins
are off this week, but look forward to their next
episode in the new year. On the Senjoh World
podcast, host Zachary Hepburn speculates on
fights between fan favorite anime and manga
characters. In January, Zach is revealing who
would win between Shigeo Kagayama, aka Mob from
Mob Psycho 100, and Tatsumaki the tornado of
terror from One Punch Man. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our show
notes to listen to all of the shows in the DynaMic
Podcast Network. But now that that's done, let's
go ahead and set the stage. We got the blue carpet
rolled out. I'm sick of the carpets. We can never
decide whether it's blue or red. You know what?
Marvel doesn't need theirs this year because our
nominees are parachuting in in style with red
parachutes. Okay, well if that's the case, the DC
nominees are just gonna teleport into their seats
in a puff of electric blue smoke with sparkles.
Magic. Like Nightcrawler? Yeah, except it
doesn't smell like farts. This is stupid. Anyway,
the nominees are making their way to the
auditorium. Let's go ahead and get into our 2025
Best of Marvel and DC Brothers Awards. All right,
everyone. Welcome to the 2025 Brothers Awards,
where we countdown the best that Marvel and DC had
to offer in the realm of television and film.
Johnny DC and myself are here on the stage hosting
you this evening. Gotta say you're looking sharp.
And you're looking a little blunt. I take it back.
Let's go ahead and start off by breaking down what
was eligible for an award in the year 2025. Spoiler
warning, for anyone who has not seen any of these
projects, we will be potentially spoiling any one
of these in the course of our award ceremony. For DC
in television this year, we had Creature
Commandos season one, Harley Quinn season five,
The Sandman season two, Peacemaker season two,
and Batman season one. And on the big and small
screens, we saw Batman Ninja versus Yakuza
League, Superman, and Aztec Batman Clash of
Empires. Gotta say that's a pretty lackluster
list overall when compared to the Marvel list. Let
me tell you what was eligible for Marvel. In 2025,
we had your friendly neighborhood Spider-Man
season one, Daredevil born again season one, Iron
Heart season one, Eyes of Wakanda season one, and
Marvel Zombies season one. In theaters, we had
Captain America Brave New World, Thunderbolts,
and the Fantastic Four first steps. I don't know
how you're going to bash DC's output. We're all by
two things on your list that you just read was pure
trash. Trash recognized trash is what I'm going to
say. Hey, I'm classy. Anyway, let's go ahead and
get into our very first award for the evening,
which will be the best trailer. Now, I don't know if
a lot of people pay attention to trailers, but
Jonathan and I like watching them. We definitely
like getting a taste of what's to come,
speculating on what the trailers show us and
getting hyped in general. Yeah, actually, by
profession, Joseph and I are both marketers, and
it's really interesting to see how studios try and
sell general audiences on the films that they're
putting out. To that end, I chose four nominees for
this award based on how well they did at selling me
and getting me excited on seeing the project.
Same. And the DC nominees for best trailer of 2025
are Peacemaker season two official trailer.
There's another dimension. It's exactly the same
as ours. But better. Best dimension ever. The
Sandman season two date announcement. A king will
forsake his kingdom. The oldest battle begins
once more. Supergirl official teaser trailer. He
sees the good in everyone and I see the truth.
Superman official trailer. I would question
myself in the same situation and consider the
consequences. People were going to die. Okay, if I
had to guess among those list of nominees, I'm not
going to say that the winner is Supergirl or
Peacemaker. I think it's going to be either the
Superman trailer or Sandman. I think you're going
to go with Sandman on this. And the winner is
Superman official trailer. Damn it. The Sandman
trailer was incredible. And I had a really hard
time choosing between that and Superman.
Ultimately, I went with Superman because I feel
like we got our first really good look at how David
Corrin set was going to portray the character of
Clark Kent and Superman really. But also a taste of
the story that we were going to get as well. To hear
the dialogue and see some of the performances
really sold me on the movie. And it got me super
excited for this new universe that James Gunn was
going to unveil. Yeah, it wasn't the first
Superman trailer. I think actually the first one
came out last year in 2024 and also got your
brother's award for best trailer. So you're just
really gunk-ho for Superman when it comes to
trailers. I am doubling down. Yes, I really liked
the movie and I thought they did a really good job
selling the movie as well. Well, audience be
prepared for most of these awards to be going to the
Superman movie. Bitch, you don't know my life.
What else is the award going to go to? Really think
about it. Anyway, let's move on to the Marvel
Award. The nominees for best Marvel trailer in
2025 are Daredevil born again official trailer. I
was also raised to believe in retribution. The
Fantastic Four first steps official trailer. Are
you the protectors of this world? Yes, we are. Your
planet is now marked for death. Marvel Zombies
official trailer. Shit. Thunderbolts final
trailer. No one here is a hero. You all have things
that we regret. But I have so many. Oh, those are
some good choices. The Marvel Zombies trailer was
super metal. I don't think they would get the win,
though. I'm going to say you're probably going to
choose Fantastic Four first steps, largely for
the same reason that I went with Superman in that
you were able to glimpse for the first time this
new-ish sort of world since the Fantastic Four
took place in an alternate universe from the MCU.
And the winner is the Fantastic Four first steps
official trailer. Yes! For exactly the reason
that you said basically, you know, with
Daredevil, we had a good feeling, especially
after the reshoots that the series was going to be
true in keeping with the Netflix show. And it was.
So that was a great trailer. Marvel Zombies was
again so metal. It was probably the most fun I had
watching a trailer in years. And the Thunderbolts
final trailer was not the best trailer that we got
for that film that actually came out in 2024. But
the Fantastic Four first steps official trailer
introduced us to this whole new world, very
stylish, very sleek, very Jack Kirby-esque. And I
was on board. Like, I saw that and I immediately
fell in love with this new universe that the film
was taking place in. I read you. I read you. You got
your guess right. I got my guess wrong. Let's not
talk about it. Let's move on to the next award. So
the next award is Best Original Music. Now, when it
comes to original scores and songs for these
Marvel and DC films, good music should do a lot of
heavy lifting emotionally as you're watching
what's unfolding on the screen. As I've said
before, the way I define a good score is one that I
don't necessarily notice as I'm watching the
film, but still moves me. Right. Movies and shows
are not just visual experiences. They are
auditory. And so I always really like doing this
award because superhero movies have such unique,
epic and interesting music out of all the other
genres out there. The nominees for Best Marvel
Original Music in 2025 are Eyes of Wakanda, Season
1. The Fantastic Four, First Steps.
Thunderbolts. Your friendly neighborhood
Spider-Man, Season 1. Spider-Man, The Final
Fantasy. Okay, another tough call here. I love all
of these scores, but if I had to guess, your vibe
would naturally be drawn to your friendly
neighborhood Spider-Man's music. And the winner
is The Fantastic Four, First Steps. Whoa, that was
way off. You know what? The friendly neighborhood
Spider-Man, Season 1 soundtrack was top tier.
This was one of the hardest years ever when it came
to music because all four of these nominees
fucking crushed it. We didn't review your
friendly neighborhood Spider-Man, Season 1, but
the show was really well done. Thunderbolts, a
very emotional score. Eyes of Wakanda, just
fucking incredible. That show was awesome, at
least visually and auditorily, if not
story-wise. I didn't love the stories for Eyes of
Wakanda. They were okay. Mostly about the War
Dogs. Like the history of the War Dogs. We got to
learn the origin of that pickaxe weapon that
Kilmogger found in the museum and stuff like that.
But the Fantastic Four, First Steps score written
by Michael Guccino was almost unlike anything I'd
ever heard before. In that he perfectly managed to
capture the artistic direction. It was kind of
like retro, futuristic, kind of Jetson style, but
very catchy. And also very epic when it came to
things like the Galactus and Silver Surfer
themes. It was nothing short of fantastic. Yeah,
he definitely nailed both the era and the niche
genre of the film. For sure. Michael Guccino has
done other Marvel works like The Doctor Strange
Movie, Spider-Man Homecoming Trilogy, and of
course he directed Werewolf by Night. He's just
kind of like a master at finding these like perfect
little vignettes for the style of each franchise.
Nice. Good choice. Good choice. Great nominees.
But now let's move to DC. The DC nominees for best
original music of 2025 are Aztec Batman, Clash of
Clans. Batman Ninja vs Yakuza League. The Sandman
Season 2. Superman. Batman Ninja vs Yakuza
League. That is all incredible music as well. I
think though you're going to give it to Sandman
Season 2 because it allegedly has the greatest
song of all time sung by Orpheus to Hades and
Persephone. And the winner is the Sandman Season
2. And you are correct. This was a tough one this
year. I think like your Isabel Kanda score, Aztec
Batman kind of perfectly captured the cultural
sounds. And the Superman score was a great update
of the John Williams score from the 70s. I did
really want to give this award to Batman Ninja vs
Yakuza League just because of how wacky that score
was and how fun it was. Ultimately though, I could
not give it to the Sandman Season 2. Not only is just
the theme of that song really haunting and good,
but the music from this season in particular
played such an important and critical role within
the story. Like you mentioned, the song of
Orpheus. And at the very end of the show, they
played this song that was a poem from The Fates at
the end of the comic. Hearing that in song form was
such a cathartic moment to happen at the end of that
series. It was very special and that's why it gets
my award this year. Yeah, kudos to the Sandman
Season 2 for putting 110% effort into the music
that was featured on that season. Really well
deserved. Orpheus's song, Holy Cow. Like The
Fates, I also will never forgive Orpheus for
making me weep during that song. You have to be a
machine not to cry. But let's go ahead and move on to
our next award, which is Best New On Screen
Character in 2025. Now one of the best things about
being a Marvel and DC fan, seeing these works
adapted on the screen, is that we get to witness the
manifestation of a lot of characters we love from
the comics in live action. Sometimes animated.
Yeah, there's been so many comic book films to have
come out in these past 20 years that I'm always
interested to see like which new characters are
being adapted. And there were a lot of fun ones this
year for both DC and Marvel, I feel. The nominees
for the Best New On Screen Character of 2025 for DC
are The Bride from Creature Commandos Season 1.
Daniel Hall from The Sandman Season 2. Crypto from
Superman. Mr. Terrific from Superman. Alright,
it's definitely not going to be crypto. I think
it's a toss up between The Bride and Mr. Terrific.
And I think personally, I just really loved how
badass The Bride was from Creature Commandos. So
that's who I think you're going to give it to. And
the winner is The Bride from Creature Commandos
Season 1. Alright, count it. My streak starts now.
So I really liked Mr. Terrific from Superman. He
almost got this award. But ultimately, I felt that
The Bride really stole the show for me in Creature
Commandos Season 1. My favorite book is
Frankenstein. And I thought I was going to like his
character the most in that show. But the episode
that delved into The Bride's origin, I think was
such a perfect origin for the character and really
delved into why she is the way she is. And honestly,
I can't wait to see more from her in the DC universe.
She basically made that show and it was a great
show. I agree. I also thought I would like
Frankenstein more, but he turned out to be so
detestable. And The Bride was so fucking cool.
Such a badass. Well deserved, let's go ahead and
move into the Marvel Award. The nominees for the
best new on-screen Marvel character in 2025 are
Galactus from The Fantastic Four First Steps. I
was once little like you billions of years ago. A
man from another world. The Hood from Iron Heart
Season 1. I knew that if I wanted you dead, I'd have
to be the one to do it. I did not come here to play with
you Parker. You came here to work. Red Hulk from
Captain America Brave New World. Since when were
they red? Century from Thunderbolts. Introduced
to you the Century. Hey guys. Wow. That's cool. All
powerful. I feel like it's either going to come
down to the Century or Galactus, but I gotta go with
Galactus. That's my guess. And the winner is
Century from Thunderbolts. How could you not go
with Galactus? Well, at least it was a portrait as a
cloud this go around, right? In the end, the
visuals for Galactus were stunning, but I just
don't think you got quite enough screen time to
warrant the best new on-screen character. I
really love what they did with the Century, with
Lewis Pullman's acting and the way they adapted
his origin story from his comic book origin. I
thought it was brilliantly done and told a really
interesting story. That's fair. I kind of felt
going in that the Century was going to be a hard
character to adapt because he's so unique, but
yeah, they did a fantastic job adapting him. They
kind of made it look easy, right? Jerks. Yeah, I
love how powerful they made the character. I love
how they interpreted his dark side, the void. Just
yeah, all around stellar job. But let's go ahead
and move on to our next award category, best
villain. In my opinion, a lot of comic book films
are only as good as their villain because as I've
noticed in a lot of projects, the better the
villain, the better I tend to feel about the story.
For sure, yeah, because they deliver the stakes
that are required of the hero to surpass and make
the story interesting. The neat thing about comic
book movies and shows, due to the nature of their
fairly black and white portrayals of morality and
justice, you get a lot of really fucking evil
characters as villains. Just dudes that you love
to hate. Let's go ahead and list them out. The
nominees for best Marvel villain in 2025 are
Galactus from the Fantastic Four first steps. I
will meet your planet slowly while your child
watches. Kingpin from Daredevil, born again,
season one. The rule of law will prevail. And
should you go back to any of your old activities,
there will be consequences. The hood from Iron
Heart, season one. Stay and I'll kill you. Talk to
the cops. Knowledge. The void from Thunderbolts.
The most shameful thing of all was thinking you
could be anything more than nothing. Okay, tough
call, tough call. My guess is either going to come
down to the void or Galactus, but I'm going to go
with Galactus again. That's my guess. And the
winner is Galactus from the Fantastic Four first
steps. And it's because he wasn't a clown. I just
think in terms of threat level, like you saw him
destroy an entire planet in the Fantastic Four
movie. And he was also really menacing when he was
like, I'm going to devour your entire world and
steal your baby. The fact that he wasn't even
tricked by the Fantastic Four's plan at the end and
they had to kind of like improvise to even defeat
him, I thought made him a great villain. There was a
little bit of a power scaling issue in that final
fight with Sue, but you know, she ended up dying. So
Galactus even has that going for him as far as a
villain goes. Galactus is one of those characters
where he felt like it was going to be really hard to
adapt the character to screen in a way that didn't
make people laugh and chuckle because he just
looks so weird and Kirby-esque. You know, it's
obviously why they didn't go that route in the old
Fantastic Four films, but the fact that Marvel had
the balls to do it correctly for this film, I have to
commend because it was super effective. I was
afraid of Galactus, maybe for the first time in my
entire life. Good. Keep it that way. Okay. Moving
on to the DC side. The nominees for best DC villain
of 2025 are the Kindly Ones from Sandman from
Batman Ninja vs. Yakuza League. Lena Luther from
Harley Quinn Season 5. I don't want to play with
your toys. I want to destroy them like you always
destroyed me, making me feel lesser an
afterthought. Lex Luthor from Superman. It is
what has driven me to annihilating you. What a,
what a, what a, what a, what a. Geez, I think it's
really going to come down to the Kindly Ones or Lex
Luthor. I think I got to go with the Kindly Ones
though because they literally killed the God.
That's my guess. The winner is Lex Luthor from
Superman. Really, it came down to Lex or Lena for
me. We didn't review Harley Quinn Season 5, but
Lena Luther is probably the best villain that that
series has had. Hey Lena, you're a bitch.
Ultimately though, I gave it to Lex Luthor because
I thought Nicholas Holt gave the most comic,
accurate portrayal of Lex Luthor that we've seen
on screen to date. He was a genius. He was an angry,
envious genius to boot, and I'm really happy with
the direction they took the character for this new
universe. And it was cool to see him again in the
Peacemaker show. Yeah, just orchestrating shit
from behind the scenes. That's what Lex Luthor
needs to be. Well, let's go ahead and move on to the
flip side of this award, Best Hero of 2025. Why do we
award the best heroes in film and television?
Because they deserve to be awarded. This is a
fucking comic book podcast. Yeah, I was gonna say
because they deserve to be rewarded for their
virtues of sacrifice, nobility, and bravery. Oh
yeah, that too. Yeah, heroism is defined by
sacrifice and selflessness. These are really
awesome traits that humanity has admired since
they first started telling stories. Marvel and DC
have some of the most iconic heroes from the past
century, so let's celebrate them. The nominees
for best DC hero of 2025 are Batman from Batman
Ninja vs. Yakuza League. This is the pain of all the
people you're watching. I'm killing you because
you took the life of the only friend I have and the
only one of us with an out... Mr. Terrific from
Superman. Get him someplace safe. Take the
T-Craft. The controls are easy and intuitive. I
need to stay back here and make sure the portal is
secure. Superman from Superman. I don't know how
else to find him. It's a dog. Yeah, and he's not even
a very good one, but he's out there alone and he's
probably scared. Gee, let me think. Could it be
Superman from Superman? And the winner is Batman
from Batman Ninja vs. Yakuza League. Why are you
lying? I'm not lying. That's who I gave the award
to. Superman, of course, was very heroic in the
Superman movie. He saved Metropolis, but equally
just as impressive, Batman saved Gotham from the
Yakuza League. And the way he went about it,
helping to defeat each member of the Justice
League, including Rassal Ghul, I think
ultimately it was just a much cooler and much more
impressive feat, so he got the win. Yeah, it was
pretty cool. I mean, he utilized a lot of the Bat
family to help him out, but that's who Batman is.
It's just kind of fascinating to see Batman go up
against these much more powerful people, and
especially in this case when the rest of them are
all alternate evil versions of themselves. And
that's why he got the win. I think it'll surprise a
lot of people with that award, but I don't
necessarily think you're wrong. Let's move on to
the Marvel side. The nominees for best Marvel hero
of 2025 are Captain America from Captain America
Brave New World. But when showing there's more to
you, it's not about when times are easy. It's about
moments like this. Daredevil from Daredevil,
born again, season one. But this is our city, not
his. And we can't take it back. Invisible Woman
from the Fantastic Four first steps. I will not
sacrifice my child for this world. But I will not
sacrifice this world for my child. Yelena Belova
from Thunderbolts. What I said to you before was
wrong, but you can't stuff it down. Okay,
personally for me, I think there's a clear
standout amongst these heroes, and I gotta say
that is Invisible Woman from Fantastic Four First
Steps. And the winner is Invisible Woman from the
Fantastic Four First Steps. Makes sense, right? I
mean, she did make the ultimate sacrifice within
that film, and a fucking broke my heart in that
scene. She gave literally everything she had to
save her son. And you know, a lot of people might
count her as being a little bit more selfish and
that she didn't want to sacrifice her son for the
sake of the entire planet, which is really the
utilitarian approach. She kind of took on the
Steve Rogers philosophy of we don't trade lives.
She knew that her family would find a solution to
really protect everybody. Oh yeah, totally. I
mean, as I was watching the movie, I was like, you
kind of gotta make the trade, right? Until she gave
her reasoning that, hey, I'm not going to give up my
baby, but I'm also not going to give up all of you
guys. I'm not going to give up the entire planet for
my baby. Right. The sacrifice she made at the end,
like you said, is the ultimate act of heroism. So
yeah, this is an easy win for her. Which is not to
discount the others. It's just that, you know,
like, I think Sam Wilson's arc in Brave New World
was kind of a rehash and also better represented in
the Falcon and the Winter Soldier TV series.
Daredevil, of course, was always great. Yelena
Bolova was a standout on Thunderbolts. I just
don't think that they compared to Invisible Woman
in terms of pure heroism. I agree. Well, moving on
to our next award category, that is for best
moment. Now for a lot of people, the main reason why
they enjoy comic book films is escapism. And with
escapism, it's really easy to lose yourself in a
film when it comes to really intense or really
funny or really action packed moments, which the
comic book genre delivers in spades many times.
It's one of the reasons why the comic book genre is
so successful in theaters as a whole. Of course,
we're seeing diminishing returns on that. But
yeah, there's a lot to enjoy about these films in
terms of spectacle and emotion. Let's break down
the best Marvel moments. The nominees for best
Marvel moment of 2025 are Celestial Island
Dogfight from Captain America, Brave New World.
Daredevil vs Bullseye from Daredevil Born Again
Season 1. Inside the Void from Thunderbolts. Sue
fights Galactus from The Fantastic Four First
Steps. Okay another clear standout winner for me
personally, I would have to say Inside the Void.
That's my guess. And the winner is Daredevil vs
Bullseye from Daredevil Born Again Season 1.
What? I thought we got such a better version of that
in past seasons of Daredevil. No, actually I think
the Daredevil vs Bullseye fight scene was the best
version of that fight that we've gotten in this
series. And it literally delivered on every
possible angle from the action to the spectacle to
the emotion. It was fucking devastating. Like,
Sue dying while fighting Galactus was
heartbreaking. But also, Foggy Nelson dying was
heartbreaking as Daredevil heard his heart stop
at the end and then he threw Bullseye off the
building and it was emotionally devastating. I
remember watching that first episode and just
being like, how the fuck are they gonna top this
because that was the legitimately perfect scene.
I guess it was cool to see the two go at it in costume
for the first time. And it was done in that now
iconic hallway fight style for the Daredevil
series. The body count alone was massive just in
that fight and it really tore the protagonist
completely apart. It was incredible. It probably
was the best scene of the entire show. Right. And I
guess that's why you gave it the award for best
moment. There you go. Okay, well moving on to DC.
The nominees for the best DC moments of 2025 are
Batman vs Kuraku from Batman Ninja vs Yakuza
League. Die! Just as expected. EarthX reveal from
Peacemaker Season 2. Fuck me. This is your perfect
world, huh? Mr. Terrific vs Lux's army from
Superman. I am giving you one last chance to start.
I was just about to say the same to you. Superman vs
Planet Watch from Superman. Kill him! Good luck
with that. These were all fantastic moments.
Geez, that's really tough. Because the Batman vs
Superman fight in the Yakuza League movie was
probably among the best that's ever been done. But
I think it's going to go to either the Mr. Terrific
scene or Superman vs Planet Watch. I'm going to go
with Superman vs Planet Watch as my guess. The
winner is Superman vs Planet Watch from Superman.
You got it. I mean, it was probably among the best
displays of Superman's abilities that we've ever
seen on screen. It was like emotional and happy. Oh
yeah, the music during this scene and just
watching Superman unload on an entire army of
flying soldiers in a way that we've never really
been able to see him do before in a city alongside
crypto. It was just magical. It was heartwarming.
I had all the feels. My arms were raised just from
the thrill of it and the theater. It was awesome. It
was amazing how he was able to fight those guys
without completely destroying the entire city
and killing millions of people. Yeah? You're
saying that to me or Zack Snyder? Zack Snyder!
Yeah, it's a fair criticism. I'm going to go with
the best. Prepare yourself for the ultimate
showdowns in comic books, video games, movies,
and anime. The Dynamite Podcast Network presents
Console Combat, where video game legends brawl
every Monday. Dynamic Duel, where comic book
titans smash every Tuesday. Max Destruction,
where TV and action heroes battle every
Wednesday. And Sendro World, where anime
champions clash every Thursday. Join us as we
speculate on the matches and armed with the power
of mathematical simulations discover who will
emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
But now let's move on to our next award category,
which is Best Actress of 2025. It gets harder and
harder every year to describe these categories in
a way that isn't over-reductive. Best Actress
Award, I think you guys all know what this means.
Yeah, often in comics, women were relegated to
sort of damsels in distress. I think as time has
gone on, comic books and filmmakers have tried to
move away from that. And of course, have been
giving women a lot of strong roles, which I think is
proudly displayed in the nominees this year. The
nominees for the best DC actress of 2025 are
Danielle Brooks as Leota Adebayo from Peacemaker
Season 2. I believe in miracles because of you. I
saw an eagle hug a human. I know who I am because of
you. Jenna Coleman as Johanna Constantine from
The Sandman Season 2. This is the head of Orpheus,
whose song was powerful enough to sway even the
hearts of Hades and Persephone. Jennifer Holland
as Emilia Harcourt from Peacemaker Season 2.
Rachel Brosnahan as Lois Lane from Superman. All
these ladies gave strong performances, but for
some reason I want to say Jennifer Harcourt from
Peacemaker. That's my guess. The winner is Rachel
Brosnahan as Lois Lane from Superman. Well, maybe
I should have given it more thought. I loved Rachel
Brosnahan as Lois Lane. I figured, even from her
casting announcement, that she was going to be the
best Lois Lane to date, and I was not wrong. She
totally pulled off the spunk and the charm and just
the love for the character of Superman that no
other actress has been able to do as well to date. It
kind of seemed like she was plucked right out of the
Superman cartoon, which I think was probably one
of the strongest depictions of the character in
modern times. Oh yeah, I totally agree. The fact
that she was able to help expose Lex Luthor the
villain, she really dealt him a major blow in that
film. Let's go ahead and move on to the Marvel side.
The nominees for Best Marvel Actress of 2025 are
Dominique Thorne as Ironheart in Ironheart
Season 1. Florence Pugh as Yelena Belova in
Thunderbolts. Julia Louis-Dreyfus as Contessa
Valentina Allegra da Fontaine in Thunderbolts.
Vanessa Kirby as Invisible Woman in The Fantastic
Four First Steps. I personally would go with Julia
Louis-Dreyfus. I thought she had a standout
performance. I'm actually surprised she was on
your list for Best Villains of the Year, and I think
partially because of that you're going to give her
the win here. And the winner is Vanessa Kirby as
Invisible Woman in The Fantastic Four First
Steps. Well shit. Well much the same reason you
gave your award to Rachel Brosnihan for
exemplifying the character of Lois Lane in the
Superman movie. I'm giving it to Vanessa Kirby for
exemplifying the character of Susan Storm in The
Fantastic Four movie. Never before in all the
other iterations of Sue Storm in the other movies
have we seen this type of very grounded, very
motherly character as we saw in First Steps. Okay,
yeah I could buy that. It was a fantastic
performance. And she had a lot to do with the role I
think. Not only did she believably serve as the
glue that holds the team together, she also
believably fought and sacrificed herself for her
kid. And I think she brought a lot of chemistry to
her role with Pedro Pascal. Vanessa Kirby just
nailed it, she crushed it. Yeah, sold, you're
right. We're moving on to our next category, Best
Actor. It's basically the same award as our last
category except these are the dudes. The
genitalia is different but the award is the same.
Exactly. There of course have been tons of great DC
and Marvel actors throughout the years. That
doesn't make the job any easier though because
these guys have to be in peak shape, they have to be
strong and charming for the most part. Yeah they
have to not only be good thespians, they have to be
stuntmen as well. Lesbians? Let's break down the
nominees. The nominees for Best Marvel Actor are
Anthony Ramos as the hood in Iron Heart Season 1. So
why are you here? I had to look you in the eye and ask
what kind of father puts his son out of the house at
12? Charlie Cox as Daredevil in Daredevil, born
again, Season 1. It occurs to me that justice will
not be served today. It won't be served because
whatever sentence is passed, foggy Nelson. We'll
still be dead. Lewis Pullman as Century in
Thunderbolts. Just like the rest of them. I'm not
afraid of you Robert. It's not Robert, you need to
be free of him. Pedro Pascal as Mr. Fantastic in The
Fantastic Four First Steps. L is the load, R is the
lever arm connected to the load, Archimedes the
law of levers. Give me a lever and a place to stand
and I will move the earth. For me, this is a toss up
either between Lewis Pullman or Pedro Pascal. But
I got to say, I think I was more surprised by Lewis
Pullman's performance and how good that was. So
he's my guess. And the winner is Lewis Pullman as
Century in Thunderbolts. Noice, nailed it. Yeah,
I was totally unsure about Lewis Pullman when he
was cast and replaced Stephen Yon as Bob in the
Thunderbolts movie. The dude fucking nailed it
though. He pulled off the psychosis, the
vulnerability, the threat that the character
posed in such a deep, emotional and convincing
way. I had to give it to the guy. It was a complex
role. Oh for sure. And honestly, I'm not sure how
Stephen Yon or literally any other actor could
have pulled it off as well as Lewis Pullman. I'm
sure he could have. But at that point, Stephen Yon
probably would have won this award. It's next to be
him, as I mentioned in our review of the movie.
Probably. But let's move on to the DC side. The
nominees for best DC actor of 2025 are David Corn
Sweat as Superman in Superman. That is being
human. And that's my greatest strength. And
someday, I hope for the sake of the world, you
understand that. David Harbour as Frankenstein
in Creature Commandos season one. That would
bring balance to life, they would say. No one would
say that. I would say that. I want. Am I not someone?
John Cena as Peacemaker in Peacemaker season two.
I can't get your fucking break. He ends up in the
land of goodness and light with a brother who's
still alive and a father who fucking loves him. The
good us. Tom Sturridge as Morpheus in Sandman
season two. You've made your choice. Just as your
life is your own. So tell us your death. I think it's
going to be a toss up between John Cena and
Morpheus. I'm going to go John Cena. That's my
guess. The winner is David Corn Sweat as Superman
in Superman. Damn it. That was so off. Now, there
was not a bad choice. I think John Cena probably
gave the best performance of his career in
Peacemaker season two. That said, David Corn
Sweat, in my opinion, is the best actor to play
Superman since Christopher Reeve. And that's a
really high bar. I think he's better in the role
than Henry Cavill, Brandon Routh, Tyler Hochlin,
better than anyone else to play the role. Because I
thought he nailed both Clark Kent and Superman
better than most. Now, is that due to the writing
you think or is that because of the performance? I
think it's both. I think James Gunn is really good
at casting for his style of writing. Because I
would say that, like, for example, Henry Cavill
gave a great performance as Superman. He was just a
very different characterization of Superman.
Fair. But also, I don't think there was enough
differentiation between his Superman and Clark
Kent. Maybe intentionally so. And there should be
because that's from the source material. Clark
Kent acts differently from Superman. Superman is
sort of the wish fulfillment idealized version of
Clark Kent, whereas Clark Kent is supposed to be
meek and mild mannered. Makes sense. Let's go to
move into the penultimate category this evening
for the Brothers Awards. And that is Best Marvel
Series or Special. There weren't any specials
that came out this year. We haven't had one since
Werewolf by Night. We're supposed to get another
special next year with The Punisher. So this is
basically the best series award for 2025. I think
we've said this before in previous award shows,
but this award, I think, becomes more and more
important every year as we get better and better
quality television series that rival and even
sometimes outperform the quality of what we're
seeing in theaters. Oh, yeah. Comics are a long
form storytelling medium. So it's no surprise
that their stories would be better translated to a
long form medium like a television series. The
production value on these things, like you
mentioned, continues to improve. And I'm pretty
excited about this year's nominees. The nominees
for the best DC series of 2025 are Creature
Commandos Season 1. Harley Quinn Season 5.
Peacemaker Season 2. The Sandman Season 2. Uh,
Sandman Season 2 final answer. The winner is...
The Sandman Season 2. Of course it was. It was so
freaking good. I was worried about it. I'm not
going to lie. I was worried about it about how they
were going to close out the show, but they did it
perfectly, in my opinion. I mean, they condensed
so much material into just like 12 episodes, but
they did a really good job in the translation from
print to screen, I think, and staying on track with
the character of Dream. Everything. Everything
from the casting, the performances, to the music,
to the direction, to, you're right, the
adaptation of the story. I feel like it should have
been harder to pull off, but they did it in just a
masterpiece of a season and really a show. I mean,
the Sandman series is one of modern literature's
greatest tragedies, and Season 2 was a lot more
heavy on the tragedy aspect of it. And I remember
being devastated watching it. If I'm ever put in a
situation where I only get to watch one television
series again for the rest of my life, I'm choosing
the Sandman. Both seasons. Really? Interesting.
Hell yeah. You think you'd pick something with
more seasons, though? That's fair. I'd probably
go like Game of Thrones or Breaking Bad or
something. You know what? No, I'm going to stand by
it. I'll stick with the Sandman. It's pretty
varied. You're probably still safe with that
choice. But let's go to move on to Marvel. The
nominations for the best Marvel series of 2025 are
Daredevil, Born Again, Season 1 Iron Heart,
Season 1 Marvel Zombies, Season 1 Your friendly
neighborhood Spider-Man, Season 1 I think this
one's obvious. I think it's Daredevil, Born
Again. And the winner is Marvel Zombies, Season 1
Well, I didn't watch it, so how would I know? Marvel
Zombies was fucking everything that I wanted it to
be. Now, it wasn't an adaptation of the comic book
story of Marvel Zombies, which largely takes
place after the zombie apocalypse has happened
and we see the state of all these Marvel heroes as
zombies. The show was more about survival and it
had a great kickoff with the What If episode. This
carried on and told a truly harrowing and
horrifying story. The main characters were
Kamala Khan, Miss Marvel, and Shang-Chi, as well
as featuring a version of Blade that was like
amalgamated with Moon Knight. So it kind of felt
like the Avengers movie that we're probably never
going to get with all those new characters. But it
was funny and it was violent, and I think it was
everything that it needed to be in a way more so than
these other shows were. Now, in all honesty, I
actually almost gave this award to your friendly
neighborhood Spider-Man because I really came
around on that show, especially in the latter half
of Season 1. Not only did it tell some of the best
origin stories for Spider-Man's villains,
probably ever when the story wasn't bogged down by
teenage drama or whatever. The show was really
well done, but in the end, I think it kind of tied for
Daredevil born again in terms of my enjoyment of
it, whereas Marvel Zombies, I had a blast from
start to finish. And Marvel Zombies was a
mini-series, right? It was only, what, like six
episodes? Four episodes. Oh, wow. Talk about
getting banged for your buck. Yeah, you should
watch it next Halloween season. I highly
recommend it if you haven't seen it. If you like
Zombie Fair, I think a lot of people will probably
not be thrilled that it stars some lesser-known
Marvel characters, but if you're a fan of Kamala
Khan like I am, like I loved the Miss Marvel
television series, and I thought Amon Valani was
one of the strongest parts of the Marvels movie. If
you loved Shang-Chi like I did, if you're really
looking forward to seeing what Blade will be like,
or if you loved Moon Knight, yeah, just watch
Marvel Zombies. But also, I would recommend
watching the Marvel Zombies episode of What If
first, and then going into the Marvel Zombies
season. Really, it's a five-episode season,
because that first What If episode is crucial.
Gotcha. Okay, good advice. Moving on to our final
category of the show of the year. Best motion
picture. Best film, really. Yeah, no one calls
them motion pictures anymore, except for the
Oscars. This award is, again, basically like the
previous award, just with, again, different
genitalia. Couldn't have said it better myself.
No, Joseph and I are huge movie fans. It's one of the
reasons we started this podcast. I love going to
the theaters, and I'm glad to see more and more
people continuing to do so after the pandemic.
Come on, that was five years ago, people. Let's get
our asses back in the theaters. My ass loves my
couch, though. That's loser talk, bro. Get out
there, lazy bastard. Honestly, the movie theater
seats in the theaters near me are like leather and
reclining now. It's great. It's way more
comfortable than my couch. All right, then. But
anyway, there's nothing quite like experiencing
a story on a massive screen with a bunch of people.
Let's break down the nominees. The nominees for
Best Marvel Picture of 2025 are Captain America,
Brave New World. The Fantastic Four First Steps.
Thunderbolts. And that's it. Just three nominees
for Marvel. Well, of those easily hands down, I
would say my favorite was Fantastic Four First
Steps. So that's my guess. And the winner is...
Thunderbolts. That would have been my second
guess. You lose. I win. I don't know what I win. No,
Thunderbolts was every bit as good as the
Fantastic Four First Steps in terms of my
enjoyment of them. They were very different
movies. The difference being that Thunderbolts
had something to say, which is not entirely common
among films in this genre. Fantastic Four looked
amazing, had great art direction, truly brought
the heroes to life on the big screen in a way that
other attempts failed. But Thunderbolts, I
think, is the best type of movie for the superhero
genre in that it really brought more to the table
than just spectacle in action. It was more of a
psychological exploration. And it was funny. And
it's still delivered on the action. Yes,
psychological thrillers are some of my favorite
films of all time. I really liked the Thunderbolts
when it came out. In fact, I called it my favorite
Marvel film up until that point. And so Fantastic
Four came out, which I started calling that my
favorite Marvel film up until that point. But only
because I think I cared about the characters a
little bit more. And I think the filmmaking was a
little better in terms of, you know,
cinematography and stuff like that. But that's
not to discount Thunderbolts. It was a really cool
movie, really well done movie, a little bit
smaller in scope. But I agree with you that I
appreciate that it had a message. Yes, scope isn't
everything. Yeah, you compare the scope of these
two films and they couldn't be more different. But
I think what also contributed to my ultimate
decision was that the first act and the latter part
of the second act of the Fantastic Four movie were
too montagey. There was too much dicing and
slicing in the editing room for the Fantastic Four
first steps, whereas that was not the case for
Thunderbolts. That's fair. Yeah, that's a fair
criticism for sure. Made it harder to connect with
the characters than it should have been. Whereas
it was surprisingly easy to connect with C tier
characters that appeared in the Thunderbolts.
Right. Good choice. Good choice. I'm glad you went
with that choice. But moving on to DC, also just
three nominees. The nominees for the best DC
picture of 2025 are Aztec Batman, Clash of
Empires. Batman Ninja versus Yakuza League.
Superman. Superman, obviously. Final answer.
The winner is Aztec Batman, Clash of Clans. I'm
just joking. Bullshit. The winner is Superman. It
was an easy choice. As much as I really liked Batman
Ninja versus Yakuza League, I had to go with
Superman. It was just a better experience
overall. An exciting experience as it kicked off
James Gunn's DCU. It was a terrific Superman film
with all of the heart and hope and goodness that you
want out of a Superman movie. In a way that I feel
like we haven't had in a really long time. The
music, the score, the story, the performances,
all commendable. I just really loved this film.
And I'm not the only one. I can't tell you how many
Instagram reels I've seen of people just loving on
the Superman movie. Just going home and feeling
good about being a punk rocker or wanting to be a
punk rocker like Superman, who's extremely nice
and sees the good in everyone. It's a great message
for a Superman film to have in particular. First of
all, Superman isn't punk rock as much as he wants to
claim that he is. He's the new punk rock. Second of
all, I totally beat you at this year's Brothers
Awards. I just want you to know that I know it's not
like an actual competition, but I won in terms of
our guesses. Oh, wait, wait, what are we keeping
score now? Is this some kind of contest? Yes. What
was the score? I don't know. Okay. Third of all,
yes, Superman was a good movie. It was fine. I don't
think he compared to Thunderbolts. And frankly,
I'm tired of hearing about Superman. Well, that's
just Hater talk. Hater. Hater's going to hate. And
I guess you'll be doing given more hating next year
because we'll be discussing Supergirl. Yeah, I'm
already not looking forward to it, but thankfully
I'll be able to go at least a few precious months
without hearing you talk about Superman. Cause
I'm a punk rocker. Yes, I am. Okay. But that does it
for this award show, guys. We hope you enjoyed it
this year. Let us know which awards you agreed
with, which awards you didn't agree with. Follow
us on Instagram where we'll be posting the awards
or join our Discord server, which is now open to all
of our listeners, not just our patrons. There is a
link to the server within the show notes. Go ahead
and click that if you are on Discord and join the
larger dynamic dual fan community. That's right.
As we transition into the new year and the new
format where we're doing only reviews, no more
dual episodes, we are doing away with our Patreon
tiers and opening up our Discord to anyone who
wants to chat about DC and Marvel films or comics,
or just shoot the shit with us because we'll still
be on there. So happy new year, everyone. AJ9K help
close this out. Thanks for listening to Dynamic
Duel. Visit the show's website at
dynamicduel.com and follow us on Instagram at
Dynamic Duel podcast. Don't forget to listen to
the other shows in the DynaMic podcast network,
including Max Destruction, Senjo World, and
Konsole Kombat. In our next episode, we are going
to be doing a duel between Animal Man and the
Lizard, the Spider-Man villain. That should be a
good one. Yeah, it's going to be our last
individual dual matchup for the show. Do not miss
it. That is it for this episode. We want to give a big
final thank you to our executive producers, Jon
Straski, Zachary Hepburn, Nathaniel Wagner,
Levi Yatn, Austin Wyselowski, AJ Dunkerly, Nick
Obanto, Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Spees,
Dean Maleski, Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, and
Paul Graves for helping make this podcast
possible. We'll talk to you guys next week. Up, up,
and away, true believers.