This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi, welcome to
the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Johnny DC and I'm his twin
brother Marvelous Joe. And in this episode we are
doing a duel between the characters of Tempest,
formerly known as Aqualad, and the Inhuman
Crystal. And this of course is in lead-up to our
Wildcats vs. Inhumans team duel that we will be
doing next week. Yeah, I've been dying to get to an
Inhumans team duel. I'm a big fan of the Inhumans,
not a big fan of the show that they put together on
ABC. But don't let that piece of shit, poor excuse,
attempt for a series detract you from learning
just how awesome the Inhumans are. The internet
never forgets. I neither will I. Before we get to
the duel, we're going to break down the comic book
movie news from the past week, of which there were
two news items, one being the Peacemaker Season 2
official red band trailer, and the new one being
the Marvel Zombies series release date. As
always, we list our segment times in our episode
description, so feel free to check out the show
notes if you want to skip ahead to a particular
topic. Guys, our artificially intelligent duel
simulator, AJ9K, has a quick message for our
listeners, so listen up. Thanks AJ9K, and thanks
to everyone who supports the podcast, including
Josh Hayward, who had a birthday this past week.
Happy birthday, Josh. Also, Zachary Hepburn, two
of our patrons actually had birthdays this past
week, and I believe they both turned 35. Great age,
you guys could both be a president, or at least Josh
could, because Zach's Canadian. And because
you're Canadian, Zach, for your birthday, if I
could get you any gift from DC, it would be Captain
Cold's cold gun, because it's cold up in Canada,
and that's all I really know about it. In the
winter, it's cold in Canada, right? You've been to
Vancouver, haven't you? Yes, and it was cold. And
for the Marvel guy, Josh Hayward, if I had to give
you a gift from Marvel, it would be the Falcons
wingsuit. Why? I don't know. Probably because I'm
looking at an image of the Falcon right now, and
that's the first thing that came to mind. Happy
birthday again to both of you guys, and thanks for
supporting the show. Be sure to tune into the other
shows on the Dynamite Podcast Network this week,
including the console Combat Podcast, where
hosts John and Dean simulate battles between
popular video game characters. In yesterday's
episode, the two determined who would win between
King K. Rool from Donkey Kong and King Hippo from
Punch Out. Great matchup. Over on the Max
Destruction Podcast, hosts Scotty and Gilly pit
your favorite action heroes from film and
television against each other. They are taking a
hiatus during the month of August, so be sure to get
caught up on their latest episodes. On the Sinjo
World Podcast, birthday boy Zachary Hepburn
speculates on fights between fan-favorite anime
and manga characters. In his next episode, Zach is
going to reveal who would win between Akuto Sai
from Demon King Daimo and Amos Voldigoad from
Misfit of Demon Academy. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our show
notes to listen to all the shows in the Dynamite
Podcast Network. Boat that out of the way. Quick to
the No Prize! A No Prize is an award that Marvel used
to give out to fans. Our version, the Dynamic Dual
No Prize, is a digital award we post on Instagram
for the person that we feel gave the best answer to
our question of the week. Last week, or two weeks
ago actually, we asked you guys, what was the best
live action Spider-Man suit and the best live
action Batman suit and why? We got a few answers for
this one, not nearly as much as I thought we would
actually, but let's go ahead and run down the
honorable mentions and the No Prize winner. Our
first honorable mention goes to Alex Albro, who
said, Hey guys, I think Toby's black suit was the
best. I can remember the way the action figure felt
in my hand even 20 years later and seeing it come on
to him in the movie with a webby black virus looking
thing was a really cool visual. As for Batman, I
think George Clooney suits the best. You know,
it's the most anatomically correct, you could
say, and it just fits the tone of that film. I never
once questioned it as a kid and also it's got the
best Robin suit in that film. Thanks guys. Yeah,
the Toby McGuire Spider-Man suit is really good.
Definitely like the raised webbing look and the
symbiote suit that he wore from Spider-Man 3 was no
exception. They basically took like the sleek
shiny black webbing portion of a suit and applied
that to everywhere as opposed to just the webbing.
And I thought that was really cool because the
symbiote, you know, is supposed to be black and
shiny, at least venom is, you know. I still
remember the first look we got at the black
Spider-Man suit from Spider-Man 3. It was a really
cool poster of Spider-Man just like kneeling at
the edge of a building like a gargoyle in the rain.
And it was just all black and white. For some
reason, the photo was so striking. I thought it
looked really cool. And as for George Clooney
suits, what? Eww, bro. Nipples. You don't like
nipples? Everybody's got nipples. Come on. No,
no. I don't want nipples. You don't want nipples?
No. Great answer. Alex, our next honorable
mention goes to Daniel Alonso. Who said? Alright,
the best Spider-Man suit hands down is the Toby
McGuire one. I mean, the raised webbing, the best
spider on the front and the back. The eyes are
amazing. And then it all has this underlying
checkered pattern throughout the fabric. Its
colors are fantastic. It's just the best suit. And
best Batman suit? Probably Batterson. I think
it's the most menacing, the most realistic. He
just looks like a tank. I love that one. Yeah,
another shout out for Toby McGuire's Spider-Man
suit. I really think that that was the suit that
brought superhero costumes into the modern age. I
mean, before that we had the X-Men, but they didn't
really quite nail the suit in a way that I think was
satisfying for fans. Nobody was complaining
about Toby McGuire suit when that movie first came
out because it was literal perfection.
Everything from the material to the design, the
eye design, as Daniel mentioned, it was flawless.
Do you think that the Toby McGuire Spider logo was
better than Andrew Garfield's though? Or maybe
Tom Holland's? It's a great question. Honestly,
my favorite Spider emblem is probably Andrew
Garfield's, I think. That's what I was thinking.
Yeah, yeah. I would agree with that. As for
Banson's suit, it's definitely the least comic
book accurate, but you're right. With the steel
plating, he almost looks like a knight in his
armor, just wearing a cowl and a cape. He looks
badass. I really, really want him to be part of the
DCU. I'm not going to stop saying it until it's like
official official. You're going to try to
manifest it? Absolutely. Like until James Gunn
announces the casting for his Batman, I'm still
going to insist that it should be Robert
Pattinson. If that does happen, though, I would
probably insist as a fan that he get a more comic
accurate bat suit. No, no, I'm fine with it. Great
answer, Daniel. Our final honorable mention goes
to Scott Camacho. Who said? Scott Camacho here. If
I had to pick a Spider-Man suit, it would be Toby
McGuire. He was our first introduction into live
action Spider-Man and his suit was pretty much on
point. And I'm a big fan of the black suit. And for
Batman, it's Ben Affleck's Batman. It's
everything we wanted from the Dark Knight Returns
put into silver screen. It was awesome. Yeah,
we've already spoken at length about Toby
McGuire's suit, but let's talk about Ben
Affleck's bat suit. I would also say that this is my
favorite bat suit on screen. I'm not counting like
the armored version from the Dark Knight Returns
when he fought against Superman. Even though that
was fantastic. I'm talking more about his
standard Batman suit from Batman v Superman, Dawn
of Justice. Extended Edition. Yeah, that one is
the most comic book accurate. That one was
straight from the page. I loved how buff he was. It
was very Frank Miller. It was awesome. I didn't
really like Ben Affleck's bat suit in Justice
League. Oh, no. Yeah, his best one was definitely
in BVS. I would agree. And then his bat suit that was
in the Flash movie fucking sucked. We don't talk
about that. Shut up. All right. Great answer,
Scotty. But the winner of this week's No Prize is
Lorenzo Valdez. Who said? This is Lorenzo Valdez.
You guys actually referenced my favorite
Spider-Man suit, which is the Amazing Spider-Man
2 suit. It doesn't hurt that that was the suit that
Spidey was wearing when Gwen died. So it has that
extra emotional impact for me seeing that suit. As
for my favorite Batman suit, that would be the Dark
Knight slash the Dark Knight Rises suit because it
improves on the texture of the begin suit and it
also has a better bat symbol. Clonifer, always
bye-bye. Yeah, this is the first guy to not mention
the Toby McGuire suit as his favorite. And I may
agree. I definitely think that the Spider-Man
suit that was in the Amazing Spider-Man 2 worn by
Andrew Garfield was the most comic book accurate.
I mean, because I've never seen a version of Spidey
in the comics where like this raised webbing look,
it doesn't look quite as homemade as it were, even
though it looked spectacular or amazing as it
were. But Andrew Garfield's looked like
something that somebody could conceivably
create that wasn't, you know, a fashion designer,
but it also looks very true to the comic books. It
had the larger eyes. It had great color, had a great
like spider emblem design. It was just
perfection, in my opinion. Yeah, the only thing it
really didn't have was Tom Holland's lenses, like
the thick Steve Ditko lenses. But yeah, still
really cool. Now, we will admit that the Christian
Bale Batman outfits are actually my least
favorite onscreen Batman suits. But of all of
them, my favorite is actually from Batman Begins.
I loved his cowl the way it made him look almost
panther-like. When he upgraded to his new suit
where he was able to turn his neck. Yeah, I get why
that would be good for a crime fighter. But I also
thought it kind of gave him a bobble head. I think
that Robert Pansen's outfit is actually a pretty
solid upgrade to the Dark Knight suits. You like
the Joel Schumacher Batsuits more than Christian
Bales? No, I guess I misspoke. Yeah, those ones are
way worse. So I should say that, well, I slightly
disagree with you, Lorenzo. They're not terrible
suits. They're just not my personal favorites. I
like the functionality of the Christian Bale
Batsuits, especially as it was explained in
universe in those films with like the special
hardening cloth when you would run an electric
current through it. Things like that make it
better than Robert Pansen's suit, who just uses a
weird ass basic squirrel suit, you know. Bale had
better shit in general. Yeah, well, Bale had
Lucius Fox as his cue, so he had better tech
overall. What about the bat emblem, as Lorenzo
Bale does mentioned? You know, I never really
cared for like the straight, flat top emblem. I
like a little bit of curves in my Batman logo, you
know. Well, great answer, Lorenzo. You win this
week's No Prize. If you're the listener, want to
shot at winning your own No Prize, stay tuned to
later on in the episode when we'll be asking
another question of the week. And now that that's
done, on to the news. OK, with the premiere of
Peacemaker Season 2 coming up soon, HBO Max has
released an official red band trailer for the
series, which I thought would delve more into the
story, but it was really just a showcase for how
raunchy and violent the series is going to be.
Like, I forgot how raunchy James Gunn can get until
this whole trailer starts off with a friggin orgy
in Peacemaker's house. And vigilante
complaining about how he wasn't invited. I'm fine
with the no story stuff, though. I don't want to
know too much about the story as we go into it, but
this trailer did remind me basically just how much
of a good time I'm in for watching it. Because the
first season was hilarious and I was laughing my
ass off during this red band trailer. Yeah, after
we learned that Rick Flagg Sr. is looking for
Peacemaker because he has a dimensional portal
similar to Lex Luthor, we just get a series of
jokes, including this creepy looking alien that
steps through one of Peacemaker's portals and
just refuses to say hi. And Peacemaker's like,
fuck you then, you cryptkeeper looking bitch. So
good. It is interesting that they are addressing
the fact that Lex Luthor had his own dimensional
portal and that Peacemaker's dad, the White
Dragon, also has one. It's strange because it
seems like White Dragon's portal is better and
more stable than Lex Luthor's. Seemingly, yeah.
So does that make White Dragon smarter than Lex
Luthor? I don't think so. I know we'll be getting
new versions of White Dragon and maybe in some
other universe there was a version that was
smarter than Lex Luthor. And he just happened to
create portals for all of the other White Dragons
and all of the other multiverses. That's just my
guess though. But I would agree that it definitely
looks more stable. It looks like there's going to
be a lot of action in this season, lots of
explosions, bloody explosions it looks like,
including an explosion where tomatoes get
flicked in the face with a nail or something like
that. And eagerly rips a dude's eyeball out. Yeah,
that was wild. Or a finger or both. Yeah, it looks
like he just shreds the guy. Of course, at the end of
the trailer, we get a callback to the dick alien.
Not too much more to the trailer other than that. If
you guys haven't watched Peacemaker Season 1,
watch it now so you can get caught up in time for the
show's release. It debuts this Thursday, August
21st on HBO Max. I can't wait for the show. I love the
writing. I love the cast. But speaking of the cast,
that brings us to our question of the week. What is
your favorite supporting cast in a Marvel or DC
ensemble series and why? Yeah, every television
series based on a superhero usually has a cast of
characters that support the main hero titular
character. We just want to know which cast of
characters is your favorite. Record your answer
at dynamicduld.com by clicking on the red
microphone button in the bottom right hand corner
of the screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long. And don't forget to leave your name in case we
include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a dynamic
duel no prize that we'll post to Instagram. Be sure
to answer before August 23rd. And in Marvel News,
we learned this past week that Disney Plus has
moved up the Marvel Zombies release date so that
instead of debuting on October 3rd, it's going to
now debut a week earlier on September 24th. The
season is going to be four episodes that are going
to be released weekly. So all the episodes will be
out before Halloween, but still close enough,
which is appropriate for a horror animated
series. I forgot that this show was even coming out
this year. How could you forget? This is going to be
amazing. The What If episode that included the
Marvel Zombies, which was called What If Zombies,
that was back in 2021, I believe. That was one of the
best episodes of that season. And Marvel Zombies
is a really enjoyable story. It really grew some
written by Robert Kirkman back in the day, but this
is going to be a new version of it. I made for screen
adaptation that started with that What If
episode. Really excited to see where it goes. If
you guys want to learn more about the Marvel
Zombies universe, definitely check out our
Deceased vs. Marvel Zombies Team Duel episode.
Yeah, that was a lot of fun. I heard that in this
upcoming Marvel Zombies season, we're going to
get other characters that weren't in the previous
episode, including Moon Knight and Blade and
Shang-Chi's also going to be there. So yeah, it's
going to be a big blast. Wait, is Blade going to be
voiced by Mahershala Ali? That I do not know. That
would be interesting. That would be fantastic.
Really looking forward to it in just over a month.
And I hope you guys are too. We're not going to be
reviewing it for this show. I guess depending on
how people react to it, we'll determine whether or
not I take the time to watch. You're going to be
watching. It's only four episodes. It's going to
be a quick, easy watch, perfect for the season. I'm
definitely going to be watching. You're
definitely going to be watching, motherfucker.
And if you don't, I'm going to make you. I don't know
how yet, but I will find a way. Yeah, bro. You don't
scare me. Why not? Your face? I don't know. It's too
much like mine. Both all the news out of the way. Now
let's get on to the main event where we find out who
would win in a matchup between Aquaman's former
sidekick Tempest and the inhuman princess
Crystal. Okay, Tempest versus Crystal. Now both
of these characters are elemental manipulators,
I guess you could say. Yeah. Crystal controls all
four of the elements, whereas Tempest controls
more temperature of water, but he could generate
water through Atlantean sorcery. And like
Crystal, he's also royalty. He's a prince of
Atlantis. Crystal can generate water too,
through chemistry. Okay, but can't she control
the temperature of that water? Yes, she can by
controlling its molecular movement. Too shane.
But we know that Tempest has some magical
abilities in addition to his hydrokinesis, and
Crystal also has some inhuman physiology traits
going for her. So we figure the characters kind of
balance each other out. It'll be interesting
really to see how this matchup goes, considering
they have very similar powers, especially when it
comes to water. Basically, who will control the
water the best is what we're asking Kare. Oh, easy.
Tempest. Oh, you think so, huh? Okay. Yeah, I do. In
fact, you mentioned earlier. That Crystal was in
the Inhumans TV series that was gosh awful.
Actually, Tempest has been in a TV series as well.
If you remember, he was in the Titan show. Was he? I
don't remember that. Yeah, he was blond in that
though. Trying to remember him. He died in the
second season in like a flashback. I see. Okay.
Well, in the Inhuman show, Crystal was played by
Isabel Cornish, and I remember she never really
got to show off her powers too much, largely due to
the insufficient budget for the show itself, I
think. One of these days, we'll get a good Inhuman
show or movie. We're moving on to the duel to
explain the methodology behind our duels. Let's
go to our sentient duel simulator, Alfred Jarvis
9000. AJ9K, tell our listeners how you go about
determining a winner in our duel matchups. Yes, of
course, sir. The way I determine a winner between
the contestants is by running 1000 Monte Carlo
simulations using the characters statistics. A
Monte Carlo simulation is a probabilistic model
used to determine outcomes through random
sampling. In this case, I randomize the
statistics along a normal distribution as a way to
simulate the many variables that can occur during
battle. The stat parameters are based on the
official Marvel power grid from which the DC
characters statistics are extrapolated.
Additional stat categories are included such as
range, damage potential, versatility and
perception in order to create a more detailed and
accurate simulation. The results of the 1000
simulations provide a percentage of wins for each
character. The contestant with the higher
percentage is declared the victor as they have a
higher probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither character should win
100% of the matches. The comic book stories have
shown that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman, so the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks, AJ9K.
Before we run the simulations though, we like to
break down each character's histories and
abilities before improvising a scenario on how we
imagine one of the 1000 simulations would play out
beat for beat. And I believe it's my turn to go first
with the Marvel characters backstory, so let me
tell you all about Crystal. Crystallia
Immaculinn was born in the hidden city of Adolan to
Cwelyn in Amber, members of the Inhumans race, a
people whose ancestors were genetically altered
by the alien Kree. As the younger sister of
Medusa-Lith Immaculinn, later Queen Medusa,
Crystal belonged to the Inhuman Royal Family.
Like many Inhuman children, she was exposed as an
infant to the Tarogen Mist, a substance for people
used to unlock powers. And she gained control over
the four elements of Earth, Air, Fire, and Water.
You can learn more about the Inhumans and
Tarogenesis in our Shazam vs Black Bolt dual
episode. When Crystal was young, her cousin
Maximus seized power and forced the Royal Family
out of the Great Refuge. During exile, they
searched across Asia, Europe, and America for her
missing sister Medusa, living in hiding along the
way. They found her in New York City, where she had
joined the villainous Frightful Four while
suffering from memory loss. You can learn more
about Medusa in her duel against elongated man. In
New York, Crystal met Johnny Storm, the human
torch of the Fantastic Four, and the two began a
romance. Maximus later trapped Adolan inside an
impenetrable barrier, separating Crystal from
Johnny. When the barrier finally fell, the Royal
Family explored the outside world. Crystal
helped the Fantastic Four rescue Mr. Fantastic
from the negative zone dimension and fought
beside them against the invader Blastar. She left
Adolan for an extended stay in New York and became
part of the Fantastic Four's daily life, running
communications and supporting the pregnant Sue
Richards. When Sue went on maternity leave,
Crystal earned a place on missions as her stand-in
proved herself by defeating their villain, the
Wizard, on her own, then battling foes such as Dr.
Doom, the Mole Man, and the Alien Scrolls. You can
learn more about the Fantastic Four in their duel
against the Justice Society. Over time, Earth's
pollution, which is toxic to many inhumans, began
to harm Crystal's health, and she set out to return
to Adolan. On her journey back, the alchemist
Diablo captured her and tricked her into
believing she was the Mayan goddess Ishal. After
the Fantastic Four freed her, Crystal
encountered the mutant Quicksilver, wounded
from battle, and she nursed him back to health.
Choosing him over Johnny, she married
Quicksilver in the first recorded union between
an inhuman and a human mutate. You can learn more
about Quicksilver in his duel against the Flash.
When Adolan was later moved to the Moon, the couple
lived there and welcomed a daughter, Luna, who
showed no special abilities. Quicksilver wanted
to expose Luna to the Tarjan Mist to grant her
powers, but Crystal refused. Life in Adolan
strained their marriage. Quicksilver's temper
and his effort to prove himself as a commander in
the Inhuman Militia kept him away from home.
Lonely, Crystal began an affair with a human real
estate agent, subtly mentally influenced by
Maximus, who sought to increase the marriage's
tensions. When Quicksilver discovered the
affair, he fled Adolan and the marriage
fractured. Crystal rejoined the Fantastic Four,
though her lingering feelings for Johnny made
life in New York tense, especially since Johnny
was then married to a woman later revealed to be the
Skrull Imposter, Lygia. Duty soon called Crystal
back to Adolan to help with a crisis involving
Medusa and Black Bolt's child, and there she and
Quicksilver tried again to make peace. Their
troubles soon expanded beyond Adolan when Luna
was kidnapped by Magneto's acolytes. Crystal
called on the Avengers to rescue her and soon
joined the team herself. She moved with Luna into
the Avengers mansion. With the team, she fought
the alien brethren, villainous alternate
universe Avengers, and the Kree Star Force during
a war between the Kree and the Shiar empires.
During this period, Crystal developed feelings
for her teammate, Dane Whitman, the Black Knight,
especially after he saved Luna from the Star
Jammer's and later saved Quicksilver's life.
Crystal and Dane shared a single late night kiss,
but she would not pursue it while still married.
Fellow Avengers Cersei of the Eternals also saw a
relationship with Dane, and Cersei and Dane later
vanished to another dimension altogether,
ending the possibility of a love triangle. You can
learn more about Cersei in her duel against
Firestorm. While battling the Bloodcursed
Warrior called the Bloodraith, Crystal was
transported into caverns beneath Adolan where
many Alpha Primitives, who were mindless slaves,
dwelt. Recovering the Black Knight's Ebony
Blade, she was briefly hailed by the Alpha
Primitives as ruler before returning to the
Avengers. Soon after, many heroes, including
Crystal, sacrificed themselves to stop
Onslaught, a world-threatening psychic entity
you can learn more about in his duel against
Parallax. Crystal and the others were not truly
killed, but reborn in a pocket universe with no
memories. There, Crystal again drew close to
Johnny Storm until they all returned to their
original reality. Back on Earth, she reunited
with Quicksilver, and a brief attempt by Maximus
to control Pietro's mind was exposed and stopped,
though he and the Black Knight still quarreled
over Crystal's affections. A later reality shift
by the Scarlet Witch depowered most of Earth's
mutants, including Quicksilver. Desperate he
stole the Tarogen crystals from Adolan,
kidnapped his daughter Luna, and exposed her to
the Mists, which granted her empathic abilities.
The Inhuman Genetics Council annulled Crystal's
marriage at that point, changed Luna's last name
from Maximoff to Immaculin, and returned the
child back to Crystal. When human authority
seized the crystals and refused to return them,
the Inhumans declared war on the United States.
During this conflict, Quicksilver submitted
himself to Black Bolt's judgment for his
betrayal, and Crystal took part in clashes with
Shield and the mighty Avengers. The royal family
soon took Adaline into space and turned against
the alien Skrulls, who had abducted Black Bolt.
Seeking support, the Inhuman Royal Family
approached the Kree Empire. Ronin the Accuser,
the Kree ruler at the time, welcomed an alliance
with the Inhumans if Crystal would marry him.
Although the match began as a political bargain,
Crystal came to respect Ronin and the stability
their union could bring. The wedding was
interrupted when the Shiar Imperial Guard
attacked, with the Inhumans being killed. During
Vulcan's invasion of Kree space, Ronan was beaten
nearly to death in the assaults, and while Crystal
visited him in recovery, she helped rally the Kree
by showing public compassion to injured
commoners. The scenes broadcast across the
empire earned her the nickname, The People's
Princess. Black Bolt later sought to spread
pterogen across the galaxy using a bomb,
believing it would make all beings equal. Crystal
judged the plan dangerous, and with the inhuman
teleporting dog, Lockjaw, she reached the bomb
and neutralized the pterogen qualities inside
the device. A final battle between Black Bolt and
Vulcan caused the bomb, now just a normal
explosive to detonate, and both rulers were
believed dead, making Crystal's sister Medusa
queen. In time, Black Bolt returned, and the
inhumans and the Kree supreme intelligence
agreed to a truce that separated Crystal and
Ronan's marriage for the arranged marriage had
grown into a genuine bond. Back on Earth, Medusa
appointed Crystal as an ambassador. She
commanded the royal inhuman vessel with a team
that included her cousin Gorgon, the stealthy
Naja, the geokinetic Flint, and the technopathic
Grid. Crystal worked to protect nations touched
by the drifting pterogen cloud that was released
by Black Bolt, which could awaken powers in latent
inhumans. The cloud however was harmful to
mutants, and she secretly coordinated with them
to help those who were threatened by the cloud.
Crystal's crew then carried out relief missions
around the world. In Sydney, Australia, she
confronted protesters who had captured a newly
formed inhuman. She used measured force to
disperse the mob, freed the captive, and added new
recruits to her ship. Crystal remained involved
in wider disputes among Earth's heroes, like when
the inhuman named Ulysses gained the ability to
foresee potential futures. Crystal and Medusa
introduced him to leading heroes to debate
whether his visions should guide crime-biting
actions, and a clash followed with Iron Man over
Ulysses' custody as tensions later rose between
heroes debating the ethics of preemptive
justice. And that's Crystal's backstory.
Powers-wise, Crystal has the enhanced
physiology of an inhuman granted to her through
pterogenesis. This includes greater strength,
speed, and durability than any normal human. She
also has the psionic ability to manipulate the
four elements of air, water, fire, and earth.
Crystal's like the Avatar, the last airbender,
and that she can control the size, shape,
intensity, and molecular motion of these
elements. She can use her power over air to fly,
create tornado-level gusts, and create force
barriers. She can also control and generate
lightning by manipulating the electrical charge
of the air. Crystal can combine oxygen and
hydrogen gases in the air to create water, which
she can also control, even dropping its
temperature to form ice and freeze things. She can
also compress the oxygen in the air to ignite
existing hydrogen, or dust, and create a
spontaneous combustion of fire, which she can
also control. Lastly, she can control the ground
and rock beneath her for various effects,
including creating seismic tremors. Crystal can
combine elemental effects to also control things
like dust storms, typhoons, steam clouds,
firestorms, and lava. She also has limited hand
combat training. And that's Crystal. So were her
powers initially just like the four Hellenistic
elements that later evolved to basically the
whole periodic table? No, she can't control the
periodic table. She can control the gases in the
air, some of which are oxygen and hydrogen, which
she can then manipulate further to create
elements that she can also control. But she can't
control something like xenon or something like
that, you know, that's not naturally found in the
air. The electricity thing is a little weird,
because even since her inception, she was able to
like throw lightning bolts, which didn't make
sense considering electricity is a part of the
four classic elements. And they kind of kept it in
more modern iterations, rationalizing it as her
ability to control the electrical charge of the
molecules she's manipulating. I get it. I mean, if
you think about it in avatar terms, lightning is
just kind of like another version of fire. Not
really, but sure. I mean, once you said she's like
the avatar, I was like, okay, I got it. A good
matchup would actually be between Ang, Inc.,
however you pronounce it, and Crystal, Inc.,
yeah, whatever. I never watched the show. Okay,
we're going to stop recording right now, so you can
watch the whole show because you need to do that.
I'll watch it eventually, maybe after the podcast
ends in January. Yeah, that should be the first
thing you do with your newfound free time. But it's
been a while, I feel like since we've found some
interesting connections between the characters
that we paint in duels against each other, there
are definitely some similarities between
Tempest and Crystal beyond just their power set
and the fact that they're royalty. But let me go
into that in Tempest's origin. Garth was born to
Queen Bera and King Thar of the Idolists, a
mystical offshoot of Atlanteans who dwelled in
the Hidden Valley for over 4,000 years. His birth
marked by the rare sign of violet eyes considered a
symbol of great magical potential came during a
time of political turmoil. Fearing that Garth's
birthright ritual could inadvertently free King
Thar's banished brother, the Necromancer
Slyzath, Idolist radicals executed King Thar,
exiled Queen Bera, and condemned Garth to death.
Labeled genetically inferior by Atlanteans
unaware of his true heritage, Garth was abandoned
on a remote seabed to die. Surviving against all
odds, Garth was secretly nurtured by the
Atlantean sorcerer Atlan who taught him basic
survival and language skills. Eventually he was
discovered by Aquaman who took him in as a ward.
Adopting the name Aqualad, Garth became
Aquaman's sidekick and served Atlantis
faithfully. When Aquaman ascended to the throne,
Garth was acknowledged as a prince by adoption,
though his presence remained controversial due
to lingering superstitions. Seeking
companionship and purpose beyond Aquaman's
shadow, Garth became a founding member of the Teen
Titans, working alongside other young heroes
such as Robin, Kid Flash, and Wonder Girl. You can
learn more about the Teen Titans in our Titans vs
X-Men Teen Duel episode. Over time, he began to
grow apart from his mentor, especially following
the birth of Aquaman's son. The death of Garth's
longtime partner Tula, known as Aqua during the
Crisis on Infinite Earths, devastated him,
pushing him to sever ties with Atlantis and rejoin
the Titans, where he continued to forge his own
path as a hero. After years of service as Aqualad,
Garth's life changed forever when he encountered
a tribe of shark-like merpeople and was drawn into
another dimension by Atlan. There, Atlan
revealed Garth's royal lineage and trained him in
the arcane disciplines of his idolist ancestors.
Garth learned to control the temperatures of
water, unleash mystical energy blasts from his
eyes, and tap into elemental forces beyond
traditional Atlantean science. To unlock his
full magical potential, Garth was required to
complete a ritual in the Hidden Valley, a rite
leaked to the prison of Slyzath. Returning to the
capital, the idolists, he found it overrun by
undead creatures and was confronted by a
resurrected Tula, whose form had been twisted
into a trap by Slyzath. Betrayed mid-ritual,
Garth overcame the deception, destroyed the
false aquagirl, and re-emprisoned his uncle.
Emerging victorious, Garth shed the Aqualad
identity and claimed a new title, Tempest. As
Tempest, Garth assumed greater leadership in
Atlantean affairs. He served as Atlantis'
ambassador to the United Nations and stood at
Aquaman's side during global and
interdimensional conflicts. Their bond was once
again tested when Dolphin, Aquaman's former
partner, fell in love with Garth. She and Garth
eventually married and had a son, Sirdian.
Seeking stability, Garth stepped back from
frontline heroics to focus on diplomacy and
family, although he briefly rejoined the Titans
to assist in critical missions. During a cosmic
upheaval, Garth attempted to use Atlantean magic
to undo a spell that had altered the Atlantean
Queen Mera's biology. The spell attracted the
wrath of the Spectre, who attacked Atlantis. The
city was nearly annihilated and Garth was
presumed dead. You can learn more about Mera in her
duel against Invisible Woman. Garth was later
found alive but a Misiak in Sub Diego, the sunken
San Diego, having lost his powers and abilities to
breathe underwater. Those magical and physical
abilities eventually returned, his wife and son
were lost in the destruction of Atlantis, both
presumed dead. Haunted by grief and guilt, Garth
crowned himself King of Atlantis in the absence of
Aquaman, believing it was time for new
leadership. Though his reign was short-lived,
while attempting to relocate Arthur Curry's
remains with Mera, he was ambushed by reanimated
Black Lanterns, Dolphin, Tula, and Aquaman
himself. Garth was killed and reanimated as a
Black Lantern, though ultimately destroyed when
the emotional spectrum was restored. Following
the Flashpoint reset of DC's continuity, Garth's
timeline was restructured. Once again, he was
depicted as an exiled Atlantean child, cast out
for his violet eyes. Rescued and raised by
Aquaman, he became Aqualad and helped form the
Teen Titans alongside Robin, Dona Troy, and
others. Though he once forgot these events due to
mystical interference, the return of Wally West
helped restore his memories and reawaken his
bonds with his teammates. You can learn more about
Wally West in our Flash vs. Speedball duel
episode. During this time, Garth enrolled in the
Silent School, Atlantis' elite College of
Sorcery. There, he studied advanced magical
disciplines and fell in love with a fellow student
named Sira. When a magical experiment caused her
death, Garth blamed the school's leadership,
particularly the headmaster, Locke, for
encouraging unsafe magical practices.
Disillusioned, he swore off magic and joined the
Drift, a Black Ops Atlantean unit specializing in
covert aquatic missions. When Aquaman was
declared a traitor and hunted by Atlantean
forces, Garth was enlisted to capture his former
mentor. Though loyal to Atlantis, Garth retained
his sense of honor and justice, ultimately siding
with Aquaman when he became clear that the true
threat came from another dimension. He fought
alongside Mara, a new Tula, and Aquaman to repel
the invading realm of Thule and helped stabilize
Atlantis in the aftermath. His connection to the
Titans was rekindled during an alien invasion.
Joining the new roster alongside Donutroy, Beast
Boy, Raven, and Miss Martian, each of whom you can
learn more about in their respective Duel
episodes, Garth helped lead a strike against
alien warships, poisoning Earth's oceans and
mutating its people. In the climactic battle, he
sacrificed himself to hold off the alien god,
Drogue, allowing the others to escape. Though
presumed lost, Garth later returned, having
survived the encounter. He eventually supported
the formation of Titans Academy, mentoring young
heroes and protecting them during times of
crisis. When Red Axe attacked the Titans Tower in
San Francisco and magical forces threatened
Earth, Tempest defended the students and battled
alongside his former teammates. Recently, he
stood with Earth's remaining defenders against
Deathstroke's corrupted army, reaffirming his
role as a steadfast protector of both Atlantis and
the surface world. The powers-wise, as an
Atlantean, Tempest possesses a range of
superhuman traits, including enhanced
strength, durability, and speed, optimized for
survival at extreme ocean depths. He can breathe
underwater indefinitely through microscopic
pores in the skin and sees clearly in darkness and
murky environments. His hearing and sense of
smell are also heightened to adapt to aquatic
conditions. While capable of functioning on
land, he does require periodic exposure to water
to maintain peak condition. Garth's magical
abilities surpass those of most Atlanteans,
stemming from his royal idolist lineage. Trained
by the sorcerer Atlan and educated at the Silent
School, he can project destructive eldritch
energy from his hands or eyes, summon and
manipulate water and rapidly heat or freeze large
volumes of liquid. He can construct mystical
barriers, perform astral projection, and open
dimensional portals. His hydrokinesis allows
him to shape whirlpools, geysers, and title
surges at will. He shares a telepathic link with
marine life, enabling him to communicate and
command sea creatures, like his mentor Aquaman.
Lastly, he is also a seasoned combatant trained in
Atlantean martial arts and armed combat. And
that's Tempest. If he could speak to marine life
like Aquaman can, then he just seems way better
than Aquaman considering he can do everything his
mentor can do and more. I think there would be more
inclined to honor the king of Atlantis over Garth,
but yeah, that's probably the only person they
would listen to over him. Seems like the trainee
has become the master. I like that. Oh, that's more
than Aquaman now. Considering I always thought
like Aquaman's ability to speak to fish was his
like unique defining characteristic. Well, it is
in a way. It's sort of like his metahuman ability,
whereas Tempest has to do it through magic. And six
one way, half a dozen the other. I don't know what
that means, but yes. In a world where fantasies
collide and heroes clash, one podcast network
rises above the rest. Prepare yourself for the
ultimate showdowns in comic books, video games,
movies, and anime. The Dynamite Podcast Network
presents Console Combat, where video game
legends brawl every Monday. Dynamic Duel, where
comic book titans smash every Tuesday. Max
Destruction, where TV and action heroes battle
every Wednesday. And Sendro World, where anime
champions clash every Thursday. Join us as we
speculate on the matches and armed with the power
of mathematical simulations, discover who will
emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
Well, now that we've got their histories and
abilities out of the way, let's speculate on how
one of the 1000 simulated matches will go. The
winner is determined by simulations, not the
speculation, but it's fun to imagine how the fight
could play out. AJ9K, what are the rules over
speculation? Well, I should say there are no
rules, other than the characters have no prior
knowledge of the other going into the fight. All
they are aware of starting out is that the other
character is a threat that needs to be eliminated.
For the speculation, the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the match
itself, as no environmental statistics are
considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. Alright
then, let's get into it. Tempest and Crystal meet
on the battlefield? Who goes first? I'm gonna say
that Crystal starts off by igniting some
fireballs in her hands and she just hurls them at
Tempest, she throws like six of them and they just
melt his face right off. Yeah, except that those
fireballs are blocked by magic, you know, this
glowing energy shield that he puts up, which is
then going to shoot out like a handful of purple
magic energy shards right at Crystal piercing her
under vital organs. These shards are magic and
they come from his magic shield? Sure, yeah. Okay,
Crystal dodges the shards, she's gonna lift into
the air with a gust of wind and while she's hovering
in the air, she is gonna form the wind into this like
mini cyclone and she feeds it with boulders from
the ground that's below them and she sends the
tornado over at Tempest and it just envelops him
and he gets smashed among all the flying boulders
within the mini cyclone, just knocked around like
he's in a clothes dryer. Okay, well as the tornado
is coming at Tempest though, he's gonna open a
magic portal at its base and that's gonna cause it
just to fill with water. So this water's gonna
quickly spread throughout the tornado and
Tempest is gonna freeze it. Okay, so you have this
like frozen tornado and he's gonna shatter it into
a million pieces and send those hurtling right at
Crystal just like this hail storm directed right
at her like a wall of bullets. Crystal doesn't give
a shit about that, she's the avatar, okay, she just
lands back on the ground and she neos that shit like
Neo from the Matrix holds up her hand and all the
hail just stops right in front of her freezing
midair and then she's just gonna vaporize all of
that water into a thick fog that covers the
battlefield so that Tempest can't see shit and
he's looking around for Crystal when all of a
sudden he gets sucked into the ground like he just
stepped into quicksand and sure he can breathe
underwater but like we can't breathe that well in a
dust storm so he suffocates in the earth and dies.
But you've forgotten that Tempest has enhanced
senses. He can see at the bottom of the ocean so he
could definitely see Crystal through this fog
this whole damn time and I mean I guess that
wouldn't necessarily help him from the quicksand
but that's fine because Tempest is just gonna use
his magic to flood the quicksand with water
turning it into like a whirlpool portal which he's
just gonna fall into and he's gonna drop through
that portal down through another one that he
formed right behind Crystal right like a badass
assassin and he's going to grab her from behind
conjure this magical energy dagger and just
assassinate her right there. Okay so he teleports
out of the quicksand? Yes. Okay now if he even lays
his hands on the Crystal he's gonna just combust
into flame okay so he tries to assassinate her but
he's too busy burning alive screaming like a
maniac and that fire is gonna like desiccate all
the moisture in his body so he's just gonna be a
dried out husk. Oh shit okay um as Tempest is
probably on the ground gasping for water he's
going to inscribe atlantian magic runes into the
ground and suddenly a tidal wave just comes out of
nowhere and crashes onto the battlefield
Crystal's gonna be smashed into the ground and the
whole environment is going to be flooded with
water and as she's bruised and broken underwater
that's when she's gonna see Tempest's glowing
purple eyes and his right hand glowing with red
energy as he boils the water around her. Alright
yeah she's battered from the wave but to keep from
burning she creates an air pocket for herself in
the water so she doesn't get touched by the boiling
heat and from her bubble air bubble she ionizes a
portion of that air and shoots a lightning bolt
into the water that just electrocutes Tempest. Oh
shit okay Tempest he's probably gonna be stunned
by that or or actually Tempest's body magically
converts the electricity into his own magic what
he's going to use to fuel an attack he's gonna swirl
the water around them into a massive just
devastating hurricane like the biggest one on
record a Tempest and that's going to overwhelm
Crystal and as she's trying to like make heads or
tails of the environment that's when she's gonna
get blasted with this massive beam of magical
eldritch energy just completely disintegrating
her so the match is over. Can he do that can he
convert electricity that's running through his
body into magic dude he's learned all kinds of
magic tricks studying with atlan and the silent
school if an electric eel can do it i bet he could an
electric eel can convert electricity into magic
i'm calling bullshit on that and you're made up
magic it's magic bitch i do what i want. Magic is
stupid okay say Tempest creates a hurricane that
doesn't matter to Crystal okay she's the master of
these elements he can try to disintegrate her with
a magic beam or whatever but before he can even do
that Crystal is gonna raise a small volcano out of
the ground beneath Tempest okay and it's gonna
shoot out this geyser of liquid hot magma all over
him and he can't get out because she forms the lava
into a sphere around him and she hardens the
outside of the sphere into obsidian so he's
trapped in this stone prison that's burning him
alive and he like no marine animal like an electric
eel or whatever can survive that so he's dead yeah
Crystal wins well i say none of that happened
because Crystal's dead for magic all right we'll
go ahead and leave the scenario there one of those
two things happens either Tempest gets burned
alive in a lava prison or Crystal gets
disintegrated by magic energy blast let's go
ahead and input the character stats run the
simulations and come back with a winner a g9k hit it
inputting data running calculations processing
results simulations complete all right that was a
really fun match i really like these two
characters they're pretty cool yeah for some
reason i thought that crystal would have the
physiological edge here considering that she's
inhuman and so she has enhanced physicals but then
you reminded me that Tempest is atlantic and so his
physicals are even more enhanced like crystal is
durable Tempest is more durable than that crystal
is fast like Olympian fast or maybe even faster
than that considering she can carry herself on
gusts of wind but Tempest is known for teleporting
and for being super speedy in the water also
Crystal's just not physically as strong as
Tempest and she's not as good of a fighter as he is
because he's been trained in the atlantic and
military well crystal has been trained but you
hardly ever see her fight in hand to hand combat i
will say that her damage potential is off the
charts sources say that she can control air around
her in a 30 mile radius that's massive that's on the
level of a city and if she can do the same with other
elements like create a massive earthquake on that
level then she can easily topple a city if she
wanted to i have seen her raise atlant from the
ground just using her powers so Tempest i don't
think he can really match that also we have to
consider that crystal can control the element
that is Tempest's weakness as it were you know heat
that can dry him out and burn him alive so she
definitely got the edge there yeah we also
downgraded Tempest's damage level somewhat
considering there was nothing besides magic
really that he was able to do to hurt her like
conjuring any kind of water whether it was boiling
or freezing she was just going to be able to
counteract that yeah it might hurt her for a time
but she would be able to defend herself like if he
put her in a boiling pool or something like that
she'd get boiled for a second before she cooled it
right magic was his only leg up they were matched
when it came to evasiveness range and perception
the letter of which actually surprised me because
you know Tempest has enhanced senses just by
nature of being an atlantian but i guess she has
full like spatial sense of all of the elements yeah
she has elemental awareness basically another
thing that surprised me was that she ended up being
more versatile than Tempest which i guess really
shouldn't have surprised me because well he
controls water she controls all of the elements
yeah although we did say that Tempest was more
intelligent considering he's one of the most
learned sorcerers and all of atlantian history
and crystal is smart you know she's she's fine
she's okay she's not as studied as Tempest with all
that said Jonathan who's taken the win here pretty
sure it's Tempest i'm not 100% on that but
instagram agrees with me as of this recording 60%
of people voted for Tempest to win they don't know
you don't know the only person that knows right now
is AJ9K who has the results so AJ9K the results
please here you are sir all right the winner in the
duel between Tempest and Crystal is Tempest yes
that does it for this episode i want to thank our
executive producers Nana what's the one
percentage out of 1000 simulated matches Tempest
won a lot of them he actually won 752 matches
whereas crystal only won 248 so it was 75.2% over
24.8% that is wild i did not think he was gonna get a
win rate that high it was the physicals and it was
the intelligence Tempest is actually pretty
impressive statistically uh whereas crystal you
know she has a lot of potential she's very powerful
but she just can't match the overallness of
Tempest that is awesome i love that freaking go
Tempest and suck it in humans no the inhumans are
gonna be pissed about this result and they're
gonna come out with a fury like the wild cats have
never seen in our next episode because of this loss
they're not fucking around clearly you don't know
the wild cats i don't know anything about the wild
cats no actually neither do i um i'm gonna learn all
about them this upcoming week in preparation for
this team duel yeah definitely can't wait for that
but that does it for this episode h a9k close us out
thanks for listening to dynamic duel visit the
show's website at dynamic duel dot com and follow
us on instagram at dynamic duel podcast you can
support the show on patreon at patreon dot com
slash dynamic duel and joining a tier that works
for you or by rating and reviewing dynamic duel on
apple podcasts spotify podchaser or on our
website don't forget to listen to the other shows
in the dynamite podcast network including max
destruction senjo world and console combat all
right as we just said our next episode is going to be
the wild cats versus the inhumans this is a team
duel determined by our executive producers and
hopefully it's good and by good i mean hopefully
the inhumans win because i'm kind of pissed right
now but that does it for this episode we want to give
a big thanks to our executive producers john
steroski zackary heppern destin belcom miggy
mattengian nithaniel wagner levi yatan austin
wisalaski aji dunkely nikobanto scott kamacho
gil kamacho adam spes dean meliski devin davis
joseph curseding josh liner mike williams oscar
galvez and paul graves for helping make this
podcast possible we'll talk to you guys next week
up up and away true believers well i control the
fifth element love