This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi, welcome to
the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Johnny DC and I'm his twin
brother Marvelous Joe. And in this episode we are
doing a team duel against two of the most baddest
teams in DC and Marvel, repeating the authority
against the Cabal. Yeah, for those who may not know
who the Cabal are, it's basically Marvel's
villain version of the Illuminati, the
Illuminati being a clandestine group of
superheroes that tackle threats covertly. The
Cabal is comprised of some of Marvel's most
nefarious villains and you are so fucked for this
episode. The authority is going down so damn hard
that there's no way they stand a chance. I'm sorry
to tell you this now. No way, the Cabal is exactly
the type of team that the authority would just
annihilate. Just freaking destroy them. You
don't know anything about the authority. They're
not originally from DC Comics, they're from
Wildstorm Comics, so I would not expect you to know
how powerful they are. But you're gonna learn
today. We're gonna tell you all about the teams,
run statistics to find out who would actually win
between them later on in this match before that.
We're gonna break down the comic book and movie
news from this past week, which is a lie again
because there wasn't any. Studios are really slow
on the news lately. It's like they're so gun-shy
right now. You don't get why. It's like give us more
stuff to talk about. Don't you want us talking
about Marvel in DC? Yeah, don't they know we have a
podcast to run here? What the hell? Selfish
bastards. But as always, we list our segment times
in our episode description, so feel free to check
out the show notes if you want to skip ahead to a
particular topic. Guys are artificially
intelligent dual simulator, AJ9K has a quick
message for our listeners, so listen up. Why hello
there. Do you want even more from this podcast?
Then become a part of the dynamic dual community on
Patreon where you can choose from three tiers. The
Dynamic 2.0 tier gives you access to our Discord
chat server. The Fantastic 4 tier gives you two
bonus episodes each month and the X-Force tier
makes you an executive producer of this show.
Lastly, the Diner Mike podcast network tier lets
you create your own podcast using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and
consultation, and get you simulation results.
Pitch the twins your ideas via email at
dynamicduelpodcastatgmail.com. Check it out at
patreon.com slash dynamicduel. Pip pip cheerio.
Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast. Be sure to tune into the other shows on
the Diner Mike podcast network this week
including the console combat podcast where hosts
John and Dean simulate battles between popular
video game characters. In yesterday's episode
they found out who'd win between Adam Smasher from
Cyberpunk 2077 versus Veronica Santangelo from
Fallout New Vegas. Over on the Max Destruction
podcast hosts Scotty and Gilly pay your favor
action heroes from film and television against
each other. The Macho Twins are taking a quick
break for the month of November but they'll be back
in December with some Christmas season duels. And
on the Send Joe World podcast hosts Zachary
Hepburn speculates on fights between fan
favorite anime and manga characters. In his next
episode Zach is revealing who'd win between
Shigio Kageyama aka Mob from Mob Psycho 100 and
Tatsumaki the tornado of terror from One Punch
Man. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link
in our show notes to listen to all of the shows in the
Dino Mike podcast network. But with that out of the
way quick to the no prize. A no prize is an award that
Marvel used to give out to fans. Our version, the
dynamic duel no prize is a digital award we post on
Instagram for the person that we feel gave the best
answer to our question of the week. Last week we
asked you guys which company would you most want to
acquire Warner Brothers and DC Studios and why and
this is coming off of the news that Warner Brothers
is for sale with a number of other studios placing
bids for the acquisition. We got three honorable
mentions which we'll go over before revealing
this week's no prize winner. Our first honorable
mention goes to Alex Albro who said, Hey guys I
think it ought to be Paramount. They've already
shown interest in acquiring DC. They don't have
any super major theme parks that they're going to
want to just market to. They produce great movies
you know early MCU films Watchmen, Top Gun
Maverick, they've done Footloose, Friday the
13th, they've done a lot of animation stuff. They
can handle anything that DC is going to throw at
them. They also seem to be interested in keeping
gun which is good for continuity and their app
doesn't charge crazy fees so more people will be
inclined to sub and watch the show. I would not mind
it if Paramount acquired Warner Brothers and I had
actually forgotten that they produced some of the
early MCU films like Iron Man. Yeah that's true
Marvel's initial deal was with Paramount for
distribution plus Paramount also owns other IP
like the Ninja Turtles and all of Nickelodeon
which I think DC would be well folded into. Great
answer Alex our next honorable mention goes to DC
Joe who said. Definitely don't want Paramount to
acquire them for political and sensitive
reasons. I'm not going to get into it you guys can
look it up. It's very well documented. As for who I
do want them to be acquired by universal
definitely universal for many synergy reasons.
The theme parks the other IPs that they hold their
distribution and they support physical media.
Yeah I had to look up Paramount politics in order to
be clear on what Jose Marcell is referring to in
regards to the politics of the studio and it looks
like decisions like ending the late show with
Stephen Colbert are all based around owners David
and Larry Ellison trying to court favor with the
administration by steering their content away
from what they perceive as a liberal bias.
Therefore universal would also not be a bad
option. I like the universal answer mainly for the
theme park angle Disney gets a lot of revenue
through their theme parks and the Marvel rides
have become some of their most popular rides. I
would love DC to be able to compete at that same
level because I actually think universal studios
is superior to the Disney parks. Having never been
to either of them I will have to take you out your
word on that. Our final honorable mention goes to
Scott Camacho who said. I think it's no question
it's wherever universal studios is. Just as you
have Disney, Marvel, and Fox universal DC and
Warner Brothers need to be together on that. I mean
just imagine even the universal studios theme
parks if you had DC attractions there it's in the
writing let it happen. Right like I said theme
parks huge attractions I want to visit the DC
universe IRL and I think the theme parks is the best
way to do that. You really hunk up on the theme park
aspect of this potential deal. Well because I know
universal could deliver on that end as well as the
movie end there's really nothing that Paramount
can do that universal can't. Plus universal has
their hands on some pretty solid IP as well such as
the Jurassic franchise. Right and movie monsters
although they're really not doing anything with
that right now. They need DC as a strong IP. So great
answer Scotty. The winner of this week's no prize
however is by DearBangora who said. Hi Denimado. I
think the best company to purchase Warner
Brothers and DC studios would be Amazon. I think
with their deep pockets and their capacity to
bring to life the boys as well as Vinceable with a
great audience and great awards for both those
shows I think they could do something truly
amazing with DC studios and DC comics in general.
I'd be so excited to see what the future would hold.
So this was an interesting answer because Amazon
is currently not one of the companies that are
courting Warner Brothers Discovery to attain
their content. That said Amazon is huge it has
their fingers in a bunch of different pies
including movie studios like MGM including
publishing which I think would be great for DC
comics. And really that's why you picked this
answer as the no prize. Right because I'm
terrified that movie studios will only want to
focus on movies and not really care about the
comics. I think if anyone were to have the best
interests of the publishing aspect of DC it would
be a company like Amazon. Yeah I'm not sure if like
Comcast Universal or Paramount or any of the other
studios have strong publishing arms. I know that
like Netflix doesn't right because they focus on
movies solely but yeah whoever ends up acquiring
Warner Brothers and therefore DC would also be
acquiring the publishing division and you would
want to make sure that that's in good hands because
you know that's the source of all this movie and TV
show content is the comic books. Exactly so great
answer by dear you win this week's no prize if you
the listener want a shot at winning your own no
prize. Stay tuned to later on in this episode when
we'll be asking another question of the week. And
now that that's done I want to the question of the
week. Now that peacemaker has come out and we've
gone through all of the Marvel and DC shows coming
out in 2025 which Marvel or DC movie or TV show from
this year has been your favorite and why. Yeah
there was a number of DC and Marvel projects to come
out this year we want to know which one was your
favorite. Record your answer at dynamic duel.com
by clicking on the red microphone button in the
bottom right hand corner of the screen which will
prompt you to leave us a voicemail. Your message
could be up to 30 seconds long and don't forget to
leave your name in case we include you on the
podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer and award
that person a dynamic duel no prize that will post
to Instagram. Be sure to answer before November
16th. Superhero tees are everywhere but finding
good ones the kind with officially licensed art
great fabric and characters you actually love
that's where old glory wins. Their catalog is huge
Marvel DC heroes villains deep cuts you name it. If
you need a gift or you just want to upgrade your own
lineup this is the place to start and I set you up
with their best discount anywhere. Give 15% off
any order with the code Duel at checkout that's D U E
L at checkout go to oldglory.com grab the
superhero gear you've been meaning to get and use
the code Duel to save instantly that's
oldglory.com promo code duel. But let's go ahead
and move on to the main event of this episode a team
duel between the hardcore super teams of DC's
authority and Marvel's cabal. Okay the authority
and the cabal as I mentioned earlier these are two
hardcore bad ass super teams who don't take no guff
from nobody. Yeah I mean the cabal got quite good at
destroying entire universes leading up to the
events of secret wars where they were ensuring the
survival of Marvel 616 at the expense of all the
other realities and the multiverse. Yeah and the
authority is no stranger to destroying planets as
well. The authority is a team of good guys but they
play by bad guy rules they're all anti heroes and
they are supposed to be getting a movie within the
DC cinematic universe led by James Gunn I wonder if
that's still gonna happen. Well we did see one of
the members of the authority the engineer in the
Superman movie that came out this past summer. The
authority was supposed to originally be the
second movie that was released under the gods and
monsters phase one essentially of the DC universe
that's changed I'm not sure when we're going to get
an authority film rumor has it that it's been
transitioned from live action into an animated
project but we'll see. Interesting interesting.
Of course we've seen a number of members from the
cabal in live action including Emma Frost, Dr.
Doom, the Submariner and recently The Hood and
Loki and Norman Osborn yeah basically Marvel is
just really on top of things when it comes to
getting their characters depicted in live
action. Unless it's Modoc then they suck. That's
true that's true Modoc being a member of the cabal
not in the comic books but in the cartoon and video
game space. I'll get into the rosters later on but
first to explain the methodology behind our duels
let's go to our sentient duel simulator Alfred
Jarvis 9000. AG9K tell our listeners how you go
about determining a winner in our team duel
matchups. Yes of course sir the way I determine a
winner between the two teams is by running 1000
Monte Carlo simulations between every character
on each team using their statistics. A Monte Carlo
simulation is a probabilistic model used to
determine outcomes through random sampling. In
this case I randomize the statistics along a
normal distribution as a way to simulate the many
variables that can occur during battle. The stat
parameters are based on the official Marvel power
grid from which the DC characters statistics are
extrapolated. Additional stat categories are
included such as range, damage potential,
versatility and perception in order to create a
more detailed and accurate simulation. The
results of the 49,000 simulations provide a
percentage of wins for each character on both
teams. The team with the higher average win rate is
declared the victor as they have a higher
probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing neither team should win 100% of
the matches. The comic book stories have shown
that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman so the confidence rate of my method falls
in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks a J9K. Before
we run the simulations though we like to break down
each team's histories and rosters before
improvising a scenario on how we imagine one of the
thousands of simulations would play out beat for
beat. It's my turn to go first with the DC team's
backstory so let me tell you all about the
authority. Now before the rise of the authority,
Earth's defense against extraterrestrial and
metahuman threats was managed by Stormwatch, a
United Nations crisis intervention force
headquartered aboard the satellite Skywatch.
Under the command of successive weathermen
including the manipulative Henry Bendix,
Stormwatch operated publicly but also covertly
through Black Ops teams like Stormwatch Black,
composed of Jenny Sparks, the spirit of the 20th
century who could manipulate electricity and
technology, Jack Hawksmore, a man biologically
engineered to bond with cities and draw power from
urban environments, and Swift, a Tibetan
meta-avian capable of high-speed flight and
combat. When Skywatch fell and most of Stormwatch
perished in an alien attack, its surviving covert
members abandoned the UN Charter and reformed
independently. From the ashes of Stormwatch, the
authority was born, a new team with a goal of
changing the world by any means necessary.
Joining them were Angela Spieke, the second
engineer who replaced her blood with
nanotechnology and became a living machine,
Jerome Thorndike, the latest doctor and wielder
of Earth's shamanistic magic lineage, and two
enhanced operatives rescued from Stormwatch
Zero. Apollo, a solar-powered superhuman with
strength and flight rivaling Superman, and
Midniter, a brutal hand-to-hand combatant with a
cybernetic brain that could predict every
possible move in a fight. The team discovered and
took residents aboard the Carrier, a sentient
interdimensional vessel capable of traversing
the multiverse through the bleed. The authority
made their debut, repelling the global assault of
Kaizen Gamora, who unleashed his engineered
super soldiers, the children of Gamora, across
major cities. The team predicted and intercepted
Gamora's final strike in Los Angeles, and
Midniter destroyed his cloning facility using
the Carrier. Their next threat came from sliding
Albion, an imperialistic version of Britain from
a parallel universe born from human alien
interbreeding. The Carrier breached their
dimension and the authority dismantled their
regime from within. In 1999, as the millennium
ended, Earth's original creator, a vast god-like
entity, returned to reclaim and terraform the
planet. The team infiltrated the being's
colossal form, and Jenny Sparks electrocuted it
from within its brain, ending the threat at the
cost of her life. As the spirit of the 20th century,
her death marked the end of her era, and leadership
of the team passed to Jack Coxmore. The authority
retrieved Jenny Quantum, a newborn in Singapore,
in the spirit of the 21st century, who had been
abducted by Medi-human engineer Dr. Jake Gip
Krikstein. Swift negotiated her release in
exchange for his services aboard the Carrier.
Soon after, the Earth's magnetic poles began to
reverse due to a former doctor who had succumbed to
despair. The authority evacuated Earth's
population to alternate Earth's to prevent
extinction, and when the rogue doctor was
overcome by empathy, he became vulnerable and was
killed by Apollo and the engineer, allowing
Earth's population to return safely. The
authority's global interventions attracted
opposition from the G7 nations. They dispatched
Seth, a being engineered with over a thousand
powers who defeated the entire team except
Midnighter. While the others were captured and
replaced with government-created duplicates,
Midnighter escaped with baby Jenny, freed
Apollo, and together they eliminated the
imposters. Jenny Quantum, now of speaking age,
activated a fail-safe that neutralized Seth's
abilities. The team was restored and Apollo and
Midnighter were married, adopting Jenny as their
daughter. They next confronted Reality
Incorporated, a multiversal corporate entity
that attempted to colonize Earth for profit, as
well as a charismatic Medi-human named John Clay,
who most of the team was affected. Midnighter and
the doctor resisted, the latter managing to purge
Clay's influence to end the crisis. In the
aftermath, the doctor founded the Church of the
Shaman to meet the world's growing spiritual
hunger. When the US military triggered a rift in
the bleed causing the destruction of Florida, the
authority staged a bloodless coup and assumed
control of the United States to enact reform and
prevent further catastrophe. Soon after Jenny
Quantum was targeted by her twin sister Jenny
Fractal, a genetically altered assassin raised
in secret by the Chinese government. Fractal
murdered Jenny, but the doctor preserved her
soul. Midnighter traveled back in time and
eliminated the infant Fractal, allowing Jenny
Quantum's spirit to inhabit her sister's body.
The authority's government collapsed when the
Sons of Liberty, a team of superhumans from
earlier generations, incited nationwide
rebellion. During the conflict, a
nuclear-powered sun detonated on the White House
lawn, destroying much of Washington, DC.
Disillusioned, the authority disbanded. Jenny
Quantum, now eight, ventured into the infinite
city, a realm inhabited by past Jennies, where she
met Jenny Sparks and resolved to rebuild the team.
Jenny Quantum aged herself into adolescence and
reassembled the authority to challenge a
resurgent Henry Bendix, who had orchestrated
their downfall. Bendix had corrupted a woman
named Rose Tattoo into the spirit of murder and
used her to assassinate the doctor, while a
president his successor, Habib bin Hassan.
During Bendix's confrontation with the
authority, he manipulated Midnighter to turn
against his team. Engineer and Jenny Quantum
disabled the threat, and Midnighter executed
Bendix. Hassan, as the new doctor, purified Rose
Tattoo into the spirit of life who joined the team.
The authority then encountered Captain Adam,
displaced from the DC universe, who you can learn
more about in our Captain Adam vs Wonderman duel
episode. Though they sought to return him home,
his unstable energies threatened to unravel
their universe's reality. As reality collapsed,
Captain Adam killed Apollo, Midnighter, and
Jenny Quantum, before the hero Void extracted
part of her essence from him, triggering a
universal reboot. You can learn more about Void in
our Wildcats vs Inhumans team duel. In the newly
formed universe, the authority crash landed in a
parallel world devoid of metahuman life. They
faced a lovecraftian creature at the bottom of the
ocean that psychically fed on the planet's
collective unconscious fears. Though the doctor
destroyed it using a local human as a conduit, the
act wiped out all life on the planet, and the
authority departed the dead world aboard the
carrier. When the number of the beast program
initiated a reality damaging event, the carrier
crashed into London, forming the city of
Unlondon. Earth became a poisoned wasteland,
Jack Hawksmore was gravely injured, the engineer
disabled by electromagnetic storms, and Apollo
exiled to the upper atmosphere to escape the
toxicity. Midnighter roamed the devastated
surface, while Swift operated as a scout.
Survivors mutated into monstrous incubates from
exposure to the Warhol virus, while Apollo became
infected and was later frozen for safety. Kaizen
Gamora resurfaced with a mobile city, seeking to
harness authority technology. Swift and the
engineer were kidnapped by Prince Lorenzo of
Sliding Albion, who sought to harvest their
technology, but the two escaped and rescued a long
lost member of the Golden, a powerful ancient race
once allied with humanity. Jack, merged with
Gamora Island's infrastructure, regained his
powers and repelled the invasion. Apollo,
thought and infected, was released to aid in the
final battle. Midnighter discovered that Habib
bin Hassan, now calling himself the Green Man, had
to become unhinged. The authority rescued Gaia, a
new century baby, who gifted Midnighter a
restorative apple. He used it to cure Apollo,
reuniting them, and once the carrier was fully
restored, Jack offered humanity refuge aboard
the vessel, and a new authority team was formed to
lead the Exodus. During the voyage, they
encountered the Caribbna, an alien race that
consumed living beings for energy. With the help
of a sentient brain, the surviving remnants of an
alien species that fell victim to the Caribbna,
the authority defeated them and liberated the
captive species. Returning to Earth during a
rampage from Gaia, Shift, as the new Doctor,
managed to calm her down and end the threat.
Following the Flashpoint event, the Wildstorm
and DC universes merged. In this new reality, a
previous version of the authority had existed,
with Jenny Sparks and the Doctor operating in
secret. A new incarnation emerged when Superman,
weakened by alien radiation, sought allies to
liberate Warworld from Mongol. Superman's first
recruit was the powerful telepath, Manchester
Black, whose injuries were healed in exchange for
service. They rescued June Moon from a magical
prison, adding Enchantress to the team, who you
can learn more about in her duel against Marvel's
Enchantress. Apollo and Midnighter joined for
their strength and precision, while Natasha
Irons, Steel's niece who adopted his mantle, came
aboard as a tech expert. Light Ray, an alternate
universe's version of the Flash, was recruited
for her light speed travel, and an Omec android was
added as a living weapon. The team's first mission
went to Rai when Omec attacked Apollo during an
attempt to retrieve Light Ray, imprisoned by
Eclipsus. Meanwhile, Superman was trapped in the
bottle city of Kandor by Ultra Humanite, who
planned to possess his body. Superman escaped
with help from Brainiac, who delayed humanites'
plans. You can learn more about Brainiac and Ultra
Humanite in their duel episodes against Ultron
and Mr. Sinister respectively. As the team
regrouped, Apollo and Enchantress and Omec
succeeded in freeing Light Ray. With their roster
complete, the Authority departed Earth in a new
carrier and launched an assault on Warworld and
its tyrannical ruler, Mongul, who you can learn
more about in our Mongul vs. Annihilus episode. In
their opening engagement, Light Ray was killed
and Apollo gravely wounded. Most of the team was
captured, leaving only Midnighter free to
initiate a rebellion that eventually led to
Mongul's death and the liberation of Warworld.
And that's the Authority's history so far. Now for
my seven member roster, I'm going with the
original team members of Jenny Sparks, Jack
Hawksmore, Swift, Engineer, Doctor, Apollo, and
Midnighter. Jenny Sparks is the cynical spirit of
the 20th century who commands electricity, is
able to travel through power lines, fire
lightning, and transform into energy. Jack
Hawksmore is a post-human urban avatar whose
cybernetic body draws power from cities, giving
him enhanced senses, leaping phasing, and even
control over the urban landscape itself. Swift is
a Tibetan-born metahuman with avian traits,
including talons, supersonic flight enhanced
senses, and a psychic rapport with birds. The
Engineer is a genius nanotech cyborg with liquid
metal blood that allows her to shapeshift,
self-replicate, fabricate weapons, manipulate
tech, and alter her size. The Doctor is Earth's
shamanistic protector with reality-warping
magic drawn from the collective memory of all who
have ever lived, granting him near-limitless
power and wisdom. Apollo is a solar-powered
powerhouse with super strength, durability, and
speed, as well as the ability to fly and emit
energy. His husband, Midnighter, is a
bio-engineered super-soldier and master
tactician with an arsenal of club and edged
weaponry, as well as enhanced strength,
reflexes, healing, and the ability to predict
every possible outcome of a fight before it
begins. That's the Authority. With as many times
as their planet went to shit in the history of the
team, I'm not convinced that they're going to be
able to hold up to the cabal. Every time I went to
shit, it was not really their fault, and they kind
of rescued it. Excuses, excuses. I don't want
their excuses. I think the team's going to be in big
trouble in this matchup, and let me tell you why by
going into the history of the cabal. The Skrulls, a
shapeshifting alien race secretly infiltrated
Earth over years by replacing key heroes,
politicians, and leaders with imposters,
believing their infiltration fulfilled a
prophecy to make Earth their new homeworld. The
invasion erupted into full-scale war between
them and Earth's protectors when their deception
was exposed. This war culminated in the public
execution of the Skrull Queen Varanke by Norman
Osborn, who at the time led the Thunderbolts and
was suppressing his Green Goblin persona through
medication. You can learn more about Osborn in our
Joker vs Green Goblin Duel and more about the
Thunderbolts in their duel against the Watchmen.
Following the secret invasion, Norman Osborn
parlayed his superheroic actions into
unprecedented political capital. He was given
command of National Superhuman Security after
the international espionage organization
Shield was dismantled and he began a new one called
Hammer. Osborn seized Avengers to have Ozborn's
Council, soon known as the Cabal, contained
influential villains from around the world. Its
initial inclusions were the Submariner, Emma
Frost, Dr. Doom, Loki, and the Hood, the latter of
whom's real name was Parker Robbins, a small-time
criminal who gained mystical powers after
stealing a cloak and boots from a slain demon
servant of Dormammu. The cloak granted the Hood
invisibility, levitation, and limited mystical
energy projection, making him a formidable
street-level crime boss with supernatural
power. Ozborn's arrangement promised each
member of the Cabal a path to their ambitions in
exchange for supporting his regime and answering
his summons when called. Ozborn's pitch tailored
incentives to each conspirator. He sought
Frost's telepathy to help keep the table's liars
honest, while capitalizing on her leadership
stature among mutants. He expected Doom to
normalize relations between Liberia and the
United States through a personal understanding.
He demanded that the Hood register his criminal
army on the streets through government channels
so they could be deployed under Thunderbolt's
control. He agreed to advance Loki's designs on
Asgard's throne and help return the realm to the
heavens, as, at the time, Asgard was in the skies
above Oklahoma after being rebuilt following the
events of Ragnarok. You can learn more about this
in our Aries vs. Loki duel. Finally, he dangled the
surface world's cooperation with Atlantis
before Namor, something that the shield had never
offered. Even as the Cabal nodded along, power
dynamics behind the scenes remained volatile.
Ozborn quietly held a deterrent in reserve, the
sentry's destructive other self known as the
Void, threatening to unleash him should any
member of the Cabal betray him. Even at its
inception, the group's alliances nested within
alliances. Namor and Dr. Doom, long comfortable
dealing at sovereigns beyond ordinary law,
renewed their understanding when Ozborn
inevitably imploded, Doom would rule the land and
Namor the seas. Emma Frost and Namor, whose brief
past romance had been revealed during an earlier
attempt to recruit him into the Hellfire Club,
forged a new pact with clear contingencies. Frost
promised to protect Namor's psyche from Ozborn's
coercion, while Namor vowed to stand for mutant
kind if Frost needed him. You can learn more about
Namor and Frost and their respective duels
against Aquaman and Poison Ivy. Loki moved first
to hasten Ozborn's downfall while empowering
himself. On the geopolitical front, Loki courted
Doom with a bargain to relocate Asgard from
Oklahoma to Liberia, provided Thor was banished,
a condition that Doom imposed to ensure his realm
did not inherit the God of Thunder. In the
super-criminal underworld, the hood's mystical
connection to Dormammu was severed when
sorcerers including Dr. Strange and Dr. Voodoo
purged the demon's influence and his signature
cloak was lost in battle. Loki exploited the
vacuum, leading the hood and Madamask to Cuba to
recover the Asgardian Nornstones, restoring the
hood's power and making him indebted to Loki. Each
maneuver weakened Ozborn's stability by army
gactors whose loyalties lay with Loki's long game
rather than with Hammer. Within mutant politics,
Frost set conditions that would determine
whether the cabal fractured or endured. As Ozborn
moved to contain the X-Men by constructing a Dark
counterpart team under his authority, similar to
the Dark Avengers. This led to intensified
friction with Namor, who called on an Atlantean
terrorist cell that in turn prompted a
heavy-handed response from Hammer. Namor's
cousin Namor interfered against Ozborn's
horses, also deepening the rift. When the moment
came, Emma Frost revealed herself as a double
agent to the cabal after discovering Charles
Xavier had been tortured in Hammer custody. With
Namor at her side, she turned the Dark X-Men
confrontation into a rout, publicly
undercutting Ozborn's claim to control mutant
affairs and forcing him to accept the new mutant
nation of Utopia near San Francisco, despite his
orders that Namor's head and Frost's heart be
brought to him as trophies. As cracks widened,
Ozborn's control faltered even within the
cabal's council chamber. A confrontation with
Doom escalated until the L'Averian ruler
retaliated with a bio-weapon attack on Avengers
Tower and then walked away from the arrangement,
forcing Ozborn to bring Taskmaster on board. When
Dr. Doom later demanded the Submariner honor
their agreement, Ozborn unveiled the terrible
deterrent he had hinted at from the start, the
Void. The Void hurled Doom through a wall, but it
was actually a Doombot who dissolved into swarms
of mechanical scarabs that overran Avengers
Tower, forcing the Dark Avengers into retreat.
The spectacle exposed Ozborn's dependence on
intimidation and the brittleness of a coalition
held together by threats. The cabal's reputation
among villains did not translate into lasting
leverage. For example, the groups perceived
influence encouraged even warlords such as
Dracula to seek latitude for his European
conquests through Doom, arrangements that Doom
refused to indulge. However, the broader villain
community ultimately turned against Ozborn due
to his own escalation. The act of his dark reign
over the superpowered populace culminated in an
attempted siege of Asgard itself. The overreach
shattered the state façade that had shielded
Ozborn and he was brought down by the combined
efforts of Earth's heroes and public scrutiny.
Ozborn was imprisoned, the Hood and Taskmaster
were apprehended, Loki's body was destroyed in
the battle, Emmafrost and Namor returned to their
ranks and Doom resumed uncontested rule in
Latteria. With its architect disgraced and its
member scattered, the cabal disbanded. However,
years later a new iteration emerged from a
different ethical crisis. The Illuminati were
forced to confront apocalyptic collisions
between universes called incursions that could
only be averted by destroying one of the Earth's
involved. For a time, the Illuminati bore that
burden, but the moral cost grew intolerable.
Everyone but Namor refused to continue
annihilating other worlds to save their own.
Concluding that survival required the will to do
what the others would not, Namor assembled a new
cabal of beings for whom extinction level of
violence was an acceptable instrument of policy.
This included Thanos and his Black Order, whom
you've learned more about in their duel against
Darkseid's elite. In contrast to Ozborn's
backroom government, this version of the cabal
was an operational death squad, aimed at
preserving a single Earth at the expense of all
others. This new group prosecuted its campaign
with Muthas efficiency. Where the Illuminati had
agonized, Namor's cabal acted, detonating
worlds and leaving entire realities in ruins.
Namor's actions destroyed his old alliances. He
didn't just abandon the heroes' methods, he
rejected their entire sense of morality. Each
successful destruction forestalled the next
incursion at the price of incalculable deaths,
and each victory pushed Namor deeper into
reliance on his new allies, whose goals of cosmic
domination and nihilistic balance diverged
sharply from his own. As the final worlds
collapsed toward a final incursion, Namor
ensured that his cabal would not perish with the
dying worlds. Anticipating the end, they secured
passage aboard a specially designed life pod unit
built by an alternate reality, Reed Richards, a
vessel capable of withstanding the universe's
unraveling. Reality gave way into the battle
world, a patchwork planet ruled by Dr. Doom and
composed of various worlds from throughout the
multiverse. The cabal endured the journey there,
but they disbanded as Thanos abandoned their
goals to instead make an attempt for Dr. Doom's
newfound power, only to have his spine ripped out.
And that's the cabal's history. For the person
roster, I'm choosing to forgo some of the key
members, such as Norman Osborn, who was part of our
Sinister Six team duel, Namor, who was part of the
Fantastic Four duel, and Thanos, who was part of
the Black Order duel. But I am including the
original members of Dr. Doom, Emma Frost, the
White Queen, Loki, and the Hood. To round out the
remaining spots, I'm going with two villains who
are members of the cabal in the Avengers Assemble
cartoon, and the contest of champions video game,
and that is Red Skull and Modoc. For the seventh and
final spot, I'm going with a villain who is also a
member of the cabal in the cartoons, and that is the
Hulk's arch nemesis, the leader, who started out
as a janitor named Samuel Stearns, who was exposed
to gamma radiation at the chemical plant where he
worked. It granted him superhuman intelligence
and an enlarged cranium, making him as smart as the
Hulk was strong. He possessed a genius-level IQ,
perfect memory, and the ability to process
information and devise strategies far beyond
human capability. He can communicate
telepathically, move objects with telekinesis,
and can emit gamma radiation blasts from his head.
He has built advanced technology including laser
pistols, kinetic absorption gauntlets, and
teleportation devices. So that's my team to
reiterate you're going up against Dr. Doom,
Ammafrost, Loki, the Hood, Red Skull, Modoc, and
the leader. In a world where fantasies collide and
heroes clash, one podcast network rises above the
rest. Prepare yourself for the ultimate
showdowns in comic books, video games, movies,
and anime. The Dynamite Podcast Network presents
Console Combat, where video game legends brawl
every Monday. Dynamic Duel, where comic book
titans smash every Tuesday. Max Destruction,
where TV and action heroes battle every
Wednesday. And Sendro World, where anime
champions clash every Thursday. Join us as we
speculate on the matches and armed with the power
of mathematical simulations, discover who will
emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
Superheroes are everywhere, but finding good
ones, the kind with officially licensed art,
great fabric, and characters you actually love,
that's where Old Glory wins. Their catalog is
huge. Marvel, DC, heroes, villains, deep cuts,
you name it. If you need a gift or you just want to
upgrade your own lineup, this is the place to
start. And I set you up with their best discount
anywhere. Give 15% off any order with the code at
checkout. That's D-U-E-L at checkout. Go to
OldGlory.com, grab the superhero gear you've
been meaning to get, and use the code Duel to save
instantly. That's OldGlory.com, promo code,
Duel. Now that we got the team's histories and
rosters out of the way, let's speculate on how one
of the thousands of simulated matches will go
between them. The winners determined by
simulations, not the speculation, but it's fun to
imagine how the fight could play out. AG9K, what
are the rules of our speculation? Well, I should
say there are no rules, other than the teams have no
prior knowledge of the other going into the fight.
All they are aware of starting out is that the other
side is a threat that needs to be eliminated. For
the speculation, the groups will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the match
itself, as no environmental statistics are
considered in my simulations. The teams must earn
victory on their own merit. Alright then, let's
get into it. The authority and the cabal meet on the
battlefield. Who goes first? I'm gonna say that
Emma Frost starts out. She's gonna scan the minds
of every member of the authority, and she's gonna
be like, holy crap, I thought we were fucked up
guys. But she delivers all the details to every
other member of the cabal, psychically. Okay, so
the Garden of Ancestral Memory is going to warn the
doctor that he's being brain scanned. And since
all of the members of the authority wear this radio
telepathic nanotech device on their temporal
lobe, the doctor is able to warn all of them that
Emma Frost is psychically scanning them. And so
Jenny Sparks is gonna tell Swift telepathically
to take out Emma Frost. So Swift jets toward her at
hyper speed, Talon's first, and she just slashes
her to rubens. Yeah, it's too bad that the cabal do
everything about the authority now, and they knew
about the nanotech device, and they anticipated
Swift's attack. Because Emma Frost just turns
into Diamond. And so Swift isn't scratching shit.
And Modoc, he's just gonna straight up
disintegrate Swift with an energy beam from his
headband. So now the authority know that the cabal
aren't fucking around. Damn, like that, huh?
Okay. Well, the authority also does not fuck
around. And they're gonna let the cabal know that
by having the engineer duplicate herself into
like six other engineers who all form their
forearms into machine guns, and start firing at
the cabal laying down suppressive fire while
Apollo is going to speed bullets Dr. Doom and
punches 10 head right off of his body. Force field.
Dr. Doom blocks both the bullets from the engineer
and Apollo's attack with a dome force field. And so
the authority are trying to get inside this force
field dome, but it fills up with green smoke hiding
every member of the cabal that's inside of it.
Except that Jack Hawksmore, he's also known as the
king of cities. He has this spatial sense that
allows him to see what they're doing within the
green smoke. And with each of their locations
pinpointed within, he's going to cause the ground
directly beneath them to quickly just launch
upwards, slamming all of them into the ceiling of
the dome shield. And it's going to knock all of them
out, as well as bring down the force field. Oh, oh,
he thinks so, huh? Yeah, when the force field
dissipates and the green smoke clears away, the
only thing that's left there is a green snake that
grows into the size of like a freight train.
Because the hood teleported every member of the
cabal out of the force field just in time, except
for Loki, who was providing a distraction with the
smoke and shape shifting into a giant serpent. And
that snake is just going to wrap around Apollo and
devour him whole. Okay, well, that snake and Loki,
I guess, is going to explode in this blinding light
of energy from Apollo from within. And with Jack
able to sense the cabal teleporting probably
behind them, he's able to warn the others. And
Jenny Sparks generates this powerful arc of
electricity that chains to all of them and
electrocutes them. Yeah, yeah, Jack thinks he's
able to sense the cabal behind him, but only
because of a psychic suggestion by Amarfrost.
Jack doesn't really know anything. He's been
manipulated this whole time. In reality, Jenny
doesn't hit anything with her electricity. And
when the cabal do reappear from the hood's
teleportation, they're actually surrounding
the authority on all sides, including Loki. He
didn't actually get blown up. It was just an
illusion diversion. And the red skull shoots from
a gas gun, his dust of death compound at midnight,
which poisons midnight and just desiccates his
face into a red skull killing him. Midnighter is
going to calculate what red skull is about to do. So
just before red skull pulls the trigger on his gas
gun, midnighters going to hurl his night stick
into Red skull's chest area with enough force that
it impales him. That's going to cause the red skull
to squeeze his trigger as he gets knocked
backward. And he ends up spraying the white queen
in the face, desiccating her and causing her to
die. Well, that's stupid. Two birds with one
stone, I guess. That's right. But the hood is going
to go for the same. He said he's going to up the game
by shooting hellfire bullets from his twin
pistols that are going to curve and hit Jenny
Sparks and Midnighter and to the doctor all in one
shot. Oh, no worries. The doctor, he's going to
transmute those bullets into butterflies and
Jack causes a massive geyser to erupt beneath the
hood that's going to launch him into the air with
boiling hot water. Hot water is not going to affect
the hood. You know, he's like partially possessed
by a demon while wearing the cloak. I don't think
boiling water is going to hurt him if he's not hurt
by like fire, you know, the hood is just going to
teleport off this geyser and then in his demon
form, he's just going to eviscerate Jack
Hawksmore. So Jack is out and then Dr. Doom shoots
an electric blast that fries the engineer
circuits. So she's out too. I'm sorry. Jenny
Sparks controls electricity, like all
electricity around them. So she redirects that
blast toward Modoc, which fries his circuits and
shuts him down. So he's out of the match.
Meanwhile, the doctor seeing the hood demon
exercises the demon using knowledge from an old
priest. And with the hood depowered, the doctor is
going to cause him to just melt into a puddle. So
he's out as well. Okay. Well, Jenny, she suddenly
gets a dagger in the back by Loki, who snuck over to
her and stabbed her. And then he teleports over to
Midnighter and freezes him with an ice blast.
Okay, well, Apollo doesn't appreciate that. So
he's going to fly over and land between Loki and
Midnighter, generating this blending flash of
light to stun Loki before picking up and flying off
with Midnighter to thaw him with heat energy.
Meanwhile, the engineer is going to go up against
Dr. Doom, and they're going to be exchanging laser
blasts as a distraction while her duplicates
maneuver behind him and infect his suit, shutting
it down. You don't think that Doom has protection
from nanite invasion? Like his systems have their
own like mini nano Doom bots that would prevent
such an attack like this. They stop the shutdown,
and then in fact, they remotely hack the
engineer's technology, infecting her with a
virus into her system that turns into like this
uncontrollable swarm of malfunctioning nano
bots. I'm sorry, you don't think engineer has
protection against other nanites? I say it's a
Doom's nano bots that get the virus, infecting his
system and causing all of his armor, like even his
helmet, to fall off revealing his ugly mug. You
can't just repeat my attack. You just literally
did what I did. I say Doom's nanite attack is
superior. You say otherwise. So it looks like we
just have a stalemate, which means that Doom and
the engineer are just going to be glitching each
other in attempts to hack each other with nano
bots. Meanwhile, while that's happening, the
leader, he's going to mind control Apollo into
crushing Midnighter like a grape, just turning
him into this paste that will take way too long for
Midnighter to heal from. Oh damn. Okay. Well, I
guess to prevent the leader from controlling
Apollo into killing everyone else on his team, the
doctor is going to have to kill his own teammate by
sucking all of the light and energy away from
Apollo with this magic black hole, which is also
going to pull him in. But the doctor is also going to
maneuver that black hole over to Loki as well,
vanishing him from the match before sealing that
black hole closed. Okay. So your guy took out both
Apollo and Loki? Yes. Okay. Uh, well, while that's
going on, Dr. Doom manages to out hack the engineer
by using magic, because he can do magic. She can't.
Dr. Doom adds magic to his computer virus that she
can't out hack. So he shuts her down with his magic
nano bots. She's out of the match. And then the
leader is going to fire a gamma mental bolt from his
brain that just fries the doctor's mind and sever
his connection to all those other minds in the
ancestral garden. Okay. For maybe like a second,
because at the last second, the doctor, he's going
to stretch time and that's going to give him enough
time for past doctors in the garden of ancestral
memory to help the doctor regain access to his
body, at which point he's just going to transform
the leader's head into an actual scrotum with
testes instead of brains. So he's out. And it looks
like all we have left is Dr. Doom versus the doctor.
So the doctor is going to end this right away by
having doom be surrounded by his worst nightmare,
a swarm of endless squirrels that devour him whole
leaving nothing but his faceplate in the end.
You're talking about when Dr. Doom was allegedly
quote unquote defeated by squirrel girl. I mean,
it was not alleged it happened. Well, Dr. Doom,
while he's being attacked by the squirrels is
going to remotely activate the time circuitry in
his armor. That's going to rewind time to the point
that the doctor summoned the squirrels and then
doom just casts a mirror spell that results in the
doctor getting eaten alive by his own swarm of
squirrels. Okay, you want to play with time? I'm
going to say that doesn't happen. And instead, the
doctor actually jumps back in time to when doom was
a newborn baby. And he just kills him in the crib.
No, Doom already has a contingency set up as like
this magic trap for anyone who would try to kill him
as a baby. And so the doctor attempts to do this, but
he just gets deatomized by like a trio of demons.
Okay, and then the doctor reatomizes himself and
then kills dooms parents instead. How does he
reatomize himself? This is magic, bitch. But it's
magic deatomization. I guess we have a stalemate
here too. It's Dr. Doom's magic versus the
doctor's magic, except that doom is going to out
magic the doctor by incorporating science into
his magic, which is something the doctor can't do.
So there you go. The cabal wins. Yeah, sorry, magic
trump science. So the cabal loses, in fact. Well,
let's go ahead and leave the match there. Let's run
the simulations. We'll find out which one of these
scenarios happens. Either Dr. Doom manages to out
time magic the doctor or the doctor manages to out
time magic Dr. Doom. It's a weird sentence there,
but let's run the stats and find out what happens.
Agenine K hit it. Inputting data, running
calculations, processing results, simulations
complete. This was a good one. The authority is
hella powerful, except for Swift, which we'll get
into later. The cabal is also hella powerful,
except for Red Skull. So it's kind of probably
fitting that we paired up Swift and Red Skull being
as they were by far the weakest members of each of
our teams. Right. Yeah, we paired up Swift and Red
Skull. We also paired up Apollo and Dr. Doom sort of
in a callback to our Superman versus Dr. Doom
episode. Statwise Midnighter was comparable to
the Hood, Jenny Sparks to White Queen, the
Engineer to Modoc and the Doctor to Loki, and Jack
Hawksmore to the leader. Yeah, that was not a great
matchup, but that was kind of all that was left. But
statwise, as always in our team battles, everyone
went up against everyone else. As we mentioned,
Swift was my weakest character. She had an average
win rate of only 12.3%. Yeah, I thought the most
powerful member of your team was going to be
Apollo, but it was actually the Doctor. And before
this matchup, I had no idea who the Doctor was.
Yeah, the guy's insanely powerful. He's actually
a pretty cool character. I'm glad we pin him up
against Loki. They're both almost omnipotent.
Loki was actually just as powerful as Dr. Doom, who
is incredibly impressive statistically. It's
probably why he beat Superman all those years ago.
He's basically like Batman meets Dr. Strange
meets Iron Man all rolled up into one. So yeah, Dr.
Doom had quite the impressive win rate winning
74.4% of all his matches. Loki won 73.9% of all his
matches. More of the authority characters on my
roster had higher win rates than yours. Four of my
guys had average win rates above 50%. Yeah,
whereas I only had three, which included Dr. Doom,
Loki, and Modok. Although the leader was right
there winning 49.5% of all his matches, so roughly
half. In regards to the overall stat comparison,
the authority just wiped the floor with the cabal
when it came to speed. But the cabal totally
dominated the authority when it came to
intelligence. There were a lot of master minds on
this version of the cabal. So taking all of this
into consideration, Joseph, which team do you
think came out on top in this team duel match? I got
to give it to the cabal. How can you not? There's
Doom. You don't bet against Doom. You don't bet
against the Red Skull, Modok, White Queen, Loki,
Leader, I just I'm naming everybody now. They're
all fantastic. Who the hell is Jack Hawksmore?
That's not even a real name. It's certainly not the
name of someone who deserves to win a match. I mean,
his nickname is also the King of Cities. King of
shitties. I don't know what I'm saying. I think
that Instagram agrees with me because 51% of our
followers who voted in our poll voted for the
cabal. Well, that's now a whole lot at all. Were you
trying to rhyme right there? No. Okay. I mean, any
chance I get? Well, let's find out who won. A.J .9K.
The results, please. The winner in the team duel
matchup between the authority and the cabal is the
cabal. Damn straight. What did you say about me
learning today earlier? What was that, Jonathan?
Are you going to learn something because the cabal
only won 50.6% of the thousands of matches
compared to the authority who won 49.4. This was an
insanely close matchup. That is closer than I
thought it was going to be. Actually, given the
stat discrepancies, I would have figured that the
cabal would have come out more wins ahead. I guess
that means that in the simulations, the team
didn't perform as well as they probably should
have. I'm not going to lie. After we entered all of
the stats, I thought the cabal was going to do a lot
better. I'm not sure what happened there. There
may have been some luck in your favor with that. Not
enough to win though, but I got close. I got real
close, and that's all that matters. It's not who
wins. It's just about having fun. I did have fun
winning. Yeah, you're right. Did you have fun
losing? I mean, not really. You just said it's
about having fun. Whatever. Great job, Marvel
fans. You did it again. Like I said, we're winning
the whole month of November. This is just the
start. AG9K, help close us out. In our next
episode, we are doing another duel, this time
pitting the cowboy, Jonah Hex against the zombie
cyborg, Deathlock. We want to give a big thanks to
our executive producers, Jon Straussky, Zachary
Hepburn, Dustin Belcom, Nathaniel Wegener, Levi
Aitin, Austin Wieselowski, E.J. Dunkerly, Nick
Ibonto, Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Speese,
Dean Malesky, Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, Mike
Williams, and Paul Graves for helping make this
podcast possible. We'll talk to you guys next
week. Up, up, and away, true believers. You will
respect my authoritar.