This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi and welcome
to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe. And I'm its twin
brother Johnny DC. And in this episode, we are
going to review the latest Marvel Studios film
that hit theaters, Thunderbolts, Asterisk. And
no, the Asterisk was not just a stand-in for a
butthole. It did in fact have meaning that we will
discuss later on this episode. If you did not see
the movie, don't spoil yourself on what the
Asterisk meant. Go see the film and then come back
and listen to our spoiler review. I really liked
the Thunderbolts. It's probably my new favorite
Marvel movie. Well, don't give away the whole
show. Save your thoughts on the movie for when we
discuss the movie. I just said I liked it. I didn't
give anything away. Way to go, Jonathan.
Everybody's tuning out now because you're
dumbass. Please stay with us, guys. Because
before we talk about the movie, we're going to
break down the latest comic book movie news this
past week, of which there was just one major news
item. We learned that Ryan Reynolds is writing an
X-Men movie for the MCU, which will feature
Deadpool. An all-Marvel episode. As always, we
list our segment times in our episode
description, so feel free to check out the show
notes if you want to skip ahead to a particular
topic. Our artificially intelligent dual
simulator, AJA9K, has a quick message for our
listeners, so listen up. The dynamic 2.0 tier
gives you access to our Discord chat server. The
Fantastic Four tier gives you two bonus episodes
each month, and the X-Force tier makes you an
executive producer of this show. Lastly, the
Diner Mike podcast network tier lets you create
your own podcast using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and
consultation, and get you simulation results.
Pitch the twins your ideas via email at
dynamicdualpodcast at gmail.com. Check it out at
patreon.com. Thanks AJA9K, and thanks to
everyone who supports the podcast. Guys, be sure
to tune into the other shows on the Diner Mike
podcast network this week, including the console
combat podcast, where hosts John and Dean
simulate battles between popular video game
characters. In yesterday's episode, they
speculated on who would win in a fight between
Isaac Clarke from Dead Space versus Pfft Rittus,
R-T-A-S, Vadom from Halo. Oh god, I'm gonna get
butchered for that. Ritas Vadom. Or Vadom. Vadom?
Is it Vadom? I don't know, please be gentle. Fans.
Over on the Max Destruction podcast, hosts Scotty
and Gilly put your favorite action heroes from
film and television against each other. They are
on a brief season break currently, so now's the
perfect time to get caught up with their past
episodes. And on the Senjou World podcast, host
Zachary Hepburn speculates on fights between fan
favorite anime and manga characters. On
Thursday, Isaac is gonna reveal who would win
between Sunraku from Shangri-La Frontier versus
Kirito from Sword Art Online. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our show
notes to listen to all of the shows in the Diner Mike
podcast network. But with that out of the way,
quick to the no prize. A no prize is an award that
Marvely used to give out to fans. Our version, the
Dynamic Dual No Prize, is a digital award that we
post on Instagram for the person that we feel gave
the best answer to our question of the week. Last
week, we asked you guys, for those of you who have
seen both films, which was better? 2009's
Watchmen or Thunderbolts and why? And we asked
this because last week's episode was a team duel
where we found out who would win in a fight between
the Watchmen and the Thunderbolts. So we kind of
continued it into the film space. We didn't get a
whole lot of answers, we just got two, largely
because there were only so many people out there
listening that could give a valid answer to this
question in time. Our first honorable mention
goes to John Sturrosky, who said, It's John
Sturrosky here. So you guys are asking which is
better, Thunderbolts or Watchmen? And to be
perfectly honest, I can't say either of them is
better than the other one because it's comparing
apples to oranges. And Watchmen, you've got a
universe where the real heroes that we know from
the DC universe don't exist. And Thunderbolts,
it's incorporated into the mainstream universe.
Again, apples to oranges, they're both fantastic
movies though, so let's just get along. John, what
do you think this podcast is all about? You gotta
take a side. Now, I know on the Discord, your server
name is JohnTheFence because you say that you sit
on the fence between both sides. But as you know, we
like to make all of our patrons pick a side between
Marvel and DC. And as the wise man once said, he who
sits on the fence has a stick up his butt. Yes, I have
heard the saying and I 100% agree with it. Yes, so
John gave pretty much a non-answer something
about, Oh, one's in a universe and one's not. I'm
not sure what that has to do with the quality of each
film, but Watchmen was clearly the correct answer
here. Actually, that was Thunderbolts. But you
know, he's saying we're comparing apples to
oranges. Here's the thing, John, oranges are way
better than apples. Fuck oranges. Orange juice.
Orange juice is fucking delicious, right? You can
like segment it off, you know, in little pieces.
Hell yeah, it's a way more versatile fruit.
Oranges all the way. Except with apples, you get
apple jam, which is way better than orange jam. You
get apple soda again, way better than orange soda.
Demand. Apples are clearly the superior fruit.
Wait, wait, wait, what the fuck is apple soda? I've
heard of orange soda. Have you never had an apple
soda? I think maybe I did at one point, but then I
blocked it from my memory because it sucked. You
are a cultured piece of shit. Guys, are you team
Apple or team Orange? Let us know in the comments.
Thanks for the answer, John. But the winner of this
week's No Price is Lorenzo Valdez. Who said? This
is Lorenzo Valdez. I just got back to my condo after
watching Thunderbolts and I really enjoyed it.
Florence Pugh is awesome. The most of the humor
really worked for me, but I can't say it's better
than Watchmen. I mean, Watchmen is such a
beautiful, elegant, thought-provoking, at
times, satirical, epic. And I love Watchmen. Clon
of Forever and Always. Bye-bye. And I love this
answer. Watchmen is all of those things and more.
Don't get me wrong, Thunderbolts is good, but it's
just not at the same caliber as Watchmen. The film
by Zack Snyder is literally a piece of art. It's his
tour de force, in my opinion. The way everything
looked combined with the music, combined with the
acting, combined with the story overall. Muah,
Chef's kiss. Oh, I'm sorry that the Thunderbolts
movie didn't have enough swinging blue dong for
you guys. For a great answer, Lorenzo, you win this
week's no prize, I guess. If you, the listener,
want to shout out winning your own no prize, stay
tuned to later on this episode, when we'll be
asking another question of the week. I gotta say
something. And now that that's done, you're not
gonna let me say anything. On to the news. Alright,
this past week we learned that Ryan Reynolds has
been tasked with developing treatments for a
Deadpool slash X-Men team-up movie. Now, he's
gone on the record before as saying that there's
probably not gonna be another Deadpool solo
movie. I mean, Deadpool and Wolverine wasn't a
Deadpool solo movie. You know, he shared billing
with Wolverine, but it's likely that there's not
gonna be like another standalone Deadpool film.
It's gonna be more along the lines of an ensemble
piece with other mutant characters. Largely,
this is happening because, you know, Deadpool and
Wolverine grossed over a billion dollars at the
box office. And that has made Ryan Reynolds
probably one of the most lucrative talents
working with Marvel Studios at this time. We don't
know too much about the movie other than a few
details that the Hollywood Reporter released,
including the news that the movie is only going to
feature three or four X-Men characters within its
lineup with Deadpool playing a character on the
sidelines as a worm. Alright, so he's not one of the
three or four characters? Correct. So it's gonna
be Deadpool and Wolverine and somebody and
somebody and somebody is a way to look at this.
Well, how do you feel about this? Because, I mean,
technically Deadpool and Wolverine, I guess, was
in the MCU. But this will kind of officially be the
MCU's like first X-Men movie, like a team movie.
Well, we don't know that for sure because there's
another X-Men movie in the works that's being
written by Michael Leslie, who wrote the Hunger
Games films. So that film is an X-Men film that's
different from this Ryan Reynolds Deadpool X-Men
movie. Oh, OK. So either that X-Men movie is gonna
come before this Deadpool team up or Deadpool's
gonna come first. I think what I would like to see as
a fan thinking about what X-Men storylines
Deadpool has been a part of, I think I'd like to see
the Deadpool team up movie come first and then lead
into the first official Marvel X-Men film. And if
they adapted the Messiah complex through the
Messiah War storyline where we see the first
mutant being born and how cable and Deadpool and
basically all the mutants are striving to either
protect or kill or use this child who ends up being
Hope Summers. I think that's a pretty good
foundation story leading into the revelation
that mutants exist in this post-secret wars
Marvel Universe. I don't know about that. For one,
it's kind of paradoxical that they're mutants
hunting the first mutant. But also, I feel like the
sooner we get to a like established Xavier school
with Professor X and Cyclops and Jean Grey at
least, the better. That's true. I mean, honestly,
in terms of how they release these films, I could go
either way. I think, yes, it would be better to have
all the classic X-Men elements in place prior to a
new Deadpool team up movie. But if you were to put
the new Deadpool movie up first, I think there's a
way to adapt the Messiah complex there. And that
way you'd be able to bring back cable and you'd have
Bishop and you could probably have Wolverine back
with Hugh Jackman. Tilly's fucking 90. This is all
speculation, but I will be really interested in
seeing which of these X-Men films comes out first.
I think it's really smart to continue to use Ryan
Reynolds and the Deadpool character. I know the
audiences, including myself, are not really done
seeing films with him. I hope yet he continues
doing this until he's 90 because the cinematic
character of Deadpool is just such a national
treasure. So unique. I'm pretty glad Ryan
Reynolds is getting this win. I think he's a
marketing and writing genius. So I think this
project is in good hands with him. I agree. But
since we don't know who's going to be in this
Deadpool X-Men team up movie, that brings us to our
question of the week. Including Deadpool, what
should be the roster for the X-Men Deadpool team up
film? Again, we're looking for three to four
characters because that's the number that the
Hollywood Reporter gave. So we want to know who you
would like to see in that film. Recording your
answer at dynamicdool.com by clicking on the red
microphone button in the bottom right hand corner
of the screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long and don't forget to leave your name in case we
include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a Dynamic
Dool No Prize that we'll post to Instagram. Be sure
to answer before May 10th. The Dark Knight's
definitive DC comic stories adapted directly for
audio for the very first time. Fear. I have to make
them afraid. He's got a motorcycle. Get after him
or have you shot? You mean blow up the building.
From this moment on, none of your safe. New
episodes every Wednesday, wherever you get your
podcasts. But that does it for all the news for this
episode, so let's go ahead and get into our main
event, where we review the latest Marvel Studios
film to hit theaters, Thunderbolts. Astros.
Thunderbolts. Thunderbolts was directed by Jake
Schreer and stars Florence Pugh, Sebastian Stan,
David Harbour, Julia Louis-Dreyfus, Wyatt
Russell, Hannah John-Cammond, and Lewis
Pullman. The film is the fifth and final film of
Marvel's Phase 5, though we won't completely be
out of this phase until the Iron Heart television
series, which will be released in June. And then
Phase 6 will start in July with the Fantastic Four
for Steps Movie. One of my bigger takeaways
walking out of the movie was that there were little
to no surprises in the film plot-wise. I think even
in the confines of this podcast, just us
speculating on the film based on the trailers, you
and I guessed most of what the movie would be, say
for the end credits scene. It's not a complicated
film with a complex story. That being said, if you
haven't seen it yet, I would still recommend going
to go see it because it's worth it. Just because the
plot is simple doesn't mean that the movie is not
good. Go see the movie, then come back and listen to
our spoiler review. It also doesn't mean that the
movie is not a spectacle that should be watched on
the biggest screen possible. Yeah, there's a lot
of practical action in this movie. It foregoes CGI
a lot, and I think that was pretty cool to see on the
big screen. So yeah, I'm starting out by saying
that the plot is simple and straightforward, but
the story is simple in the way something like
Reservoir Dogs is. That is to say, the plot is
uncomplicated, but the characters are anything
but. The film really is more of a character study in
that it takes these very unique, established,
anti-heroic characters and spends its time
exploring who they are and how they interact more
than doing stuff like expositing or world
building. That's pretty unique for a Marvel
Studios project, and so right off the bat, the film
has an identity that's all its own that sets it
apart from its contemporaries. Where you could
describe the typical Marvel film as, you know,
exciting, funny, action-packed, flashy. The
Thunderbolts film could be described as more
authentic, snappy, you know, it's nuanced, it's
mature. It's still loads of fun, though. And I'm
not going to say that these descriptors make
Thunderbolts better than other Marvel films if
there are people out there thinking that I'm
knocking your average Marvel fare, but I do think
that it's fresher and therefore more important
for the genre as a whole, which seems to be flagging
among general audiences, you know, and could use
some fresh material like this movie. Yeah, this is
very different from, say, Captain America Brave
New World, which felt more like a typical Marvel
film to me. Thunderbolts is exactly what I was
hoping would come from Marvel Studios,
considering we're kind of experiencing a genre of
fatigue amongst the film-going audiences
currently. And I think this was a really smart
release on behalf of Marvel. And probably a cheap
one, too. I mean, there's really only two, like,
major locations throughout the entire film,
which surprised me. Yeah, there's the Ox Vault in,
like, Utah, and then there's the Watchtower in
Manhattan. And really, the film takes place over a
matter of hours, if not, like a day or so. Again, the
story is pretty straightforward, and in that
regard, I think, less is more. It gave us time to
really sit down and observe these incredibly
complex characters in a way that we normally
wouldn't otherwise if they're, you know, like the
Eternals circumventing the globe and setting up
all this backstory and world-building for the
future. The movie, in effect, is almost the
Anti-Eternals. That's exactly what I was
thinking as I was walking out of the theater.
Really? Just comparing the Century to someone
like Icarus, I was like, man, I kind of wish the
Eternals didn't come out until, like, years from
now, as opposed to when it did, because it kind of
ruined a lot of future Marvel films, in a way, I
think, because it was just so large in scale and
would obviously affect the larger Marvel world in
a way that they probably weren't ready for. To me,
the Century was much more interesting of a
character than Icarus was. Yeah, I totally agree.
That being said, I also liked Eternals. I liked how
kind of existential it was and how it also took a
different approach to the superhero genre,
albeit, you know, a less successful one. You know,
we did have someone on the Discord, and I can't
remember off the top of my head who, so I'm sorry for
not giving credit where credit is due, but someone
posited that perhaps the Golden Century Serum
that was created by Project Century in this movie
used a bit of like Eternals DNA or something in
there, in conjunction with the Super Soldier
Serum, because the way the Century would
sometimes glow golden was semi-reminiscent of
how the Eternals powers would manifest visually.
Yeah, we never quite learned how they developed
the Century Superpowers, did we? No, I mean, it's
just as vague as it was in the comic books, you know,
where the government was trying to recreate the
Super Soldier Serum, and so they outsourced it to a
bunch of subcontractors, and then this high
school chemist professor ended up cracking the
case, and then one of his students, Bob Reynolds,
broke into his lab and then drank the formula in an
attempt to get high. You know, they don't go too
much into the specifics into, you know, what went
into the cauldron, as it were. We just know that it
worked. And actually, one of the things I really
like about this film is how I didn't feel that
despite all these different characters having
all of these different histories from other
Marvel projects, like films and television
series, that it felt like I needed to do homework
before watching it. Like, honestly, I feel like
this could have been the first Marvel film I had
ever seen, and I still would have mostly
understood everything. It was very standalone in
that way. For sure. I mean, the film is somewhat a
quasi-sequel to the first Black Widow film, but it
also continues the story from the Captain America
franchise and the Falcon and the Winter Soldier
and Ant-Man and the Wasp. But nowadays, you know,
that's not too much homework compared to some of
the other Marvel films that have come out. This
movie was less interested in continuity, and
really, it seems like The Thunderbolts was made by
people who were less interested in the MCU as a
whole, less interested in, you know, CGI and the
colorful spectacle, and they were more
interested in practical action, grounded tones.
They were less concerned with the big players and
more interested in creating these portraits of
the universe's more sidelined characters. And
that's to the film's benefit and detriment, I
think, because on one hand, you get these
interesting explorations of themes like
depression and introspection, but on the other
hand, you have a film that treats some characters
like Taskmaster and Songbird with such apathy for
the source material that they probably didn't
even need to be in the film to begin with. As a fan,
mostly as a comic book fan, that sucks. Yeah,
Taskmaster was definitely done dirty here. I
don't understand why they chose to even include
her honestly, and regarding Songbird, I didn't
even know that was Songbird, or I wouldn't have
known if you would not have mentioned it like last
episode. For sure, yeah, they were both done
dirty. Like, Taskmaster was included in the
marketing material, but she really only had one
line of dialogue this film and probably under a
minute of action, and she was badass in the minute
that she had. You know, I understand that fans were
disappointed with the revelation in the Black
Widow film that Taskmaster was Antonia Drakov,
but like, wasn't the character at the very least
worth redemption? And at the most, wasn't she
still a fucking badass? I think considering
Taskmaster's backstory in the MCU and her power
set, and even, you know, the actor who plays her,
Olga Korylenko, I think she would have made for an
interesting conclusion into this story. And
yeah, the filmmakers may say that they took her out
early in order to set the stakes for the film, but
they treated her death as an afterthought. Like,
there was like little to no impact there to even
make those stakes feel earned. Like, if they were
going to kill her as a way to set the stakes, they
should have had the Void killer during his fight
with the Thunderbolts in order to increase the
stakes there. Like, that would have been
impactful. Yeah, or the Void accidentally killed
her during their escape from the vault. Like, she
fell down the elevator shaft or something like
that. Something like that. That would have been
more shocking than what happened. And as for
Songbird, like, I thought they included Melissa
Gold in this film because she was eventually going
to become the hero's Songbird, even if it was at the
end as an end credit stinger or something. Like,
how do you include who is perhaps the most iconic
and tenured member of the Thunderbolts from the
comics and not have her in this movie with her sonic
powers or any reference to her heroic persona?
Like, the Melissa Gold character in this film
could have been literally anybody. Her name could
have been like Trixie Tinklemuffin or whatever,
and the movie would have been exactly the same.
It's like putting Harley Quinn in a Suicide Squad
film and then just making her an assistant to
Amanda Waller. Well, I think it would have been
like her as Harley and Quinzel sort of setting up
the character. That's what I got from this film. I
got no impression that we were ever going to see
that assistant Melissa character again ever. I
mean, when Valentina said that she was getting a
lesson in loyalty or something like that, I
thought there she was going to get like her sonic
powers, but then nothing came of that. I'm not sure
it really would have fit into the film though.
Maybe not, but like again, even as an end credit
stinger, something like that. You just can't put
the most iconic Thunderbolts member from the
comics in this movie and not have any reference to
Songbird whatsoever. Yeah, I guess they could
have done that instead of the Wheaties box thing.
Yeah, exactly. That was funny though. It's kind of
like they put Songbird in this movie for
fanservice and then forgot to service us. Oh,
shit. Like what's the opposite of fanservice? Fan
disrespect. There you go. There you go. I feel very
disrespected as a fan. In the grand scheme of the
film though, those gripes could be considered
nitpicking probably. I don't want my bitching to
negate the big thematic swings that the film took
in terms of things like self loathing and mental
health and what heroism looks like for people who
do not see themselves as heroes. That's stuff
that's not really explored in a lot of other
superhero movies. Yeah, exactly. You mentioned
that the film felt like it was made by people who
were less interested in the MCU and more
interested in the characters. I kind of felt like
it was made by people who were more interested in
theme. And like you mentioned, the whole theme
here is pretty much mental illness. Yeah, it's a
big one. You know, heroism is also a major theme. I
like what the film had to say about all of that
because like, you know, we've gotten projects
with anti-heroes in them, like The Punisher or
Black Adam, but it's rare to see a project with an
anti-hero questioning whether they could be an
actual hero. And I think that's fascinating.
Like, what if The Punisher felt guilty over his use
of guns and instead picked up a shield? What if
Black Adam took notes from Shazam? How would it
speak to their tragic histories? How would it
redefine them as characters? Like, I'm not saying
that all anti-heroes should go through this
journey. They shouldn't, you know, betray who
they are. But going from an anti-hero to a hero, I
think, is a pretty interesting thought
experiment that they did well here in The
Thunderbolts. Yeah, it's one that Bucky, I feel
like, has been going through for a long time and
seeing that other characters in the MCU could
relate with that and kind of go on that journey with
him. Even though the film primarily focuses on
Yelena, I thought that was a cool dynamic and good
for a team of characters within Marvel.
Absolutely. I want to talk more about that in the
character breakdown, but before we get there, I do
want to touch on the asterisk. The asterisk pretty
much meant what we all thought it would mean in that
The Thunderbolts team was not really The
Thunderbolts, but actually a New Avengers team.
Like, when I saw that on the screen, I was like, oh
yeah, called it, but it made me think that you have
to admire Marvel's tenacity in not marketing this
film as a New Avengers movie. Because I think
calling this movie New Avengers probably would
have accounted for a bigger box office opening. I
mean, this movie got a decent box office, but, you
know, The Thunderbolts name is not a household
brand like The Avengers is. They could have easily
called this movie New Avengers, and they chose not
to, for the sake of art, we'll say. And I think
that's pretty admirable. Although I think the
whole thing was made moot by the end credits scene
where it's revealed that, oh hey, they're not
actually The New Avengers. So they really are The
Thunderbolts. They are The New Avengers. They're
just not the only Avengers out there. They're
Avengers with a Z, right? Oh my gosh. I mean, it
happened in the comic books where you had
simultaneous Avengers teams going, especially
around the events of Norman Osborn's Hammer
Organization, where he had his Avengers team, and
then you had the mighty Avengers, led by Luke Cage.
So this dilemma is not without precedence within
the comic book. They were really fighting over,
like, who was the true bearers of the Avengers
legacy, and I think that's an interesting thing to
explore. But you didn't answer my question about
Marvel's boldness in how they chose to market this
film. Slow clap for Marvel. Thank you. Slow clap.
Yeah. I don't really give a shit. Well, you're just
a sellout, so whatever. Well, okay. I have no idea
what that means, but sure. Let's go to move on to our
character breakdown. Starting with Black Widow,
a.k .a. Yelena Belova, played by Florence Pugh.
Now Florence Pugh is such an interesting Yelena
Belova, largely because of how, like, deadpan and
dry she is as an actress. I'm not sure if any other
actor could pull this version of Yelena off like
she does. I think it makes her more interesting
than a lot of her peers, including, dare I say it,
Scarlett Johansson as the Black Widow. In that
Yelena has a lot more going for her
personality-wise in that she's funny, but she's
also flawed. She's also very endearing. She goes
in this movie from being in a very deep depression
to refinding herself in a new family, The
Thunderbolts, that's not too dissimilar from the
family she had as a kid with Natasha and Melina and
Alexi. It's Alexi who helps her see past her own
flaws that she only sees in herself and helps her
realize that she's already more of a hero than she
likely ever thought she could be. I thought that
was a fascinating journey. It's interesting to
hear you say that you think Yelena Belova is more
interesting than Natasha. Right when you said
that, I was like, is that true? And I think it is,
actually, because they really had a fight to give
Natasha a personality in a film like Avengers Age
of Ultron with the backstory that, oh, she's sad
because she can't have children. But it's like
that kind of felt like it was a few films too late, I
suppose. Whereas with Yelena, you're right,
she's a lot more funny than Scarlett Johansson's
Black Widow. And I love just the tragic backstory
that they continue to expand upon for the
character. Well, I mean, Yelena's backstory is
the same as Natasha's backstory, right? So
they're very similar characters in that regard.
They both grew up in the red room and had to go
through horrible things to get where they are. But
Yelena's personality manifested a little bit
differently than Natasha's. You know, I think
Scarlett Johansson's character was well used in
films like The Winter Soldier or Civil War or even
her own film Black Widow. I think it was nice to get
the differences between the two sisters there.
But I don't think anyone would deny that Florence
Pugh's Yelena Belova is just a terribly
fascinating character. She's more spunky. Yeah.
Let's move on to The Winter Soldier, aka Bucky
Barnes, played by Sebastian Stan. You know,
Sebastian Stan's great as always as the
character. Here, Bucky really serves as the team
leader. You know, he's the precedent for taking
your sins from the past and transforming them from
a source of guilt to an impetus for change. He is the
template from which the rest of the characters can
base their journey off of because he's been
through it. And what's interesting is that here,
his journey takes him to Congress where he serves
as a representative for the New York City area,
which I thought was interesting. It was a strange
choice considering, I don't think, political
diplomacy and blowing up bad guys really go hand in
hand. And really, I'd be shocked if he was still a
congressman by the time we see him next as a new
Avenger, which makes me wonder why they even
bothered to put Bucky into politics to begin with.
I wouldn't say it was 100% necessary for this film.
It kind of seems like an element that they wanted to
explore early on, but then just kind of abandoned
while writing the script. But I think they
explained that he, by joining the Thunderbolts
team, pretty much resigned his role as a
congressman. Yeah, I think they did say that. It
was implied at least by Valentina. Right. To me, I
thought Bucky was sort of the least interesting
character in this film. I don't know if it's
because we've gone through his whole arc pretty
much already, but it also kind of felt like
Sebastian Stan was kind of just going through the
motions with the role. I mean, that's the Bucky
character, you know, he's tired. He's been
through a lot. He's fucking 100 years old. And
yeah, he's probably gone through most of his
journey, but it is nice to see him taking up the
torch for other characters in his place. That's
definitely an interesting direction to take the
Winter Soldier. I hope that as a member of the New
Avenger, The Avengers. They give his arm all the
cool upgrades that he has in the comic books like
the Metal Spike, the Taser arm, and like the
Flamethrower. I think that'd be pretty badass.
Let's go ahead and move on to US Agent, aka John
Walker, played by Wyatt Russell. Wyatt Russell
does a great job of playing the guy that you love to
hate to love. His John Walker is so believably a
douchey asshole, yet somehow still charismatic
enough to make you root for him as US Agent. I think
it's because he fills his performance with enough
insecurity behind his facade that you know that
he's not actually coming from a place of arrogance
necessarily, but from a place of deep hurt. And I
think that makes him endearing. His whole arc was
about wanting to be a hero that could live up to the
legacy of Captain America and he failed in The
Falcon and the Winter Soldier show. He failed in
his eyes and he failed in the public eye. So by the
end of that show, he became more of an agent for
Valentina and by the end of this film, he's
stepping back into that hero role and you could
tell he was a little bit reticent to go back there,
but he did it anyway because that's probably his
calling. Yeah, next to Yelena, he was probably my
favorite character in the film. I didn't really
like him in The Falcon and the Winter Soldier
because of how much of a douchebag he was, but
somehow, yeah, you're right, that made him
endearing in this movie and relatable in a way
because, you know, as a father, I'm probably
guilty of looking at my phone when I should
probably be interacting with my daughter. So that
kind of cut deep. Oh, yeah, I think as parents
nowadays, we've all done that, but his big mistake
was that he left his family. Oh, I thought they left
him. Yeah, one of those two things, but it just
added to the tragedy because like Ghost was asking
Kim how he balanced it all and he's just like, you do
what you got to do. And then later on, it was
revealed as they were chained up in the garage that
he wasn't even a family man anymore. He didn't have
everything. He didn't have it all. A quick note
here. I really love how by when the end credits came
along, he still had his shield taco. It was like how
many months later after the events of this film was
the end credits and yet he was still sticking with
that bent shield almost like he had come to just
accept it. I thought that was hilarious. I thought
that was super dumb. I did not get that. Let's go
ahead and move on to the Sentry, aka Bob Reynolds,
played by Lewis Pullman. It sucks so much to see how
much of a revelation Lewis Pullman was in this
role, to see how much nuance and believability the
actor brought to this very difficult role and yet
still wonder how Stephen Yuen would have pulled it
off. Oh, no, just watching this, I was like, this
actor was so perfect for this role. I am so glad they
replaced Stephen Yuen. I mean, it's Yuen's loss,
right? Because the Sentry has long been one of
Marvel's most psychologically complex heroes.
And it seems like such a meaty role for any actor to
sink his teeth into. Oh, yeah. I thought Pullman
brought layers to his performance with every
subtlety, every weird posture or shy smile or hand
twitch. I think he realistically portrayed
mental illness in a way that felt, I guess,
respectful for those who suffer from any
psychological affliction. It just felt real and
not like a caricature of mental illness. You know,
there were times where he was scary and there were
times where he was funny. There were times where he
was heartwrenchingly sympathetic. I think his
Bob Reynolds is by far one of the MCU's most
interesting characters. And I can see him growing
in the role in much the same way Tom Hiddleston did
as Loki, because there's just so much going on
behind the performance and so much space to
explore and to grow from here. I have never been a
big fan of the Sentry as a character. I always kind
of saw him as an April Fools Superman knockoff
character. But his performance made me really
appreciate aspects of the Sentry that I hadn't
really before. Yeah, the whole mental illness
thing is unique to the character, right? He is Bob
Reynolds, the addict. He is also the Sentry, the
all powerful hero. He is also the void, a soul
leading pit of darkness. I was surprised that they
went as hard into that as they did with this film. I
thought maybe they were just going to kind of
tangentially address that. But no, that whole
relationship of the beings that are the Sentry
kind of became the crux of the film. Oh, yeah, no,
absolutely. I mean, it was the stakes of the film.
It was the climax of the film, them going up against
this dark side of the character. I jokingly texted
you right after I saw the movie saying that this
film was essentially an MCU version of My Little
Pony and the whole like friendship is magic thing.
And the bad guys defeated in the end by a group hug.
That said, they did an unbelievably good job of
making that work for the audience in a way that
surprised me. Well, I didn't know what you meant by
that My Little Pony text message that you sent me
because I'm not a brony like you. OK, I have two
daughters that are older than your daughter. I
still I have no idea what reference I've never
watched My Little Pony. So I don't know exactly
what you're saying. I'm saying everything was
solved by the power of friendship and a group hug at
the end. It's not like they defeat the void in the
comic books in any less roundabout manner. In the
books, they have to defeat the void by essentially
making everybody forget about the Sentry and Bob
Reynolds and the void to begin with. There's no
easy solution there. You can't just take him down
by force. So I don't I don't begrudge the film
taking that kind of approach of the group hug,
where really they're trying to solve the issue of
the void through therapy, right? Well, I don't
begrudge it either. That's what I'm saying. I'm
saying like I feel like I should, but they did it so
well that I don't. Yeah. I mean, one of the main
themes of the movie was mental illness. So the fact
that it was therapy that helped solve everything.
I think that's what makes it work. What did you
think of the Sentry's powers in this movie?
Because they were a little bit different from what
they are in the comic. Yeah, they focused a lot more
on telekinesis, which is not really something
that I know the Sentry to have in the books. For the
void, they really focused on his telepathic
powers, which I thought was pretty interesting.
He was kind of like a psychic entity on the astral
plane, right? He was bringing all these people
into his astral realm where they would live out
their biggest regrets in life or their most
depressing moments or something like that. It was
different from what I know in the books, but I
wouldn't say that it's out of the concept for the
Sentry. You know, the Sentry is supposed to be this
all powerful being void is supposed to be this soul
sucking dark creature. I think it all works. In the
future, I would like to see them use less
telekinesis for the character and focus more on
his strength. I don't know if they were just doing
that in an attempt to make him seem less like
Superman or not, but it was strange to me. I want to
see them focus more on his light powers. Yes. Yeah,
that would be good. Let's move on to Red Guardian,
a.k .a. Alexi Shostakov, played by David Harbour.
I love David Harbour in this role. You know, we
mentioned he was great in the Black Widow movie,
mostly as comic relief. And he plays the role of
comic relief in this movie, too. But he also serves
as a beacon for the team and especially Yelena on
how to be a hero. He was the first one in Manhattan to
just do what was right and do what came naturally to
him by saving these people. And he seemed to see the
heroic side in his teammates and believed in them
more than they believed in themselves. And he
cheered them on. It was awesome. But his arc was
interesting in that, you know, you can view it
cynically because I was trying to think about what
his motivations were. And you could say that he was
pushing a heroic agenda on these people so that he
could selfishly live out his old glory days. But I
think when you look at David Harbour's
performance, it kind of pushes that cynicism away
because there's such honesty to his optimism and
in his lovable buffoonery. Yeah, he's just
excited about being a hero and helping people.
There's perks that come with it, and he definitely
takes advantage of those. Like the Weedies box.
Yeah, exactly. But I also felt like he genuinely
wants to help. Yeah, he was a great mentor figure in
this movie. And I liked him here a lot more than I did
in the Black Widow movie. There he kind of got
annoying to me. And I thought he was going to be
annoying in this film as well. But I was just
surprised to think about how well he helped direct
Yelena's arc through the conversations he had
with her at the beginning. And right before the
climax, it worked really well. I don't think David
Harbour was annoying in the Black Widow film. I
thought it was great. I did think his character was
annoying in the What If episode that he shared with
Bucky. I think the dynamic that we got between the
Winter Soldier and the Red Guardian in this movie
was better than that entire What If episode. Oh,
yeah. Regarding his look, it was nice to see him
cleaned up during the Weedies mid-credits scene.
But then by the time the end credits scene rolled
around, he was back to having a completely shaped
head with a really long wild man beard. So I thought
that was a little bit weird the way they jumped
between his looks from the movie to the
mid-credits scene to the end credits scene. The
inconsistency just was strange. Yeah, all of
those characters had interesting looks in the
final end credits scene. I didn't really care for
any of them, honestly. Really? Yeah. They all look
like wigs, right? Right. It was just a little too
polished, a little too like 70s. I don't know.
Well, that's how they'll look in the upcoming
Avengers Doomsday movie because the end credits
scene was filmed on that set. Let's go ahead and
move on to Ghost, a.k .a. Ava Star, played by Hannah
John-Kamen. So Ghost was a character that
appeared in this film. Yeah, she didn't really
contribute to anything too much other than
getting them out of the vault. Yeah, I feel like
there's not a whole lot to say about Ghost. She
seemed really just along for the ride, for the most
part, without any notable motivations or
character building. We do know from Ant-Man and
the Wasp that she had a painful childhood with her
chronic quantum instability. You know, we know
that she became an assassin for Shield and tried to
steal the quantum tunnel from Hank Pym, and was
subsequently healed at the end of that movie by
Janet Van Dyne. But I don't think I learned
anything really new about Ghost in the
Thunderbolts movie. And I'm sure there are like
probably things from her past that she regrets,
but we never got to see any of that. We never got any
specifics on her regrets. I think it would have
been nice to have gotten a vision from the void with
her character. Or any of the other characters
besides Yelena and US Agent. Right. Really, Ghost
just seemed to hang around because she has a cool
power set. But I feel like the character of
Taskmaster probably would have been more
interesting to explore in terms of past regrets
and becoming a hero. I don't know. I'm still just
salty about Taskmaster at the end of the day. Let's
move on to the Contessa Valentina Allegra da
Fontaine, played by Julia Louis-Dreyfus. Julia
Louis-Dreyfus is a whole lot of fun to watch
because she's such an intelligent actor who can
deliver lines like they were all written by Aaron
Sorkin or something like that. I think that's her
special ability as an actress. Really, much of the
dialogue in this movie was written by Joanna
Collow, who wrote The Bear for FX. So that may have
something to do with how enjoyable Julia's
performance was. But I thought she was great. She
was actually more enjoyable in this role than I
thought she was going to be. I do wish that we got
more information on her motivations. Like we did
get a vision with her character where she was a
young child in Italy and her parents were freedom
fighters going up against the suppressive
regime. Or maybe it was a mob thing. It wasn't quite
clear because she's certainly not old enough to be
a child during like World War Two. But whatever
happened there didn't really serve to inform her
decisions in this movie, unless that is to say she
learned that fear and power can be valuable tools
in life. I'm not quite sure what to read off of that
memory that she had. But there's still a lot of
questions around her character, like is she
acting alone? We never really got to learn things
like that here. I kind of got the impression that
her character is all about having more power than
anyone else who can use it against her. Because
what she witnessed as a child left her feeling very
powerless. And she is threatened by other
countries like Wakanda, who may again be more
powerful than her and she doesn't want that.
That's a great way to read into it. Yeah, her
character is very, very similar to Amanda Waller,
who I think has a similar viewpoint in regards to
power and obtaining power and using power because
of her tragic backstory as well. I very much saw
Valentina as the analog of Amanda Waller in this
film. Yes, like she's Amanda Waller, but with an
actual personality. How dare you, sir? Biola
Davis would kick your ass for saying that. And I'll
have Julie Louis Dreyfus backing me up. She has way
more personality than Amanda Waller. Probably my
favorite moment in the film involves Valentina
when the century just kicked the asses of the
Thunderbolts characters and they're going down
in the elevator and she's like, and you're going to
do what I say. And he's like, why? And then she just
looks at him and she's like, what? I loved that
moment. It was just perfectly acted by Julie Louis
Dreyfus and Louis Pullman. I'll tell you about my
favorite moment when we get into the story
highlights. In a world where fantasies collide
and heroes clash, one podcast network rises above
the rest. Prepare yourself for the ultimate
showdowns in comic books, video games, movies and
anime. The Dynamite Podcast Network presents
Console Combat, where video game legends brawl
every Monday. Dynamic Duel, where comic book
titans smash every Tuesday. Max Destruction,
where TV and action heroes battle every
Wednesday. And Cendro World, where anime
champions clash every Thursday. Join us as we
speculate on the matches and armed with the power
of mathematical simulations, discover who will
emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com
where we settle the debate and settle the score. In
Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia, mercenary Yelena Beloba
destroys evidence of a lab belonging to the OXE or
Ox Corp. In Washington, D.C., CIA director
Valentina Allegra de Fontaine testifies in her
impeachment trial, where a congressional
subcommittee investigates her involvement in
Ox's potential illegal activity, including
human experimentation to create superhumans.
Defending her actions as necessary in a world
without Avengers, she orders her assistant
Melissa Gold to destroy all of Ox's evidence and
loose ends. After visiting her surrogate
paternal figure, Alexi, Yelena resolves to
better her life and come out of her depression by
becoming more of a hero like her late sister. She
accepts a mission from Valentina to stop a
corporate spy at a covert ox vault in Utah. I
thought the opening scene was really well done.
You know, a lot of the marketing of the film went
into Florence Pugh's actual practical stunt of
diving off of the Madurka 118 in Kuala Lumpur. It
was actually a pretty impressive stunt that I
thought did a great job with like its natural
lighting and everything like that, of really
setting the tone of the cinematography and the
practical action that we would be getting in the
course of the film. Yeah, I believe that's the
second tallest building in the world if I'm not
mistaken. Right, yeah. Arriving at the vault,
Yelena finds evidence of Project Sentry before
being attacked by US agent John Walker, who in turn
is attacked by Taskmaster, who is in turn attacked
by Ghost Yelena's target. After a fight in which
Ghost kills Taskmaster, the group meets Bob, who
stumbled out of an ox containment pod. Confused,
they determined that they've all worked for
Valentina and were sent to the vault to be
eliminated as loose ends. At a gala in Washington,
DC, New York congressman, Bucky, tries to
convince Valentina's assistant, Melissa, to
divulge incriminating information on her.
Despite the fact that Taskmaster went out dirty at
the end of that fight scene, I did think that was a
pretty damn cool fight scene that was kind of
reminiscent to how we describe and speculate the
battles within our dual episodes. You know, it was
like a lot of like causality. This leads to this
leads to this leads to this. I thought there was
just kind of like a great story kind of being told
through the action of their fight. It may be wonder
like what all their stats were and what it would
look like if I plugged them all into the simulator.
Yeah, it was a really cool fight. I don't think I've
mentioned this yet, but I really like Ghost's new
look in this film. They all looked really cool. I
don't know, but I really liked her look in M.N. and
the Wasp, too. Her white suit, that was pretty
badass. I do like her new helmet, though. Yeah,
yeah, that's really cool. Back in the vault, the
group escapes being incinerated. While making
contact with Bob, Yelena has a vision of a
childhood memory when she got another girl
killed. Valentina learns about the group's
survival in the vaults and plans to send a squad
after them, a plot that Alexi overhears as her limo
driver. Melissa reaches out to Bucky and lets him
know that Valentina is plotting something at the
ox vault. Which, holy cow, how irresponsible of
Valentina to just riff in the back of a limo and let
the limo driver hear what she's saying. Yeah, it
was a little convenient, especially having Alexi
turn out to be the limo driver. But, I don't know, I
also thought it was kind of clever, story-wise.
Yeah, it was a nice way to get him involved. Yeah.
Back of the vault, the group, jokingly referred to
by Yelena as the Thunderbolts, her Peewee soccer
team, attempts to climb an elevator shaft. At the
top, Walker has a memory of his family leaving him,
a vision also induced by contact with Bob. They
fight some of Valentina's forces, taking their
gear as a disguise and attempt to steal a truck to
escape. When stopped at a checkpoint, Bob creates
a diversion by drawing enemy fire and is revealed
to be invulnerable. Thunderbolts escape as Bob
attempts to fly, but he crash lands and is
captured. The elevator shaft scene was
horrifying in some aspects. Oh yeah, absolutely.
Like, not only did it trigger claustrophobia in
me, but also it made me really not want to skip leg
day the next day I ever do leg day, because that
would have sucked. Yeah, that would have been
really hard. It was funny how it seems to work and
then they got to the top and they were like, well,
what happens now? And I was like, oh yeah, what does
happen now? It was an interesting ethical
experiment because there was no way that they all
would be able to survive, despite the fact that
they all needed each other to even get to the top of
the shaft. Right. The way they pulled it off,
though, I thought was pretty neat. And by pull it
off, I mean, survive US agents general
douchebaggery. It did make me wonder why, though,
if Yelena had a grappling hook, launcher,
mantetour, wrist, which she used to save Bob, she
could have easily used that to get to the top of the
elevator shaft, or at least, you know, get all of
them through the shaft safely. That's true. Yeah,
she definitely could have used it as a means to get
them all up. And really, Bob wouldn't have died
from that fall either. He would have found out that
he was invulnerable and then probably learned how
to fly from there. But I thought it was an exciting
moment nonetheless. Yeah, definitely. As the
Thunderbolts escape into the desert, they are
rescued by a lexie in his limo and are pursued by an
ox military convoy. They're saved by Bucky on his
motorcycle, who captures the team in order to
bring them in as evidence against Valentina. In
New York, Bob is brought to the former Avengers
Tower, renamed by Valentina as the Watchtower.
She manipulates him into becoming a hero under her
control known as the Sentry. Holding the
Thunderbolts in a garage, Bucky learns from
Melissa and corroborates with the team that Bob's
power and instability will threaten New York.
Now, this brings me to my favorite moment in the
movie, which I think was the funniest moment,
which was the Molotov cocktail, where you have
this thrilling chase and a lexie is yelling for the
vodka and they give it to him and he like takes a
swig. You're not sure where he's going with this.
You think maybe he's just getting drunk, but he
creates a Molotov cocktail out of it, lights it on
fire like a badass. He tosses it out of the window
and it bullseyes the convoy exactly as he intended
to little to no effect, which was the joke. But it
was a good throw, right? It was a great throw. Just
the subversion that I thought was so hilarious. I
really liked how the redesign of the Avengers
Tower by Valentina was making it look more like the
Sentry Watch Tower in the comic books, where I had
those like black curved elements coming out the
side of it. I thought that was a really clever way to
incorporate the Sentry's headquarters into that
building, because in the comic books, he had
established his headquarters on top of Stark
Tower when he was a member of the New Avengers.
That's right. Yeah, totally forgot about that. He
was a member of that team. The Thunderbolts crash
their van into the Watch Tower where they're
invited to the penthouse to meet Bob as the Sentry.
Valentina reveals her plan for the Thunderbolts
to be discredited as rogue criminals in the media
when they try to stop the Sentry, now branded as
Earth's mightiest hero. The team tries to defeat
Bob anyway and are easily defeated and forced to
retreat. Bob's instability has him turn on
Valentina and he transforms into the Void. As most
of the Thunderbolts give up after their defeat,
they witness the Void begin terrorizing
Manhattan. One by one, they begin doing what they
can to save who they can. It was pretty telling to me
how in the fantastic scene where the Thunderbolts
characters meet with Valentina at the penthouse,
and she just begins insulting each and every one of
them, except for Ghost, who she's just like, oh
yeah, Ghost. Oh, and Yelena, you look terrible.
The fact that she didn't insult Ghost like the
others just kind of proved the point that Ghost
really wasn't a big enough character in the movie
to insult. Yeah, she was kind of a little bit more
pointless in that regard. I bet you that Valentina
would have had some stuff to say about Taskmaster.
I don't know. I liked the fight against the Sentry.
Again, I do wish there was less telekinesis, but it
was cool to see them, you know, give their all
against this all powerful being. What can you do at
that point but retreat? And Alexi's pep talk to
Yelena, where she's telling him that all she sees
in herself are these flaws and she's such a
horrible person. But he refers to this instance in
her life where she chose to be the goalie of her
Thunderbolts Pee Wee team, not because she was
lazy and didn't want to run like she thought, but
because she said she wanted to be the one people
could count on if they made a mistake. It was such a
touching heartfelt moment to just build her up in
that way and tell her that she's better than she
thinks she is, you know. I was kind of confused how
the void took over the Sentry character when the
Sentry was dead. But I also thought that the void
was a very effective villain, like very scary,
especially with the display of his powers, how he
just essentially turned everyone into these
shadows. And the fact that it affected like
everyone in New York City was even more
terrifying. Yeah, when he first used it against
that little girl that Alexi had saved, you know,
like she smiled at the Red Guardian and then all of a
sudden she just disappeared. Like all of his
actions were for naught in that very heroic
moment. And there was just something really
disheartening about that that made the void such a
compelling villain. As the void's darkness
spreads, Yelena steps into it and finds herself
back in her previous vision. She breaks through to
other difficult times in her life, such as the
Black Widow training program and her time as an
alcoholic. She ends up finding Bob in his own
memory in his childhood attic. The rest of the
Thunderbolts end up finding them by entering the
void as well. Together they fight off Bob's abuse
of stepfather, a sign twirling chicken high on
meth, and the void himself at the Ox Lab where Bob
underwent the Sentry project. Bob tries to
overpower the void through violence, but the team
learns the only way to overcome the void is through
healing Bob's trauma and showing him he's not
alone. The chicken twirling moment was so damn
good. I was cracking up in the theater. Srishten,
he was like, I was high at the time. Just knowing
that something like that happened is funny.
Seeing the Thunderbolts fight a high sign
twirling chicken was not on my bingo card for this
year. No, it's definitely the biggest surprise of
the movie, I would say. It was a great gag, though.
As silly as it was, it didn't overstay its welcome,
thankfully. They didn't have a whole scene of them
fighting the chicken. They were in and out, but it
worked so well because of that. Going back to
Yelena's trauma about having her friend killed,
man, I really have to wonder what this 12-year-old
girl did to deserve an assassination from the Red
Room. I think the Red Room was in the practice of
weeding out the girls that didn't perform to their
expectations. Oh, you thought that girl was a
member of the Red Room as well. OK, well, that makes
sense. Yeah, real dark shit. Real dark shit. Super
dark. It was also really dark seeing Yelena Bolova
on the bathroom floor with all the bottles around
her. There wasn't really much to that
performance, but it was still very powerful.
Seeing Florence Pugh like that. Back on the
streets of Manhattan, the city returns to normal
as the void disappears. The Thunderbolts see
Valentina and try to apprehend her, only to
stumble onto a press briefing she arranged,
announcing the team as the new Avengers. Yelena
warns her that they own her now. In a mid-credits
scene, Red Guardian tries to get a grocery store
patron to notice him on a weedy cereal box. After
the end credits, the new Avengers debate how to
address Sam Wilson's Avengers team, and they
notice a distress signal from outer space coming
from a ship bearing the Fantastic Four emblem. I am
curious what you thought about the sort of end
reckoning with Valentina or the lack thereof, I
should say. So the lack of closure with Valentina
wasn't surprising to me. And I'm not sure what it
would have looked like if she did get her
comeuppance. Obviously, she would be impeached.
She would probably go to jail. But even then, at
least like in the comic books, we still wouldn't
have seen the end of her. It kind of felt like the
Thunderbolts traded justice for fame. They kind
of traded justice for an opportunity, I think, to
be the people they wanted to be. I think they found a
way to manipulate the situation and really give
Valentina her comeuppance by being in control of
her as opposed to the other way around. Did you
think that that was like in character for someone
like Bucky, though? Sure. I think so. Yeah, I mean,
he's been an anti-hero before. I think in this
regard, they would all see that the ends justify
the means. And I think he sees the benefit a new
Avengers team would have, especially using
Valentina's resources. I think he sees that as the
greater good. Again, I don't think this is an
absence of justice so much as a kind of twisting of
it to suit their needs. I didn't love the ending,
I'll be honest, because it did feel like justice
was not met and it did feel very shallow on behalf of
the team members. It's one of the few things I
really didn't like about the film. I kind of liked
the subversion of the ending, actually. It was
anti-heroes being anti-heroes. But that's the
film overall. I think the film stands out as a
unique entry from Marvel. And I think because of
that, it'll be appreciated more by fans and
general audiences who I don't think necessarily
are tired of Marvel. They're just looking for
something new and different. And I think that
prioritizing introspection over exposition,
The Thunderbolts film uniquely delivers one of
the more mature and thoughtful experiences in
Marvel's film catalog. I am giving it four and a
half out of five stars, a fresh rating on Rotten
Tomatoes. Which is a really high rating. It's only
half a star away from a perfect rating. But I would
actually agree with it. Now, this is the same
rating we gave Watchmen and the Suicide Squad.
Well, I still think those are better films than
this. I also can't see giving this a lower rating
because it was just so well executed. It's much
more simple than those films. And I think in part
that's why it feels a little bit more pure in terms
of like a character study that they were going for.
I thought they nailed the execution of this film.
Yeah, it's nice for Marvel to have a movie like
this, I think, in their filmography. Oh,
absolutely. For sure. But that does it for this
review. AJ9K helped close us out. Our next episode
is going to be a dual episode where we find out who
would win in a fight between the DC hero Ray and the
Marvel mutant character Havoc. Yeah, two of the
coolest and more interesting looking characters
in either universe. Definitely looking forward
to this matchup. But that does it for this episode.
We want to give a big thanks to our executive
producers. John Straussky, Zachary Hepburn,
Dustin Balcombe, Mickey Mathen-Gian, Brandon
Esregard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yatyn, Austin
Wieselowski, A.J. Dunkerly, Nick Cabanto, Scott
Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Speese, Dean Malesky,
Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, Josh Leiner, Mike
Williams, Oscar Galvez and our newest executive
producer, Paul Graves, for helping make this
podcast possible. We'll talk to you guys next week
up, up and away. True believers. Honestly, I just
thought the asterisk was going to be a symbol for a
butthole.