This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. The holidays
are just a few weeks away and if you haven't started
shopping yet, this is your sign. Head to
OldGlory.com, the ultimate store for superhero
fans. They've got officially licensed Marvel and
DCTs, hoodies and gifts perfect for every hero,
sidekick or villain lover on your list. Order now
and get 15% off anything when you use the promo code
Duel at checkout. That's D-U-E-L. Don't wait
until the last minute. Your favorite designs ship
fast but they won't last forever. Start your
holiday shopping today at OldGlory.com and make
this season heroic. Hi and welcome to the Dynamic
Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we review
superhero films and debate the superiority
between Marvel and DC by comparing their
characters in stat based battle simulations. I'm
Marvelist Joe and I'm his twin brother Johnny DC.
And in this episode we're going to find out who
would win in a fight between the new gods from DC and
the Eternals from Marvel. And one of our final team
duels for this podcast, we knew we wanted to go all
out and pit the two most formidable teams against
each other. I don't know if the Eternals is
Marvel's most formidable team but they are
certainly up there. They basically have all the
powers. So I could totally see the new gods getting
dog walked in this matchup. That is the stupidest
thing I've ever heard. No way the new gods are
losing this. They are literal gods. And the
Eternals were once worshipped as gods. So there
you go. Before we get into that matchup though
guys, we're going to break down the latest comic
book movie news that came out this past week of
which actually were not because there is no news.
But as always we list our segment times in our
episode description so feel free to check out the
show notes if you want to skip ahead to a particular
topic. Our artificially intelligent duel
simulator AJ9K has a quick message for our
listeners so listen up. Why hello there. Do you
want even more from this podcast? Then become a
part of the dynamic duel community on Patreon
where you can choose from three tiers. The dynamic
2.0 tier gives you access to our Discord chat
server. The fantastic 4.0 tier gives you two bonus
episodes each month and the X-Force tier makes you
an executive producer of this show. Lastly, the
Dynamite podcast network tier lets you create
your own podcast using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and
consultation and get you simulation results.
Pitch the twins your ideas via email at
dynamicdualpodcastatgmail.com. Check it out at
patreon.com slash dynamicdual. Pip pip cheerio.
Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast including Travis Herndon and the
Kamacho twins who we are very late in wishing happy
birthday. Yeah, if I could give Gilly and Travis a
get for Marvel, I would give Gilly Hawkeye set of
trick arrows and I would give Travis Mr. Fantastic
stretch powers. That is random as fuck. I'm gonna
say that since all three of these guys are twins,
since you know we have the running joke that Travis
Herndon is the twin of Travis Bailey, I'm going to
give all of them the power of the Wonder Twins.
Which one? Xan or Jan or whatever her name is. The
power to turn into any animal or the power to turn
into any water form. Let's see we'll make Scotty
Xan, we'll make Gilly Jaina and we'll make Travis
Gleek. So still the power of stretching, except he
could just stretch his tail. Yes, it's his tail.
Happy birthday guys. Be sure to tune into the other
shows and the Dynamite Podcast Network this week
including the Console Combat Podcast where hosts
John and Dean simulate battles between popular
video game characters. And yesterday's episode,
they celebrated two years of the Console Combat
Podcast, which is a huge feat for those guys.
Congrats to them. Go ahead and check out their
anniversary special. Over on the Max Destruction
Podcast hosts Scotty and Gilly, pet your favorite
action heroes from film and television against
each other. The Macho Twins are returning this
week with a Christmas duel right out the gate. Jack
Skellington versus The Grinch. And on the Sanjo
World Podcast hosts Zachary Hepburn speculates
on fights between fan favorite anime and manga
characters. In his next episode, Zach is
revealing who'd win between Shigyo Kageyama, aka
Mob from Mob Psycho 100 and Tatsumaki the tornado
of terror from One Punch Man. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our show
notes to listen to all of the shows in the Dynamite
Podcast Network. But with that out of the way.
Quick to the No Prize. A No Prize is an award that
Marvel used to give out to fans. Our version, the
Dynamic Duel No Prize, is a digital award that we
post on Instagram for the person that we feel gave
the best answer to our question of the week. Last
week, we asked you guys, what was your favorite
story within the Batman Deadpool crossover comic
and why? And this is coming off of DC publishing the
Batman Deadpool crossover comic, of which there
were a lot of stories, including, of course,
Batman Deadpool. There was Harley Quinn Hulk,
Nightwing Wolverine, Miss Marvel and Static and
Dr. Strange and Constantine. We received a grand
total of one answer this week from Steve Wozniak,
co-founder of Apple. He said. This is the Woz, not
Wozniak. Just simply the Woz. And my favorite part
of that comic book is simply Batman. Why does
Batman rocks? He's actually the only thing in DC
that rocks because Marvel is better. Marvel is
amazing. And that's all I got to say to that. And
Steve Wozniak's right. Batman is better than
Marvel. Well, what he actually said was that
Marvel was better than all of DC. It was just that
Batman was better than anything else DC had.
That's not what I heard. Well, clean your fucking
ears then. Because the Woz does not lie. So the Woz
gets this week's No Prize. His name is not actually
Steve Wozniak. It's Josh Wozmont. That's not what
I heard. Congrats, Josh, for winning this week's
No Prize. If you, the listener, want a shot at
winning your own No Prize, stay tuned to later on
this episode when we'll be asking another
question of the week. And now that that's done. On
to the question of the week. Guys, we have
completed all of the review episodes before the
final episode of this podcast in mid January.
There's nothing else to review because Wonder Man
got pushed back. So with that said, what review of
ours, what review episode of Dynamic Duel did you
get the most out of? Whether you thought it was
funny or insightful or way off base, let us know
what stood out to you. But that does it for the
upfront portion of this episode. Let's get on to
our main event where we find out who would win
between the DC team of the new gods and the Marvel
team of the Eternals. All right, the new gods
versus the Eternals. Both of these teams are
members of a race of godlike beings. So this will be
quite the clash of Titans as we're actually the
Eternals who live on Saturn's moon of Titan are
called Titans. And that's actually where Thanos
is from. He's actually one of the Titans. Of
course, the Eternals had their own movie, which
sucked. The movie did not suck. It was entirely
different from everything else that Marvel had
put out. Not in a bad way. I just don't think it was
what people were expecting. Being a big fan of the
lore of the Eternals, you could definitely listen
to our review and hear how I actually enjoyed the
film for what it was. Wait, so remind me, is Thanos a
robot person like they are? No, well, he's a member
of a race of beings that were created by the
Celestials. They're not robots, though. This
matchup, though, is probably going to be similar
to our Darkseid's elite versus Thanos's Black
Order duel that we did a few months ago. Right,
because the new gods are essentially the good
counterparts to Darkseid's elite, who are also
new gods just from Apocalypse, as opposed to New
Genesis. There's a lot of lore surrounding both of
these teams. Actually, both the new gods and the
Eternals are creations of comic book legend Jack
Kirby. I believe Jack Kirby first created the new
gods for DC and then kind of carried them on back at
Marvel with the Eternals, who are kind of the
spiritual successors of the new gods, I would say.
Right, yeah, Eternals is a Jack Kirby ripoff of a
Jack Kirby DC creation. Hey, you can't rip off
yourself. That's fair. Can't wait to get into this
duel matchup. First, to explain the methodology
behind our duels, let's go to our sentient duel
simulator, Alfred Jarvis 9000. AJ9K, tell our
listeners how you go about determining a winner in
our duel matchups. Yes, of course, sir. The way I
determine a winner between the two teams is by
running 1000 Monte Carlo simulations between
every character on each team using their
statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation is a
probabilistic model used to determine outcomes
through random sampling. In this case, I
randomize the statistics along a normal
distribution as a way to simulate the many
variables that can occur during battle. The stat
parameters are based on the official Marvel power
grid from which the DC characters statistics are
extrapolated. Additional stat categories are
included such as range, damage potential,
versatility and perception in order to create a
more detailed and accurate simulation. The
results of the 49000 simulations provide a
percentage of wins for each character on both
teams. The team with the higher average win rate is
declared the victor as they have a higher
probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither team should win 100%
of the matches. The comic book stories have shown
that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman, so the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks AJ and IK.
Before we run the simulations though, we like to
break down each team's histories and rosters
before improvising a scenario on how we imagine
one of the thousands of simulations would play out
beat for beat. And I believe it's my turn to go first
with the Marvel team's backstory. So let me tell
you all about the Eternals. About a million years
ago, a host of cosmic giants called Celestials
visited prehistoric Earth and experimented on
early Homo erectus. Their work produced three
branches of humanity. The long-lived Eternals,
the unstable Deviants and ordinary humans, which
were seated with the potential to become
superpowered mutants later in evolution. The
Eternals were engineered to channel immense
cosmic energy as custodians of the Celestial's
mankind experiment, while the Deviants warped
genetics drove them to dominate and terrorize
early humans. As the Eternals multiplied, they
built the city of Olympia in the mountains of
Greece. Their power and proximity to the Olympian
gods led ancient Greeks to confuse the two races,
and some Eternals even impersonated gods as part
of a treaty, most notably Azura, whose name was
changed to Athena, so she could serve as the
earthly Athena before mortal worshipers. An
ideological rift soon tore the young race of
Eternals apart. Uranus, brother of the peaceful
scientist, Chronos, believed the Eternals
should conquer Earth. Civil war erupted, Chronos
prevailed, and Uranus and his fathers were exiled
into space. They founded a colony on the planet
Uranus, where their presence attracted the alien
Kree. When a Kree armada destroyed their ship, the
survivors crashed on Saturn's moon Titan and
created a new colony there. Back on Earth, Chronos
continued his experiments with cosmic energy
until a catastrophic accident disintegrated his
body and permanently awakened his full power.
With Chronos, now a disembodied entity, the
Eternals merged into a unimined and chose
Chronos' son Xurus as the new prime Eternal, while
his other son Alars departed the planet to avoid
another schism. Alars traveled to Titan and found
the first Eternals colony there devastated with
only one survivor named Sui-san. Together, they
rebuilt Titan's society under the guidance of the
artificial intelligence Isaac. Alars and
Sui-san's children would define Titan's future,
giving birth to Aros, a carefree adventurer, and
Thanos, a mutant Eternal whose deviant-like
appearance and obsession with death would one day
lead him to massacre most of Titan's population
and to become one of the universe's greatest
threats. You can learn more about Thanos in his
duel against Darkseid. The survivors of Titan
rebuilt the colony yet again and its Eternals
repeatedly aided Earth's heroes against Thanos,
while Aros, eventually known as Starfox, left
Titan to join the Avengers and roam the cosmos as a
hero. Back on Earth, Xurus consolidated Eternal
Society in Olympia, near a gateway to the Olympian
God's realm. His daughter, Athena, grew into a
scholar and warrior, often acting as the God's
representative. Over millennia, she became
entangled with Crow, a deviant warlord who first
spared her life in ancient Babylon. Their long,
uneasy romance produced secret twin children,
whom Athena hid inside a human surrogate to be
raised as ordinary mortals, even as she continued
to command Eternals in battle against deviant
armies. Other Eternals similarly wove
themselves into human legend. Icarus helped
shepherd humans during ancient cataclysms and
later guided a refugee ship to safety in stories
remembered as the tale of Noah's Ark. Centuries
later, while fighting deviance in Greece, he
married a human woman and fathered his son Icarus.
The boy died when Mechanical Wings' father built
carried him too high into the atmosphere, and in
grief, the Eternal took his son's name. Makari,
another Eternal of Olympia, was fascinated by
speed and technology. Under various aliases, he
taught writing, carried messages for early
civilizations, and inspired myths of swift gods,
later operating openly in the 20th century as the
speedster Hurricane and then Mercury. Cersei
stood apart from her kin by fully embracing
humanity. A fourth generation Eternal born in
Olympia to Helios and Percy, she delighted in art,
magic, and mortal company, appearing across
history as a performer and benefactor in
legendary courts and cities. In the modern era,
after helping repel a major deviant assault on New
York, Cersei lived as a Manhattan socialite,
befriending several Avengers and ultimately
joined the team herself, entering a complicated
romance with the Black Knight that later tied into
her struggle with an eternal mental illness
called Maud Wirie. You can learn more about Cersei
in her duel against Firestorm. Humanity's first
broad exposure to the Eternals as a people came
during the arrival of the Celestial's fourth
host. Anticipating their return, Xurus
stationed Icarus in an ancient city in the
Peruvian Andes to awaken Ajax, a priestly Eternal
who had chosen to sleep between Celestial visits.
With Ajax revived, the Eternals rushed to prepare
for the Celestial's descent and clashed with
deviant plots to turn humanity against the
towering judges. The Eternals merged into a
unimined to augment the Asgardian destroyer
armor in a desperate attack that failed to sway the
Celestial's. The aftermath, the Celestial's
spared Earth, destroyed the deviant ruling class
and left Xurus dead, prompting many Eternals to
depart the planet while a smaller faction
remained under Thena and then Icarus. In the
modern age, eternal deviant tensions continued
as the Lemurian deviant priest lord Gar sought
Celestial power. Thena, who had once sheltered
the deviant gladiators from Lemuria's brutal
culling rituals, found herself torn between Crow
and her responsibilities as the new prime Eternal
on Earth. The strain left her vulnerable to a
mental brain-mind that Crow had implanted in her
mind and her increasingly erratic decisions led
to Icarus eventually challenging and replacing
her as the prime Eternal. As the superhero era
unfolded, Cersei, Gilgamesh, and Starfox all
served as Avengers, bringing eternal power
directly into Earth's most famous team.
Gilgamesh, long known as the Forgotten One for his
earlier interference in human history, briefly
fought alongside Earth's heroes before Grievous
Injury sent him back to Olympia. During this
period, Cersei's mental instability worsened
and the Eternals bound her mind to the Black Knight
in a soul bond known as a Ganjosen, untangling
their lives until the onslaught crisis scattered
the heroes again. You can learn more about the
Black Knight in his duel against Amethyst. The
Eternals' understanding of themselves changed
completely when the childlike trickster Eternal
called Sprite rebelled against his unending
existence. Using stolen Eternal technology and
the dormant dreaming celestial deep in the
Earth's crust, Sprite rewrote reality so that the
Eternals became ordinary humans with fabricated
histories and no knowledge of their true nature.
Makari lived as a medical student, Mark Curry,
Cersei as a party planner, Thena as a Stark
Enterprise scientist with a husband and young
son, Faistos as an engineer in Sweden, and Icarus
as the mysterious Ike Harris, who alone
remembered fragments of the truth. Their reunion
at a European diplomatic party triggered the
return of their powers and set them on a path to
restore their memories. Icarus reestablished
Olympia as their base, while Makari became the
chosen communicator for the awakened dreaming
celestial. The celestial revealed that every
seated world receives 100 Eternals and 100
Deviants and that the Celestials stand ready to
scour a planet if deviant corruption outweighs
eternal guidance, forcing the Eternals to
confront not just Deviants but also the
Celestials' scouting efforts. As they completed
the task of reawakening their scattered kin, the
Eternals debated their role toward humanity,
whether to rule, protect, or stand apart, and
ultimately chose distance, even as individuals
like Cersei continued to live among mortals. That
uneasy equilibrium shattered when a corrupted,
final host of Dark Celestials descended on Earth.
When Iron Man and Doctor Strange saw answers from
the Eternals in the mountains of Greece, they
discovered almost all of the Eternals dead by
their own hands. Icarus lived long enough to
explain that the Eternals had learned a final,
devastating truth, that they had never been
destined as noble guardians of humanity, but as
caretakers meant to defend the Celestial's true
interest in the human race. This revelation drove
them into madness and suicide, seemingly ending
the Eternals saga on Earth. However, Celestial
Resurrection technology eventually restored
the Eternals once more, to live in a world that no
longer clearly needed or trusted them. In this new
age, they grappled with their manufactured
purpose and renewed threats from Thanos himself,
who targeted Earth's Eternals on the principle
that only death should be truly eternal. After the
Resurrection, the Eternals discovered that each
revival by the machine killed a random human,
shattering their moral certainty and dividing
them between those who wanted to end the system and
those who accepted it. Thanos returned, seized
control of the Resurrection machine, unaware
that the psychic, Eternal Druig had implanted a
failsafe designed to destroy him. Thanos used his
brief rule to eliminate rivals until Druig's trap
activated, seemingly killing him and further
destabilizing Eternal Society. Druig then
claimed leadership as the Primeternal and
labeled mutants as excess deviation, launching
an assault on the mutant island nation of Krakowa
and unleashing the imprisoned warlord Uranus for
one hour to devastate Krakowa's counterpart,
Arrakko, on Mars. You can learn more about Krakowa
and Arrakko in Krakowa's duel against Danny the
Street. The resulting crisis pushed Ajax and
Makari to resurrect the Progenitor Celestial for
guidance, but the Progenitor instead judged
Earth unworthy and threatened global
destruction. The Progenitors' defeat ended the
conflict but forced the Eternals to confront the
cost of their immortality and the devastation
carried out in their name, leaving their people
fractured and directionless. That's the
Eternals backstory. For the seven-member roster
in this team duel against the new gods, I'm going
with the following seven Eternals. Cersei,
Icarus, Thena, Makari, Faistos, Gilgamesh, and
Starfox. All the Eternals have essentially the
same power set of immortality, near
invulnerability, flight, increased strength
and speed, regenerative healing, telepathy,
telekinesis, cosmic energy projection,
teleportation, illusion casting,
shapeshifting, molecular reconstruction, and
matter transmutation. However, through
training and discipline, many Eternals hone a
specific aspect or specialty of their abilities.
Cersei specializes in matter transmutation,
Icarus in cosmic energy projection, Thena in
weapons and combat, Faistos in engineering,
Gilgamesh in strength and durability, and
Starfox in empathokinesis, meaning he can affect
the emotions of others. They're all at least
moderately gifted and intellect having lived for
thousands of years. And that's the Eternals. To
reiterate my team is Cersei, Icarus, Thena,
Makari, Faistos, Gilgamesh, and Starfox. Why did
you decide to go with Starfox over Druig? That's a
good question. So Druig was in the movie, but I
always thought of Thanos' brother Starfox, who
actually was also in the Eternals movie in the end
credit scene played by Harry Styles. I always
thought of him as more of a prominent Eternals
character with his ability of empathokinesis. I
largely saw Druig's telepathy as unnecessary
because I could get the same effect of quote
unquote mind control using Starfox. Gotcha. I do
think it's pretty lame that they all essentially
have the same powers. That's a pretty impressive
power set. I don't think that's lame for me. I think
it's, yeah, for sure lame for the new gods because
they're going to get their ass beat. Basically the
Eternals have all the powers. Sure, a lot of them
specialize in some abilities at the expense of
other abilities, but you're going to have a real
hard time dealing with the Eternals versatility.
Maybe, maybe it won't matter. We'll see. Let me get
into the new gods backstory. Long ago, before time
as it is now understood, the cosmos was ruled by a
pantheon of beings known as the Old Gods, who waged
a catastrophic war amongst themselves on the
world of Urgrund. The conflict culminated in the
cataclysmic event known as Ragnarok, which tore
Urgrund asunder. From its destruction rose two
diametrically opposed worlds, Apocalypse, a
smoldering furnace of tyranny and suffering, and
New Genesis, a verdant realm of peace and
enlightenment. These twin worlds occupied the
sphere of the gods and were populated by a new race
of beings, immortal, evolved, and godlike. They
called themselves the New Gods. Apocalypse came
under the dominion of the malevolent dark side,
who ruled with absolute cruelty. New Genesis was
led by the wise warrior, Isiah, who became
Highfather after communing with the mysterious
cosmic force known as the Source. Highfather
transformed the floating city of Supertown into
the capital of New Genesis and established a
culture built on peace, wisdom, and divine
ascension. But tensions between the two worlds
escalated into a devastating war after
Darkseid's uncle Steppenwolf murdered Isiah's
wife, Avaya. In retaliation, Isiah slew
Steppenwolf and ignited a war between Apocalypse
and New Genesis that threatened to consume the
universe. Seeking a temporary end to the
violence, the pact between New Genesis and
Apocalypse. Highfather and Darkseid agreed to
exchange their sons as wards. Orion, son of
Darkseid, was sent to be raised in New Genesis
under Highfather's guidance, while
Highfather's own son, later named Scott Free, was
consigned to the brutal orphanages of Granny
Goodness on Apocalypse. Though the exchange
forced an uneasy truce, hostilities resumed when
Darkseid set his sights on Earth, believing its
inhabitants collectively held fragments of the
elusive anti-life equation, a formula capable of
eliminating free will throughout the universe.
The renewed war was fought not only across the
stars, but also on Earth, where the new gods allied
with heroes such as Superman to repel Apocalyptic
incursions. In times, Scott Free escaped
Apocalypse and returned to New Genesis as the
master escape artist Mr. Miracle, joined by a
fellow fugitive and formidable warrior, Big
Barda. You could learn more about Inher Duel
against Ronan the Accuser. Orion, despite his
apocalyptic lineage, embraced the values of New
Genesis and became its fiercest defender, often
fighting alongside the radiant warrior,
Lightray. You could learn more about Orion and his
duel against the Silver Surfer. Both Orion and
Lightray led numerous campaigns against
Apocalypse's forces, including brutal battles
in the fire pits of Armageddo and the skies above
Earth. To bolster their efforts against
Darkseid, Highfather supported the emergence of
the Forever People, a team of young new gods
empowered to summon the mighty Infinity Man, who
was secretly Drax, Highfather's brother, and the
original intended heir to Apocalypse before
Darkseid's rise. Even the lower caste of New
Genesis, represented by the brave bug warrior
Forager, rose to prominence during this time,
proving vital in numerous conflicts and bridging
the social divide between Supertown and the
insect colonies below. Through his wonder staff
and communion with the Source, Highfather
presided over battles not just of strength but of
cosmic consequence. When Darkseid sought to
breach the Source Wall and harness the Source for
himself, Highfather assembled the gods of other
Pantheons, including Zeus and Odin, to form a
composite being known as the One. Together they
entered the Source to stop cosmic collapse caused
by the God Wave, a universal surge of divine
energy. Highfather perished in the effort,
sacrificing himself to protect reality, though
his essence remained one with the Source. After
Highfather's death, his mantle was offered to his
son, Scott Free, who declined the role, leading it
to pass instead to Tachyon, a human imbued with
Source energy to guide New Genesis. Even in death,
Highfather continued to appear to others as part
of the cosmic quintessence, overseeing events
that threatened reality. The New Gods suffered
their darkest hour when the sentient Source
turned against its creations, determined to
usher in a more perfect fifth world The source
employed the Infinity Man to eliminate the flawed
gods of the fourth world. One by one, the new gods
fell, until only Darkseid and his son Orion
remain. In the final conflict, Orion tore out his
father's heart, delivering justice in the name of
the fallen. The source merged Apocalypse and New
Genesis into a single world, signaling the end of
the fourth world. In the wake of their
destruction, the new gods were reborn in the realm
of Earth 5.1, reconstructed by the monitor Nix
Uhtun after the events of the final crisis. You can
learn more about the monitor in his duel against
the Watcher. As Darkseid's essence attempted to
conquer Earth from within the body of Metropolis
Detective Dan Turpin, the remaining new gods
returned in more evolved forms. Metron, Black
Racer, and others reemerged to guide and protect
creation. With the fall of Darkseid, the gods of
New Genesis resumed their stewardship, their
spirits reborn to guide a new age. After the
timeline-altering Flashpoint event, the
history of the new gods was rewritten. In this new
continuity, Ixaya and Uxas, or Darkseid, were
once peasants on the world of Urgrund, ruled by the
destructive Old Gods. When the war among the
deities erupted, Uxas manipulated the conflict,
stole their powers, and transformed into the
being known as Darkseid. Ixaya pleaded with the
gods for salvation, and one dying god gifted him
the power of the Alpha Effect. Reborn as
Highfather, Ixaya battled his brother in a clash
that destroyed their world. From the ruins, Ixaya
forged the floating city of Supertown and
rechristened his people, the new gods of New
Genesis. Though Highfather led with strength and
resolve, the devastation wrought by war hardened
him. The death of his second wife at Darkseid's
hands reignited hostilities, culminating in a
second pact. As before, Orion was sent to New
Genesis, and Highfather's infant son, Scott, was
given to Apocalypse. Though the truce held, it did
little to prevent Darkseid's continued conquest
of the Multiverse, and Highfather became
increasingly authoritarian in his governance.
Years later, as new threats emerged, Highfather
sought to end the eternal conflict once and for all
by acquiring the Life Equation, an antithesis to
Darkseid's Anti-Life Equation. To that end, he
dispatched the Council of Aids to retrieve the
emotional spectrum rings from the Lantern Cores
and captured the White Lantern Kyle Raynor, who
you learn more about in his duel against Null.
Though Highfather claimed his actions were
noble, he used the Life Equation to transform
innocent beings into soldiers in his war,
including the citizens of the planet Moos. When
confronted by the Lantern Cores and his own
people, Highfather recognized his descent into
tyranny. In a moment of clarity, he relinquished
the Life Equation and sought redemption. He
helped save New Genesis from the revived Source
Titans, acknowledging the need to rebuild both
the trust of his people and the shattered order of
their society. Darkseid meanwhile perished in
battle against the Justice League, consumed by
the power of Anti-Life. His disappearance
created a cosmic imbalance that the universe
attempted to correct by giving rise to a new God of
Evil, an emergent infant named Kamal. Orion,
tasked by New Genesis to destroy the child before
he could awaken his godhood, found himself torn
between duty and conscience. Refusing to carry
out the execution, Orion defied the edicts of
Supertown and fled with the child, triggering
political upheaval across the realm. In the wake
of Orion's defection, an alien race known as the
Nektari, who were descendants of the forgotten
old god Nektar and former slaves of Apocalypse,
emerged from the shadows of the cosmos and
launched a genocidal crusade against all
fourth-world gods. The Nektari declared
themselves heirs to the divine legacy lost in the
fall of the old gods and viewed both New Genesis and
Apocalypse as aberrations born from blasphemy.
Their assault culminated in the destruction of
Supertown, forcing the surviving new gods into
exile. In the battle's final moments, Lightray
was slain defending the celestial bridge from
Nektari warships, his body igniting into radiant
flame visible across the multiverse. Scattered
and wounded, the remnants of the new gods
established a refugee fleet shepherded by
Metron's Mobius chair across forgotten star
lanes in search of safe harbor. Big Barda and Mr.
Miracle led rescue operations to salvage
survivors from the ruins of Supertown, while
foragers people, long overlooked, rose to the
front lines as guerrilla fighters. Highfather,
stripped of his capital and humbled by war,
governed from a fractured command, relying on
Tachyon to maintain communion with the source.
Orion, now a fugitive among his own people, raised
Kamal in hiding, seeking to guide the child away
from the shadow of Darkseid. The war with the
Nektari marked the twilight of the fourth world,
as the new gods fought not for dominion or dogma,
but for survival. And that's the new gods history
so far. Now for my seven-member roster, I'm going
with Orion, Mr. Miracle, Big Barda, Light Ray,
Metron, Forager, and Becca. Orion is Darkseid's
son, raised in Supertown, a brutal warrior with
superhuman strength, speed, durability, and the
power of the Astro Force, an explosive energy he
projects from his harness in battle. Mr. Miracle
is the universe's greatest escape artist, armed
with a sentient mother box computer and high-tech
gadgets that let him fly, phase, and break through
any trap or barrier. Big Barda is a fierce
frontline combatant raised by granny goodness of
apocalypse, wielding her indestructible mega
rod and enhanced armor. Light Ray is a radiant and
optimistic warrior who manipulates solar
energy, granting him light speed, flight, laser
precision blasts, and blinding luminescence.
Metron is an aloof observer of reality who
traverses time, space, and dimensions with his
Mobius chair, granting him unlimited knowledge,
teleportation, and technological control.
Forager is a swift and agile warrior from New
Genesis' bug colony, Cast, fighting with
energy-based stingers, mines, and exo-armor.
And for the seventh member of my roster, I'm going
with Orion's wife, Becca, the goddess of love
capable of inspiring overwhelming devotion in
others while wielding advanced New Genesis
technology, including a phase-shifting suit
that grants her invisibility and intangibility.
I do want to say that I originally wanted to use
Highfather in this duel, but Joseph's a big fat
cheater who would not allow me to do so. No, I mean,
I'm not using Mentor or Zurus or anything like
that. So yeah, you can't use Highfather. He's just
too powerful, I think, for this group. So to
reiterate, my seventh member roster consists of
Orion, Mr. Miracle, Big Barda, Light Ray, Metron,
Forager, and Becca. Yeah, it's a good team. I like
how the history of the New Gods is no less
convoluted than the history of the Eternals. I
actually think it got better with the
post-Flashpoint retcon. It's not Jack Kirby, but
it is pretty cool. Yeah, the Eternals got
retconned a few times as well, even by Neil Gaiman.
But I think really actually the movie helped
solidify some of those ideas that Jack Kirby
originally had, and they've since brought some of
those concepts into the comic book universe as
well. The holidays are just a few weeks away, and if
you haven't started shopping yet, this is your
sign. Head to oldglory.com, the ultimate store
for superhero fans. They've got officially
licensed Marvel and DCTs, hoodies, and gifts
perfect for every hero, sidekick, or villain
lover on your list. Order now and get 15% off
anything when you use the promo code dual at
checkout. That's D-U-E-L. Don't wait until the
last minute. Your favorite designs ship fast, but
they won't last forever. Start your holiday
shopping today at oldglory.com and make this
season heroic. Now that we've got the team's
histories and rosters out of the way, let's
speculate on how one of the simulated matches will
go. The winners determined by simulations, not
the speculation, but it's fun to imagine how the
fight could play out. A.J. and I.K., what are the
rules of our speculation? Well, I should say there
are no rules, other than the teams have no prior
knowledge of the other going into the fight. All
they are aware of starting out is that the other
side is a threat that needs to be eliminated. For
the speculation, the groups will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the match
itself, as no environmental statistics are
considered in my simulations. The teams must earn
victory on their own merit. Alright then, let's
get into it. The new gods and the Eternals meet on
the battlefield who goes first. I'm actually
going to say that Lightray starts off the match
since he's the fastest one out of both of the teams
and he's going to begin by emitting this blinding
flash of light that is going to blind all of the
Eternals and that's going to allow Orion to
unleash this wide astrophors blast against the
entire team while they're trying to blink the
light out of their eyes. So they're all just
basically destroyed from the get go. Okay, but
Eternals, I mean they have eyes that can adapt to
brightness and darkness better than humans. So
like this flash of light by Lightray, it doesn't
affect them more than it would like a normal human
looking at a bright light bulb. So not too bad. You
know, like they witness Orion about to unleash his
astrophors. So Cersei is going to construct a wall
shielding them that's made out of pure diamond and
Makari, you know, my resident speedster, she's
going to phase through the wall and straight up
pinball herself among the new gods, just you know,
karate chopping some of them in the head, kicking
others in the chest and like judo tossing at least
one of them. But like for sure knocking down each
one of the new gods on their ass. A diamond wall
wouldn't be much of a shield against the
astrophors, but sure, we'll say a stand's long
enough for Makari to get through it before you know
it becomes diamond dust, essentially. Luckily
enough for the new gods, though, I'm going to say
that the first one Makari approaches happens to be
Becca, the new goddess of love, who is constantly
radiating empathic waves that force those in
proximity to her to fall in love with her. So while
Makari suddenly becomes smitten with her, Big
Barda is going to use her Mega Rod as like this jet to
launch herself straight into the biggest guy on
your team, Gilgamesh, and she's just going to
pummel him with her rod. I don't know why that
sounds gross, but it does. But Gilgamesh, like
he's so fucking strong, he's going to straight up
catch Big Barda's Mega Rod as she's like bringing
it down on him, and he's going to just snap it like a
twig before feeding one of the broken ends to her,
just like busting her right in the face. Then
Thena, just out of thin air, she conjures a Mega Rod
of her own, except it's going to be three times as
long and twice as girthy, and it also has a blade at
the end, like a spear, and she uses it to fire a blast
at Barda that knocks Barda off of Gilgamesh. Okay,
first of all, the Mega Rod is apocalyptic in
technology. There's no way Gilgamesh breaks it,
bends it, maybe, but you know, a Baren rod is
nothing to be ashamed of, you know. Barda just
angles it slightly when she uses it, and she's
going to use it to counter Thena's blast with one of
her own. And because Mr. Miracle saw Thena try to
attack his wife, he's going to get between them and
whip out his multi-cube that he's going to use to
fire this unbreakable net around Thena, which
pins her to the ground. Thena would just teleport
out of the net. So no big deal there. Faistos is
going to use his Warhammer to smash Mr. Miracle's
multi-cube, and then he's going to throw out a
gadget that ensnares Mr. Miracle in this, like,
intricate trap. It kind of looks like a golden
four-dimensional clock with, like, these gears
that distort time and make whoever is trapped
inside of it go back in time with every motion Mr.
Miracle makes. So it's basically impossible to
escape from. Well, I wouldn't say that. It just
means he needs to break out of it in one motion. And
that's going to be easy. He will use his mother box
to generate a boom tube around him, and that's
going to allow him to escape the trap by falling
into a boom tube. Meanwhile, Forager is going to
douse Faistos and his hammer with a stream of acid
from his acid pod on his wrist, and that's going to
disintegrate him. Except Cersei just turns that
acid into clone midair before it lands on Faistos.
So all Forager did was make Faistos smell like a
suave motherfucker. That's when Icarus just
flies right through Forager, turning him into,
like, this cockroach smear on the battlefield.
Okay, but actually Icarus is just going to bounce
right off of Forager's bug shield that he was
wearing on his back. So, ha ha. We'll say Forager
does get smashed into the ground, but you know,
he's pretty resilient, so he'll be fine.
Meanwhile, Metron is going to catch Icarus in a
tractor beam and teleport him near Becca. So now
she's in control of both Makari and Icarus, and
because they're under her thrall, they're going
to start attacking the other Eternals at super
fast sonic speed. Okay, except when Icarus and
Makari try and attack Starfox, he gets them under
his thrall, so they don't want to hurt him or his
teammates the rest of the Eternals. And then
Starfox is going to extend his apathokinesis to
Becca, so Becca falls in love with Starfox too, and
therefore she drops Icarus and Makari completely
out of their empathic days, and Becca straight up
starts making out with Starfox. What? Okay, well
that's going to piss off Orion since that's his
wife, and we'll say it enrages him so much that it's
going to short-circuit his mother box, which is
usually what keeps his innate rage in check. So,
with his power unleashed, Orion, who at this point
is irrational and made impossible to be affected
by Starfox's empathic power, he's going to plow
straight into Starfox at light speed on his astral
harness, while engulfed in astrophors energy.
So, Starfox gets vaporized, after which Orion's
mother box is going to repair itself and restore
Orion's mind. I guess that's fair, considering he
did make out with Orion's wife and all. Yeah, but
you know what? Orion's going to be angry again when
Thena shoots a bolt from her cosmic energy
crossbow that's going to strike Becca right
between her eyes, so Becca's out. Yeah, Becca has a
phase shifter built into her suit that makes her
intangible, and you know, she probably activated
that at the very start of this match, smartly. So,
that bolt is actually going to hit Gilgamesh
instead, which is going to take him out. No, he's
fine, but Becca may be intangible, but Cersei's
just going to force her to become tangible, either
by like turning her phase shifter into dust or like
even just rendering her molecule solid. Either
way, Becca does not survive Thena's next bolt,
which fires from her crossbow. So, Becca's out,
and Orion's not going to do shit about this,
because Faistos slaps a magnetic technology
hacker onto Orion's astro harness, and that's
going to infect Orion's mother box with a
celestial virus that causes him to become docile,
and like so docile, in fact, that he just lets
Icarus hurl him into outer space, never to return.
Oh, dang, that was a good move, actually. All
right, well, I'm going to say by this point, Mr.
Miracle Boomtube is back into the match, and right
away, he's going to quickly grab Gilgamesh and
toss him into the tube before it closes. So,
Gilgamesh also never returns to the match.
Meanwhile, Big Barda uses her mega rod to teleport
behind Icarus, and she's going to use that rod to
garot and kill him. Okay, she's choking him out
with the mega rod. Still sounds gross. He wrestles
to free himself from getting choked out, but his
eyes are still free. He's going to shoot massively
powerful cosmic eye beams at forager that just
incinerate the guy. So, Icarus may be out, like he
gets taken out by Barda choking him, but he's also
going to take that cockroach guy with him, and then
suddenly, Mikari steals Barda's mega rod and then
uses her speed power to phase the rod through her
chest, just impaling her and taking her out of the
match. Is Mikari a man or a woman? Well, both.
Mikari started out as a man then was resurrected as
a woman in her latest incarnation. Oh, okay. So,
Barda's out, but as Mikari proceeds to zip around,
I'm going to say Light Ray flies out in front of her
path and stays in front of her no matter where she
turns as he blasts her with a series of lasers,
taking out each leg before beaming her right
between the eyes. So, she's out. Okay. I mean,
while Light Ray was so focused on eliminating
Mikari and staying in front of her, one thing he
didn't notice was his own decapitation by Theanus
Sword. So, he like lasers Mikari out of the match,
and then all of a sudden, he sees his own body. He's
like, oh, shit, there's my body. Oh, no, I'm dead.
Jeez. Actually, I'm going to say that Metron just
rewinds time. So, that Light Ray is no longer
decapitated. Now, he's just going to duck below
Theanus Sword and sever her torso in half with a
laser beam. So, she's actually the one that's
taken out. Time manipulation is bullshit. What
controls Metron's time powers? Is it, it's his
chair, right? Yeah, the Mobius chair. I'm going to
say that it is now the Mobius pilot dog shit,
because Cersei is going to transform Metron's
chair into dog shit. So, now Metron is sitting on
it, and he's like, eww, gross, I'm sitting on this
big ass pile of dog shit. And then, he and his pile of
dog shit get turned into marble. So, he's a marble
statue now that will forever commemorate that
one-time Metron sat on a big ass stinky pile of
sloppy dog shit. That is the most disrespectful
thing you've ever said. I feel like Metron also
would have seen that coming. But whatever, Mr.
Miracle, he's going to use his mother box to
transmute Cersei into, I don't know, what's worse
than shit? Vomit? Nothing. A pile of vomit. That's
what Cersei is now. Alright, so who, I only have
Faistos left. Right, and I have Mr. Miracle and
Light Ray. Okay. So, Faistos, he's going to throw
out a device, a celestial technology device that
transforms into a portable version of the
Eternals Resurrection Engine. And this is going
to awaken a whole new set of the same Eternals that
you knew gods just destroyed or removed from the
battle. And then Icarus, now resurrected, he's
the head Eternal, he's going to start the Unimined
Ritual by creating this pillar of blue flame that
all the other Eternals fly into, and that is going
to form the Unimined, which is a composite being
that together is like more powerful than the sum of
its parts. That's right, you're totally screwed.
The fuck? He's like Infinity Man? Sure. I still
don't quite know who Infinity Man is. It's High
Father's Brother or whatever. This is a composite
being of Eternals. It's like a floating energy
head with all the powers that can take on any form it
wants to actually. And so this Unimined is going to
compress matter inside of Light Ray's body into
this mini black hole that causes him to implode.
That's going to kill him. And the mini black hole
also sucks in Mr. Miracle. Like, Light can't
escape a black hole. How the hell is Mr. Miracle
going to escape a black hole? He's not that smash
over. That was awesome. Escape a black hole? I
mean, that'd be easy, actually. Like all Mr.
Miracle has to do is take over this Unimined by
reciting the Anti-Life equation, which he knows.
And with the Unimined under his control, not only
does he close up the black hole, but the match is
over since to be under the control of Anti-Life is
essentially death. What good is the Anti-Life
equation if Mr. Miracle is unable to speak? What?
Because the Unimined just erased his mouth and Mr.
Miracle gets sucked into the black hole. I don't
know. I mean, Mr. Miracle doesn't have to speak it
out loud. He could think it. I'm assuming the
Unimined is psychic. So it probably still hears
the equation in Mr. Miracle's mind. How is Mr.
Miracle going to think this equation before he
dies, before he gets sucked into the black hole?
That's dumb. We'll just say he resets it before the
Eternals even had time to form the Unimined. Like
you're saying Faistos was able to activate this
celestial machine, recreate the Eternals, have
them form the Unimined and form the black hole
before he could recite the equation? No way.
That's wishful thinking. That's bullshit. It
could happen. Sure, why not? Okay, that is a lot of
steps. We'll go ahead and leave the match there.
Either Faistos and the Eternals are able to form
the Unimined, which in turn creates a black hole
that destroys Lightray and Mr. Miracle, or Mr.
Miracle recites the Anti-Life equation taking
control of the Unimined or the Eternals and ending
their lives. We'll go ahead and leave the match up
there, input the character stats, run the
simulations and come back with the winner. AJ9K,
hit it! Inputting data, running calculations,
processing results, simulations complete. Man,
I was really looking forward to using the Unimined
against you, but you're right. Like it just, it was
just too many steps. I don't think I could pull that
off quite cleanly. I'm just glad Mr. Miracle
survived to the end of that speculation to use the
Anti-Life equation because I'm not sure how else I
would have overcome the Unimined. Not that the
speculation matters, it all comes down to stats in
the end of what you were right. The Eternals
stomped on the new gods when it came to
versatility. That was the biggest discrepancy
between both teams. Yeah, the Eternals
definitely had the edge over the new gods when it
came to versatility considering they have
basically all the powers, but the new gods did
stomp the Eternals when it came to evasiveness,
largely because characters like Becca, Mr.
Miracle, and Metron are over and above highly
evasive. Both teams were fairly durable, fairly
fast, they were pretty much even when it came to
damage level, actually, and their range was also
very similar. Overall, it looks like the Eternals
were a group of better fighters, which surprised
me. Yeah, Acheris, Stina, Gilgamesh, they're all
really well-adept fighters who have lived for
close to a million years, quite a lot of experience
under their belt. Whereas someone like Metron,
like have you ever seen Metron throw a punch even?
No, actually, he had the lowest fighting stat out
of anyone on either team. That being said, he was
still the most powerful member overall. Yeah,
Metron was by far the most powerful character. He
had a win rate of 82.1%, though I also had the
weakest member of the other side with Forager, who
only had a win rate of 24.4%. Most of my Eternals
were actually right around the same level
stat-wise, and so a lot of them also had around the
same win rate, ranging from about 55% to 45% win
rate. People like Gilgamesh excelled in
strength, McCurry, and speed, things like that,
but overall, they were pretty well balanced. That
being said, Jonathan, can the new gods overcome
that level of versatility and balance? I think so.
I mean, I think the Eternals are not specialized
enough, I would say. Not as much as the new gods, and
I think that's going to be in the new gods' favor.
And Instagram agrees with me. Of those who took our
Instagram poll, 62% sided with the new gods, which
is lame because the new gods haven't even had a
movie, so I think that's just a lot of people
hating. Well, some of the new gods made an
appearance in Zack Snyder's Justice League. I
mean, no one who's on my team, they're all from
Apocalypse, but people know about them. I don't
think they do, but let's see which team won. Age of
9K, the results please. Alright, the winner
between the new gods and the Eternals is... The new
gods. Yes! Not by much though. Not by much. Not even
close to what you are probably hoping for, out of
the thousands of simulated matches, the new gods
only won 51.2% of the time, whereas the Eternals
won 48.8%. So what you're saying is that the new
gods aren't stoppable. What I'm saying is the new
gods are big fucking losers, and they can go fuck
themselves, and I hate them. That's what I'm
saying. Geez, jealous much? I'm not jealous
because I know at the end of the day the new gods are
inferior. Clearly not! Well, if they weren't,
then they would have had a movie made about them
already. Wouldn't they have? That's what I
thought. You mean a shitty movie? Yeah, if they had
a movie made about them, it would have been shitty.
Yeah. No, I mean, the Eternals movie was shitty.
Fuck you. Never mind. In the end, I don't feel too
bad because it was such a close matchup. It's
almost a coin toss really. And it looks like the
coin came up. New gods. That's stupid. You lose,
bitch! But that does it for this team duel. AJ9K,
help close us out. Alright, our next episode is
going to be an individual duel. We're going to find
out who would win in a fight between Gypsy, who I
think is a Titan? No, a member of Justice League
Detroit. Okay, I don't know anything about Gypsy,
but we're going to learn about her. She's going up
against Shadowcat, who everybody knows as a
member of the X-Men Kitty Pride. That does it for
this episode, guys. We want to give a big thanks to
our executive producers, Jon Straski, Zachary
Hepburn, Dustin Belcom, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi
Yatyn, Austin Wazalowski, AJ Dunkerly, Nick
Ibonto, Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Speese,
Dean Maleski, Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, and
Paul Graves for helping make this podcast
possible. We'll talk to you guys next week. Up, up
and away, true believers. I'm glad Druig wasn't in
this duel. Druig sucks.