Superhero T-shirts. I want them, you want them, we
all want a good superhero T, especially with the
holidays around the corner. And that's where
OldGlory.com comes in. They've got officially
licensed Marvel and DC apparel. Shirts, hoodies,
hats, gifts, so you can rep your favorite hero in
style. Whether you're Team Captain America or
Team Batman, you'll find something epic in their
massive catalog of over 300,000 items
celebrating all things pop culture. Right now you
can save 15% off any purchase when you use our promo
code Duel at checkout. That's Duel D-U-E-L at
OldGlory.com because you deserve great
superhero merch. On with the show. This is a
DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi and welcome to the
DynaMic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Marvelist Joe. And I'm his twin
brother, Johnny DC. And in this episode we're
getting back to the reviews. It's been a while
since we've done a review. We're trying to hammer
out a lot of Duel episodes and lead up to the show's
finale. But I know a lot of people have been waiting
for this peacemaker season two review, so we're
definitely going to talk about that. Yeah, I've
been dying to talk about this show for weeks now. We
pushed it off in order to get a lot of spooky
Halloween-esque duels in the month of October.
But now we're finally reviewing it and I have a lot
to say later on in this episode. Before that, we're
going to break down the comic quick and movie news
from the past week, of which we have just one news
item and that is the talks about the upcoming
potential acquisition of Warner Brothers and DC
Studios by another studio. As always, we list our
segment times in our episode description, so feel
free to check out the show notes if you want to skip
ahead to a particular topic. Guys, our
artificially intelligent Duel Simulator, AJ9K,
has a quick message for our listeners, so listen
up. Why hello there. Do you want even more from this
podcast? Then become a part of the dynamic duel
community on Patreon, where you can choose from
three tiers. The Dynamic 2.0 tier gives you access
to our Discord chat server. The Fantastic Four
tier gives you two bonus episodes each month and
the X-Force tier makes you an executive producer
of this show. Lastly, the Diner Mike podcast
network tier lets you create your own podcast
using this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe
will help you develop your show, provide graphic
support and consultation, and get you simulation
results. Pitch the twins your ideas via email at
Dynamic Duel Podcast at gmail.com. Check it out at
patreon.com slash dynamic duel. Pip pip cheerio.
Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast. Be sure to tune into the other shows in
the Diner Mike podcast network this week,
including the console combat podcast, where
hosts John and Dean simulate battles between
popular video game characters. In yesterday's
episode, they reviewed the Super Mario Brothers
movie. Over on the Max Destruction podcast, hosts
Scotty and Gilly pet your favorite action heroes
from film and television against each other. The
Macho Twins are taking a quick break for the month
of November, but they'll be back in December with
some Christmas season duels. On the Central World
podcast, host Zachary Hepburn speculates on
fights between fan favorite anime and manga
characters. In his next episode, Zach is
revealing who would win between Shigyo Kageyama,
aka Mob from Mob Psycho 100, and Tatsumaki the
tornado of terror from One Punch Man. But with that
out of the way, quick to the no prize. A no prize is an
award that Marvel used to give out to fans. Our
version, the Dynamic Duel No Prize, is a digital
award that we post on Instagram for the person we
feel gave the best answer to our question of the
week. Last week we asked you guys, what scary story
this episode was your favorite and why? And of
course in our last episode, we told you guys six
short scary stories as narrated by Nightmare from
Marvel and the Phantom Stranger from DC. They were
original stories written by Jonathan and myself
and we hope you guys enjoyed them, but which one did
you guys find the scariest? Let's find out by going
through our honorable mentions and our no prize
winner. Yeah, we got two honorable mentions. The
first one goes to Alex Albro who said, Hey guys, my
favorite story was definitely the story of
Greyhaven with the breathless boy and the silent
citizens and everything that the ghost trend was
there the whole time. And to be honest, I never saw
it. It was pretty cool surprise. Also, you just you
don't know who lays down the fog and it just felt
real. It's really good story. Honestly, the
scariest thing though is this win streak that DC's
on feels like Marvel's just a step behind in the
race to January. Maybe next month we can be
thankful for the comeback. I fully expect this
Thanksgiving holiday to be sitting at my dinner
table and saying I am thankful for Marvel making a
comeback in the month of November. Yes, it's going
to happen. I mean, it's going to be a lie, but you
could say it. Yeah, and the Greyhaven story that
Alex referred to was the veil of fog, a story about
the hero Nightshade. It was a pretty good story. It
had an interesting twist where everyone in the
town of Greyhaven, including this little boy that
she befriends is actually a ghost, which gets
revealed when she fixes this lighthouse that
burns through the fog. And it turns out the entire
populace is made out of fog, basically. So the way
Joseph and I approached both of our stories were a
little bit different. In the Phantom Stranger
Horror Anthology series, there is always a lesson
or a morality tale to be told. So I wanted each of my
stories to sort of have that lesson since Phantom
Stranger was my narrator. And I thought something
along the lines of the road to hell is paved with
good intentions would be a good moral lesson. So
that's what inspired the veil of fog. Yeah, with my
stories, I was just going for good like
campfire-esque tales in the vein of scary stories
to tell in the dark or tales from the crypt. Great
answer, Alex. Our next honorable mention goes to
Nate, who said, Hey, it's Nate here. And I just want
to thank House of Mystery for giving me those
amazing bedtime story for my nieces. And I even
found myself falling asleep to those. So thank you
for that. The one, though, that really kept me up
was Crypt of Shadows. So I think the wind goes to
Marvel for giving me nightmares. I totally agree,
man. Yeah, the House of Mystery tales were boring,
and they put you right to sleep. The Crypt of
Shadows stories, on the other hand, were
dread-inducing and hopefully kept a lot of people
awake at night. Yeah, I won't deny it. I thought
they were actually really scary. I mean, maybe not
the Ghost Rider one. That one was more exciting,
maybe. But the other two, yeah, they had some
really good imagery associated with them. Yeah, I
said they were scary, not as scary as the House of
Mystery stories, but scary. Sure. Yeah, I thought
they were more scary, too. Great answer, Nate. But
the winner of this week's No Prize is Noah Terry,
who said, My favorite scary story would have to be
the Manitou, because it's just super creepy in the
moral dilemma. And also, your guys' storytelling
is just top notch. And just a great story,
spine-chilling, amazing Halloween tale. Just
loved it. Thanks. Thanks, Noah. I had a lot of fun
writing that one as well. That one was actually
inspired by my favorite horror film, The Cabin in
the Woods. That film deals with the sacrifice of
five archetypal youths, and I kind of ran with that
for my Manitou Raven story. That story wasn't like
Cabin in the Woods at all. It was more like Evil
Dead. Manitou is very Evil Dead-esque. That's
definitely not what inspired it, though. Like, if
you notice, the characters were the archetypes of
the soldier, the virgin, the harlot, the scholar,
and the jester, essentially. And they were each
killed by the four Hellenistic elements of earth,
fire, water, and wind, plus shadow. That
essentially was the framework for my story. I knew
I wanted to get those elements specifically in
there. Well, the Ghost Rider one was based off of a
popular, scary story where a woman thinks a guy is
chasing her in his car, but really, he's trying to
warn her about the killer in the back seat. That's a
pretty common one, actually. I just spun it with
Ghost Rider. And then the many angled ones is
actually a riff on my favorite short horror story,
The Bookie Man, written by Stephen King. And then
the Crimson Lands one was just a zombie tale,
because I wanted to write a Jennifer Kale story. I
thought it'd be cool to set it in the swamp, and it
was kind of reverse engineered from wanting to
have zombies in the swamp, but not have them be
traditional zombies in the sense that they were
controlled by necromancy, but instead by Black
Tom Cassidy, who could control plants. Yeah,
having Black Tom Cassidy be the villain who just
destroys man thing, I thought was a stroke of
genius. Yeah, I wanted to get in a lot of villains
that we haven't used yet in Duel's, including
Black Heart, Black Tom Cassidy, and Shumagorath.
And that was really cool, too. That's actually
something I wish I would have thought to do with my
stories. Yeah, mine were better. I mean, we're
giving the no prize to Noa Terry, who said that my
story was better, which means that I not only won
the team duel, I won the story contest. So there in
your face. What are you trying to prove, man? What
are you trying to prove? I'm better than you, bro.
Great answer, Noa Terry. You and this week's no
prize. If you, the listener, want a shot at winning
your own no prize, stay tuned to later on this
episode when we'll be asking another question of
the week. And now that that's done, on to the news.
Okay, years ago, as everyone may remember, AT &T
sold Warner Brothers to the head of Discovery,
David Zaslov, who merged the two companies
together with the intention of flipping the
studio, as it were. Many of us who followed the
story, including myself, were kind of hoping he
would sell to Comcast Universal to make them more
competitive against Disney and their theme
parks. But it looks like Paramount has emerged
recently as the studio most interested in
acquiring Warner Brothers Discovery. Warner
Brothers Discovery has a lot of debt. So what David
Zaslov has done is talk about splitting the
companies in two, just to make it more attractive
to buyers. But it looks like Paramount wants the
whole enchilada, and they offered an initial bid
of $57 billion, which David Zaslov rejected,
because you always reject the first offer. It's
about $24 a share. Warner Brothers Discovery is
currently trading at about $22 a share. So I think
it was a smart move. I think they could get more. So
while Paramount is working on a follow up bid,
Netflix has also entered the arena, actively
exploring a bid and even hiring a bank to put
together an offer. And with Warner Brothers
Discovery, suddenly the bell of the ball, even
Comcast owners who own Universal have talked
about potentially putting in a bid. Now that's
less likely to happen, even though I would love for
it to happen. Forbes recently came out with an
article saying that there's less than a 10% chance
of approval of Comcast acquiring Warner Brothers
because of the potential antitrust issues that
would come with Comcast getting more of a monopoly
on internet services. The Paramount deal, Forbes
is giving a 30 to 40% chance of approval for the
acquisition. It's just that Paramount as a studio
is smaller than Warner Brothers, so they would
need to acquire a lot more money to buy it.
Interestingly enough, Forbes is giving Netflix
the highest likelihood of approval between 50 and
60%, although Netflix is not interested in
acquiring all of Warner Brothers, just the parts
that they can use essentially. Like I'm not even
sure Netflix would want something like DC Comics
the comic company. No one does. I mean, I would.
We'll put together a bid. I'm poor. But it's really
interesting to see all of these players suddenly
come out of the woodwork for an opportunity to get a
hold of Warner Brothers content library, which is
massive, and again includes DC Comics and DC
Studios. There's been a lot of rumors as to whether
or not James Gunn would stay on board if Warner
Brothers were to be acquired. But it looks like at
least if Paramount makes the acquisition,
they're very much interested in James Gunn
staying on board. Yeah, it would suck for DC
Studios to just undergo this reboot only to have to
do it again almost immediately. Actually, that
would make me laugh. I would be very upset. I would
be very upset. I don't know which of these three
would probably upset me more. I don't love really
any of them. They all have their potential pros and
cons. I think what DC Studios has going now is good.
I mean, Warner Brothers is having a fantastic year
at the theaters. So I would say don't change
anything right now, but we'll see how things go. Do
we know when we're expected to hear something? I
think we'll hear something before the end of the
year for sure. And then it'll take a year or two to
get everything sorted out with the government
potentially. But considering the three suitors
interested in Warner Brothers, that brings us to
our question of the week. Which company would you
most want to acquire Warner Brothers and DC
Studios? And why? Yeah, I don't know how business
savvy a lot of you guys are, but basically I think a
good way to approach this question is to look at the
existing buyers, see what existing libraries
they have in terms of content, and then think about
which of those libraries would incorporate DC
Studios most easily. I think that's how I would
approach it at least. Record your answer at
dynamicdool.com by clicking on the red
microphone button in the bottom right hand corner
of the screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long. And don't forget to leave your name in case we
include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a dynamic
duel note prize that we'll post to Instagram. Be
sure to answer before November 8th. But that does
it for all of the news for this episode, so let's go
ahead and move into our main event where we review
the HBO Max DC television series, Peacemaker
Season 2. Okay, Peacemaker Season 2, written by DC
Studios head James Gunn, is the third entry in DC's
new cinematic universe, following creature
commandos and Superman, also written by Gunn.
Season 1 was a spin-off of James Gunn's film The
Suicide Squad, in which Peacemaker betrayed the
Squad and later dealt with the ramifications of
his actions in Season 1 of his HBO series, while
also saving the world from a secret alien
invasion. I loved The Suicide Squad and Season 1 of
Peacemaker, both had a terrific blend of action,
comedy, and heartfelt themes, as did creature
commandos. With the success of Superman, I had
fairly high expectations for Peacemaker Season
2, especially when James Gunn revealed that this
season would be setting up the story for the
Superman sequel, Man of Tomorrow. So did
Peacemaker Season 2 meet those expectations?
Sadly, no. Not even close for me personally, for
reasons I will get into in this spoiler review. If
you haven't seen Peacemaker Season 2 yet, but want
to and lead up to Man of Tomorrow, stop listening
now to avoid spoilers. Now, as I mentioned,
because of James Gunn's creative momentum with
creature commandos and Superman, my
expectations for Peacemaker's sophomore season
were sky-high, and maybe that's my fault for not
checking my expectations. I will admit that. I
keep telling you. You do. You do. You think I would
have learned 10 years into this. But with creature
commandos and Superman, Gunn had set a newish
tonal standard for the DCU, a reverent yet
respectful to the source material, heartfelt yet
humorous and fully character-driven. So my
anticipation centered on how he would evolve
Chris Smith's story within the DCU's refreshed
continuity. The promise of exploring new
dimensions this season, both literal and
thematic, had to be convinced that it was going to
top its predecessor, Season 1. Now, at its core,
Peacemaker Season 2 aimed to tackle identity,
guilt, and redemption, which are fitting themes
for a hero defined by contradiction, like
Peacemaker, who's willing to kill for peace. The
interdimensional realm known in the show as the
Quantum Unfolding Chamber opens this gateway not
only to alternate realities, but also really into
the fractured psyche of Chris Smith himself,
because he's forced to confront ghosts from his
past, the Earth-X version of his father, brother,
and even himself. So the show initially plays like
this surreal therapy session, which is
interesting, but these rich themes of duality and
self-confrontation, I think lose focus amid the
uneven pacing and just narrative clutter. What
could have been a poignant reflection on
accountability just gets buried beneath all of
the season's truly unnecessary subplots and
tonal detours. I totally agree. I actually
thought we were going to spend much more time in
Earth-X and kind of explore that where there was
going to be a lot more consequences, I think for all
the Nazis that lived there. There wasn't nearly
enough action in this season overall. No, no. That
being said, I don't think I went in with any
expectations regarding this particular season,
and so I think I liked it a little bit more than you
did save for the final episode, which I thought was
totally and utterly pointless. They should have
ended the series on episode seven, which I thought
was a much more fitting cliffhanger. They should
have ended it on episode 10, where they had a few
more episodes to flesh everything out. Oh. I
agree. The last episode is bad. We'll get to that.
But my personal biggest gripe is that the show,
like you mentioned, completely dropped the ball
in exploring Earth-X, which I thought presented a
politically timely setup that the show,
frustratingly, never explored beyond
short-lived surface-level irony. Even in the
comics, Earth-X is a world where Nazis won World
War II, which I think as a concept could have and
probably should have encompassed the entire
season. Like, I would have loved to have seen Gunn
introduce the freedom fighters, characters like
Uncle Sam, Phantom Lady, Black Condor, Ray, and
Human Bomb. That would have been a huge surprise,
but instead I found myself more surprised that
that didn't happen. Yeah, Earth-X was almost
treated as an afterthought secondary to Chris's
personal dilemma, which was interesting, but
also somewhat of a retread. From season one? Yeah,
it was. They didn't need to do that. It made me feel
like James Gunn really didn't know what else to do
with the character, when really, like the Earth-X
storyline, exploring fascism and things like
that would have been perfect for the character of
Peacemaker, who is a fascist. Yeah, he'd have to
weigh his own personal ideals around fascism with
the world of Earth-X. Which would have been really
interesting. As I was watching this season, I just
recognized so much like that that it should have
either been expanded upon or cut entirely to make
room for what should have been expanded upon, like
Earth-X. Things like the Justice Gang's sudden
early cameo felt arbitrary, serving very little
narrative purpose, and I thought it teased a
larger DCU integration that never materialized.
There were so many superfluous jokes and
characters, like Red St. Wild, and indulgent
moments like Foxy Shazam's musical number
undercut the narrative tension instead of
reinforcing it. And if not more Justice Gang or the
introduction of the Freedom Fighters, or heck,
even the Suicide Squad, I figured we'd at least get
live-action cameos from the creature commandos.
Like, what's the point of having a shared
cinematic universe if outside characters can't
make significant contributions to the story?
Instead of getting characters we as DCU fans
really want to see, James Gunn leans into
characters he's invented, like, Audubio. Who
might love, don't get me wrong. But I don't love
characters like Langston Flurry, or especially
Red St. Wild. I get wanting to work with Tim Meadows
or Michael Rooker, but you shouldn't write dumb
parts just to include them, because that time we
should be better spent. I don't know, I liked Tim
Meadows. I think I could watch a whole series just
based on that character. What? Bird blindness?
Yeah, his bird blindness is hilarious. It is
hilarious, but it's also unnecessary. Like, if
you're going to have jokes, have them serve the
story, I would say, you don't need to start
inventing characters. There's already a huge
stable of DC characters to use, and I really loved
that Hughes to Sasha Bordeaux. I forgot that she
was going to be in this season. She wasn't probably
maximized as well as she could have been, but, you
know, it's characters like that that I would love
to see more of. What really turned me against the
show, however, was the finale's cliffhanger,
like you mentioned, in which Chris was trapped in
the dimension of salvation, leaving the season
feeling incomplete rather than open-ended. It
felt lazy, and with no plans for a season three that
possibly means that the salvation storyline from
the comics will be picked up in Man of Tomorrow, as
James Gunn has teased, but I don't know how you
could do both salvation and Brainiac. If you're
not familiar with the storyline of salvation from
the comics, basically, Amanda Waller finds this
planet, and she sends all of the supervillains
from Earth there. And basically, the
supervillains have to find a way back to Earth.
It's a great storyline. It sounds like Lord of the
Flies meets DC supervillains. It was like that
exactly. It was that awesome. And we didn't get any
of that. That's why I wanted like three more
episodes of this season. I just feel like James
Gunn is juggling too much as a studio head. He's a
writer, and maybe he shouldn't be an executive,
because as he's juggling so much, he's dropping
balls, which is not great this early into a
cinematic universe. Luckily, for everything
wrong with the season narratively, Peacemaker's
cast of characters still makes the show worth
watching. Let's talk more about them in our
character breakdown. Starting with Christopher
Smith, aka Peacemaker, played by John Cena. Now,
before I saw Peacemaker on screen, I never really
wanted to. Like, there's a long list of characters
that I would have rather seen adapted to live
action. But since the Suicide Squad and these
Peacemaker seasons, I've become a real fan of the
character, and especially of John Cena's
portrayal. He has made Peacemaker way more
relatable than I would have thought, and I hope
John Cena never stops playing him. No, John Cena is
to Peacemaker as Ryan Reynolds is to Deadpool. I
agree. They're just so endearing and really fill
shoes that no one else can fill. And I'm not a big
wrestling guy. Like, I didn't really follow John
Cena's career prior to him being cast as
Peacemaker. I'm still surprised about how much he
nails the role. He is a really good actor. I would
argue probably even better than The Rock or Dave
Batista. I would agree with that, yeah, for sure.
Probably the best wrestling actor ever. Although
I haven't seen that new movie with The Rock playing
the MMA fighter guy. Oh, that's fair. Yeah, I
haven't seen that either. Apparently he's pretty
good in it. So maybe we spoke too soon. Yeah, I heard
he was good. Now we're season one of Peacemaker
forced Chris to reckon with guilt and morality.
Season two pushes him into self confrontation,
literally, through the quantum unfolding
chamber, Chris faces alternate versions of his
family and himself, forcing him to question
whether redemption is possible, or just another
delusion. The death of his counterpart shakes
him, but also tempts him with the idea that maybe
another reality, one where he's not the screw up,
is the only place he belongs. His arc becomes about
learning that peace isn't something he can find by
escaping his past or reality. It's something he
has to make within himself, even when surrounded
by ghosts of who he could have been. The tragedy in
this season is that by the time he realizes that
he's once again trapped, this time not by guilt,
but by the consequences of his past actions,
because he killed Ric Flagg Jr. and his dad has
access to the salvation dimension. Moving on to
Amelia Harcourt, she was played by Jennifer
Holland, who is James Gunn's wife. She's a
fantastic Harcourt. She pulls off the badassery,
the sexiness and the chemistry with John Cena very
well. Like honestly, I'm not sure why as an actress
Jennifer Holland doesn't get more work outside of
this role, because she should. Yeah, in real life,
she seems very much like a non-Harcourt type
person, so it kind of speaks, I think, to her range
and skill as an actor that she pulls off this gruff
badass so well. Now, Harcourt's story this season
is about divided loyalties and buried affection.
After season one, she's disillusioned with Argus
and unsure of her place post-government work,
intentionally getting into bar fights just to hit
and feel something. She resists her feelings for
Chris, seeing them as a liability, but his
disappearance forces her to confront the truth
that her cynicism is really just armor. Her
reluctant alliance with Ric Flagg Sr. shows how
easily she slips back into the system she
despises, but her ultimate decision to defy it and
risk everything to bring Chris home shows real
growth this season. Harcourt begins as someone
who believes connection makes you weak and ends as
someone who realizes it's the only thing that
gives strength, her strength specifically,
meaning. Yeah, I was really impressed with her
character growth this season. Like when she made
that call, just a matter of factly, that they were
going to go get Chris from the other dimension, I
was like, okay, so she is in love with him and she is
willing to make these sacrifices for him and she's
not a total ice queen. Yeah, when Audubio got that
huge smile on her face, so did I. Yeah, I thought it
was a really interesting surprise when it was
revealed. That whole moment kind of brushed past
me when I first saw it, but right after that I
started thinking about the implications of what
that actually meant and how she would hold a grudge
against Peacemaker for killing one of her best
friends slash lovers. Yeah, that was a great
retcon that I thought added a great bit of conflict
to her character. Yeah, and context. For sure.
Moving on to Leota, Adubio, she was played by
Daniel Brooks. She delivers probably the
strongest performance of the show. She works so
well with both the comedy and drama throughout the
series. Next to Peacemaker, she's probably my
favorite character within the 11th Street Kids. I
agree, except again in that final episode where
everything was just way too fucking dramatic and
simultaneously boring. The rest of the episodes,
I thought Adubio was great. I felt truly horrified
for her on Earth X when she was being chased. Daniel
Brooks just gave a great performance. For sure.
Now Adubio starts this season still weighed down
by the moral compromises she made for her mother,
Amanda Waller. This season reframed her as the
conscience of the group, the one who tries to
anchor Chris as he unravels. When she follows him
across realities, it's not just loyalty. It's
sort of almost penance. And her experiences on
Earth X, where minorities are hunted, push her
from passive guilt into active conviction. She
finds her voice again, not as an agent executing
orders, but as a friend willing to defy authority
for what's right. She reclaims her integrity
after her betrayal, and she learns that
redemption isn't just about saying sorry, it's
about what you stand for when no one's watching.
Yeah, I thought it was a great continuation of her
arc from the first season where she kind of started
out as this kind of bumbling idiot and grew into
this super badass who was made for this shit and
decided that's where her calling was. Right,
exactly. She started off not wanting to be a spy and
to realizing that's exactly what she was born to
do, although struggling at it. To end, creating
Checkmate, where they all could work together.
Now, explain Checkmate. Checkmate is sort of like
it's like shield in DC Comics. It's a clandestine
organization, the structure of which is ranked
like pieces of a chess board. Oh, kind of like the
Hellfire Club. Exactly. But what a rip-off.
Better. I will say that Checkmate is a better name
than Hellfire Club, though. Yeah, for a chess
themed organization, absolutely. Yeah. Moving
on to John Economos. He's played by Steve Aggy, who
is perfect as economists. I love seeing how he
handles conflict as a character. It feels very
true to the actor. I don't know if that's an insult,
but he does it really well. It's just comedic gold.
Yeah, the fact that he's a coward. Yeah, it was
funny to see him get stabbed in the hand and be like,
holy shit. And then just totally unravel with all
their secrets. As much as you want to hate him for
that, it's understandable and at least
consistent for who he is. Right. Yeah. Now,
Economos continues as the team's reluctant
straight man. But this time, his arc turns inward,
continuously lying as a double agent of sort
within Argus while remaining loyal to the 11th
Street Kids. When he's literally stabbed by Aggy
on Earth X, it's almost like a metaphor for the
truth cutting through a self-deception. By the
end, his loyalty to Chris and the team isn't about
job security or fear anymore. It's about choosing
family. Economos starts the season trying to
justify his usefulness to Argus and ends up
realizing his worth has nothing to do with the
bureaucracy that exploited him. Moving on to
Adrian Chase, a.k .a. Vigilante. He's played by
Freddie Strowma, who's kind of like the DCU's
answer to Ryan Reynolds, though he wasn't as funny
this season as he was in the last, I thought. I did
not get all of the animal trivia obsession. Just
served as an example of all the useless filler
jokes that I thought permeated this season. I
agree. Yeah, the animal trivia thing got old
pretty quickly, although I really did like the
joke when Steve Aggy was like, how many eyes does a
spider have? And he was like, too. He was like, you
said that so confidently, I actually had to look at
my phone. Now, Adrian's relationship with Chris
has always been rooted in hero worship. But this
season, Adrian's loyalty becomes less about
blindly following Chris and more about
protecting him from himself. Though in the end,
killing Aggy probably put a wedge between him and
peacemaker, more so than what we saw, though, who
knows if that will ever be explored further. I
don't think it'll affect their relationship too
bad. I mean, Vigilante was just doing basically
what he thought he had to. I did love that it was
revealed that he was like secretly a millionaire
with all this drug money hidden in his basement. He
just refused to do anything with it. Spending
blood money will curse you for generations. The
last character on this list is Ric Flag Sr., who is
played by Frank Grillo. He plays a great tough guy
who appears in control, but he's teetering on the
edge. I didn't know he was going to end up as like the
main antagonist of the season. But I thought he did
a good job with the role. Yeah, it makes sense. So I
mean, it covers up a plot thread that has been
existing since the Suicide Squad in having that
whole retribution for the murder of Ric Flag Jr. I
really don't like what they did with his character
in the last few episodes, though, where he really
became a stooge to Lex Luthor, which seems out of
character. I know that his motivation was to get
back at peacemaker at any cost. But he also seemed
to be enjoying himself with the Lex Luthor part.
But that kind of makes sense to me. Like, it makes
sense that Lex Luthor would turn someone like Ric
Flag Sr. into his stooge. It's in character for Lex
Luthor, if not Ric Flag Sr. I guess it makes me
respect Lex Luthor more as a formidable villain,
but it makes me respect Ric Flag Sr. less and he's
the antagonist of this show. That's fair. He ends
up not being the strongest villain. And maybe
that's another reason why he felt so disappointed
by the final episode. And plus, he seemed terribly
inconsistent with his appearance in the Creature
Commando show. Oh, and that he didn't have white
hair. Well, not just an appearance, just in terms
of how he acted. Like, I couldn't imagine the
animated version of Ric Flag Sr. like, laughing
and drinking with his buddies while people were
getting killed. Maybe? Maybe you're right. But
let's go ahead and move into our story highlights.
The Dynamite Podcast Network presents Console
Combat, where video game legends brawl every
Monday. Dynamic Duel, where comic book titans
smash every Tuesday. Max Destruction, where TV
and action heroes battle every Wednesday. And
Cendro World, where anime champions clash every
Thursday. Join us as we speculate on the matches
and armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge
victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com, where we
settle the debate and settle the score. Episode
one was titled The Ties That Grime. Well, using his
quantum unfolding chamber, also known as the QC as
storage, Chris Smith, the peacemaker, discovers
a doorway to an alternate reality, Earth X, where
his father, Augie Smith, is alive and a superhero.
Six months later, Chris struggles with not being
taken seriously as a hero and being rejected by the
Justice Gang. Hardcore remains unemployed due to
Amanda Waller's influence, while Argus director
Ric Flagg Sr. distrusts John Economos' reports on
Peacemaker. Chris revisits Earth X and learns
that his brother Keith is also alive there. After
meeting his alternate self, the two fight in the
QC, ending with the Earth X peacemaker, mortally
wounded and dying in Chris's arms. Great setup to
the show. I thought the final scene where the Earth
X peacemaker dies, just seeing John Cena's acting
performance on that was definitely harrowing. It
was just like a, oh, shit, moment. Yeah, this was
the episode with the Augie scene. Yes. Yeah, which
is a hell of a way to kick off the first episode of
season two. I gotta say, I didn't think that was
necessary at all. I did think that parts of it were
hilarious. And also I was really put off by some
parts of it. Like there was a lot more dudes jorkin'
their dork than I would have liked in a streaming TV
series. Can you imagine being a fan of Superman and
being so excited about this universe and wanting
to watch more, only to see that in episode one?
There was a hilarious part, though, where as
peacemaker was going through the kitchen on his
way to the portal, there were a bunch of people
having sex in his kitchen, but there was one guy in
the background who was just eating a sandwich
watching everybody. You know, James Gunn has
talked about his creative process before, where
he says basically as a writer, you just need to
write and not really have an emotional reaction to
what you're writing because it just needs to get
done as the head of DC studios. It sounds like he
really has no one there to say, hey, James, this
might not be a good idea. And I kind of wish he did.
Like where was Peter Saffron to be like, maybe
don't do an orgy in episode one. Fun fact,
actually, I had to pause it a few times during that
scene because my wife was convinced that she went
to college with one of the actresses in the scene.
And I was like, whatever, no, it's just someone who
looks like somebody you went to college with. And
no, it turns out because she looked it up in the end
credits that, yeah, the one who like took a dump and
then didn't wash her hands in the second episode is
an acquaintance of my wife's. They hung out a few
times during college, but she was like telling me
this and I'm like, what the fuck am I supposed to do?
Should I avert my gaze now? Or like, what's
happening? I'm just going to keep watching the
show. That is a profound moral conundrum that I
never would have expected you to be in. For sure.
Moving on to episode two, it was titled, a man is
only as good as his bird. Argus agent Langstrom
Flurry is assigned as a condom as handler, as flag
senior grows suspicious out of by a warrants Chris
that he's being monitored and urges him to
surrender the QC. Adrian Chase Vigilante helps
Chris dispose of his counterparts corpse during a
rooftop party with Chris, Adabayo, Harcourt,
Adrian and Economos, the 11th Street kids. Flurry
leads a raid on Chris's home, but is attacked by his
bald eagle, Eagle Lee, later a drunk Chris
reenters Earth X and messages that universe is
Harcourt, who was the former lover of the Earth X
peacemaker. I have to say that so far, these two
episodes, I thought were great. And I was totally
on board with the show. I liked the direction it was
going. I was really interested in seeing where the
story was going to go. But then again, I also
thought like a majority of the remaining episodes
were going to take place in Earth X. Well, how did
you know that? Was the season spoiled for you? No, I
didn't know it was Earth X at the time. I just
thought it would take place in the other
dimension. Oh, I'm calling it Earth X now because I
know that in hindsight. Gotcha. Now, as much as I
don't like the inclusion of the character of
Langstrom Flurry, I do have to say him and Steve
Aggy do need their own show together. Yes, maybe
not San the DC universe, but their comedic riffing
off of each other was pure gold. It was so good. The
show could be called Ginger Cool. Ginger Cool and
Bird Blindness Guy. Episode three was titled
Another Rick Up My Sleeve. Chris meets Earth X
Harcourt at Argus headquarters, learning that
universe's Rick Flag, Jr. is alive and dating her.
Harcourt X reveals she broke up with peacemaker X
for being unfaithful and unwilling to commit.
Their talk is cut short when the Sons of Liberty
threatened to blow up a building. Chris kills the
terrorists and diffuses the bomb. After an
emotional talk with his brother, Keith, Chris
returns home unaware that Argus agent Sasha
Bordeaux has assembled a team, including
economists Flurry, Judo Master and the Eagle
Hunter Red Saint Wilde to raid his house. This is
actually my favorite episode. I just feel like a
lot happened in terms of like action and building
up the intrigue of what was going to happen in the
later episodes that just never really came to
fruition. Seeing peacemaker take on a whole squad
of terrorists is just so damn cool. I feel like
that's probably the best action scene that
peacemaker has on screen out of all of his
appearances. Even in the Suicide Squad? I can't
think of one better. What about the scene when he
was competing with Bloodsport? I liked this more.
OK. Less dick, you know. What did you think of Red
Saint Wilde? He was just a strange character. I
think his inclusion was to set up this whole
eagerly being like the prime eagle sort of thing.
But that didn't really go anywhere. And I don't
really know what that means, actually. Like, what
does it mean to be the prime eagle? That means you
could control other eagles, apparently. I guess.
I mean, the only purpose that served was to kill Red
Saint Wilde later on. So he was completely
unnecessary, in my opinion. There were some parts
that made me laugh out loud, though, like when John
Economist pushed the character over and like he
hit his head on the rock. It was just so slapstick
and stupid. I did laugh out loud. And then when he
tasted the eagle poop, he was like, he's been
eating Cheetos and ribeye steaks. And John
Economist was like, there's no way you could
possibly know that. I will say that it's a
character that no one else could play, I think,
other than Michael Rooker. It does pose a
continuity issue where Michael Rooker is playing
two characters in the DCU, if the Suicide Squad is
considered continuity and that he played Savant
and Red Saint Wilde. Well, I think they
established in the previously in the DCU tag at the
beginning of this season that any continuity
errors, you just have to kind of retcon mentally.
So like in Peacemaker Season One, it was Aquaman
and the Flash and, you know, the Standard Justice
League that showed up. Whereas the retcon showed
that it was like Green Lantern and Hawk Girl and the
Justice Gang that showed up at the end of that
adventure. So you'd have to think that the retcon
with Michael Rooker would be that it was just a
different actor playing Savant within that
universe's story regarding the Suicide Squad.
Fine by me. I never liked him as Savant anyway.
Episode four was titled Need I Say Door. Economist
warns Chris about the Argus raid, prompting him to
flee with the Eagle Lee and the QUC Gateway device.
Economists incapacitate Savant Wilde to save
Eagle Lee while Chris defeats Judo Master in the
woods. Chris and Adubio regroup at a cabin in
Subdler's Hill, where he transfers the QUC portal
to a new location. Meanwhile, Flag Senior temps
Harcourt with reinstatement if she helps capture
Peacemaker. Chris tells Adubio he plans to move
permanently to the alternate reality and later
texts Harcourt to meet him. Unaware, she's
accepted Flag Senior's offer. St. Wilde performs
a ritual that reveals Eagle Lee's location at the
cabin. Can you remind me why at this point that
Peacemaker was on the run? Why they didn't access
his location via the chip in his head like they did
later on in the season? OK, bad writing is the
answer. Really? OK. I thought maybe it was a plot
hole, but also I thought maybe I missed something.
No, I don't think you missed anything. There is
something about security clearance. But I don't
think there was an issue for Flag Senior because he
was the head of Argus. Right. Like I said, James
Gunn, he's juggling too many balls. Episode five
was titled Back to the Suture. At their meeting,
Harcourt insists there's no future between her
and Chris, the Noxum and Conscious to prevent
Bordeaux from killing him. At Argus
headquarters, she convinces economists to book
Chris in jail to save him from Flag Senior's
brutality. Adubio later bails Chris out and
drives him to the cabin, trailed by Judo Master,
feeling he doesn't belong in this universe. Chris
decides to cross over permanently with Eagle Lee,
who summons a flock of eagles to kill Saint Wilde.
Judo Master sneaks into the queue you see before it
closes and after reading Chris's farewell
letter, Harcourt vows to bring him home. It was
cool to see Sasha Bordeaux actually be a cyborg in
this series because she is in the comics. She used
to be Bruce Wayne's bodyguard until she was in a
terrible accident and that she was kind of rebuilt
by the government. She probably doesn't have that
history with Bruce Wayne in this universe. I'm
guessing it could be wrong. But I just like her as a
character and I definitely like that she was
included in the creation of Checkmate because she
is the Black Queen. I'm wondering why they chose to
include that romance between her and Ric Flagg
Senior. It really didn't go anywhere. And it was
vague as to what was happening to begin with.
That's a good question. Yeah, that was another
unnecessary element within the show. Another
reason why writers like James Gunn probably need
checks and balances. Episode six was titled
Ignorance is Chris. The 11th Street Kids activate
the dimensional portal at Adrian's home and
travel to retrieve Chris. In Earth X, Harcourt X
meets Chris with help from Keith, while Adrian
meets his counterpart, who reveals he joined the
Sons of Liberty because of Peacemaker X.
Economist is found and stabbed by Augie, forcing
him to confess that Peacemaker X is dead. Chris
admits his love for Harcourt but refuses to leave
the dimension. When Chris discovers a US flag
replaced with a Nazi swastika, Harcourt X alerts
security. Meanwhile, Adebayo is hunted by Earth X
residents and Flagg Senior makes a deal with Lex
Luthor to help locate Peacemaker's portal in
exchange for a transfer to Van Kul prison. It was
cool to see a cameo by Nicholas Holt as Lex Luthor in
this series. Yeah, I forgot to mention it, but Joel
Kineman also had a cameo in a couple of episodes
here. It was cool to see him back. The guy was
actually pretty damn funny in his Earth X
appearance. I thought that was pretty damn good.
It did make me miss him as Ric Flagg Junior. Yeah, he
was a good character. For sure. What was your
reaction to the Earth X reveal? Really? I thought I
was like, oh, that's a cool Easter egg. I thought so
too. I was like, oh, shit. Shit just got real. This
is going to be an awesome season. And then like
after the next episode, nothing really happened
with it. It's almost like the show let Earth X off
the hook for being this like Nazi controlled
nightmare universe, just completely forgot
about it. Sort of. I mean, with Augie revealing
that not everyone wants to be under Nazi control
kind of made it a little bit more sympathetic. But
still, you would think that if you visit a place
where Nazis took control, you would want to do
everything you can to stop that. Yeah, I don't
think that Augie's reasoning, therefore,
accepting the status quo was good enough because,
you know, superheroes are meant to fight Nazis.
It's the whole reason comic book superheroes were
invented to begin with. And, you know, any true
superhero would have taken it to the regime. And
that would have been the big battle, I think, that
this series sorely needed. It would have been cool
to see the 11th Street Kids team up with White
Dragon and Keith's character partnered maybe
with even the freedom fighters and see them all
take down the Nazis. That's what I wanted to see.
That would have been awesome. Moving on to Episode
7, it was titled Like a Keith in the Night. Chris and
hardcore escape Argus, but are captured by Augie
and Keith. Judo master rescues Adebayo as Flag
Senior and Bordeaux team up with ex Luther Corp
employee Sydney Happerson to find the portal.
When the police arrive, Augie lets Chris and his
friends go despite Keith's protests. Adrian
kills Augie, horrifying both brothers. The group
flees toward the portal pursued by Keith, who is
badly injured by Eagle, Adrian and Harcourt
before Chris stops them from killing him,
overcome with guilt over the deaths around him.
After a shootout with police, the group returns
home and seal the portal, only to be surrounded by
Argus. Chris surrenders and hands over the QC
device to Flag Senior. My favorite line from this
episode was, that was the most people I've ever
killed with an electrical cable in a swimming
pool. I actually really liked Judo master this
season. Yeah, he was better in this season than
last I would agree. Mainly because he teamed up
with the 11th Street kids. And I feel like he's
better served as an ally because he's just such an
asshole. But they're all assholes, you know?
Right, right, right. Again, the season should
have ended here and the story picked up in the next
season. Because you had like the perfect setup
where like Judo master was on the team of the 11th
Street kids, but also it was the culmination of the
Earth X storyline. Right, exactly. And it was a
great culmination, too. Like Peacemaker just
feeling so much guilt again over his father's
death and the near death of his brother once again.
That was powerful stuff. Yeah, for sure. But it
didn't end there. There was one more episode,
episode eight titled Full Nelson. A flashback
shows Chris in hardcore sharing a kiss during a
boat concert before she walked away in the
present. Chris sits in prison, refusing
visitors. Argus investigates new doors and
worlds accessible through the QC, where numerous
agents are killed. Adebayo and Adrian bail Chris
out, but he vanishes with eagerly. Argus
discovers a livable dimension dubbed salvation,
which flag senior proposes as a metahuman prison.
Disillusioned, Bordeaux exposes the plan to
Harcourt and the two quit Argus. Together with
Adebayo, Adrian and Economus, they find Chris at a
motel and reassure him of his worth. Harcourt
admits that their kiss together meant something
and they begin dating. A week later, the group
forms a new agency, Checkmate, alongside
Bordeaux, Flurry and Judo Master. But in a final
twist, Peacemaker is abducted and trapped in
salvation by flag senior and Argus, who also
closed the portal back. Now, here's the main
problem I have with this finale and the reasoning
of Rick flag senior. If he didn't care what
happened to the prisoners, knowing that they
would eventually just kind of die by being
stranded on salvation. Why even put them on a
livable dimension to begin with? Like, why not put
them in the candyland dimension if you don't care
about them? I thought the exact same thing.
Literally, it doesn't matter where you dump them.
If what happens to them is of no consequence to you.
I thought maybe he was trying to work around a legal
issue, but I don't even think that was the case.
Well, yeah, if it was, that was never explained. So
I don't think it was. It's really weird because he
could have done two different things. He could
have put prisoners in a lethal dimension and
exploited salvation for its resources, and it
seems weird that that's not what he chose to do. You
would think that he would just toss Peacemaker in
that hell dimension, which I thought was
hilarious because like they opened the door and
they're like, let's not go in there. Yeah. Yeah,
but the whole thing could have been about
resources. Like they hypothesized in this
episode. You're totally right. It was weird, just
a weird ending. I didn't like it at all. It just felt
really rushed and tacked on. It left me really
disappointed with this season. Well, it also
provides a stumbling block for checkmate, right?
Because now they don't even get to be the
organization they want to be until they finish the
side quest with Chris. Right. If they had plans for
a season three, which they don't, they could have
started that season off with them doing
investigative work. But now they can't do that.
Unless again, they're planning on appearing in
Man of Tomorrow, which that's a huge cast of
characters to have appear there. Overall, I think
while this shows heartfelt and humorous ensemble
cast delivers, the story fails to live up to its
potential, making for a disappointing early
entry in the DCU. I'm giving it two and a half out of
five stars, which is a rotten rating on rotten
tomatoes. It's a little harsh, but I don't fully
disagree with that rating. Again, I really liked
like the first three to four episodes of this show.
And really, what happened is that it didn't go
where I thought it would. And it didn't fulfill
that potential, that great potential that it had
established. There were some weird moments. A lot
of it was just kind of like jumbled together in a way
that made it feel half hazard. Absolutely. Yeah,
between the filler, the plot holes, the
unnecessary characters and subplots, the missed
opportunities and unsatisfying ending, I really
had a hard time justifying a higher rating than
this, which I agree does feel harsh, especially
considering a majority of critics liked it. Like
we're late in getting up this review. Currently,
season two is standing at a 95 percent on the tomato
meter. Although I think most of those reviews were
just of the initial episodes. Hopefully they do
announce a season three and maybe the show can
redeem itself. I feel like they're not going to
announce anything until this potential Warner
Brothers acquisition happens. So who knows how
long it'll be before we get some news. That's just a
guess, though. But that does it for this review.
A.G .9K help close us out. Support the show on
Patreon at patreon.com slash dynamic dual and
joining a tier that works for you or by rating and
reviewing dynamic dual on Apple podcasts,
Spotify, Podchaser or on our website. Don't
forget to listen to the other shows in the dynamite
podcast network, including Max Destruction,
Senjo World and Console Combat. In our next
episode, we're getting back to the duals.
Actually, it's going to be a team dual where we find
out who would win in a fight between the authority
originating in DC's Wildstorm Universe and the
Cabal, which is like the villain version of the
Illuminati in Marvel. That does it for this
episode. We want to give a big thanks to our
executive producers, John Starosky, Zachary
Hepburn, Dustin Belcombe, Nathaniel Wagner,
Levi Aitin, Austin Wazalowski, AJ Dunkerly,
Nikobanto, Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam
Speese, Dean Molesky, Devin Davis, Joseph
Kirsting, Mike Williams and Paul Graves for
helping make this podcast possible. We'll talk to
you guys next week. Up, up and away, true
believers. Don't talk your joke. You'll go blind.
Superhero T-shirts. I want them. You want them. We
all want a good superhero T, especially with the
holidays around the corner. And that's where
OldGlory.com comes in. They've got officially
licensed Marvel and DC apparel, shirts, hoodies,
hats, gifts so you can rep your favorite hero in
style. Whether you're team Captain America or
team Batman, you'll find something epic in their
massive catalog of over 300,000 items
celebrating all things pop culture. Right now,
you can save 15 percent off any purchase when you
use our promo code dual at checkout. That's dual D U
E L at OldGlory.com because you deserve great
superhero merch.