This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi and welcome
to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe and I'm his twin
brother Johnny DC. And in this episode, we're
going to find out who'd win in a fight between the
powerful psychic and emotional entities of
Parallax and Onslaught. Yeah, these are two major
earth-shattering villains from the 90s in the
comics, like some of the coolest villains of all
time from Marvel and DC. Yeah, really looking
forward to this one. We got to thank John Staroski
for pitching this particular matchup. He's one of
our executive producers and of course the host for
console combat. Before we get into that matchup
though, to find out who'd win mathematically,
we're going to go over the latest comic book movie
news to come out this past week, of which there was
none, but we did get really exciting Marvel vs DC
comic book news, so we're going to talk about that
briefly. As always, we list our segment times in
our episode description, so feel free to check out
the show notes if you want to skip ahead to a
particular topic. Our artificially intelligent
dual simulator AJ9K has a quick message for our
listeners, so listen up. Thanks AJ9K and thanks to
everyone who supports the show. Guys, be sure to
tune into the other shows and the Dynamite Podcast
Network this week, including Max Destruction,
which pits your favorite action heroes from film
and television against each other. This
Wednesday, hosts Scotty and Gilly are finding out
who'd win in a fight between Mewtwo from Detective
Pikachu and Shadow from Sonic the Hedgehog 3. On
the Senjoh World podcast, hosts Zachary Hepburn
speculates on fights between fan-favorite anime
and manga characters. Zach is on a brief season
break right now, but anime fans should check out
his episode archive, including his recent
Akatsuki vs Espada matchup. His next episode is
going to be Vasto Lord Ichigo from Bleach vs Six
Tail Kyuubi Naruto. I was way off on that. On the
console combat podcast, hosts John and Dean
simulate battles between popular video game
characters. In yesterday's episode, they found
out who'd win in a fight between Morgan from Dragon
Age and Yennefer from The Witcher. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our show
notes to listen to all of the shows in the Dynamite
Podcast Network. But with that out of the way,
quick to the no prize! A no prize is an award
Marvel used to give out to fans. Our version,
the Dynamic Dual No Prize, is a digital award we
post on Instagram for the person that we feel gave
the best answer to our question of the week. Last
week we asked the guys if you could take either the
Marvel or DC Cinematic universes and place them in
a separate film franchise, what would it be? And
this is coming off the news of the leaked concept
art that we saw a few weeks ago for Avengers Secret
Wars, which seemed to set the film in a high fantasy
Lord of the Rings Game of Thrones-esque world
recreated by Dr. Doom. We got quite a number of
answers, but we're going to break down our three
honorable mentions before revealing this week's
no prize winner. Our first honorable mention goes
to Lee Tapscott, who said, Hi, this is Lee. I'd like
to see the MCU in the Terminator future. The movie
starts out as the surviving Avengers are fighting
Terminators. Skynet knows it's about to lose
because of Tony Stark. The main story of this
movie, like the original film, Skynet sends a
Terminator back to the kill a young Tony Stark. Who
will be sent back in the past to protect an
unprepared Tony as he watches his parents die from
the Terminator? Yeah, this is a great answer. I
would love to see the MCU set in the universe of the
Terminator franchise. Of course, I think the
Avengers vs. the Terminators would play out
probably pretty similarly as Avengers Age of
Ultron, but I would really like to see the movie
where the Avengers send someone back in time, be it
the Hulk or Captain America or Iron Man himself,
goes back to protect young Tony Stark from like a
T-1000 who gets sent back to kill him. Yeah, maybe
it's like the Winter Soldier and Captain America
sent back in time to protect young Tony from him.
That would be cool. Yeah, like somehow the
Terminators brainwashed Bucky or basically they
just turned him into a full on cyborg or something
like that, sending him back in time. That's a
pretty good concept. I like it. Great answer, Lee.
Our next honorable mention goes to Travis
Herndon. Who said? What's up, Dine Medus? Travis
here, shout out to my evil twin. So my answer had to
be the MCU with the old Toho Godzilla franchise
movies. Like, I'm managing the Avengers and
Godzilla teaming up against Thanos and King
Ghidorah and other aliens and stuff, or them
fighting Ultron controlling like a whole army of
mecha-gazillas. Just seeing like an old school
type movie universe combined with this New Age
superhero stuff would be sick. That would be sick.
Yeah, this has been done in the comics, or actually
it's going on right now in the comic books, where
they're doing a Marvel vs. Godzilla crossover
similarly to what they did with DC last year. But
would I want to see that in a movie format? Hell
yeah, I would. Hell yeah. Yeah, the stuff that
Warner Brothers and Legendary have been doing
with Godzilla lately has been pretty awesome. The
monsterverse as a cinematic universe is
incredible. Well, Travis was also referring to
the old Toho films, you know, that would be cool
too. That's true. Honestly, Godzilla minus one
and Shin Godzilla are probably better than what
Warner Brothers and Legendary are doing with the
monsterverse. I just feel like because the
monsterverse is Hollywood, you would have an
easier time of getting that made. And there's a lot
of established characters there already,
because like you could have King Kong show up as
well. Great answer, Travis. Our next honorable
mention goes to Matt from Texas. Who said? Hey
guys, it's Matt from Texas. I would like to see the
MCU merged with the Jurassic Park franchise.
Maybe they can think they're going to the Savage
Land, but these dinosaurs are going to be way
worse. The DCU, I would like to see merged with the
Alien and Predator franchise. Get Batman vs.
Predator, see if the Alien blood could harm
Superman. That's going to be freaking awesome.
Yeah, I think the Marvel Universe meets Jurassic
Park movie would play out kind of similarly to
Godzilla. Godzilla is kind of dinosaur like it
would be really cool to see though. And of course,
the Savage Land exists in the comic book. So we've
seen these characters interact with dinosaurs
and the source material. But we've also seen like
Batman go up against Predator and the source
material as well during those like Dark Horse DC
comic crossovers. Oh yeah, Batman vs. Predator
was pretty damn good. Not going to lie. And so with
Superman vs. Aliens, that was cool. Get Alien, get
Predator, get Superman and Batman all in one film.
Make it like a sci-fi horror superhero fight for
survival. I think that'd be really fun to watch.
It'll be the first trillion dollar film. So great
answer, Matt. We want to give a quick shout out to
Colby Hentges who said he wants Marvel or DC to show
up in 80s hijinks films like Johnny Hughes films. I
feel like we kind of got that vibe in the recent
Spider-Man Home trilogy because the vibe of those
films was heavily influenced by 80s high school
films. Daniel Alonso said DC should appear in
their own DC cinematic universe because they're
having trouble getting one started, which I
thought was a really good burn. Dishonorable
mention, John Serozky said he would like to see the
Thunderbolts or the Suicide Squad crossover with
the hateful eight. Quentin Tarantino movie,
which was basically a bunch of outlaws in a powder
keg environment where they're snowed in in this
cabin altogether. I think that'd be pretty fun as
well. And then the Kamacho twins from the Max
Destruction podcast said DC and Marvel should
cross over with each other's cinematic
universes. That's the best answer. It's
definitely the definitive answer, but probably
not right now because I'm not sure what DC universe
would cross over. Because the DC EU is dead and the
new DC EU has yet to begin. So I just couldn't
picture it as things stand right now. But the
winner of this week's snow prize is Mason
Thompson. Who said? Hey, it's Mason. I would have
to have the boys or invincible because I'd kind of
like to see how the picture perfect superheroes
interact with the corrupted. More in like the
boys, but kind of how like everything goes perfect
in those universes and then like invincible and
the boys, everything's kind of like a little bit
corrupted. I don't know. I just like to see like the
dynamics between the heroes. I know one thing for
certain. No matter who shows up in the boys
universe, homelanders get in the Zaskik. Yeah, I
agree 100%. And I haven't even seen the show and I
agree. I haven't seen it either. Actually, every
time an acquaintance or someone finds out that I do
superhero podcasts, they ask me, have you seen the
boys? And I don't know why because it's neither
Marvel nor DC and I think people just get confused.
But no, I haven't seen the boys largely because I
watch so much superhero television from Marvel
and DC that I just don't have time to watch the
Amazon Prime show. But I'm interested in it. You
know, I like Garth Ennis's writing him and Mark
Millar and like Warren Ellis. They do a great job of
taking these tropes from Marvel and DC and really
deconstructing the superhero genre. I'm not the
biggest fan of that type of work, but I really liked
Invincible. Invincible was a great show. Yeah, I
mean, I see Invincible and the boys as sort of a
parody of sorts of the Justice League. Like even
wanted was a parody of the Legion of Doom because
the DC heroes and villains are so iconic. It's kind
of easier to lampoon and spoof those characters.
So that kind of turns me off and that's probably one
of the reasons why I haven't checked out these
shows too thoroughly. I did watch a majority of
Invincible season one. I just haven't finished it
yet. I thought that was good. But again, I'm Johnny
DC for a reason. The DC characters to me are more
interesting. Robert Kirkman had Invincible show
up in a Marvel team up issue. I remember I actually
really liked it. It was funny because he was like
making fun of all the Marvel characters names. He
was like, OK, so you're Spider-Man. If that's how
you guys are naming people around here, I'm
guessing your flag, man. It was hilarious. Nice.
Great answer, Mason Thompson. You win this week's
No Prize. If you the listener want to shout out
winning your own No Prize, stay tuned to later on
this episode when we'll be asking another
question of the week. But now that that's done, on
to the news. OK, a couple of weeks ago at Comics Pro,
which is a comic book retail summit in Glendale,
California, the two heads of Marvel and DC
publishing, namely C.B. Sibulski for Marvel and
Marie Jevins for DC, were on stage talking about
the comic book industry and they began joking
about how they should do another comic's
crossover. And the audience just roared. It looks
like they're going to do it. They're saying
they're going to release it this year. We don't
know anything about this crossover, except that
it's going to be two one-shot comics tentatively
titled Marvel slash DC and DC slash Marvel. Yeah,
we've had previous major crossovers between
Marvel and DC in the comic books. You know, back in
the mid 90s and 96, they came out with DC versus
Marvel. And that was a big event. And then in the
early 2000s, we had JLA slash Avengers. And I was a
big fan of both events. I really liked the JLA
Avengers crossover. Yeah, that was done by George
Perez and Kurt Busick, an iconic phenomenal team
who knocked it out of the park with that mini
series. But of course, there have been other
one-shot comics to feature Marvel and DC
crossovers like the very first one, Superman and
Spider-Man. There's been a Punisher in Batman,
Batman and Captain America. There was Superman,
Silver Surfer. And of course, all of these were
collected last year into graphic novel omnibuses
when focusing on the 90s crossover and one
focusing on the one-shots. For some reason, they
didn't include the Avengers JLA crossover. Not
sure why. But essentially, these omnibuses were
the catalyst for this upcoming crossover that
they were talking about at Comics Pro. They don't
know what characters are going to be featured and
who's going to be writing and drawing the
one-shots. But I am so excited that they're even
joining forces because it's been a long time since
they've done that. Yeah, almost 20 years now. I
think Marvel and DC should cross over at least once
a decade. At least. And to me, I feel like if a lot of
people jump on board this, there's a stronger
likelihood for the cinematic universes to cross
over as well. Particularly with James Gunn at the
helm of DC Studios considering he's worked for
Marvel in the past. That would be awesome. Maybe
we'll even get a Marvel vs DC video game. Which is,
you know, like the end all be all, I feel like. The
dream. The dream! We'll see what happens. We'll
keep you guys updated on this particular
crossover event in the comic books so that we can
all just jump on it when it gets released. But
speaking of DC and Marvel Comics Crossovers, that
brings us to our question of the week. What is your
favorite Marvel and DC Comics crossover and why?
Yeah, we've mentioned quite a few of them during
this segment. If you guys haven't read any of them,
definitely check them out. And then call us with
your answer. Record your answer at
dynamicdool.com by clicking on the red
microphone button in the bottom right hand corner
of the screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long and don't forget to leave your name in case we
include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a dynamic
duel no prize that we'll post to Instagram. Be sure
to answer before March 15th. But that does it for
all the news for this episode, so let's go ahead and
move on to our main event where we find out who would
win in a fight between the all-powerful entities
of Parallax and Onslaught. Alright, Parallax vs.
Onslaught. Both of these characters were really
big in the 90s, so they've made subsequent
appearances in the comic book since then. But
basically they were known for their corrupting
influence over major, beloved comic book heroes.
In the case of Parallax, he heavily corrupted the
character of Hal Jordan, the Green Lantern, and
then on the Marvel side, Onslaught corrupted
Professor X. Yeah, of course Parallax was the
primary villain in the Green Lantern film
starring Ryan Reynolds, but we're not going to
hold that against him because the character
really wasn't done justice in the way he has been
done in the comics. Yeah, as far as I know, the comic
book version of Parallax looks kind of like a big
yellow lobster kind of. I would say cockroach.
Okay, but in the movie he was definitely like a big
watery shit with a face. Yeah, like a turd
sandwich. Yeah. Whereas Onslaught, you know, he
doesn't really have a form. He has an energy form
when you remove his armor, but he's basically just
this psychic entity and he's never been in the
movies. They kind of did allude to him, I think, at
the end of X-Men 97 season one, but we'll see if he
manifests in season two. I have no idea how this
matchup is going to go down because I don't know
much about the entity of Parallax, but I gotta say
if he's a giant cockroach, he's nowhere near as
badass as Onslaught and he's probably going to
lose. Oh, you think, huh? Yeah, cockroaches were
meant to be squished. Well, I mean, the cockroach
form is just an energy form. Parallax and the other
emotional entities typically possess beings. So
I was thinking for this matchup, he was going to
have a host body. Could be Hell Jordan, could be
Kyleraynor, could be any Green Lantern, really.
Okay. Oh, has he possessed Kyleraynor in the past,
too? Yes, yeah. Well, I'm sure we'll learn all
about that as we get into the character's
breakdowns. But first to explain the methodology
behind our duels, let's go to our sentient dual
simulator, Alfred Jarvis 9000. AJ9K tell our
listeners how you go about determining a winner in
our dual matchups. Yes, of course, sir. The way I
determine a winner between the contestants is by
running 1000 Monte Carlo simulations using the
character's statistics. A Monte Carlo
simulation is a probabilistic model used to
determine outcomes through random sampling. In
this case, I randomize the statistics along a
normal distribution as a way to simulate the many
variables that can occur during battle. The stat
parameters are based on the official Marvel power
grid from which the DC characters' statistics are
extrapolated. Additional stat categories are
included such as range, damage potential,
versatility and perception in order to create a
more detailed and accurate simulation. The
results of the 1000 simulations provide a
percentage of wins for each character. The
contestant with the higher percentage is
declared the victor as they have a higher
probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither character should win
100% of the matches. The comic book stories have
shown that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman, so the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks, AJ9K!
Before we run the simulations though, we'd like to
break down each character's histories and
abilities before improvising a scenario on how we
imagine one of the 1000 simulations would play out
beat for beat. And I believe it's my turn to go first
with the Marvel character for this episode, so let
me go ahead and tell you guys all about...
Onslaught. The psionic entity known as Onslaught
was created during a climactic battle between the
X-Men and Magneto's Acolytes. During the fight,
Magneto used his powers to rip the adamantium from
Wolverine's skeleton, an act so brutal that it
left Wolverine severely injured, exhausting his
healing factor. Enraged by the attack, Professor
Charles Xavier retaliated by using his
telepathic powers to shut down Magneto's mind,
rendering him catatonic, an act with unforeseen
consequences. During this psionic contact,
Magneto's anger, grief, and thirst for vengeance
penetrated Xavier's subconscious, mingling
with Xavier's own long suppressed negative
emotions. This fusion of consciousness gave rise
to a new sentience, Onslaught, an entity that
initially laid dormant deep within Xavier's
psyche. You can learn more about Professor X and
Magneto in their respective dual episodes
against the Chief and Sinestro. As Onslaught
remained hidden, he subtly influenced Xavier's
thoughts and emotions, catalyzed by Xavier's
growing frustration with humanity's fear and
hostility toward mutants. The deaths of mutants
from the Legacy Virus, his inability to reform
dangerous individuals like Sabertooth, and the
overall rising anti-mutant hysteria all
contributed to Xavier's increasing doubts about
his dream of peaceful coexistence. The final
breaking point came when a young mutant was killed
near the grounds of the Xavier Institute for
Higher Learning. At that moment, Onslaught
awakened, beginning to exert control over
Xavier's mind and actions. One of Onslaught's
earliest manipulations was targeting Jane Gray.
He lured her to the astral plane, revealing
long-buried secrets about Xavier's past,
including the suppression of her telepathic
powers when she first became his student.
Onslaught hoped that this revelation would
shatter her faith in Xavier's ideology. Jane
resisted Onslaught's influence, though,
rejecting his offer to join his cause. In
response, Onslaught branded his name into her
mind before returning her to the real world. You
can learn more about Jane Gray in our Raven vs.
Phoenix episode. Onslaught also attempted to
recruit Xavier's stepbrother, Juggernaut.
Seeking to use Juggernaut's immense power for his
own ends, Onslaught approached him in Vancouver,
Canada, offering him a place in his crusade. When
Juggernaut refused, Onslaught lashed out,
blocking his memory of their encounter and
magnetically flinging him across the continent
to New Jersey. Juggernaut, dazed and unable to
recall what happened, managed to utter only one
word upon being discovered by the X-Men,
Onslaught. You can learn more about Juggernaut
and his duel against Atrocitus. As Onslaught's
influence grew, he infiltrated a
government-sanctioned sentinel base, where he
downloaded schematics and reprogrammed the
mutant hunting machines to serve him.
Onslaught's plans escalated further when he
encountered Nate Gray, the telepathic and
telekinetic mutant known as X-Men. During the
astral encounter, Nate inadvertently pulled
Onslaught's consciousness into the physical
world, allowing him to manifest as an independent
entity for the first time. Onslaught revealed
himself to the X-Men, declaring his aim to reshape
the world by creating a new order, one where
mutants ruled supreme. However, unlike Magneto,
Onslaught did not merely wish for mutant
superiority, he intended to force all of humanity
into a collective intelligence. To achieve this,
he set his sights on Franklin Richards, the son of
Mr. Fantastic, an invisible woman whose vast
reality-warping powers could make Onslaught's
vision a reality. Onslaught created a childlike
psionic projection of a young boy named Charlie to
befriend Franklin and lure him into his grasp. In
addition to capturing Franklin, Onslaught
abducted Nate Gray, further augmenting his own
immense psionic power. With these two young
mutants under his control, Onslaught turned his
attention to New York City. He set his
reprogrammed sentinels to seize control of
Manhattan, forming a barrier around the island,
isolating it from the rest of the world.
Establishing a citadel in Central Park,
Onslaught prepared for the final phase of his
plan. The X-Men, the Fantastic Four, and the
Avengers all converged to stop Onslaught. During
their initial confrontation, the heroes managed
to sever the link between Onslaught and Xavier,
hoping that this would weaken the entity.
However, instead of diminishing Onslaught's
power, the act allowed him to evolve further,
becoming a being of pure psionic energy. Now fully
independent, Onslaught unleashed an
electromagnetic pulse that crippled electronic
systems across the city, plunging Manhattan into
chaos. You can learn more about the X-Men,
Avengers, and Fantastic Four, and their
respective duels against the Titans, Justice
League, and Justice Society. Determined to end
humanity, Onslaught used Franklin Richards'
abilities to create a second sun in Earth's
atmosphere, threatening to incinerate the
planet. To stop him, Jean Gray suppressed Bruce
Banner's rational mind, allowing the Hulk's full
rage to take over. In a mindless fury, the Hulk
launched a brutal assault on Onslaught, tearing
through his armor. However, this inadvertently
made Onslaught even more dangerous, as his
psionic energy form was now uncontained and
immune to physical attacks. In a desperate final
gambit, Thor flew into Onslaught's energy mass,
attempting to disrupt him from within. Realizing
that Onslaught needed a physical anchor to be
destroyed, the non-mute members of the Avengers
and the Fantastic Four sacrificed themselves by
merging into his energy form. With Onslaught now
bound to something tangible, the remaining
heroes struck their final blow, seemingly
destroying him. Although it was believed that
these heroes had perished, Franklin Richards
subconsciously created a pocket universe
Transporting them to an alternate reality known
as Counter-Earth. They remained there for some
time before eventually returning to the primary
Marvel universe. Though Onslaught was thought to
be eradicated, remnants of his consciousness
persisted. Years later, in the aftermath of the
Scarlet Witch's depowering of most of Earth's
mutants, Onslaught resurfaced. Reforming from
the residual energies of Xavier and Magneto's
powers, he set his sights on Franklin Richards
once more. Onslaught manipulated the human torch
and Mr. Fantastic into attacking Franklin, but
the boy managed to escape into the recreated
Counter-Earth. Onslaught followed him where he
battled the heroes of that world. Ultimately,
Ricky Barnes, the Bucky of Counter-Earth,
sacrificed herself to banish Onslaught into an
alternate dimension known as the Negative Zone,
which you can learn more about in our Mongol vs.
Annihilus episode. Despite being trapped,
Onslaught eventually found a way to escape. He
possessed Ricky Barnes' form using her as a vessel
to return to Earth. However, Ricky resisted his
influence and in a final act of defiance, had
herself killed to ensure that Onslaught could not
return. Later, a new version of Onslaught known as
Red Onslaught emerged when the Red Skull grafted a
portion of Xavier's brain onto his own, granting
him powerful telepathic abilities. This new
incarnation of Onslaught spread hate and chaos
across the world, manipulating heroes and
villains alike. He was eventually defeated when
Scarlet Witch and Dr. Doom performed a magic spell
that temporarily inverted the morality of
everyone affected. Most recently, when the
Earth's mutants created an independent island
nation for themselves on Krakowa, Onslaught
returned once again as part of a plot by the
anti-mute organization Orcus. They implanted a
fragment of Onslaught's essence into the mind of a
mutant named Lost, allowing him to infiltrate
Krakowa undetected. Under the guise of a psychic
entity called Patchwork Man, Onslaught preyed on
the negative emotions of Krakowa mutants, subtly
influencing them toward destruction. He was
eventually discovered by Xavier, who believed
this Patchwork entity to be a manifestation of one
of his son, Legion's personalities. However,
Legion revealed it was actually Onslaught who had
returned. You can learn more about Legion in his
duel against Crazy Jane. Onslaught eventually
possessed most of the mutants on the Krakowa
island, planning to have everyone kill each other
without the benefit of the mutant resurrection
process, which you can learn more about in our
Danny the Street vs Krakowa duel episode.
Nightcrawler managed to free everyone by
teleporting them into a pocket universe inside of
Legion's mind, and together, the mutant
collective united in communion to embrace
Onslaught instead of fighting him. Their
combined will weakened Onslaught to the point
where Nightcrawler crushed him, seemingly
ending his reign of terror for good. Powers-wise,
Onslaught as a psychic entity possesses the
combined powers of his creators, Professor X and
Magneto. This means that he has vast telepathic
abilities which grant him mind reading, mind
control, mind erasure, mind transference,
thought casting, illusion casting, psychic
cloaking, psychic shielding, psychic pain
induction, and psychic astral projection, all on
a global scale. Onslaught can also control the
fundamental horses of electromagnetism, which
grants him complete molecular control of metals
at any scale, from manipulating iron and
hemoglobin to moving mountains. He can also fly,
create impenetrable electromagnetic energy
shields, and emit electromagnetic blasts and
pulses at the level of a nuclear bomb. In a
combination of these powers, Onslaught also
possesses telekinesis, allowing him to move or
destroy matter with his mind, from small objects
to entire city blocks. His telekinesis can
teleport and can be used with such acuity as to
create holographic illusions by manipulating
dust particles and water vapor to refract light
waves. Physically, Onslaught has vast strength
and durability able to lift in excess of 100 tons on
his own. He can psychically absorb mutants in
order to gain their abilities as he did with
Franklin Richards and Nate Gray, but he won't be
wielding those additional powers in this match.
Finally, with the combined expertise, training,
and strategic thinking of Professor X and
Magneto, Onslaught is supremely intelligent
with some combat experience. Interesting. This
almost feels like it's going to be a beefed up
version of Sinestro vs. Magneto and Atrocitus vs.
Juggernaut. Oh, for sure. Yeah, but that makes me
think that Parallax's abilities are to create
constructs like a Green Lantern or a Red Lantern.
He can do that and a whole lot more. Let me get into
his backstory. No, Parallax was a primordial
entity that came into existence with the dawn of
sentient life in the universe. In the spectrum of
emotional energy that emerged, Parallax was the
embodiment of fear, yellow, and color, a
parasitic force that thrived by instilling
terror in its victims and feeding on the emotions
of those it infected. As it traveled from world to
world, it consumed entire civilizations,
driving them into madness and self-destruction
through paranoia and terror. Billions of years
ago, the Guardians of the Universe from the planet
Owa recognized the danger posed by Parallax and
sought to contain it. They imprisoned the entity
within the Green Lantern Central Power Battery on
Owa, sealing it away with the green energy of will.
To prevent others from learning of Parallax's
existence, the Owens concealed the truth,
allowing the legend of the yellow impurity within
the battery to persist. This impurity limited the
Green Lantern's ability to affect anything
yellow and ensured only that those who could
overcome great fear could wield a Green Lantern
Ring effectively. For centuries, Parallax
remained contained within the Green Lantern
Central Power Battery, but its influence subtly
seeped into the minds of the Green Lantern Core.
When the renegade Green Lantern Sinestro was
imprisoned within the battery, his cordian
yellow power ring unknowingly drew upon
Parallax's energy, awakening the entity from
dormancy. You can learn more about Sinestro in his
duel against Magneto. Over time, Parallax's
influence began affecting Hal Jordan,
recognizing him as one of the greatest Green
Lanterns of all time. Without Hal's knowledge,
the entity slowly planted seeds of fear and doubt
within him, causing minor but noticeable changes
in his psyche. You can learn more about Hal Jordan,
of course, in our Green Lantern vs. Nova duel
episode. Parallax's influence on Hal became more
pronounced after the destruction of Coast City at
the hands of Mongol and the Cyborg Superman.
Overcome with grief and desperation, Jordan
sought to use his ring to restore the city, but when
the Owens refused his request, his emotional
state deteriorated further. Secumbing to
Parallax's control, Jordan turned against the
Green Lantern Core, attacking Oa and
slaughtering the Lanterns who stood in his way.
Upon entering the central power battery and
absorbing all of its energy, Hal fully merged with
Parallax in the process. Now wielding
unimaginable power, Hal cast aside his identity
as a Green Lantern and took on the name of Parallax,
seeking to reshape reality itself. With the full
power of Parallax, Jordan attempted to reshape
time and recreate the universe to his own liking in
order to undo the chaos and destruction that
plagued existence. After teaming up with the
villain Extant, who shared similar goals, their
plan to rewrite history nearly succeeded, but
Parallax was ultimately defeated by Earth's
heroes and the timeline was restored. In the wake
of his defeat, Jordan began to fight back against
Parallax's control. When Earth's sun was
extinguished, Jordan, in an act of sheer
willpower and redemption, used his power to
reignite it, sacrificing himself in the process.
His soul, however, was not allowed to rest,
instead becoming bonded to the Spectre, the
spirit of divine vengeance that you could learn
more about in our Spectre vs Galactus episode. But
even in death, Parallax's influence lingered
with Jordan, corrupting his time as the Spectre's
host and preventing him from fully embracing the
entity's mission. Parallax remained dormant
until Kyle Reiner uncovered the truth behind the
yellow impurity in the central power battery. He
discovered that Parallax was not merely a
weakness in the rings but a sentient entity
imprisoned within the battery for billions of
years. With this knowledge, Ganthit and the
remaining Owens worked to separate Parallax from
Hel Jordan's soul. You can learn more about Kyle
Reiner in our White Lantern vs Null dual episode.
As Parallax was exercised, Jordan was
resurrected, regaining his physical body and
status as a Green Lantern. Parallax, meanwhile,
was re-emprisoned within the central power
battery. Sinestro, having formed his own army of
fear-wielding lanterns known as the Sinestro
Core, sought to use Parallax as a weapon against
the Green Lanterns. He freed Parallax from its
prison and bonded it to Kyle Reiner, forcing
Reiner to become its host. Under Parallax's
control, Reiner led an assault on Owa, spreading
fear across the universe. Hel Jordan and the other
lanterns managed to free Reiner and Parallax was
recaptured. This time, to prevent its escape, the
Owens split the entity into four parts and
imprisoned each portion within the personal
power batteries of Hel Jordan, Kyle Reiner, John
Stewart, and Guy Gardner. During the rise of the
Black Lantern Core, Parallax was once again
unleashed when Hel Jordan voluntarily allowed it
to possess him in order to battle the Undead
Spectre, who had been corrupted by a Black Lantern
Ring. With Parallax's power, Jordan was able to
free the Spectre and push back the Black Lantern
forces before expelling the entity once more.
Parallax was later captured by Krona, the rogue
guardian of the universe who sought to use
Parallax and the other emotional entities to
exert control over the Green Lantern Core. Krona
placed Parallax back into the central power
battery, reinstating the yellow impurity and
corrupting nearly every Green Lantern in the
universe. Jordan and his allies, however,
resisted its influence using the rings of other
Lantern Cores to combat Krona's forces. In the
final battle, Parallax was removed from the
central power battery and Krona was defeated.
Eventually, Sinestro, seeking ultimate power,
allowed Parallax to possess him, though he was
able to maintain control over its influence. With
Parallax's power, Sinestro became one of the most
formidable beings in the universe, enabling him
to kill the Guardians of Oa. When the other
entities of the emotional spectrum were drawn
back to the Source, the primordial origin of all
energy, to restore the emotional spectrum when it
was thrown into disarray, Parallax was the only
one who remained behind, still bound to Sinestro.
Parallax was eventually separated from Sinestro
and was greatly weakened. Struggling to regain
its strength, Parallax began abducting
children, feeding on their fears to sustain
itself. In a desperate bid for power, it possessed
the Reverse Flash, who you can learn more about in
his dual episode against King the Conqueror.
Parallax was ultimately expelled, however, and
left once again without a host. Now, powers-wise,
Parallax is an entity of pure fear energy, capable
of infecting minds and its victims and exerting
near total control over them. It possesses
individuals who experience even the slightest
fear, corrupting their thoughts and twisting
their emotions. Those under Parallax's
influence exhibit immense power, often
surpassing the capabilities of a standard
lantern. Parallax creates energy constructs
similar to a green or yellow lantern, but on a far
greater scale, often forming monstrous avatars
of fear to intimidate and attack its enemies. It
can instill terror on a planetary level and can
drive entire civilizations to
self-destruction. In its true form, Parallax has
no physical body, existing as a shapeless entity
that takes on forms designed to terrify those who
behold it. Though it is vulnerable to willpower,
it is nearly impossible to destroy. That's
Parallax. Interesting, yet the entity of
Parallax is a little bit more abstract than the
entity of Onslaught, so I'm really curious how
this speculation is going to go down. But if we can
make a sentient street go up against a sentient
island, we could probably do anything. So let's
give it a shot. Now that we've got their histories
and abilities out of the way, let's speculate on
how one of the 1000 simulated matches will go. The
winner is determined by simulations, not the
speculation, but it's fun to imagine how this
fight could play out. AG9K, what are the rules of
our speculation? Well, I should say there are no
rules other than the characters have no prior
knowledge of the other going into the fight. All
they are aware of starting out is that the other
character is a threat that needs to be eliminated.
For the speculation, the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the match
itself, as no environmental statistics are
considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. All right,
then let's get into it. Parallax and Onslaught
meet on the battlefield. Who goes first? I'm going
to say Parallax goes first by, you know, of course,
probing the fears of Onslaught. That's stupid
because Onslaught is a manifestation of negative
psychic energy, like he has no fears. I don't even
think he's literally capable of fear. I think any
sentient mind has at least a fear of dying. So, you
know, Parallax, he's going to create a yellow
energy construct of this giant moonsized skull
that's going to crash onto Onslaught like an
asteroid and just demolish him. Onslaught's
going to be terrified of that. No, he's not. All
Onslaught is going to do is going to look up at this
moonsized skull and he's going to stretch out his
hand and be like, behold, my mighty hand. And it's
going to send out this electromagnetic shockwave
that's so powerful that it rips into this asteroid
and just like crumble it into boulders, like
thousands of boulders that are going to rain down
all around Onslaught. But he's going to be okay
because he has his energy shield up. But like the
planet they're fighting on is probably
completely devastated and they're probably just
fighting now on like this demolished asteroid
belt in the middle of space. But that is when
Onslaught is going to probe the mind of Parallax's
host and learn exactly what this entity is. Okay,
yeah, sure. You know, Onslaught, he's going to get
a glimpse of Parallax's true like dragon
insectoid form, which is scary as fuck. And while
Onslaught is the slightest bit momentarily
distracted and jarred by this reveal, Parallax is
going to spew from his mouth like dozens of
tentacles with razor sharp claws in place of
suction cups. And they're going to wrap around
Onslaught and just rip his armor off. Okay, we'll
say that these tentacles remove a portion of
Onslaught's armor. But all that's going to do is
make Onslaught stronger because as he becomes
less contained, he grows more powerful, you know,
he's going to grow in size so large that he breaks
free of these tentacles. And he's going to snatch
up Parallax's hosts and hold him in the palm of his
hand and just crush him into dust. And when he opens
his hand, that's going to reveal Parallax's true
demon form. And he's going to telepathically pull
this entity into the astral plane. So now, both
Onslaught and Parallax are psychic entities
battling it out in a realm where anything goes now
basically. Well, wait, so Onslaught's willingly
going to allow the universal embodiment of fear
onto a plane where Parallax doesn't need a host. So
he's like unbound to be his most pure night
marriage self. I will allow this. I will allow
this. So right away on the astral plane, like this
putrid yellow sky is going to emerge and suddenly
these two bright yellow terrifying eyes open in
the sky looking down and piercing Onslaught with a
gaze that would drive mortal minds insane. And
it's going to shatter Onslaught's mind. Okay, you
know what? I'm starting to think that maybe taking
Parallax to the astral plane was not my best play.
I'm going to admit that. Except Onslaught's no
mere mortal mind. Okay. In fact, he brought
Parallax to the astral plane for a reason. And that
is because he absorbs mental energy. So like these
yellow eyes feed into Onslaught, which is going to
make Onslaught grow larger than the sky. You know,
his form abstractly like surpasses all horizons
and all dimensions on the astral plane until he
like actually embodies the astral plane because
he's so powerful now and he consumes Parallax into
himself taking on his power. And now Onslaught
becomes more frightening and powerful than both
Parallax and Onslaught combined. Onslaught. I
was thinking more like Paronslunks. I don't know.
Slunks. Okay. I mean, none of this actually
happens. You know why? Because bringing Parallax
onto the astral plane gives Parallax access to
Onslaught's powerful mind. And that's going to
allow him to extend his fear influence beyond the
planetary level to the universal. And Parallax is
going to draw upon the emotional turmoil to infect
Onslaught's mind like a parasite, making him
think he's one. But really Parallax is in control.
No, Onslaught's in control. Sure. Yeah. That's
exactly what I want you to think. If someone like
Sinestro can still be in control while possessed
by Parallax, then Onslaught sure as hell can. Oh,
you think so, huh? Yeah, that's fine. Meanwhile,
Parallax uses Onslaught's body to take over the
universe and win this match. No, you mean
Onslaught uses Parallax's power to take over the
universe and win this match? Oh, sure. Yeah.
Definitely not the other way around. Wink. The
listeners don't know, but I'm winking. Let's go
ahead and see which of these results happens by
inputting the stats and running the simulations.
It sounds like either way, Onslaught is absorbing
Parallax into himself. It's just a question of
whether Parallax is then in control or Onslaught
is then in control. Let's find out who's in control
with our simulator. 8G9K, hit it. Inputting data,
running calculations, processing results,
simulations complete. All right, guys, that was
pretty fun. Didn't quite go down like how I thought
it would be, but really, if you think about it, I
don't think he could finish any other way. Oh,
yeah, totally. It was very different from what I
thought it was going to be, but essentially, these
are two abstract energy entities. So yeah, it's
not like they're going to throw hands against each
other. I mean, Onslaught has thrown hands before,
you know, against the Avengers and the X-Men and
the Fantastic Four, but we said that both of these
guys have about the same level of strength, also
the same level of durability and also equal in
range. Although we gave Parallax the edge when it
came to movement speed, because he could traverse
the universe much easier than Onslaught can.
Yeah, for as powerful as Onslaught is outside of,
you know, being able to handle a majority of
Earth's heroes, he doesn't have any really
planetary or cosmic level of feats on the same
level as Parallax, but he's a mind reader with a
combined intellect of Professor Exo Magneto,
whereas Parallax is more of like a primordial
entity who's maybe not as evolved and usually gets
captured, you know. So we said that Onslaught has
greater intellect. Yeah, Parallax kind of seems
to drive more on instinct. He's kind of at the whim
of the host regarding his intelligence. He's less
of a mind reader and more of a fear sensor. So
Onslaught got the advantage and perception as
well. Parallax in his Green Lantern host is much
more versatile than Onslaught as well. And we also
gave him the edge when it came to damage level.
Yeah, I mean, for as strong as Onslaught is, he
hasn't destroyed a planet like Parallax has.
Right, which makes me really surprised at our
Instagram poll results, considering that 53% of
our poll takers chose Onslaught for the win. Like,
do you guys know how powerful Parallax is? The guy
literally almost rewrote all of reality in the
universe. Our Instagram poll takers are pretty
keen, though. It's not like Onslaught hasn't
worked reality before, you know, using the powers
of Franklin Richards, of course, but, you know,
he's still done it. Let's find out who won. AJ9K,
the results, please. Hey, you are, sir. All right,
the winner in the duel matchup between Parallax
and Onslaught is Parallax. Hell yeah! Hell yeah!
How did this like little worm guy beat one of the
biggest badasses that Marble has to offer?
Parallax is a universal embodiment of fear, and
Onslaught is just like the embodiment of shared
tantrum. How much did Parallax win by? Out of the
1000 matches, Parallax won 524 of them compared to
Onslaught's 476 wins. So Parallax wins 52.4% of
the time. I'm not gonna lie, I actually thought the
percentage was gonna be much higher for Parallax
than that. Well, what kind of saved Onslaught was
his intellect and perception. Basically, his
ability to telepathically read and control minds
made sure he didn't lose too bad here. Parallax may
win a majority of the matches in a fight against
Onslaught, but there's one thing that he can never
take away from Onslaught, and that is the cool
factor. Marble just says that cool factor that DC
cannot hope to touch, and so I feel like Marble fans
can still take away that consolation. Plus, who
thought Parallax was a good name? Like, that's a
stupid name. I will cede that Onslaught has the
much cooler name. I think DC was just trying to go
for something that sounded like parasite, but
didn't want to use parasite because that was
already taken. That makes sense, actually, I can
see that. But that does it for this duel, guys. A.J.
and I.K. help close us out. Our next episode is
going to be another team duel episode, where in
honor of Women's History Month, we're going to pit
the female teams against each other of Birds of
Prey and A-Force. Yes, it's a surprise team duel
episode. Actually, we're planning on surprising
you guys with a new team duel episode every month
this year. So look forward to that. Well, didn't
you just ruin the surprise by saying that?
Surprise! But that does it for this episode. We
want to give a big thanks to our executive
producers, John Staroski, Zachary Hepburn,
Miggy Mathen-Gian, Brandon Esregard, Nathaniel
Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Austin Wizalowski, A.J.
Dunkerley, Nick Ibonto, Scott Camacho, Gil
Camacho, Adam Spees, Dean Maleski, Devin Davis,
Joseph Kirsting, Josh Leiner, Mike Williams, and
Oscar Galvez for helping make this podcast
possible. And we'll talk to you guys next week. Up,
up and away, true believers! The best amalgam of
parallax and onslaught would be Papa's X-Lacks,
obviously.