This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
Hi, welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Marvelous Joe. And I'm his twin brother,
Johnny DC. And in this episode, we are going
to find out who would win in a fight between
the Superman villain known as the Ultra Humanite
versus the X-Men villain known as Mr. Sinister.
Now, I can't believe that we are over 375 episodes
into this podcast and we have not done a duel
episode with Mr. Sinister yet. That's basically
a crime. Yeah, same with Ultra Humanite. I mean,
no one knows who Ultra Humanite is. He's like-
BITCH! He's the very first Superman villain.
That's all you need to know. Actually, I would
describe him more as a JSA villain. But yeah,
he's got some notoriety. If by notoriety you
mean obscurity, then yeah, notoriety. Basically
both of these guys are elite genetic scientists
with super powerful power sets. Yes, specifically
when it comes to telepathy and telekinesis.
We'll go ahead and speculate on the battle and
input the stats and run the simulations later
on this episode. Before that, we're gonna break
down the comic book movie news that came out
this past week, including news about Joker Follyadoo
and what kind of musical it's gonna be. And
we also got a teaser trailer for the Penguin
Max series. As always, we list our segment
times in our episode description, so feel free
to check out our show notes if you want to
skip ahead to a particular topic. Our artificially
intelligent duel simulator AJ9K has a quick
message for our listeners, so listen up. Why
hello there. Do you love listening and chatting
about Marvel and DC? Then become a part of the
dynamic duel community on Patreon, where you
can choose from three tiers. The dynamic 2-0
tier lets you listen to this podcast without
ads and gives you access to its Discord chat
group, where you can chat with Johnny DC and
Marvelous Joe. The fantastic 4 tier gives you
that and more with two bonus episodes each
month, including bloopers and top 10 shows where
Johnny and Joe count down your favorite Marvel
and DC subjects. The X-Force tier makes you
an executive producer of Dynamic duel. where
every month you help the hosts choose what to
review and who to fight against each other.
And finally, the Dynamite Podcast Network tier
allows aspiring podcasters to create their
own battle-focused show using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and consultation,
and get you simulation results to announce
on your show. Pitch the twins your show via
email at dyna or by reaching out to them on
social media. Check it out at patreon.com slash
dyna your pip cheerio. Thanks AJ9K and thanks
to everyone who supports the podcast. Guys be
sure to tune into the shows on the Dynomic
Podcast Network this week including Max Destruction
which pits your favorite action heroes from
film and television against each other. This
week they're going to find out who's going
to win between Ned Leeds from Spider-Man Homecoming
and Micro from Punisher Warzone. On the Sindroworld
podcast host Zachary Hepburn speculates on fights
between fan favorite This Thursday, we'll find
out who would win between Sengoku from One Piece
and Nitero from Hunter x Hunter. And finally
on the Console Combat Podcast, host John and
Dean find out who would win in fights between
popular video game characters. Yesterday's episode,
they gathered a bunch of people from the DynaMic
Network to review Scott Pilgrim vs. the World,
which is a movie that I love. I was really
sad that I was not able to join that review.
Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link
in our show notes. to listen to all of the shows
in the DynaMic Podcast Network. But with that
out of the way... Quick! To the No Prize! A
No Prize is an award Marvel used to give out
to fans. Our version, the Dynamic duel No Prize,
is a digital award that we post on Instagram
for the person that we feel gave the best answer
to our question of the week. Last week we asked,
what Marvel or DC film do you think had the
best subtitle? and why and this is coming off
of the news that the upcoming Venom sequel is
going to be titled Venom the Last Dance and
we thought that was stupid as hell but we wanted
to hear what the best ones were. We got so
many answers for this question you guys came
out of the woodwork. I was not expecting that
but I truly appreciate it. Yeah we actually
got 10 total answers this week. I can't remember
the last time we received that many answers
so that's exciting. We're going to break down
this week's honorable mentions before revealing
the no prize winner. Our first honorable Nate
Wagner who said, Hey, it's Nate here and I got
to go with Captain America Civil War. I think
reading the comic originally just had me excited
of how they were going to adapt it into a movie,
but almost worried at the same time, just because
there was so much in the comic. And I feel
like they did a really good job overall with
it. So yeah. Okay. So
I don't think Nate Wagner has a kid, so I'm
gonna guess that was a dog. And it seemed like
he disagreed with you. But you know what? I'm
gonna go ahead and agree with you, Nate. I
thought Civil War was a great storyline from
the comics. I was super excited when they announced
that as the subtitle for the third Captain America
film because I didn't think that they were
gonna go there. But they went there. And you
know, it was really off the back of the announcement
of the Batman v Superman movie. But right, I
don't count it as copying because Civil War
was actually a better movie than BBS. Oh, it's
copying. It's 100% copying. But you admit that
Civil War was a better movie than BBS. I did
not do any such thing. Although I guess when
it comes to specifically the theatrical versions,
sure, I will admit that Civil War was better
than BBS, even when it comes to the subtitle,
Civil War versus Dawn of Justice. Yeah, that
was stupid. Thanks, Nate, for the answer. Let's
go ahead and move on to making my thank you
answer, which also gets an honorable mention.
He said. Hey what's up guys, this is Miggy
and my favorite subtitle is the Judas Contract.
This is just a badass sounding biblical illusion.
The foreshadows the plot pretty well. But really
I'm just using this as an excuse to answer
the question of the week that you guys should
have gone with and give my fancast for the
Teen Titans. So I'm gonna say Wolfgang Novogratz
as Robin slash Nightwing, Coco Jones as Starfire,
Stefan James as Cyborg, Amber Mithunder as Raven,
and Marcel Ruiz as Beast Boy. Thanks guys.
Yeah, Mickey Mathagian is an executive producer
of the show, so he does have some leeway regarding
the questions that we ask on this podcast. And
we should have consulted basically, I think,
with our ex-pros before coming up with our question
of the week last time, because I think that
with the announcement that DC is working on
a Teen Titans movie, that should have absolutely
been our question of the week. And it's not
a terrible cast that Mickey came up with. As
far as the Judas contract goes. Also a great
choice and also like you mentioned an allusion
to a betrayal that would happen within the team
much better than you know Teen Titans, Terror's
Betrayal Let's go ahead and move into our final
honorable mention which goes to Caleb Folk
who said hey guys Caleb Folk again I think the
best marveler dc subtitle has to be avengers
endgame Just because not only did it leave suspense
After the infinity war ending But also it symbolizes
the ending of Iron Man, Captain America, Black
Widow, Thor not being the leader of Asgard
anymore. I just think that has to be the best
subtitle that any movie's had. Yeah, Infinity
War ended with such a cliffhanger. You know,
basically half the entire universe was snapped
out of existence by Thanos. So I remember everyone
who was on the edge of our seats, including
this podcast. And if you go back and listen
to those episodes, we were heavily speculating
on what the subtitle would be for the fourth
Avengers film. When it was revealed to be endgame,
it just felt right. Not only because it was
a direct reference to a quote from Dr. Strange
in the Infinity War film where he says, run
the end game now, but it just had this finality
to it where you knew that this was going to
be the culmination of the entire Infinity War
saga and that it was just going to be epic.
Right. And especially, you know, like post
end game, you kind of wish the end game was
the end of all MCU films because they've just
got to shit since then. Now, it really should
have been the end. Shut up. Just you sound
stupid right now. That was the dumbest thing
I've you've ever said on this podcast. I don't
know. I think a lot of people agree with me.
Well, those people are wrong and they could
be wrong. Great answer, Caleb. We want to give
a quick shout out to Travis Herndon, who gave
the answer of homecoming. Andrew Shunk, who
gave the answer The Quest for Peace. Colby
Hentges, who gave Four Vendetta. Mitchell Smoothie,
who said Under the Red Hood. Scott Camacho,
who gave the answer of the Dark Knight trilogy.
And Sean Curtis, who gave an answer from last
week regarding video games. Basically chiming
in since nobody gave a DC answer for the last
question of the week. But the winner of this
week's NOAH Prize goes to Noah Terry, who said.
Hey guys, I think that the best subtitle for
a Marvel or DC movie has to be Black Panther
Wakanda Forever. I feel that the movie is just
a perfect tribute to Chadwick Boseman, and
the way that the subtitle perfectly represents
Shuri taking up his legacy as the Black Panther
is just perfect. It's an amazing movie. Thanks.
Bye, guys. Wakanda Forever is basically this
salute representing the pride that Wakandans
have in their home country and Chadwick Boseman
personified the vision of T'Challa the Black
Panther in the first Black Panther film and
after his untimely tragic passing due to cancer.
It was a really nice tribute for the sequel
to reference that pride that a lot of people
felt in seeing Wakanda represented on screen.
It just felt like it was a mark. of his legacy
on the franchise. Right, that even though he
had passed, Wakanda was still going to live
on in the hearts of everyone who just fell
in love with the concept of the African nation.
Yeah, it was a very sentimental subtitle and
I think it was just perfect. I also like the
fact that not only did it allude to Shuri carrying
on the mantle of Black Panther, but also that
T'Challa's legacy would continue as well. Yeah,
the movie's all about legacy and... the title
definitely evoked that. It worked on a variety
of different levels. And that's why that answer
wins this week's No Prize. So congrats to Noah
Terry for winning. If you, the listener, won
a shot at winning your own No Prize, stay tuned
to later on this episode when we'll be asking
another Question of the Week. And now that
that's done, on to the news.
Okay, so last week Variety shed some light on
the type of musical that the Joker sequel,
Joker, if all you do, is going to be. When we
first heard that the Joker sequel was going
to be a musical, there was quite a bit of mixed
reaction online. Most of it was rage. Not too
many people like the idea of the sequel being
a musical. I for one was not one of those people
though. I like some musicals. You know, I like
Sweeney Todd. I like Prince of Egypt. I even
liked the new Wonka movie that came out recently.
So I thought a musical could make this movie
fairly interesting. But now we've learned that
Joker Fali Ado is going to be a jukebox musical
in that it's not going to have original songs.
It's going to have up to 15 cover songs. So
it's going to be something more like Mamma Mia
or Moulin Rouge. And to me, those films are
more about the music as opposed to the story.
Yeah, the quality of the movie is almost more
about the song choices that they make, right?
Exactly. So hearing this news was so extremely
disappointing because I had been really championing
this film to all the haters who did not like
the fact that it was going to be a musical.
And now I myself am not excited that this film
is going to be a musical because it's like a
lazy musical. They didn't put forth any effort
to write original songs, even though there may
be two original songs in the movie. They're
not sure yet if they have enough time to insert
them. One of the songs we've learned is going
to be That's Entertainment from the 1953 musical
The Bandwagon starring Judy Garland. The one
interesting thing about this is that I guess
Hildur Gunnedadder, who did the score for the
first film and won an Oscar for that film, is
recomposing all of the new pieces and Variety
says that she will infuse her distinctive haunting
music cues into each number. I guess that's
kinda cool. Ultimately, I think it kinda depends
on what song choices you're going with though.
Are people who aren't fans of the bandwagon
going to be excited by that's entertainment?
I don't think so. If they're going with that
song, it almost seems like they're going with
music throughout cinematic musical history.
Kind of like how the first Joker film was an
homage to Martin Scorsese films, you know? Right.
This movie might be an homage to classic musicals.
Yeah, maybe. Yeah, maybe we'll get like Singing
in the Rain, almost like giving a Clockwork
Orange kind of homage. I don't know. I have
no idea. The trailer is supposed to be coming
out soon-ish, I think in April, but I'm not
sure how much music they're going to... unveil
in that trailer or even market it as a musical
because Warner Brothers recent musicals haven't
been advertised that way including Guanka. Yeah
I also am disappointed to hear that this is
gonna be more rock of ages than Sweeney Todd
but I wonder if Lady Gaga is gonna have any
of her own songs in there like Bad Romance or
something that would be so bizarre. That would
be awful I would hate that. Harley Quinn all
of a sudden is like I want to take a ride on
your disco stick. Eh, jeez. Who knows? Maybe.
But considering the fact that Joker Folly I
Do is going to be a jukebox musical, that brings
us to our question of the week.
What song do you hope to hear in Joker Follyadoo,
and what character would sing it? This is a
fantastic question. If you guys wanna sing your
answer to as you submit it, you might get extra
points. Oh my gosh, I'm gonna love this. Ha
ha ha. Record your answer at dynamicduel.com
by clicking on the red microphone button in
the bottom right-hand corner of the screen,
which will prompt you to leave us a voicemail.
Your message could be up to 30 seconds long,
and don't forget to leave your name in case
we include you on the podcast. 30 seconds,
you guys are gonna have to rap your songs. We'll
pick our favorite answer and award that person
a dynamic duel no prize that we'll post to Instagram.
Be sure to answer before March 30th. In other
DC news, in good DC news, we got our first official
teaser trailer for the Mac series The Penguin,
which is a sequel to the phenomenal 2022 film
The Batman. Colin Farrell is returning as The
Penguin. And the teaser trailer shows him recounting
the story of this old mobster that he used
to look up to who died and how a parade was
thrown in his honor. He really likes the idea
of that kind of legacy. Intercut between his
voiceover, we see a lot of shots of the penguin
walking around being menacing. But we also get
our first looks at Sofia and Alberto Falcone,
which is really exciting and interesting. These
are characters that play big roles in The Long
Halloween. which is a comic book storyline that
is often touted as inspiration for many of
these Batman films. And we also get to see Clancy
Brown as Salvatore Moroni and Michael Kelly
as Johnny Vitti. All of these characters were
in The Long Halloween and I bet these are going
to be amazing performances. But of course the
best one looks like it's going to come once
again from Colin Farrell. He is still unrecognizable
in the role of Oswald Cobblepot. Yeah, he definitely
inhabits his character. It's interesting that
they chose to go with this anecdote about a
local mobster that was in his neighborhood as
a child. It makes it seem like his entire motivation
throughout the course of this season is going
to be the respect and love of the people around
him, which is an interesting motivation for
a character like the Penguin, because usually
his motivation is avarice. You know, he's a
greedy son of a bitch in the world of Batman
and I don't remember him ever like looking for
adoration in that way. Um, I think it still
fits with the character because you know, the
character is deformed. We see that he's wearing
a leg brace in the teaser trailer, which gives
him a wobble, probably why he's referred to
as the Penguin. I absolutely buy the fact that
the Penguin would be looking for adoration
and respect from his community. Because I feel
like because of his deformities, he probably
doesn't get too much of that. So it'd be something
the character wants. Do you think he doesn't
get too much respect because he walks around
in a fat suit? That is obviously a fat suit.
That is not obviously a fat suit. That is like
one of the best makeup jobs I've ever seen.
Obviously a fat suit. Oh, my gosh. You know
it. I know it. He's basically fat bastards,
Italian gangster cousin. is not a good color
on you, my friend. You know this show looks
incredible and you can try to insult it all
you want. It doesn't change the fact that the
show looks like it's going to be like a really
awesome DC Comics, sopranos type crime drama.
I would like to get a hashtag going inspired
by John Strausky of the Console Combat Podcast,
who on the Discord referred to the Penguin as
Fat Mobstered. I think that's perfect. I think
that's a perfect description of him. and henceforth
I will only be referring to Colin Farrell's
Penguin as Fat Mobster. And I would like to
get a hashtag going that's hashtag fuck Joseph.
That could go the wrong way real quick. Let's
not do that. Wait what? Okay yeah let's not
do that. We don't have an official release date
for the Penguin yet. We just know that it's
coming out this fall and I'm super looking forward
to it. This teaser trailer totally did its
job. And it makes me look forward to the Batman
sequel that we're getting in 2026 even more.
Get in my belly.
But I think that does it for all the news for
this episode, so let's go ahead and get into
our main event where we find out who would win
in a fight between the JSA slash Superman villain,
Ultra Humanite, versus the X-Men villain, Mr.
Sinister.
Alright, Ultra Humanite versus Mr. Sinister.
As we stated at the top of this episode, we
are pitting these two characters against each
other because they both are experts in genetics
and they both have psychic abilities. They're
super powerful too. Ultra Humanite is the villain
for not only Superman, but the entire JSA. And
Mr. Sinister is an acolyte of Apocalypse himself,
even though he's kind of branched away from
Apocalypse and has gone on to plague not only
the X-Men, but mutant kind in general. Yeah,
of course we saw a brief cameo of Mr. Sinister
in X-Men Apocalypse. It wasn't a cameo of him,
it was a cameo of someone who worked for SX
Corporation. Which is supposed to be, I guess,
one of Mr. Sinister's holding companies or
something. I don't know. They were obtaining
a genetic sample of Wolverine from the Weapon
X program. Okay, that's lame. We did get the
Ultra-Humanite as the main antagonist of Stargirl
season 3. three and really the main antagonist
of the whole series. Interesting. I never watched
that show. Was he primarily a big white gorilla
or did he have another form? To answer that
would probably be a spoiler so I plead the fifth.
Interesting. Okay. I think the initial matchup
for this episode was gonna be Mr. Sinister versus
Malefic who is Martian Manhunter's brother
who you know has the Martian abilities of telepathy
and is also a shapeshifter just like Mr. Sinister.
I think that would have been a wiser choice
on your part, and I think that you and Team
DC are going down for switching to Ultra Humanite.
And I think you will rue the day that you ever
underestimated Ultra Humanite, fool! Okay. To
explain the methodology behind our duels, let's
go to our sentient duel simulator, Alfred Jarvis
9000. H-E-9K, tell our listeners how you go
about determining a winner in our duel matchups.
Yes, of course, sir. The way I determine a
winner between the contestants is by running
1000 Monte Carlo simulations using the characters
statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation is a probabilistic
model used to determine outcomes through random
sampling. In this case, I randomise the statistics
along a normal distribution as a way to simulate
the many variables that can occur during battle.
The stat parameters are based on the official
Marvel power grid from which the DC characters
statistics are extrapolated. Additional stat
categories are included such as range, damage
potential, versatility and perception in order
to create a more detailed and accurate simulation.
The results of the 1000 simulations provide
a percentage of wins for each character. The
contestant with the higher percentage is declared
the victor as they have a higher probability
to win any given battle. In an equitable pairing,
neither character should win 100% of the matches.
The comic book stories have shown that there's
even a way for Batman to defeat Superman. So
the confidence rate of my method falls in line
with the precedents that have been established
in the source material. My mathematical simulations
are without subjectivity or bias. Feats are
not the sole consideration, nor are fan votes
tabulated for determination of the winner. Thanks
AJ9K! Before we run the simulations though,
we like to break down each character's histories
and abilities before improvising a scenario
on how we imagine one of the 1000 simulations
would play out for beat. and I believe it's
your turn to go first with the Marvel characters
backstory. That's right, yeah, let me go ahead
and tell you all about Mr. Sinister. Nathaniel
Essex was born in England in the mid-1800s
to a noble British family. Growing up fascinated
with biology, Nathaniel studied at Oxford University,
becoming one of the foremost minds of his generation.
He fell in love with an English woman named
Rebecca, and the two had a son named Adam. However,
Adam was born with numerous birth defects and
ailments, passing away as a child at the young
age of four. This tragedy drove Nathaniel deeper
into his studies in genetics and Darwin's theories,
leading him to believe that through rapid evolution,
humanity could achieve perfection without defects.
Obsessed, he sought to push evolutionary science
to its limits, believing his contemporaries
were too bound by their concepts of morality.
Nathaniel became rejected by his peers for his
work. as he hired a group of criminals he dubbed
the Marauders to kidnap people with deformities
for him to experiment on. He even exhumed his
son's corpse to further his research, an act
which estranged his wife, who was once again
pregnant. In the Marauders' search for test
subjects, they stumbled upon and awakened the
ancient mutant known as Apocalypse, who sought
to reshape the world into its strongest potential
through survival of the fittest. Seeing Nathaniel's
work as a means to that end, Apocalypse offered
the scientist immortality and power if he served
him. Conflicted by the offer, Nathaniel returned
home to Rebecca, only to find that she and their
new baby were dying due to a premature labor.
Though he pleaded for his wife's forgiveness
in her last moments, her final words were simply
to call him, sinister. Distraught, Nathaniel
returned to Apocalypse to swear fealty to him.
who genetically altered him into a superhuman,
undying, psychic being, now going only by Mr.
Sinister. You can learn more about Apocalypse
in our duel episode where we pit him against
Black Adam. Apocalypse had Sinister create a
plague to wipe out most of humanity, but Sinister
was hesitant as he figured it would hamper his
experiments. Fearful of Apocalypse, Sinister
instead created a techno-virus that would infect
Apocalypse's forcing Apocalypse to retreat
to his regeneration chamber for decades as he
purged the infection. Knowing that he had created
an enemy out of the world's most powerful mutant,
Sinister began working on genetically enhancing
his own form. He traveled the world searching
for mutants to obtain their genetic samples
to aid his research and occasionally add their
power set, such as shapeshifting, to his own.
Sinister worked alongside the high evolutionary
for a time. whom you can learn more about in
his duel against Despero, and he worked as a
Nazi scientist where he was given free rein
to experiment on any prisoner he desired. This
earned the enmity of Magneto, who was a prisoner
at Auschwitz and whom you can learn more about
in his duel against Sinestro. With the Nazis
defeated and Sinister's labs shut down by Captain
America and Nick Fury's howling commandos,
he set about finding another way to protect
himself from apocalypse. Eventually, Sinister
set up orphanages where he would seek out young
mutants to manipulate, and found the perfect
candidate in Scott and Alex Summers, the boys
who would grow up to become Cyclops and Havoc
respectively. He separated the brothers to isolate
and study Scott's genetics, theorizing that
the offspring between him and another young
mutant named Jean Grey would be powerful enough
to challenge apocalypse himself. Sinister planned
to kidnap young Jean Grey, sensing her vast
psychic potential, but the child was discovered
and mentored first by Professor Charles Xavier,
whom Sinister knew to steer clear of. Coincidentally
however, both Scott and Jean were eventually
recruited into Professor X's school for the
gifted, and Sinister's secret plan was set
into motion. You can learn more about this in
our Negative Man vs Cyclops duel, our Raven
vs Phoenix duel, and our Chief vs Professor
X duel. When it later appeared as if Jean Grey
died during an X-Men mission in space, Sinister
used a genetic sample he had to produce a clone
of her, which he named Madeline Pryor. He psychically
brainwashed her into loving Cyclops and arranged
for the two to meet. Sinister's plan worked,
and the couple wed and became pregnant with
a son named Nathan. Meanwhile, in an effort
to ensure the mutant gene pool remained strong
and without defects he deemed as lesser, Sinister
ordered his newest team of Marauders to massacre
a group of mutant outcasts that had been living
in the sewers in fear of humanity. The X-Men
tried to stop this mass murder, but suffered
heavy casualties in the process, including
the Mutant Angel, whom you can learn more about
in our Zereal vs Archangel episode. Eventually,
Jean Grey was revealed to still be alive, prompting
Sinister to try to kill her clone, Madeline
Pryor, before the secret behind her creation
was revealed. Though the X-Men managed to save
Madeline, Sinister was successful in kidnapping
Baby Nathan for a time, planning to train him
against Apocalypse. However, Cyclops was able
to rescue his son by destroying Sinister with
a massive optic blast that the villain was only
able to survive thanks to his highly malleable
and regenerative form. Soon after, Apocalypse
returned. Upon learning of Sinister's plan
for Cyclops' son, Apocalypse infected the baby
with a techno-organic virus that would consume
his body with cybernetics and kill him, prompting
Cyclops and Jean Grey to send the child into
the future where he could be cared for, a timeline
where Apocalypse ruled and where Nathan was
prophesied to defeat him. Eventually, Nathan
would return to the present as the mutant soldier
hero Cable, whom you can learn more about in
our Booster Gold vs. Cable duel episode.
offering to give him Cyclops and Jean Grey in
exchange for Strife getting him the future
genetic material of the Summers family. Sinister
double-crossed Strife by leading the X-Men
to him, however he was also betrayed as the
canister that was supposed to contain the genetic
samples actually contained the Legacy Virus,
a pathogen that was released into the atmosphere
that was fatal to mutants. Seeing the virus
as detrimental to his work, he went about studying
it to find a cure. and though the solution would
ultimately be discovered by the X-Men member
Beast, Sinister's research did assist him. With
the mutant population having dwindled in the
wake of the legacy virus, Sinister's pool of
test subjects was running low, leading him
to create a formula that would spontaneously
induce mutation in humans. This was opposed
by the X-Men members Bishop and Gambit, who
destroyed Sinister's laboratory and research.
After the events of Emde, when the Scarlet Witch
depowered most of the world's mutants in a
fit of madness, Sinister found his entire cause
destroyed. The first new mutant child to be
born after Emde was sought after by many groups,
seeking to kill, use, or experiment on her,
Sinister being one of the latter. He reformed
the Marauders to seize the child, and though
they were successful, Sinister was killed by
Mystique who also sought her. In the end, Cable
was able to rescue the firstborn mutant and
took her into the future, naming her Hope.
Sinister had a plethora of fail-safes for death,
however, including a vast legion of his own
genetic clones for his mind to possess. He and
his clones created in the underground city
in Alaska, inspired by 19th century London,
from where he attempted to manipulate the returning
Phoenix Force, which had possessed a group of
mutants including Cyclops, Emma Frost, the
Sub-Mariner, magic and colossus. Despite Sinister's
efforts to transfer the power into five Jean
Grey clones that he could control, the Phoenix
V incinerated his city and the Phoenix's power
would eventually be used by Hope to restore
the mutant abilities of those who lost them
on M-Day. During a battle with Thanos, the hero
Blackbolt released the Terragen mists into
the atmosphere, an event you can learn more
about in our Shazam vs Blackbolt episode. These
mists, though they induced change in inhumans,
proved to be fatal to mutants that were exposed
to them. This inspired Sinister to capture inhumans
and mutants to combine their DNA. Those efforts
were discovered and stopped by the X-Men. When
Professor X and Magneto founded a new mutant
paradise nation on the Sentient Island of Krakoa,
they developed a means of mutant resurrection
using a combination of mutant powers, including
mass generation, reality warping, manipulation,
and genetic and psychic archiving. Since Sinister
had a database of DNA from nearly every mutant
who ever existed, Professor X approached him
to request access to it. Sinister initially
declined, but the Professor, being the more
powerful psychic, repressed Sinister's memory
of their meeting so that he would give Krakoa
the access it needed without him ever knowing
it. In exchange, Professor X and Magneto asked
Sinister to join their head council of government,
over the island and mutant affairs. Sinister
used his position to secretly implant a portion
of his own DNA into every resurrected mutant,
planning on eventually transforming every mutant
into a clone of himself. Eventually he was successful,
leading to a timeline where he had subjugated
the entire planet and eventually the galaxy,
ruling for a horrific 1000 years as he attempted
to evolve into godhood. However, that timeline
was eventually reset. and Sinister was exiled
into the pit of Krakoa for eternity for his
deeds. And that's his backstory. Powers-wise,
Mr. Sinister is a human mutate with genetic
enhancements given to him by apocalypse. These
include the psychic abilities of telepathy and
telekinesis, which allow him access to opponents'
minds within moderate proximity wherein he can
read their minds, psychically communicate with
them, sedate them, erase them, alter them, and
control them. He can emit psychic blasts that
cause mental pain, as well as erect psychic
defenses to protect his own mind. He can also
project his consciousness into others, which
he commonly does to escape death. With his
telekinetic abilities, Mr. Sinister can project
a psychokinetic force that allows him to levitate
himself or other objects. With this, he can
also generate concussive blasts or force fields.
Having incorporated the powers of other mutants
he has encountered over the decades, Sinister
also has the ability to shape shift and has
complete control over every molecule in his
body. This not only makes him virtually indestructible
or permeable, but it also gives him a regenerative
healing factor and makes him a master of disguise.
Sinister also acquired physical enhancements
including strength, able to lift 10 tons, enhanced
durability, and speed. He's one of the most
intelligent minds on Earth as a genius level
scientist in biology, chemistry, and psychology.
He's highly adept in the fields of mechanics
and engineering, having developed a number
of inventions in his fortress to aid him in
his research, such as genetic transfer machines
and teleportation devices. And that's Sinister.
Oh, you think Sinister's smart, huh? Ultra-Humanite
has actually been said to be the smartest being
on Earth in the DC Comics universe. Smarter
than Lex Luthor, smarter than Batman. He is
the smartest. And yet he's basically achieved
nothing. What? Hence his obscurity. He has achieved
plenty. Let me get into it. For reasons unknown,
Gerard Schuegel was born with an advanced intellect
and a degenerative disease that caused him
to age rapidly. Though he came to believe his
body was unable to cope with the vast amount
of energy his brain required. By the time Gerard
was a young man, he resembled an elderly man
and was confined to a wheelchair, forced to
experiment on himself in order to survive.
which further boosted his intellect. Angered
by his predicament, Gerard began devising plans
to conquer and rule the planet as the villain,
Ultra Humanite, battling Superman from behind
the scenes with experimental weaponry, vehicles,
and plagues. You can learn more about Superman
in our Superman versus Dr. Doom episode. After
an attempt to hypnotize Superman failed, Ultra
Humanite attempted to shoot Superman with a
laser cannon. only for Superman to pull Ultra
into the Fire Inc path. Though Ultra seemingly
died, he had arranged for his brain to be placed
into a kidnapped actress named Dolores Winters
to avoid any suspicion for his continued criminal
activities. While in this form, Ultra battled
the All-Star Squadron during World War II using
a power-boosting gemstone known as the Power
Stone to bestow powers to several villains,
including Amazing and Death Bolt. Ultra's future
self also aided in his villainous campaign
to extort the US for millions of dollars by
sending a brainwashed Infinity Inc., a team
largely composed of the superpowered children
of the Justice Society of America, and members
of the Seeker Society of Super-Villains back
in time to battle the Squadron. Ultimately,
Amazing Band and Cyclotron turned against the
Ultra-Humanite who made them and seemingly
killed him, or her as Dolores. Ultrahumanite's
mind survived, however, trapped within the
mind of Dolores Winters, who was revealed to
have cancer and was hospitalized. Eventually,
the time-traveling villain Perdigaton and Despero
found Ultrahumanite and kidnapped Dolores from
the hospital, allowing Ultrahumanite to transfer
his mind into a genetically mutated albino
gorilla from Gorilla City, which possessed the
strength to house his mind. while also giving
him a formidable physical form as well. You
can learn more about Gorilla City in our Gorilla
Grodd vs Psylocke episode. For a time, Ultra
Humanite traveled through time with Perdegaton,
Despero, and Mr. Mind, among other villains,
forming a group known as the Time Steelers,
though they were eventually defeated by Booster
Gold and the Blue Beetle Ted Kord and sent
back to their original timelines. Back in his
timeline, Ultra formed the Seeker Society of
Super-Villains, which battled the Justice League
and Justice Society before being banished to
an interdimensional limbo. The Ultra was rescued
from this fate with the help of his past, Dolores
Winter, self. The two versions of the Ultra-Humanites
teamed up to stop the All-Star Squadron in
the past, though the Ape Ultra ultimately fell
at the hands of Infinity Inc. Ultra-Humanite
eventually became the chief antagonist of the
Justice Society of America. After several battles,
Ultra secretly took over the body of retired
JSA member Johnny Thunder, who you can learn
more about in our Jekim Thunder vs Wiccan duel
episode. With the power of Johnny Thunder's
5th dimensional genie under his control, Ultra
Humanite took over the planet, becoming a dictator,
placing a majority of Earth's heroes under suspended
animation and forming new futuristic cities.
With help from a time traveling hour man, however,
Ultra Humanite lost his connection to the Thunderbolt,
and in his human form was shot through the brain
by the Crimson Avenger. You can learn more
about our man in his duel against Bishop of
the X-Men. Ultrahumanite's mind survived, however,
within a stolen copy of a helmet worn by Mento,
a former psychic member of the Doom Patrol,
and he eventually became a recurring foe of
Power Girl, aka Karen Starr, who seemingly
helped reform Ultrahumanite by helping clone
young and sustainable version of his Gerard
Shugal body. In post-Flashpoint continuity,
for a time, Ultra Humanite was reimagined as
an alien shapeshifting prisoner of the Phantom
Zone capable of feeding on the emotions of
others, though this was retconned and Ultra
Humanite returned to his albino gorilla form.
It was revealed that Gerard Shugal had a daughter
named Laura, a criminal scientist who married
a fellow scientist named Winston Shen. both
of whom aided the Ultra-Humanite in his villainous
endeavors. Fifteen years ago, the Ultra-Humanite
attempted to open a portal to the Phantom Zone,
where he knew the Monkey King was trapped, in
an effort to force him to be his henchman.
Though Ultra's plan was foiled by the Justice
League, one of the Monkey King's hairs escaped
the Phantom Zone disguised as a baby, who was
adopted by Laura and Winston, and eventually
became the hero, the Monkey Prince, who you
can learn more about in our Monkey Prince vs.
Mantis duel episode. Ultra later teamed up with
Gorilla Grodd and Monsieur Malat to take over
the cities of Bloodhaven and Gorilla City, who
the Monkey Prince and Detective Chimp teamed
up to stop them. And that's Ultra Humanite's
backstory so far. Powers-wise, Ultra Humanite's
powerful psychic mind grants him telepathy and
telekinesis, and his genius-level intellect
allows him to create advanced technology, including
weaponry such as laser cannons, portal generators,
and pain-inducing nanites. but also body switching
tech, which has allowed his brain to inhabit
the form of a genetically enhanced gorilla,
granting him enhanced strength, speed, agility,
and durability. Ultrahumanite has also proven
extremely difficult to kill due to his ability
to transfer his consciousness, sometimes just
via his telepathy alone, into others or one
of his genetically enhanced gorilla clones.
And that's the ultrahumanite. Literally what
makes this guy any different from Gorilla Grodd?
He's a lot smarter than Gorilla Grodd. They
both have telepathy and telekinesis, but Ultra
Humanite tends to bring advanced weaponry and
firepower. Doesn't Gorilla Grodd also use advanced
tech in his battles? Yeah, I guess. I'm just
trying to understand why you even need Ultra
Humanite in the DC universe if you already
have Grodd. The characters seem way too similar
for them to both exist. I think if it came
down to it, Ultra Humanite would stomp Gorilla
Grodd though, because he's just way smarter.
This Gorilla Garage copy is going down, that's
all I know. There's no way he's gonna stand
a chance against Mr. Sinister. Okay, well what
do you know? You sound extremely confident
for someone whose character is about to get
their ass beat. We shall see.
Where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
Dynomic Podcast Network presents Console Combat,
where video game legends brawl every Monday.
Smash every Tuesday, Max Destruction, where
TV and action heroes battle every Wednesday,
and Sendro World, where anime champions clash
every Thursday. Join us as we speculate on
the matches and, armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge victorious.
Visit dynamicpodcast.com where we settle the
debate and settle the score.
Now that we've got their histories and abilities
out of the way, let's speculate on how one
of the 1000 simulated matches will go. The winner
is determined by simulations, not this speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how this fight could
play out. AJ9K, what are the rules of our speculation?
Well, I should say there are no rules, other
than the characters have no prior knowledge
of the other going into the fight. All they
are aware of starting out is that the other
character is a threat that needs to be eliminated.
For the speculation... contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the
match itself, as no environmental statistics
are considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit." Alright
then let's get into it. Ultra Humanite and
Mr. Sinister meet on the battlefield. Who goes
first? I feel like it's hard to say who would
go first since they both seem so calculating.
But I think Ultra Humanite is like, you know,
he's an 800 pound mass. of genetically enhanced
gorilla badassery. So I'm going to say he goes
first and he's going to start by straight up
charging Mr. Sinister during which he activates
a gadget that encases him in an energy field
as he rolls into Mr. Sinister Donkey Kong style,
just crashing into him and vaporizing him on
contact. What is he like Blanka? Exactly. Okay,
um, but Mr. Sinister is going to throw up a
telekinetic force field and Ultra Humanite
just bounces off of that. So yeah, he doesn't
get hit. Okay. But, you know, he's an agile
gorilla. So without missing a beat, Ultra Humanite
is going to land on the ground and fling his
gadget at Mr. Sinister, using it to trap him
in an energy bubble, at which point he's going
to pull out a remote that's going to allow him
to zap Mr. Sinister with millions of volts
of electricity. while in that bubble. That's
a pretty good starting move. Maybe I shouldn't
have called him a Grilla Grot copy. Yeah, yeah,
maybe shouldn't have. Okay, so Sinister is
stuck in this energy sphere and he's being electrocuted.
I'm gonna say he just reaches out telepathically
to mentally force Ultra Humanite to depower
the energy field. No, that's not gonna work.
Mr. Sinister is gonna try to mind control Ultra
Humanite. and you know he's only gonna end
up with searing brain pain because of Ultra's
telepathic shielding. Okay, so then he reaches
out telekinetically then and he shoots out this
powerful concussive force blast from his hands
that smashes Ultra Humanite's energy field device
and it's also gonna send the Big Ape just flying
backward. So Mr. Sinister is free from the energy
field now and I think he's probably gonna want
to get his genetic sample of Ultra Humanite.
so that he can study him after the match. So
he's going for blood, you know? He's gonna reach
his hands down toward the ground and just telekinetically
break the floor apart in a small circle around
him. And he's gonna lift some of that debris
as small shards that he just launches at Ultra
Humanite and they slash through him and just
spill his blood onto the battlefield. I mean,
that would have to be some very sharp stone
shrapnel. Like, Ultra Humanite's durable enough
to take blows from Superman and Power Girl.
They're sharp. They're sharp. Okay. Alright,
uh, so Ultra, you know, he gets tagged by a
few sharp pebbles, I guess. Big whoop. He's
gonna respond by whooping out this huge-ass
laser cannon, and he's gonna fire, like, a massive
disintegration beam at Mr. Sinister, just disintegrating
him. No, the laser beam just goes through Mr.
Sinister. It, like, it, like... permeates him
like if he were made out of liquid, you know,
and the hole that it creates in Mr. Sinister's
chest just seals immediately once the laser
stops and at that point Mr. Sinister is gonna
throw out this device that looks like a red
ruby thing and it floats midair before opening
up to expel several like red and black blobs
is what it looks like but those take shape
as Mr. Sinister clones. So now there's like
four Mr. Sinisters on the battlefield. What?
And they're all gonna smile like really creepily
at Ultra Humanite with their black eyes and
sharp teeth, you know? Uh, and then at that
point, they're all just gonna simultaneously
blast Ultra Humanite with lasers from their
foreheads. So like Ultra Humanite's getting
hit from all directions now. And Ultra Humanite's
probably like, what the shit? So as he's, you
know, getting blasted, that's when he quickly
pushes a button on his suit. and that's going
to instantly inflate a mini like zeppelin like
vessel, like a blimp around him. And so he's
going to rise into the air with shielding that
blocks the lasers. So while he's in the ship,
you know, trying to buy all these buttons, he's
going to hit one of them and the zeppelin is
going to emit a purple gas and it's going to
spew out of its ventilation. And the sinister
clones are going to breathe that in and it's
going to start breaking down their bodies.
They just start falling apart from this purple
plague. A zeppelin? Yeah. That seems very not
high tech. It's a very high tech blimp. Okay.
So the sinister clones get poisoned. Maybe
only one of them falls apart due to this purple
gas, but the gas actually gets blown away by
one of the other clones who transforms his arms
into like this giant paddle that just fans
the gas away from them. And then the other clone.
He's gonna fly up to the zeppelin. He just
rips that thing open by turning his hand into
a sword and flying across it. And while that's
all happening, the real Mr. Sinister, he's going
to collect the blood sample from ultra humanite
that's on the ground. And he's going to mix
it in this glass vial that he then loads into
an injection gun. Okay. Well, okay. So Ultra's
ship is going down. So he's going to eject
out of it armed with a. Nanite dart launcher
that looks like a high tech crossbow and he's
going to fire a dart at the sword wielding sinister
clone And it's going to penetrate him and just
explode him from within at which point the dart
is then going to track the fan wielding sinister
zip into him and blow him up too and Finally
it's going to go to the real mr. Sinister and
blow him up. No that darts never going to reach
mr. Sinister He just like telekinetically smacks
it out of the air real easy and then he's gonna
stretch his arm over to ultra humanite once
the gorilla lands on the ground and he's gonna
inject him with this injection gun dosing him
with this genetically modifying serum that's
gonna basically just turn the ape into just
a regular old ape, you know, without like psychic
powers or anything so the ape is just gonna
stand there scratching his butt or whatever
and at which point Mr. Sinister telepathically
erases his brain killing him and then he's gonna
experiment on the body match over wait so he
kills an innocent monkey like humanely he wipes
his mind it's humane it's fine okay not that
mr. sinister would care about that that's probably
fair um but removing the genetic modifications
to Ultra's eighth body would not eliminate Ultra's
powerful mind It would probably cause his eighth
body to age rapidly because it can't contain
his mind. So, you know, Ultra realizes that
he's going to need to abandon this body. And
so he's going to smash open a tiny capsule
on the ground before his body completely withers.
At which point, a tiny ant that was within
the capsule rapidly grows to human size. And
it's equipped with a headband that allows Ultra
to psychically transfer his mind into it. And
this ant is also strapped with an ice cannon
that Ultra uses to freeze Mr. Sinister before
telekinetically just slamming him into the
ground and causing his body to shatter into
thousands of pieces, like T-1000 style, match
over. What is he, Ant-Man? Where'd the ant come
from? He's been an ant in the comics before.
Really? Yeah. That's stupid. I mean, he can't
transfer his mind if he doesn't have psychic
powers. The serum that he was injected with
removed his psychic powers. Dude, how the psychic
powers aren't linked to the Apes genetic enhancements?
Because I said so. That's how it was a power
negating formula. All powers are gone. All right.
Well, that's probably a good place to leave
it either. Mr. Sinister. removed all of Ultra
Humanite's powers including his mental powers,
preventing him from transferring minds before
dying. Or in a more badass version, Ultra Humanite
becomes an ice cannon wielding ant that just
shatters Mr. Sinister. That seems more like
the wacky version than the badass version. It
could be both. But we'll go ahead and leave
our speculation there, let's enter the stats
and run the simulations before coming back
with a winner. AJ9K, hit it! Inputting data,
running calculations, processing results, simulations
complete. All right, these guys are more even
than my shit talking would have you believe.
On one hand, you have Mr. Sinister, who is highly
evasive. As a matter of fact, that was the
biggest discrepancy between these two characters.
You know, given the fact that Mr. Sinister
has complete control over every molecule in
his body, he can make himself permeable. He
can make himself indestructible in addition
to the telepathic and telekinetic shielding
he can generate. Yeah, Ultra Humanite has the
shielding, but in my research I found out he
doesn't use it as often in his ape form as he
did when he was like in his Dolores Winters
form. Because he's pretty durable and can basically
tank hits from Superman, Power Girl, Martian
Manhunter. So yeah, he's definitely less evasive.
He is slightly more durable, we said though,
than Mr. Sinister. Yeah, Ultra Humanite was
able to compensate not only with durability
but also his strength and damage. Strength makes
sense because Mr. Sinister is only around class
10 whereas Ultra Humanite can go toe to toe
with the likes of DC's heaviest hitters, but
damage was interesting. Mr. Sinister doesn't
usually employ citywide destroying methods
in a lot of his schemes, you know, they're a
lot more subtle than that usually, whereas
Ultra Humanite seems capable of mass destruction.
Yeah, he has no qualms about busting out huge
ass weapons in his battles. It's kind of his
thing. We also said that Ultra Humanite was
slightly more intelligent than Mr. Sinister,
which I thought was bullshit. I'm calling bullshit.
We argued so long about this, guys. And I don't
want the Marvel guys to come at me saying like,
oh, you must not really know how smart Mr. Sinister
is. Oh, I do. I know how smart Mr. Sinister
is. He's also the guy that wasn't able to cure
the legacy virus where Beast did. Whereas Ultra
Humanite, I guess, is touted as being smarter
than Lex Luthor. Yes. It's said he's like twice
as smart as Lex Luthor, who claims to be the
smartest man on the planet. So. Well, I mean,
I would put Mr. Sinister at Lex Luthor's intelligence
level easily. I just think maybe Jonathan is
cheating and the whole being smarter than Lex
Luthor thing is just a statement of hyperbole
on behalf of the villain himself just claiming
that. He was like the original mad scientist.
Like he was Lex Luthor before Lex Luthor was.
And I mean, his feats may not be comparable
to Lex Luthor in terms of success, but he also
has some pretty incredible feats on his own
when it comes to like his inventiveness. I guess
we've never seen Lex Luthor transfer his mind
into an ant that grows and shoots an ice cannon
or something. It's just wacky. It's wacky shit.
That's like Mr. Fantastic type shit. Yeah, exactly.
In terms of versatility, like both of these
guys are off the charts. Mr. Sinister went accounting
for his psychic abilities, his shape-shifting
abilities, his engineering abilities, the tech
and gadgets that he brings into battle. You
know, he's as versatile as they come. Same thing
with Ultra Humanite because they have a similar
power set. Although Ultra Humanite doesn't have
the shape-shifting. So with all that said,
Jonathan, who do you think is winning this match?
I mean Ultra Humanite, I think it's going to
be really close. That evasiveness stat really
scares me. but I think Ultra Humanite is gonna
squeak out a win here, I hope. Well, everyone
on Instagram thinks you're dumb. I know, well,
what else is new? 75% of people who took our
poll said that Mr. Sinister was going to win.
And of course this is a popularity contest.
Ultra Humanite was in the Justice League cartoon,
but that was in the 2000s. And I feel like our
fan base is largely kids from the 90s. So they
grew up with Mr. Sinister in like the X-Men
cartoons. Yeah, and the X-Men cartoon is back.
I haven't watched it yet, but I heard it's good.
And of course, we will be reviewing it when
it finishes in about a month and a half here.
But let's go ahead and get to the results of
this match. AG 9K, the results, please. Here
you are, sir. The winner between Ultra Humanite
and Mr. Sinister is. Ultra Humanite. Yes. Yes,
is really dumb. Fuck all the haters. It just
makes me think that. Maybe I don't know much
about Ultra Humanite because he won 529 matches
out of the 1000 simulations whereas Mr. Sinister
only won 47.1%. This could be a case of Jonathan
cheating. It probably is. Oh my gosh. Just taking
a lesser known character and then making up
a bunch of bullshit about him so that he wins.
Because no one's going to call him out on his
shit because no one knows if he's telling the
truth or not. I'm not actually the one who
even thought of this match. goes to our executive
producer, Mickey Math and Gian. Well, he pulls
the same shit too. What? He'll pick the most
random obscure character and they'd be like,
oh, you didn't know? He's smarter than Lex Luthor.
So he gets higher on the intelligence stat.
Stupid. I don't know what to tell you. Like
DC characters are just better. And I feel like
you're slowly learning that fact. I'm sorry,
it hurts. The truth hurts. I'm sorry. Truth
can also be manipulated as we saw here today,
folks. No, no, there's one truth and that is
AJ 9k. We waited all this time to put Mr. Sinister
in a duel only to have him lose against a monkey
who flings his own shit. I can't I can't accept
that at all. I feel bad for you. I truly do.
Like just switch to Team DC already. If you
felt that bad for me, you would change the
results of this match so that Mr. Sinister would
win. I mean, I don't feel that bad for you.
All right. Well, that does it for this match,
guys. Let us know what you thought about the
bullshit results by writing to us at dyna or
by visiting us on Instagram, which you can
find a link to in our show notes or by visiting
our website at dynamicduel.com. And on our
site, you could also find a link to our Patreon
page where you could join our dynamic 2-0 tier
and chat with us and fellow listeners, our fantastic
4-tier, which gets you bonus content each month,
our X-Force tier that makes you an executive
producer of this podcast. or our newest tier
that lets you join our DynaMic podcast network.
Please, guys, don't forget to rate our show
on Apple podcast, Spotify, Podchaser or on our
website, unless you're a big Mr. Sinister fan,
in which case don't rate the show because you're
probably going to give us a bad rating. But
all you ultra humanite fans out there, five
stars. There's only like two of them. Come
on. Our next episode, guys, we actually don't
know what our next episode is going to be because
we haven't had our monthly executive producer
meeting yet. That'll happen. this Saturday,
March 30th, at which point we'll be discussing
the April calendar. And at that point, we'll
know what the episode's gonna be. But definitely
tune in next week. That does it for this episode.
We wanna give a big thanks to our executive
producers, King Johnson, John Strausky, Zachary
Hepburn, Dustin Balcom, Miggy Mathingian, Brandon
Estregard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yaten, Austin
Wazilovsky, AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Adam
Spies, Andrew Schunk, and Dean Molesky for
helping make this podcast possible. Talk to
you guys next week. Up, up and away, true believers.