This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the superiority
between Marvel and DC by comparing their characters
in stat-based battle simulations. I'm Johnny
DC. And I'm his twin brother, Marvelous Joe.
And in this episode, we will be reviewing part
three of DC's Justice League Crisis on Infinite
Earths animated film. It is the conclusion
of not only the trilogy of Crisis films, but
also... of the tomorrow verse as a whole. Good
riddance is what I say. You know, I wasn't with
you early in the tomorrow verse, but I'm there.
I'm right there. Of course, we're going to be
talking about the film later on in this episode.
Actually, you know what? I lied. It's going
to be right now because this is a short episode.
It's sort of the column before the storm that
is Comic Con. Joseph's going on vacation this
week, so we're recording this episode really
early. and we're pretty much gonna just get
right into it. Yep, yeah, we're gonna skip over
the no prize because we only got two answers
by the time we started recording this episode.
So we're gonna give you guys another week for
the question of the week, which is.
What has been your favorite Disney Plus original
series from Marvel Studios so far? Thanks to
everyone who's called in with an answer so far.
Everyone else, record your answer at dynamicdool.com
by clicking on the red microphone button in
the bottom right-hand corner of the screen,
which will prompt you to leave us a voicemail.
Your message could be up to 30 seconds long,
and don't forget to leave your name in case
we include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a Dynamic
Duel No prize that we'll post to Instagram.
Be sure to answer before July 27th. Real quick
guys, our artificially intelligent duel simulator
AJ 9k has a message for our listeners. So listen
up. Why hello there, do you want even more
from this podcast? Then become a part of the
dynamic duel community on Patreon, where you
can choose from three tiers. The dynamic two-oh
tier gives you access to our Discord chat server.
The fantastic four tier gives you two bonus
episodes each month, and the X-Force tier makes
you an executive producer of this show. Lastly,
The DynaMic Podcast Network tier lets you
create your own podcast using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and consultation,
and get you simulation results. Pitch the twins
your ideas via email at dynamicduelpodcast at
gmail.com. Check it out at patreon.com slash
dynamicduel. Pip pip cheerio. Thanks AJ and
AK, and thanks to everyone who supports the
podcast. Be sure to tune into the other shows
in the DynaMic Podcast Network this week.
including Max Destruction, which pits your favorite
action heroes from film and television against
each other. This week, hosts Ken and Scottie
are pitting Deadpool against the mask. On the
Senjou World podcast, host Zachary Hepburn speculates
on fights between fan-favorite anime and manga
characters. The show is currently on a season
hiatus, but it's coming back in a few weeks,
so this is the perfect time to catch up on Senjou
World's 40-episode library. And on the Console
Combat podcast, hosts John and Dean find out
who would win in fights between popular video
game characters. In yesterday's episode, they
found out who would win in a battle between
Bowser, Mario's villain, and King Dedede, Kirby's
villain. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or click
the link in our show notes to listen to all
of the shows in the DynaMic Podcast Network.
But with all of that out of the way, now let's
move on to the main event of this episode,
where we review Justice League. Crisis on Infinite
Earths, part two.
The final crisis on Infinite Earth's Part III,
as I mentioned earlier, is the conclusion to
a trilogy of films that in themselves are the
conclusion to a 10-part DC animated film series
known as the Tomorrowverse, which began with
Superman Man of Tomorrow in 2020. The Tomorrowverse
in itself follows a 16-film animated universe
from DC, officially known as the DC Animated
Movie Universe that began with 2013's Justice
League The Flashpoint Paradox and ended with
2020's Justice League Dark Apocalypse War. You've
already lost me. No, I haven't. You know what
I'm talking about. Though I will admit, maybe
some people don't. And that's the problem.
Basically, DC has had two long-running animated
movie universes. The initial major one was
the DC animated movie universe, which was 16
films, and then the most recent one, which
started in 2020, was the Tomorrowverse. Sort
of. It's actually recently been revealed that
the Tomorrowverse is in fact considered to be
a part of the DC animated movie universe, just
its second phase, or the second story arc as
it were. And I'm not gonna lie, I hate that.
I thought Justice League Dark Apocalypse War
was a perfect conclusion. We rated it 5 stars
in our review. And while Crisis Part III doesn't
diminish Apocalypse War as I was afraid it
was going to while watching it, it does make
it all the more obvious that the Crisis trilogy
is nowhere close to being as good of a film.
In fact, I'd say each film in the Crisis trilogy
got subsequently worse, which is unfortunate,
because I wanted the Tomorrowverse to be good.
And with its conclusion dropping the ball, I
feel like the Tomorrowverse in its entirety
is kind of pointless and better off forgotten.
Well, it's strange because it introduced the
concept of the multiverse to DC animation, right?
And at the conclusion of this film, that's
all gone now. So you largely have an exercise
in redundancy, I guess. I'm afraid that this
is what's going to happen to the Marvel multiverse
saga, is that when all is said and done...
after the events of Avengers Secret War and
everything is perhaps collapsed into one universe
again, a lot of people are going to feel like
these whole series of Marvel phases were pointless.
Yeah, that's, you should be afraid. You should
be very afraid. Because clearly that's possible.
Now I've recommended some Tomorrowverse films
in the past and if you've gotten to this point
in the universe based on my recommendations,
I just want to apologize. I'm not going to
recommend this film, but just in case you plan
on watching it for yourself and want to avoid
spoilers, I'd probably stop listening to this
episode now, then come back later and finish
it once you've seen the movie. You may have
been spoiled on something already, just go
with it, it's fine. Now I was excited for this
film initially, I thought Crisis Part 1 was
really interesting and Part 2 was a decent enough
setup for what I had hoped. would be a conclusion
as epic as Justice League Dark Apocalypse War,
but what I got instead was actually almost
an hour and a half of people just talking. Like,
there was little to no action and not against
any kind of threat that you actually cared about.
That's true. I don't think a single punch was
thrown in this movie. You know, there were a
lot of like beams being fired and stuff like
that, but it was primarily against the anti-monitor.
They did fight some dinosaurs, which I thought
was kind of weird. But yeah, little to no action,
which I think is the major downfall. Like the
movie could have been serviceable. Yes, there
was a lot of exposition, a lot of talking and
stuff like that. But I think its biggest crime
was that it wasn't entertaining from a superhero
action standpoint, which is what people watch
these movies for. It's why the genre exists.
Yeah, I mean, that's fair. I don't necessarily
always need to be entertained as long as the
story is good and is captivating. But that was
not the case here. It definitely suffers from
a villain problem, you could say. You know,
in the first film, there was a mezzo in the
crime syndicate. In the second, there were shadow
demons and psycho pirates. In the third, there
was the anti-monitor? Though I'm hesitant to
even call him that because none of the characters
ever did in the film, and he bears little to
no resemblance to the anti-monitor from the
comics. This is more of like a shadow demon.
Megazord of sorts, but without any of the character
or motivation that was teased in conversations
with Psycho Pirate in part two. Right, yeah,
they hinted at some characterization of the
Anti-Monitor, like you said, toward the end
of part two, but here he was more like a force
of nature, the Anti-Monitor, and there were
like dozens of him, or like millions, I guess.
Right, exactly. Yeah, I wanted that motivation.
that hint of it that I saw in part two, but
that never materialized into anything. And
I think there was a huge, huge downfall for
this film. Now I've said in the past that if
you're going to adapt the crisis on infinite
earth's comic storyline to a film, you first
need to establish a cinematic multiverse beforehand.
For anyone not familiar with the comic storyline
from the eighties, it was a way for DC comics
to consolidate the continuity from their golden
and silver age comic stories, which had been
established. as existing within separate but
parallel universes, a multiverse which was revealed
to contain a near infinite number of Earths.
On Earth 1 you had the Justice League, on Earth
2 you had the Justice Society, on Earth 3 the
heroes were villains and the villains were heroes,
Earth 5 was home to the Charlton Comics characters
that DC had acquired, Earth S was home to the
Fawcett Comics characters,
so on and so forth. By the Tomorrowverse's second
film, Justice Society World War II, the multiverse
was established and it was something most subsequent
films continue to build upon in anticipation
for this concluding trilogy. Now a lot of people
have not loved the Tomorrowverse. From the
beginning, I praised the character designs,
but story-wise, other than a fantastic adaptation
of Batman the Long Halloween and a decent Green
Lantern film, The Tomorrowverse wasn't really
good enough to build any kind of anticipation,
and the approach to adapting the crisis storyline
across three films was inconsistent at best
and super confusing at worst, because the first
two films kind of play loose with time and don't
follow a linear narrative structure. This one
does. I wasn't anticipating that, and it was
kind of disappointing. Now, unfortunately,
I wouldn't be surprised if most audiences found
the film super confusing and inaccessible because
it requires you to have knowledge of animated
projects outside of the existing Tomorrowverse
films. Not only do they reference Justice League
Dark Apocalypse War, but they have homages
to Super Friends, Teen Titans, and The Timverse,
which includes Justice League, the animated
series, and Batman, the animated series. The
thing is, though, Even if you're a fan of those
shows, the brief cameos they offer really weren't
enough to get excited about, except for maybe
the final performance of Kevin Conroy as Batman
and Mark Cowell's Joker in that homage. But
otherwise, yeah, I was not impressed. I agree.
I do want to take a moment to highlight Kevin
Conroy's final performance, though. If you're
going to go out with a bang, that is how you
do it. The scene between his Batman... and Mark
Hamill's Joker, you know, it was less than
a minute long. But the dialogue between the
two of Batman realizing that his universe was
coming to an end and to decide to go out fighting
the Joker was perfection. And I'm so glad that
Kevin Conroy got that opportunity as his final
performance, because it was very touching and
probably honestly the best part of this film.
Hands down, it was the best part of this film.
It was so meta and yet so epic and even cathartic
in a way. Yeah. If you find the clip online,
that's all you need to watch from this film,
essentially, is what I'm saying. It's a great
clip. You guys should watch it if you decide
not to watch the film. But even then, the Batman,
the animated series homage, along with the other
homages and so many things in this trilogy
felt shoehorned. For sure. You know what it
reminded me of? It reminded me of DC's attempt
to explore the multiverse in the Flash movie,
the live action Flash movie that came out with
Ezra Miller, how we saw all these different
worlds with like, you know, Adam West's Batman
and George Reeve's Superman and Christopher
Reeve's Superman. It was a nice little wink
and nod for fans of the DC comics and DC media,
but it's hollow because there's no real substance
there. Like just showing them and not having
them be really a part of the story is kind
of a waste and it's not substantial enough.
It's cheap. It's cheap. It's a cheap way to
get you excited. And I'll be honest, I loved
that scene in the Flash. The more I look back
on it, the more I don't like it as much. I think
it was probably just the experience of seeing
it in the theater that really made me enjoy
that. And I definitely did not get that same
kind of feeling watching this version of it
because this was like you said, essentially
the animated version of that. It was just thrown
in there as were a ton of characters, like
they introduced us to a modern black canary,
just so she and green arrow can essentially
wink at each other. And that's basically it.
They introduced us to the losers, which Okay,
kind of unnecessary and obscure. They teased
Darkseid, but we didn't get to see a new version
of him either. The Losers thing actually surprised
me because I realized that there was no DC
showcase short that came out in the time of
the Tomorrowverse that did not in some way
tie into this crisis series of films. Every
short had a purpose, whether it was Commandy
or The Losers or Constantine House of Mystery.
Right. it was all kind of required viewing
for full enjoyment of these crisis films. Exactly,
yeah. And if you think it's hard to get people
to watch Marvel Disney Plus television shows
that tie into films, look at how the Marvel's
movie performed because it required so much
Disney Plus viewing, such as WandaVision and
Miss Marvel and Secret Invasion to enjoy that.
Try getting people to watch the DC Showcase
shorts. I don't think anybody really watches
those. Of course we review them on this podcast,
They're some of our least listened to episodes,
you know? Yes. By far. So kudos to the people
who actually watch the DC Showcase shorts and
are big enough fans to basically consume all
the media that DC is throwing at them. I think
you guys are the ones that are going to get
the most out of this movie and everyone else
is just going to be left so cold. But even
if they did watch the Losers short, it's not
like there's any kind of payoff here. They
mentioned that they're just a bunch of losers
and that's it. Like it's kind of cool to see
Aquaman fight a dinosaur, but it's a very fleeting
moment in a film that feels very long. Both
of my daughters and my wife fell asleep during
this movie, and I wanted to. I think the third
act was the best part, though. Really? I was
not happy with the third act. I actually liked
the first act the most. The first act was a
bunch of randomness because they were in the
Bleed universe where the laws of physics did
not apply. So it was just... Yeah, it was very
chaotic and strange. Whereas the third act wrapped
everything up, kind of, and answered a lot
of questions. Yeah, I guess, but it wrapped
everything up in an underwhelming way. Like,
everything about this film to me was so underwhelming
and unsatisfying. The only redeeming quality
I really have to comment on, besides the Kevin
Conroy cameo, is the film's ambition. Like
creating a 10 film universe for the sole purpose
of adapting the Crisis on Infinite Earth storyline
is no easy task because it requires the filmmakers
to capture the same sense of shock and awe
that readers initially had when decades of storytelling
culminated in this epic story with unbelievable
stakes. It was the infinity war and end game
of its time. And while most of the films in
the Tomorrowverse probably worked really well
on paper. As we've mentioned in our past reviews,
when you see the final product, all you can
do is hope that they get it right the next
go-round. Except this time, there won't be.
And I guess all I'm left with is the hope that
James Gunn can do better when DC's next animated
universe begins with Creature Commandos next
year. That is definitely a good thing that you
can say about this film is that at the end
of the day, it gives you hope, again, that something
better will come along next time. That said,
I have faith that James Gunn will be able to
put out a better product. Yeah, same. And honestly,
like James Gunn was going to do that whether
this film provided closure to an existing animated
universe or not. So there's not much solace
in the fact that this sets up something new
because it was going to happen anyway. Now usually
in our reviews, we have a character breakdown.
And I'll be honest, there's really no character
arcs in this film to break down. Like sure
there are. character moments that are cathartic
in some way, but those characters also only
have like two lines in the entire movie. I think
the character with the most development was
probably Constantine. Yeah, you could say that.
His story really revolves around his past actions
that resulted in the creation of the multiverse,
him and the Flash, but a lot of it is just
really exposition. I'm not sure if he learns
anything. He does get to move on to the afterlife
at the But other than that, yeah, not much more
to say. Well, he tried to sacrifice himself,
which felt very unconstantine-like, but the
dream machine or whatever that was. The miracle
machine. Honestly, I don't remember what that's
from. That was the one thing that had me scratching
my head. Oh, that was from the Legion of Superheroes.
You remember when Supergirl had to make a wish
at the very end and like reality kind of split.
It was a weird scene. Is that the thing that
Brainiac was using to try to take over the universe?
Yes. Okay, alright, yeah, I remember what it
is now. But it was strange because for some
reason, the dream machine was outside of time
and space, and yet the bleed dimension was also
outside of time and space, and I don't know,
there were a lot of disparate elements that
seemed a little convenient in terms of being
able to withstand the destruction of the primary
universe. Right, and you're referring to the
end of the film. The thing is, though, at that
point, they're outside of the bleed. They are
on the monitor's spaceship, which exists between
dimensions, but they're also on war world,
which also exists between dimensions. But they
say that the miracle machine exists between
dimensions. So it's like, what, how many in
between dimensions are there? Yeah. It seems
like there's a lot of different places to go
to escape the anti-monitor is all I'm saying,
especially when you don't have someone like,
like sleuth or ratting you out, you know? Right.
I guess the only other character worth mentioning
was Supergirl. Of course her arc kind of continues
from the past film, but for a majority of this
film she basically just feels guilty for killing
the monitor and at the end decides to sacrifice
herself because she feels responsible for the
predicament that all of the Earths find themselves
in. So it was inevitable, you know, she died
in the comic storyline as well. Totally saw
it coming. The one character that should have
had more backstory I feel like was Batman.
dick to everyone, didn't learn his lesson, and
then for some reason at the end of this film
he's like, oh, I'm going to lose you all kind
of in a way. And it's like, okay, buddy. All
right. Yeah, we never really saw that growth.
Not at all. Which is a shame because Jensen
Ackles was a good Batman. Actually a lot of
the cast was good here. I just want to make
that shout out. Jensen Ackles as Batman, Megan
Donnelly as Supergirl, Darren Criss as Superman,
and Stan Akadik as Wonder Woman. I will miss
this voice cast for sure. And Matt Ryan came
back, who has always in my mind been the perfect
voice for Constantine. And this is like for
sure, for sure the last time we're probably
going to hear him as the character. So that's
a little bittersweet. Yeah, yeah, I do wish
his dialogue was better. I wish the character
was written better. Definitely not as good as
Apocalypse War, but that would be a challenge
in and of itself. A few things are as good as
Apocalypse War, right? Right, fair.
Where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
Dynomic Podcast Network presents Console Combat,
where video game legends brawl every Monday.
Comic Book Titans smash every Tuesday. Max Destruction,
where TV and action heroes battle every Wednesday.
And Sendro World, where anime champions clash
every Thursday. Join us as we speculate on
the matches and armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge victorious.
Visit dynamicpodcast.com where we settle the
debate and settle the score.
Let's move on to the story highlights. The film
begins with the heroes of the multiverse attacking
the Anti-Monitor, successfully damaging him
with light-based attacks, though he adapts
and generates armor to protect himself. Before
the Anti-Monitor can fully charge up and project
an antimatter wave, the Monitor, having just
been fatally burned by Supergirl's heat vision
with his dying breath, sends the
where the anti-monitor can't find them. I wonder
why he didn't do that to begin with. Why did
he wait until the moment of his death to send
everyone to the bleed where they were more
safe? Oh, cause he sucks. That's the only reason
I don't know. All right. It seemed like a last
ditch effort, but it was also the best way to
protect so many earths that had been destroyed
by this point. I think maybe he didn't want
to do it because it was a last ditch effort,
knowing the chaos that would befall the different
Earths if he did. Oh, you mean due to the lack
of laws of physics? Right, quantum physics specifically.
I guess Lex Luthor did mention in the movie
that all the Earths were going to eventually
die due to these catastrophic events, so maybe
that's the answer to why the monitor didn't
do this in the first place. Right, right, exactly.
Like I said, it was a last ditch effort. Now,
flashing forward eight months, Superman of
Earth-1 and Hawk Girl find Wonder Woman adrift
in the bleed and bring her aboard their ship,
explaining that they found her tiara floating
in the interdimensional space and suspected
her immortality allowed her to survive the Anti-Monitor's
antimatter wave from the previous film. After
reuniting with Earth-2 Superman, Wonder Woman
is taken to the Monitor ship, where she learns
that because the bleed exists outside of space-time,
Both space and time are in flux across the
surviving worlds, making it a challenge to protect
and provide for the survivors. Wonder Woman,
the Superman, and others then rescue the inhabitants
of Earth-1 from dinosaurs that emerged from
a chronal anomaly along with the losers. Now
does this movie imply that there was only one
Wonder Woman in the multiverse? It kind of seemed
that way. Right, because then you would have
a whole multitude of Wonder Women surviving
the destruction of their universe due to the
antimatter wave. Which to me is dumb, because-
It's bullshit. Wonder Woman has never been
immortal. I mean, immortal, yes, in the sense
that she doesn't age, or like ages very slowly,
and may not die from aging. But the fact that
she could survive antimatter when so many other
things in the universe couldn't, makes me wonder
why she gets to be so special. Yeah, none of
the other Themyscirans or even like the Olympian
gods or anything else that was around in that
universe were able to outlive its destruction.
But she was. So dumb, I hated that. They used
that at the end though, implying that like because
she was immortal she had like almost infinite
life to sacrifice, I guess was the idea. That's
how I understood it. Also hated that. If you
make Wonder Woman immortal, why even give her
bracelets? You know? That's true. I don't get
it, I don't get it. Now, Secret Society of Super-Villains,
led by Lex Luthor, convenes on Earth 10, where
they discuss how the multiverse Earths can't
survive the bleed. It's revealed that Psycho-Pirate
is Lex's prisoner, and Lex forces Psycho-Pirate
to reach out to the Anti-Monitor. Meanwhile,
on the same Earth, Batman and his allies battle
an army of time-displaced Nazi soldiers armed
with weapons from Gotham's villains. When Batman
is gassed with fear toxin, He remembers encountering
an elderly Barry Allen during his time on Warworld.
Now of course Earth-10 in the comics is actually
Earth-X. It's like the Roman numeral 10 where
Nazis never lost the war. It's the Earth where
the quality comics characters like Uncle Sam
and Black Condor live. One thing I really didn't
get in this film is how Psycho Pirate became
so freaking weak. Like how would he become
Lex Luthor's prisoner when he could totally
just take control of Lex Luthor and all of
the other villains? Well, he was being tortured
at the start of this movie, so you have to
assume that somehow he was captured and tortured
immediately, I guess? Okay, maybe, but also
he's the freaking Psycho Pirate. Like he was
totally amped up with power in the second film.
and could have easily just projected his emotions
to take control of the situation, whether he's
being tortured or not. Like if he's feeling
pain and like distress from being tortured,
he could project that distress onto the people
torturing him. That's valid. So that was dumb.
Moving on back on the mothership, as Supergirl
expresses remorse for killing the monitor,
Lex Luthor arrives just as the Anti-Monitor
finds and destroys Aquaman's underwater world
of Earth-146. by projecting an antimatter wave.
After Batman confides with Dr. Midnight about
his vision of the Flash, Dr. Fate confirms that
Batman's vision was real and that to solve
their ongoing crisis they would need to look
back to before the creation of the multiverse.
When Jon Stewart remembers that John Constantine
mentioned that he'd been around since before
the universe began, they manage to find him
drunk in a saloon on Earth 18. and suffering
from memory loss. The scene in which Supergirl
is confessing her guilt to Batgirl, I assume
is around the time that Supergirl revealed the
existence of the dream machine to Barbara Gordon,
and I'm wondering why she didn't ever think
to use the dream machine to stop the Anti-Monitor
to begin with. That's a great question, and
that's a major plot hole. She knew the location,
so she could have easily told everyone where
to find it and how they could use it. It's
really weird that she didn't do that. But, you
know, regardless, at the very minimum, they
should have had the scene where she told Batgirl
about it. Yeah. Maybe they didn't have that
because then they realized that if that had
been the case, she could have used the Miracle
Machine to save everyone from the very start.
Plot hole. Now after the Anti-Monitor finds
and destroys Earth-2, the heroes on Monitor's
ship deduce that the Anti-Monitor is able to
find their worlds in the Bleed. because someone
there is in contact with him. While Lex Luthor
confesses to sacrificing worlds to gain more
information on the anti-monitor, back on Earth
18, Batman, Dr. Fate, and Constantine perform
a seance to access Constantine's past memories,
where they view the concluding events of the
film Justice League Dark Apocalypse War and
learn that Constantine encouraged the Flash
to go back in time to kill Darkseid as a baby,
so that he could never destroy their universe.
Unknown to the Flash, Constantine sacrificed
a part of his soul to place a spell on Flash
so that any being he encountered would die,
knowing that the Flash wouldn't be able to bring
himself to actually kill a baby. As one of
the immutable pillars of existence, Darkseid's
death shattered reality, creating a multiverse
of infinite Earths. First of all, how cute was
baby Darkseid? I just wanted to grab him and
squeeze him and just be like, aw, little baby
Darkseid. I don't think I could have come to
kill him either. He was just too adorable. Second
of all, how do you feel about Darkseid being
like a pillar of the universe what the MCU would
call an absolute point or a nexus being or
something like that? I think it makes total
sense. I actually really liked that explanation.
They also refer to him as like a fixed point
in time. So yeah, it reminded me a lot of like
a nexus being for a Marvel. Does that mean though
that the DC universe is- always destined to
be destroyed by Darkseid obtaining the anti-life
equation. I think so. I think so. I think that's
what the final crisis was all about in the comics
because that's what happens. Darkseid is essentially
DC's devil, and there's only one of him in the
entire multiverse in the comics when the multiverse
was reestablished. So yeah, I actually really
liked that. My understanding of the situation
is that because Constantine and the Flash created
a universe in which there was no Darkseid,
universe kind of shattered and started cascading
in a series of events and choices that would
split off alternate dimensions and whatnot.
Yeah, an infinite number of dimensions. It
was unsustainable essentially is how they explained
it. Now when the heroes witness anti-monitor
destroy Earth A.D. which is Commandy's Earth,
Lex deduces that the energy of the merged suns
should be powerful enough to destroy the anti-monitor
though Superman would likely die absorbing
and delivering the Guilt-stricken, Kara takes
Superman's place, flying into the sun to absorb
its energy. When the Anti-Monitor appears in
the Bleed once again, the heroes of the Multiverse
attack it in an effort to buy Kara time to absorb
enough energy. When Martian Manhunter takes
over Lex Luthor's mind, using him to encourage
Superman to disable the Earth's towers and
pull the planets out of the Bleed, the heroes
comply, allowing
and deliver a blow to Anti-Monitor strong enough
to crack his armor. Meanwhile, on Earth 18,
new members from the Green Lantern Corps find
Jon Stewart and deliver him a Green Lantern
Ring. And now we finally know why the Warworld
movie even existed, because I think we speculated
in previous reviews that the Warworld movie
had no purpose in the larger Tomorrowverse
narrative, and we were wrong. this was its purpose,
to be used as a weapon against the Anti-Monitor.
Right, exactly. Part of me still doesn't care.
Part of me doesn't think that needed to be
a film. But I mean, it is honestly cool to see
Warworld in action. When Anti-Monitor attacks
Warworld, Jon Stewart and his core members manage
to shield it from the Anti-Monitor wave. To
fuel Warworld with enough emotional energy to
attack Anti-Monitor again. Martian Manhunter
takes control of the mind of Electrocutioner
on Earth-10 to persuade Psycho Pirate to use
his power to unify the emotions of every Earth
in the Multiverse. With Warworld able to breach
the Anti-Monitor's armor once again, a solar-energized
Supergirl flies into Anti-Monitor and sacrifices
herself to destroy him. Superman brings her
body to Warworld, where the heroes and villains
of the Multiverse have grouped. Now, one thing
that I thought was bullshit was the fact that
the Green Lanterns were able to stop an anti-monitor
wave. Because everything that the heroes have
been throwing at it prior to this proved ineffective.
So why now all of a sudden? Yeah, the Green
Lanterns were like, this isn't going to work.
And just it was like, you just have to have
the willpower or something like that. I'm like,
that's such crap. Because then you could just
have the Green Lanterns going and protecting
every Earth. They could have been doing that
this whole time. The movie does make you think
that Psycho Pirate would find newfound motivation
in trying to take over Warworld because the
Psycho Pirate controlled Warworld would be
almost unstoppable, you would think. Oh, absolutely.
Yeah, that'd be wild. I am really curious as
to what emotion he had everyone in the multiverse
feel, all of the different Earths, because
they never say. They all got super horny. That's
it. That's probably it. I can see that. Yeah.
Stupid. When Batman and Doctor Fate explained
the reason for the multiverses broken and expanding
nature, it's deduced that the Anti-Monitor was
the multiverses natural defense to stop its
limitless and chaotic expansion. As hundreds
more Anti-Monitors suddenly emerge, Batgirl
reveals that Supergirl once told her of a miracle
machine that existed in a pocket dimension
between realities. Using Nightshade's teleportation
powers, the heroes are able to transfer the
miracle machine to Warworld. As Earth's 508
and 12 fall to the Anti-Monitors, the heroes
come to the conclusion that to save the multiverse,
they need to merge it into one prime universe
with its own history. How did Marshall Manhunter
know where to find the Dream Machine? So my
guess is that since Warworld exists between
universes, he was able to expertly navigate
them because that's what he had been doing this
whole time. You know, he was in the bleed with
everyone else. He had always been on Warworld,
just in between everything. How he was able
to get Nightshade to teleport the miracle machine
onto Warworld, even though she was like, I
can't do it, was weird, because he was just
like, oh, yeah, you can. And it was just there.
Good explanation. Exactly. I wonder why if Marshall
Manhunter had control of. Warworld this entire
time if he didn't kind of corral the surviving
heroes and use it as a base since apparently
It was able to navigate the multiverse in that
way. It became a base at the end But I feel
like that could have happened sooner Yeah, he
really should have been around in the first
two movies, but they did that whole trick with
like Oh, he was there when Warworld exploded.
Wait. No, he wasn't It was cheap. In the final
moments of the film Wonder Woman sacrifices
her immortal self to power the miracle machine
to create a new universe, which a majority
of the heroes and villains step into, saying
goodbye to one another before merging into
the new universe. As the rest of the multiverse
and war world are destroyed, the Spectre and
Constantine move into the afterlife. In the
new single Prime Universe, a young Wonder Woman
plays on the island paradise of Themyscira.
Which makes me wonder how she got there, because
she wasn't one of the few that walked into the
new universe. I assume the new universe is
populated by people whether they sacrifice themselves
or not. I mean, people who did sacrifice themselves
were just a part of a larger whole, I guess,
as it were. But the line regarding Wonder Woman's
immortality not being a thing anymore kind of
threw me off because I guess they're saying
she's not immortal now? Yeah, her mother Queen
Hippolyta implied that. She was like, princesses
aren't immortal. I was like, what? Now she's
not? Okay? I didn't quite look hard enough
to determine if the art style of the new DC
Prime animated universe was very different
from the Tomorrowverse. Like, was that final
scene done in the same style that the upcoming
Creature Commandos is going to be in? And if
so, is this our first look at James Gunn's
new DCU? It's hard to tell. Because the character
designs in the Tomorrowverse weren't like that
same kind of blocky Tim-verse style, you know,
they were all pretty unique. I can't tell if
this is a new style of animation or if it's
more of the same. It looks like it's more of
the same to me personally. But who's to say
that that's not the style that we'll be seeing
with Creature Commandos? It could be. I guess
we'll find out later this year. If this in
fact is that same style, I wonder if this implies
that this is our first look at Wonder Woman
in James Gunn's DCU. And maybe our first look
at- Themyscira that's gonna be in the Paradise
Lost HBO series. And maybe our first look at
the Wonder Woman costume that she'll be wearing
with like the pants, which I would hate. Lot
of speculation, lot of unanswered questions,
which I don't love. Like at the end of a cinematic
universe, as it were, I would love for everything
to be wrapped up in a nice bow. That's not the
case here. And I can't express how disappointed
I am. by the whole Tomorrowverse project. Now,
with this film specifically, though it's ambitious
and heartfelt, it's convoluted and it's a dull
conclusion to the Tomorrowverse that proves
inaccessible to all but DC's most diehard animation
fans. I really hope you guys are out there
and I really hope you were able to get some
enjoyment out of this if you were, because
no one else did. And I say that as a diehard
animation fan from DC. Now we gave Crisis Part
1 3.5 stars, we gave Crisis Part 2 3 stars.
I think this film, Part 3, is one step below
that. So I'm giving it 2.5 stars, a rotten rating
on Rotten Tomatoes. I don't recommend it, and
overall I can't really say I recommend the Tomorrowverse
as a whole, unfortunately. I would recommend
if you're interested in getting into DC animation.
to either re-watch or watch for the first time
the DC animated movie universe, which began
with Justice League the Flashpoint Paradox
and ended with Apocalypse War. And just end
there. Like, don't continue on after that.
It's not worth it. Except for maybe Batman and
Long Halloween. That was good. Yeah. But if
anything, the brief glimpse that we got in this
film of Justice League Dark Apocalypse War,
you know, like seeing those characters and that
art style. and all that, just maybe remember
how much we connected with those characters
emotionally. So much more than we did with
these hollow shells that were in the Tomorrowverse.
And it also reminded me of just how great Apocalypse
War was. It definitely makes me want to rewatch
it again. It makes me want to watch all of
the films in the DC animated movie universe
because actually there's a few that I haven't
seen. And it was just a really well put together
cinematic universe, one that rivaled, in my
opinion, the MCU's Infinity Saga. Absolutely,
but you're not going to get a chance to re-watch
the DC AMU films because you have a whole lot
of other animated television shows to watch
this summer including My Adventures with Superman
season 2, Suicide Squad Isekai season 1, Batman
Caped Crusader season 1, Kite Man season 1,
and Watchmen chapter 1. So you have all of
your free time accounted for basically. If you
guys don't hear from me, it's because I'm watching
TV. That is my life now. I have to start watching
Hit Monkey too, but I'm really looking forward
to that. I'm looking forward to all of it. Though
I will say, we will be dropping some of our
reviews a little late, I think, just so that
all of my life is not just television. I do
have a job, I do have a family. So if things
are coming late, just expect that. Yeah, just
know that they are coming. But I think that
does it for this review. AJ9K helped close
us out. Thanks for listening to Dynamic duel.
Visit the show's website at dynamicduel.com
and follow us on Instagram at dynamicduelpodcast.
You can support the show on Patreon at patreon.com
slash dynamicduel and joining a tier that works
for you, or by rating and reviewing Dynamic
duel on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser or
on our website. Don't forget to listen to the
other shows in the DynaMic Podcast Network,
including Max Destruction, Senjou World and
Console Combat. Our next episode is going to
be another review, but it's going to be an
awesome review because it's going to be of Deadpool
and Wolverine. Another culmination of a trilogy
that is infinitely more awesome than Crisis
on Infinite Earths. I'm expecting a lot from
Deadpool and Wolverine and I hope it meets my
expectations. I have to try to manage them
because I am just off the walls with anticipation.
This is the only MCU film that you're getting
this year, right? Correct. There's still a couple
more Sony Marvel movies coming out this year,
including Venom and Craven the Hunter. But Deadpool
and Wolverine is the only MCU film. Yeah. We're
not getting another Marvel Studios film until
Valentine's Day with Captain America Brave
New World. I was going to say sucks to suck,
but I only have Joker 2 coming out this year.
But that's going to be phenomenal, like way
better than Deadpool and Wolverine. Manage
your expectations. We all know Joker Part 2
is going to suck. OK. It's a musical. All right.
I don't know that. You can't say that, I don't
know that. But that does it for this episode
guys, we want to give a big thanks to our executive
producers Ken Johnson, Jon Sturawski, Zachary
Hepburn, Dustin Belcombe, Miggie Bantanghian,
Brandon Estergard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yeaton,
Austin Wiselowski, AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho,
Gil Camacho, Adam Spies, Andrew Schunk, Dean
Molesky, Devin Davis, and Joseph Kersting for
helping make this podcast possible. And we'll
talk to you guys next week. Up up and away,
true believers. My middle name is Miracle Machine.