This is a Dynamike Network podcast. Hey everyone,
Marvelous Joe here at the top of the episode.
With the approaching holiday season, we're officially
underway with this year's Holiday Charity Drive
and lead up to our charity dual episode in December,
which is going to be Alfred Pennyworth versus
Edwin Jarvis. This year, all donations will
be going once again to Pop Culture Classroom,
a non-profit organization that delivers high
quality, all-inclusive educational resources
to school districts, teachers, and community
organizations using comics, graphic novels,
and related pop culture media. Their mission
is to inspire a love of learning, increase
literacy, celebrate diversity, and build community
through the tools of popular culture and the
power of self-expression. To donate, visit our
official store through dynamicduel.com where
you'll find two donation options, one if you're
Team DC and one if you're Team Marvel. Or you
can go directly to dynamicduel.com slash Donate
DC, one word, or dynamicduel.com slash donatemarvel,
which are linked in our show notes. We're making
the charity drive a competitive duel this year,
except the only stat that matters is which side
can donate the most. Everyone who donates will
receive a digital poster featuring original
art of Alfred and Jarvis draw New Yorker style
by Jonathan. One lucky random donor will win
a framed print of the Alfred vs Jarvis art
that we'll announce during that December duel
episode. which fanbase will be the most charitable,
we'll keep everyone posted as to which team
is winning as donations come in during these
upcoming episodes. As of right now, Marvel is
ahead with four more donations than DC. So
you gotta catch up DC fans, on with the show.
Hi, welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based simulations.
I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin brother, Marvelous
Joe. And in this episode, we're doing a duel
between DC's Enchantress and Marvel's Enchantress.
That's right. Both Marvel and DC have a sorceress
character named Enchantress. Obviously the better
one is going to be the Marvel version, but
we're going to find out who'd win in a fight
between these two characters by inputting the
stats and running a thousand simulated matches
between them. I bet you Enchantress is going
to win. Oh dude Enchantress is totally going
to stomp. Yes she is. Yeah. Now of course this
episode was supposed to be a review of Loki
season two. but because I'm going on a business
trip this week, we're recording this episode
early, and since I haven't seen all of Loki
yet, we are doing a duel for right now. Next
week, we'll review Loki Season Two. Yeah, but
this episode is a good tie-in to Loki Season
Two because the Enchantress, like Loki, is
an Asgardian. Since we're recording this episode
early, we're gonna skip over the no prize and
the news portions of this episode and jump straight
into the duel. But before we do that, as our
listeners may know, our dual simulator is so
advanced that it's gained sentience and has
named itself the Artificial Lifeform for running
extensive duels, just a rather very intelligent
Simulator 9000, or Alfred Jarvis 9000. Here's
a quick message for our listeners, so listen
up! Why hello there. Do you love listening and
chatting about Marvel and DC? Then become a
part of the dynamic dual community on Patreon,
where you can choose from three tiers. The
dynamic 2-0 tier lets you listen to this podcast
without ads and gives you access to its Discord
chat group, where you can chat with Johnny DC
and Marvelous Joe. The fantastic 4 tier gives
you that and more with two bonus episodes each
month, including bloopers and top 10 shows
where Johnny and Joe count down your favourite
Marvel and DC subjects. The X-Force tier makes
you an executive producer of Dynamic Dual. where
every month you help the hosts choose what
to review and who to fight against each other.
And finally, the Dynamite Podcast Network tier
allows aspiring podcasters to create their own
battle-focused show using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and consultation,
and get you simulation results to announce on
your show. Pitch the twins your show via email
at dynamicduelpodcast.gmail.com or by reaching
out to them on social media. Check it out at
patreon.com slash dynamicduelpodcast.gmail.com.
your Pip Cheerio. Thanks AJ9K and thanks to
everyone who supports the podcast. Be sure to
tune into both the Max Destruction and Sanjo
World podcast this week. We actually don't know
what the episodes are going to be, but I guarantee
you they're going to be awesome because the
shows are awesome. Yeah, every episode is a
good time. And we're happy to announce now that
we have another show joining the Dynamike Podcast
Network. Starting in December, the show is going
to be called... Console Combat with Kaze. And
in it, host John Storosky and his co-host Dean
are going to be finding out who would win in
a fight between two characters from your favorite
video games. So look forward to that podcast
again coming out starting in December. It's
gonna be a whole lot of fun. The Dynamica Podcast
Network keeps growing with incredible shows
beyond dynamic duel where you can now hear
battles between your favorite movie characters,
anime characters, and video game characters.
Make sure to check out dynamicpodcast.com or
click the link in our show notes to listen
to all of the shows in the Dynamite Podcast
Network. But with that out of the way, on to
the question of the week.
That's right, we're going with the same question
of the week that we had from last episode,
which is What other characters from the Sandman
universe do you hope to get their own series
on Netflix? And this is coming off of the first
trailer we received for the Dead Boy Detectives
television show on Netflix. That question still
stands for this week, so go ahead and record
your answer at dynamicduel.com by clicking on
the red microphone button in the bottom right
hand corner of the screen, which will prompt
you to leave us a voicemail. Your message can
be up to 30 seconds long, and don't forget to
leave your name in case we include you on the
podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer and
award that person a Dynamic Dual Note Prize
that we'll post to Instagram and our email newsletter.
Again, be sure to answer before November 25th.
And now let's move on to the main event of this
episode where we find out who's gonna win in
a matchup between the Sorceress, the Enchantress
against the Sorceress, the Enchantress.
Alright, Enchantress vs Enchantress. As we mentioned
earlier, DC and Marvel both have characters
named Enchantress who are sorcerers within their
respective universes. I don't know much about
Marvel's Enchantress. I just know that she's
inferior to DC's. No, because DC's Enchantress
was in a shitty Suicide Squad movie. Oh, you
mean the Academy Award winning Suicide Squad
movie? That's so stupid. Were any of the Thor
movies Academy Award winning films? Did not
think so. I don't think so. Exactly, neither
did I. Marvel's Enchantress though has kind
of made an appearance on the screen in the Loki
television show because the second iteration
of the character was named Sylvie. And so the
Loki TV show Sylvie is kind of a riff on that
version of the Enchantress. So it's real fitting
that this episode is in tie-in to our Loki
season two review that's coming out next week.
Oh, that's interesting, I didn't know that.
Yeah, but I'm going to be going with the original
version of the character who's an Asgardian
named Amora. I thought her name was Enchantress!
No! Okay. Well, to explain the methodology
behind our duels, let's go to our sentient duel
simulator, Alfred Jarvis9000. AJ9K, tell our
listeners how you go about determining a winner
in our duel matchups. Yes, of course, sir.
The way I determine a winner between the contestants
is by running 1,000 Monte Carlo simulations
using the character's statistics. A Monte Carlo
simulation is a probabilistic model used to
determine outcomes through random sampling.
In this case, I randomised the statistics along
a normal distribution as a way to simulate the
many variables that can occur during battle.
The stat parameters are based on the official
Marvel power grid from which the DC characters'
statistics are extrapolated. Additional stat
categories are included such as range, damage
potential, versatility and perception in order
to create a more detailed and accurate simulation.
The results of the 1000 simulations provide
a percentage of wins for each character. The
contestant with the higher percentage is declared
the victor, as they have a higher probability
to win any given battle. In an equitable pairing,
neither character should win 100% of the matches.
The comic book stories have shown that there's
even a way for Batman to defeat Superman, so
the confidence rate of my method falls in line
with the precedents that have been established
in the source material. My mathematical simulations
are without subjectivity or bias. Feats are
not the sole consideration, nor are fan votes
tabulated for determination of the winner.
Thanks AJ9K! Before we run the simulations though,
we like to break down each character's histories
and abilities before improvising a scenario
on how we imagine one of the 1000 simulations
would play out beat for beat. And I believe
it's my turn to go first with the DC characters
backstory, so let me tell you all about Enchantress.
Jun Moon was a timid whose entire life was
changed, the fateful evening her boyfriend,
Alan Dell, surprised her by bringing her to
a costume party at an old, abandoned, and supposedly
haunted castle, aptly named Terror Castle.
Overwhelmed by the party and the supernatural
forces within the castle, June snuck away to
a secluded area and accidentally slipped through
a secret panel in a wall.
known as Zamor, who explained to June that fate
had brought her there, and that she was destined
to be a powerful sorceress that could rid the
castle of its evil. By speaking the word Enchantress,
June transformed into a mystical witch, and
was able to defeat the evil forces haunting
the castle. June became a superhero, transforming
her blonde hair black and blue eyes green whenever
she summoned her magical Enchantress alter ego.
to save the life of her boyfriend, Allen, who
found himself attracted to Enchantress, not
realizing she was really June. Eventually,
June got a full-time job at the New Athens Experimental
School in Florida, where Linda Danvers, aka
Supergirl, also worked. You can learn more about
Supergirl in our Supergirl vs. Captain Marvel
duel episode. It was at New Athens that June
stumbled upon Zamor once again, and the creature
explained to June, that soon the moon was going
to align with a star that would allow June
to gain omnipotent magical power and the potential
to destroy all evil at the cost of also destroying
all scientific laws that governed the universe.
Deciding it was worth the risk, June attempted
to gain the power, but Supergirl prevented her
from doing so by moving the moon out of alignment.
Whether it was due to Supergirl's misalignment
of the heavenly bodies that affected June,
or June's own frustration at being forced to
fight a never-ending battle against evil, the
Enchantress became corrupted and attempted to
take over the world, forming a team known as
the Forgotten Villains, though their plots were
continually defeated by Supergirl and Superman.
After the Crisis on Infinite Earths event, June
sought penance for her actions as the Enchantress
and volunteered for Amanda Waller's Task Force
X, aka the Suicide Squad. which you can learn
more about in our team duel episode, Suicide
Squad vs. the Defenders. As various missions
undertaken by the squad were completed, June
stayed on with the team while others left,
as Waller had promised to help her control the
corrupted evil Enchantress entity that she
believed now dwelled within her. June was diagnosed
with schizophrenia, and the Enchantress seemingly
became more and more powerful and volatile with
each new mission, often forcing her teammates
to subdue her while in the field. The field's
team leader, Bronze Tiger, who you can learn
more about in our Bronze Tiger vs White Tiger
episode, took June to see the ancient mystic
Madame Xanadu, who explained to June that her
lack of training had resulted in her aura succumbing
to evil influences. June learned that if she
stopped using magic, her aura would eventually
heal, and Madame Xanadu gave June a necklace
and ring that would help her suppress the evil
within her. With the warning, the Enchantress'
magic would also build up over time and would
likely be unstoppable if she ever emerged again.
While aiding the Suicide Squad on a mission
to the Nightshade Dimension, June learned that
the Enchantress was in fact a separate entity
from another dimension known as Succubus, the
sister of Incubus, who had conquered that dimension.
Incubus ripped Succubus out of June's body,
leaving her powerless, and June left the team
soon after, it eventually ended up in a mental
institution. Succubus herself later escaped
to Earth during the Day of Judgment storyline,
only to seemingly be sacrificed by the warlock
Sebastian Faust to reignite the fires of Hell.
In reality, however, Sebastian had merely captured
Succubus, who later escaped and assumed the
identity of Anita Solida. Faust was able to
re-bind Succubus to June, however, and when
the Spectre attempted to Enchantress was able
to nearly defeat the Spectre by channeling magic
from all magical beings on Earth, but the power
proved to be too corrupting an influence for
her, and she was forced to give it up. Once
the Spectre was defeated, she joined the magic-based
team known as Shadow Pact. In post-Flashpoint
continuity, June's history remained largely
the same, though in one of the Justice League's
early adventures, they failed to stop the global
chaos wrought by the Enchantress entity. when
she was exorcised from June Moon by Madame Xanadu.
This resulted in the formation of the Justice
League Dark Magic Team, who was forced to re-merge
Enchantress with June in order to protect the
world from the succubus's power. You can learn
more about Justice League Dark in their team
duel episode against the Midnight Suns. June
later joined a new version of the Suicide Squad
and was pivotal in supping Superman with her
magical powers during the Justice League versus
Suicide Squad run. Now powers-wise, Enchantress
is an entity of nearly limitless magical potential,
and regarded as one of the most dangerous mystical
beings in existence. Her power is quelled only
by her host, June Moon, who over the years has
learned to channel the power of the Enchantress
to transform and manipulate objects, often bringing
them to life, and also transforming her own
appearance or making herself intangible. She
has telekinesis, can fly, can fire devastating
blasts of magical energy, and generate magic-based
constructs. She's also one of the foremost
spellcasters, able to heal, teleport, cast illusions,
and bind herself to other magic users, able
to track them and even remotely sap or steal
their powers. Her only weakness is actually
using too much power, as it strengthens the
evil succubus within her, who, when unleashed,
is a nigh-omnipotent reality warper. That's
Enchantress. So in the Suicide Squad movie,
the Enchantress also had a brother. I forgot
what they named him in the film, but was that
guy Incubus? Yeah, that was Incubus. Oh, interesting.
I'm surprised he didn't jam out with like whatever
tomorrow brings. I'll be there. Holy shit, that
was awful. Never do that again. No one remembers
that band, dude. No one remembers the band.
Incubus is timeless. I just have to say that,
so. But let me go ahead and tell you about the
backstory of the superior enchantress in the
Marvel universe. Millennia ago, Amora was born
in the realm of Asgard, one of the nine realms
of Norse mythology, and as the goddess of youth
and fertility, grew to be renowned among the
gods for her astonishing beauty. In her adolescence,
she ran away to the land of the Norns, an apprentice
under one of the most powerful sorceresses in
all of the realms. Training in magic into adulthood,
Amora proved to be an adept sorceress herself,
using enchantments primarily to enhance her
natural allure to influence others and developing
a reputation as a seductress. Of all the Asgardian
men she was able to manipulate, however, Thor
Odinson, the God of Thunder, was beyond her
temptations. Driven to infatuation with Thor
and obsessed with the challenge of conquering
his heart, Amora was relentless in her pursuit
of him. occasionally teaming up with Thor's
brother Loki to try and break down the God of
Thunder spirit. You can learn more about Thor
and Loki in their respective dual episodes against
Wonder Woman and Ares respectively. Beyond
scheming for Thor's affection, Amora deceived
other fellow Asgardians such as the beautiful
Valkyrie using her magic to trap her in a mystic
crystal, a story you can learn more about in
our Power Girl vs Valkyrie dual episode. Chief
among Amora's many suitors was the Asgardian
named Scourge the Executioner, who was madly
in love with her and bowed to her every whim
despite his affections being unrequited. When
Thor was banished to Earth by his father and
fell in love with the mortal woman Jane Foster,
a jealous Amora went to Earth and tried to
seduce him. After getting spurned once again,
Amora ordered Scourge to eliminate Jane Foster,
but Thor stopped them and hurled the pair back
to Asgard. Amora and Scourge went on to join
Baron Zemo's Masters of Evil supervillain team
in order to beset the newly formed Avengers,
of which Thor was a founding member. As a recurring
villain for the Avengers, Amora eventually
expanded her list of enemies to include some
of Earth's other mightiest heroes, such as
Hercules, whom she also became smitten with,
and the Scarlet Witch, whom she considered
her rival. Amora was one of the many villains
and heroes abducted by the all-powerful entity
called the Beyonder. to take part in his grand
morality experiment to see who would win in
a battle between good and evil, known as the
Secret Wars. On his patchwork planet called
Battleworld, Amora found herself trapped alongside
Thor, and the two finally shared an intimate
encounter. Thor tried to convince Amora to leave
the villains and join the side of good, but
Amora shamefully declined, fearful of the consequences,
but flirting with the idea of being a hero.
With the Secret Wars over, Amora and Scourge
fought alongside their fellow Asgardians to
defend their home against the fire demon Surtur,
preventing him from causing Ragnarok or the
Twilight of the Norse gods. The pair also defended
the realm from the Asgardian goddess of death,
Hela, though Scourge died in that battle. Amora
later discovered her sister Lorelei had put
a love spell on Thor and she freed the hero
from her sister's bewitchment. Seemingly over
her infatuation with Thor, Amora grew close
to Heimdall. who was the sentry of Asgard's
rainbow bridge known as the Bifrost. Inspired
by his nobility, she became a more unselfish
figure and even fought against her former ally
Loki, protecting Odin's throne. This wasn't
meant to last however, and Amora returned to
her scheming ways after realizing Heimdall
would always be more devoted to Asgard than
to her, and she parted from him. After menacing
Doctor Strange, the Sorcerer Supreme, She moved
to Hollywood and became a movie star for a
while, winning the hearts of men through her
films. Amora tried to seduce fellow superhero
actor Wonder Man, whom you can learn more about
in his duel against Captain Adam, but she was
unsuccessful. Eventually, Amora returned home
and fell in battle with the rest of the Asgardians
when Loki successfully fulfilled the Ragnarok
prophecies and caused the destruction of the
Nine Realms. Amora was later restored to life
along with the rest of her kind when Thor returned
to Earth. Since Scourge was still dead, having
fallen prior to Ragnarok, Amora magically attacked
the World Tree Yggdrasil in an effort to resurrect
her old ally, having come to the realization
how much he meant to her. Thor and Loki stopped
her, however, convincing her that bringing
Scourge back from Valhalla would only dishonor
his death. Amora wasn't the only one meddling
with the World Tree, however, as Hela sent most
of the Nine Realms to Hell after gaining the
magical Twilight Sword. Amora teamed up with
Thor to battle the Goddess of Death, helping
him reunite with his hammer Mjolnir in order
to win back the Twilight Sword, which Thor
then entrusted to Heimdall. Later, Amora allied
herself with the villainous dark elf Malekith,
joining him in his war to take over the Nine
Realms. She journeyed to Alfheim using her
magic to manipulate Queen Elsa of the Light
Elves into marrying Malekith, and then she
invaded the dwarven realm of Nidavellir alongside
the Eventually, the war came to Midgard, aka
Earth's realm, and Amora took the continent
of South America as her prize. After receiving
a premonition of Captain Marvel and Doctor Strange
coming to defeat her, she used a spell to swap
the two heroes' bodies, though they were still
able to defeat her, and Malekith's war was
put to an end. Amora was then imprisoned beneath
Asgard in the Root Dungeons before escaping
back to Midgard. There, Amora clashed once again
with Captain Marvel. who tried to get her help
in defeating one of Amora's future sons. She
then met with her estranged twin sons that
she had with an Asgardian palisade that she
seduced years ago, rescuing the boys, Eirik
and Alvi from an evil wizard named Pulsari,
who had kidnapped them as infants. And that's
her backstory. Powers-wise, the Enchantress
has the physiology of an Asgardian god, meaning
she is strong enough to lift around 25 tons,
has enhanced durability, speed, longevity and
healing, as well as enhanced senses. She is
among Asgard's strongest sorcerers, just below
the level of Loki, the god of mischief. Enchantress
can cast all matter of magic spells for a variety
of effects, including, but not limited to, shapeshifting,
illusion casting, teleportation, matter transmutation,
hypnosis, telepathy, telekinesis, and manipulation
of magical energies such as magical blasts
and shields. Though her specialty is in the
art of magical seduction, able to enthrall
others to do her bidding with a kiss, mere words,
or even a glance. She is quite intelligent,
often thinking up devious and manipulative schemes.
And? That's it. Okay, yeah, that's nothing!
You got nothing! You're gonna lose! Good day,
sir! You stole fizzy lifting drinks! I didn't
realize Enchantress was so, like, kinky. Like,
like, is this is this speculation going to
turn into some kind of like erotic fanfiction?
No, we can't let that happen. Like you tried
to do with Catwoman and Hellcat and Poison Ivy
and White Queen. All right. I'm not going to
let that happen. We'll see. We'll see where
it goes.
Hey guys, Johnny DC here to remind all of you
that the holidays are fast approaching and
that there's no better time than now to start
shopping for gifts for your loved ones. And
if one of those loved ones happens to be a fan
of this podcast, odds are they'd love something
from cufflinks.com as it has a plethora of DC
and Marvel men's fashion accessories such as
cufflinks, money clips, and ties. We've teamed
up with them this year again to get all of
our fans 20% off the entire site by using the
code dual 20 at checkout. I recently got their
new Batman Batmobile black man's tie. It's a
dark silk blend with pops of orange and light
blue Batmobile glyphs and Batman logos. It's
a slick design. I have a few other Batman ties
but this one is definitely my favorite and I
can't wait to wear it to the next business
conference I attend where I fully intend to
use it as a conversation starter. Go to cufflinks.com
Check out their Marvel and DC stuff or Star
Wars Harry Potter. They have it all and shop
for the holidays using dual 20 at checkout.
Thanks, guys. But now that we've got their
histories and abilities out of the way, let's
speculate on how one of the 1000 simulated
matches will go. The winner is determined by
simulations, not the speculation. But it's
fun to imagine how this fight could play out.
Alfred Jarvis, 9000. What are the rules of
our speculation? Well I should say there are
no rules, other than the characters have no
prior knowledge of the other going into the
fight. All they are aware of starting out is
that the other character is a threat that needs
to be eliminated. For the speculation, the
contestants will begin approximately 50 meters
apart, in a nondescript environment that will
have no bearing on the match itself, as no environmental
statistics are considered in my simulations.
The contestants must earn victory on their own
merit. Alright then, let's get into it! Enchantress
and Enchantress meet on the battlefield. Who
goes first? Enchantress. I think to just avoid
confusion, I'm going to refer to Marvel's Enchantress
as Amora for the purposes of the speculation,
so we don't get confused. OK, I still think
my Enchantress will go first because she's
just a little bit more crazy. And I think she's
going to start by hurling. a volley of green
fireballs that crash into Amora and set her
on fire. Boom! Magic Shield! Amora absorbs
the fireballs with her magic shield and then
she's gonna reshape that energy into magic
tendrils that shoot out and wrap around Enchantress's
arms and legs, just lifting her into midair
and binding her there. And then Amora's gonna
use a time spell. to age Enchantress centuries,
like just turning her into this dusty old skeleton.
Okay, that's fine. This dusty skeleton, her
eyes are gonna glow green and she's gonna just
like start cackling like an evil witch and
grow to be like four stories tall so that she
breaks free from her restraints. And then she's
gonna raise her arms up and summon this magical
dust storm with particulate that's gonna slice
into Amora. and prevent her from being able
to see anything as well. Okay, all right, so
to block this magic dust storm, Amora is going
to conjure up this magical mirror in front
of her that's gonna reflect the particulate
that's being directed at her back at Enchantress
tenfold, which is gonna knock Enchantress to
the ground and quells the storm. Then Amora
is gonna step into the mirror that she conjured
and the mirror vanishes with her inside of
it. Okay, uh, well the magic that bombarded
the giant skeleton Enchantress only empowered
her because it was her own magic. So that's
gonna blow away the oldness and reveal the
young normal-sized Enchantress who, you know,
she doesn't see Amora anywhere. So yeah, apparently
Amora has left the battlefield, so I guess Enchantress
wins. That's what she wants you to think. Suddenly
Enchantress, she turns around and sees a reflection
of herself. in this other magical mirror that
pops up next to her, and Enchantress just becomes
transfixed with her own reflection, like Narcissus
staring at the pool. Okay, I see what you're
doing here. Okay, Enchantress, she walks up
to the mirror, approaching her reflection apprehensively,
almost shyly at first, but then she and the
reflection starts to kiss gently, but soon...
Like before it even gets to that level of weirdness,
Enchantress, you know, paralyzed, we'll say,
by her own reflection. She gets blasted in
the face with a magic beam that shoots through
the mirror, shattering the mirror and revealing
Amora once again on the battlefield. OK. Enchantress,
you know, she's probably knocked to the ground.
In fact, actually, she falls into the ground
by turning herself intangible. And before Amora
even has time to wonder where Enchantress went,
this horde of like Netherworld spawn hands
just burst from the ground beneath her and pull
her down to the ground where they just tear
her apart. Okay, uh, I'm gonna say that as the
spawn pull Amora down into the ground, she's
gonna expel this like bewitching spell that
is gonna put all of these Netherworld spawn
in her thrall. So as she gets back to her feet,
you know, this entire army rises up from the
ground. just ready to kick some Enchantress
ass. Okay, but one of the spawn next to Amora
isn't really a spawn, it's actually Enchantress
in disguise, who is gonna generate this green
flaming dagger when Amora has her back turned
to her and Enchantress just stabs her from
behind. All right, well Amora is no stranger
to back shots, and she detects this attack
coming because her mystic senses see that one
of the spawn isn't under her control. So she's
going to expel her astral form from her body
just in time, thereby evading Enchantress's
magic blade. And in her astral form, she's going
to fly into Enchantress's body and cause the
Enchantress to just explode from within, leaving
behind just June Moon on the battlefield. And
then that's when Amora's spirit flies back into
her body, magically healing it in the process.
Okay, no way that works. If anything, I'm going
to say that with that act, Amora exercises
the succubus from June. But June is the only
thing stopping the succubus from essentially
taking over reality. So that's what the succubus
does. She reforms her body from this dark cloud,
and she's going to open this glowing green fissure.
beneath Amora from which this magical green
lava just explodes upward in like this super
volcano level blast that's just gonna incinerate
Amora completely. Match over. Oh well I guess
Amora's dead. Yep she's dead. Except Enchantress
sees her charred body. It's just an illusion.
And when Enchantress approaches the real Amora
just grabs her arm from out of nowhere and kissy
kiss smoochy smooch on her lips. Basically
confining Enchantress to a lifetime of servitude
to the Asgardian goddess. Okay, I mean, Enchantress
is shocked by this at first. But like as Amora's
kiss lingers, Enchantress feels complete in
a way that she never has before. And you know,
after- So you admit that Amora wins then. Damn
it. No. All right. We'll go ahead and leave
the match there. We'll say that either Enchantress
blows up Amora in the Super Volcano Magic Blast,
or Amora seduces Enchantress and turns her
into her eternal slave. We'll see which of these
scenarios happens by inputting the stats of
these characters and running 1000 simulations,
and then coming back with a winner. AJ9K, hit
it! Inputting data, running calculations, processing
results, simulations complete. Okay, this was
a struggle for me stats-wise because DC's Enchantress
is definitely not the physical specimen that
Marvel's Enchantress is, being that Marvel's
Enchantress is Asgardian. Right, yeah, you
know, just due to her natural physiology, Marvel's
Enchantress has increased strength, increased
durability that the Enchantress really doesn't
have. That being said, Enchantress, we said,
was a better fighter. than Marvel's Enchantress
because she's actually gone to blows with Superman
using her magical fists. Whereas Marvel's Enchantress,
I don't think I've seen ever throw a punch.
She usually prefers to have other people do
the fighting for her. That's kind of the nature
of her whole manipulation based magic. Right.
When it came down to things like movement speed,
evasiveness, perception, and even versatility,
you said that they were pretty much equal.
Yeah. You know, since they're both powerful
sorceresses. they can essentially almost do
anything due to the nature of their magic powers.
So taking all of the stats into consideration,
Joseph, who do you think came out on top in
this match? I'm gonna say Marvel's Enchantress,
just due to her Asgardian physiology. We didn't
run any polls on Instagram, but I think that
if we did run a poll, our Instagram followers
would have clearly shown a preference for Enchantress.
Oh, for sure. Yeah, definitely Enchantress.
Well, I have the results right here. Let's
find out who won. AJ9K, the results please.
Here you are, sir. The winner of the matchup
between Enchantress and Enchantress is Enchantress.
She totally stopped Enchantress winning 64.9%
of the 1000 matches. Enchantress, meanwhile,
only won 35.1%. I gotta say, I'm not too surprised
that Enchantress won. Um, I think I saw that
coming from the get-go, which, you know, depending
on your perspective, you're either thrilled
about or you think is a bummer. In the end,
Enchantress just had too much going for her
over Enchantress. I'm glad you agree! Actually,
no, I don't. I hate it, because it was Marvel's
Enchantress that won. Ha ha ha! I figured.
Uh, yeah, it was, I mean, it was the Asgardian
physiology that put her over the edge statistically,
right? Yeah, absolutely. Yeah. And while you
can say things like, you know, strength stat
doesn't matter to DC's Enchantress who can essentially
lift things through telekinesis, I mean, so
can Marvel's Enchantress, right? So when they
cancel each other out like that, you're just
left with things like physical stats to go off
of. And at the end of the day, Marvel's Enchantress
just outclasses her in that regard. I think
what really hurt DC's Enchantress was actually
June Moon, because when Enchantress is not tied
to her host, she's insanely powerful. She could
defeat the entire Justice League level power,
like Spectre level power. And I think in that
mode, she's definitely powerful enough to take
on Marvel's Enchantress. It's just that rarely
happens in the comics, especially as June gains
more and more control over the Succubus entity.
So you're lucky I counted for June in the stats.
You son of a bitch. Otherwise, Enchantress
would have won. Enchantress never would have
won. I agree. Yeah, I agree. Wait, what? All
right, guys, that does it for this duel. Let
us know what you thought about the results
by writing to us at dynamicduelpodcast.gmail.com
or by visiting us on Instagram or X. You can
find links to all of our accounts by checking
out our show notes or visiting our website
at dynamicduel.com. And on our site, you could
also find a link to our Patreon page. where
you can join our Dynamic Duo tier and chat with
us and fellow listeners, our Fantastic Four
tier, which gets you bonus content each month,
our X-Force tier that makes you an executive
producer of this podcast, or our newest tier
that lets you join our Dynamike podcast network.
If you can't join Patreon, you can still support
the show by signing up for our e-newsletter,
also at dynamicduel.com, so you'll never miss
an episode. And please don't forget guys to
visit our website to leave a donation for Pop
Culture Classroom, which will get you a digital
poster of our upcoming Charity Duel episode
in December. Alfred Pennyworth vs Edwin Jarvis.
Again, Marvel's beating you DC guys out so you
should go to dynamicduel.com, go to the store
and donate. Yeah, come on DC guys, let's pump
up our charitable giving stat. For our episode
next week, as we mentioned a few times, we will
be reviewing Loki Season 2. I have only watched
two episodes so far, but I'm going to finish
out the rest. I've been trying to avoid all
spoilers at all costs across the internet. And
so I need to watch it like immediately before
something truly tragic gets spoiled for me.
Yes, I've been seeing hints of stuff, but I'm
just like, no, get behind me, Satan. And just
like looking away. But that does it for this
episode, guys. We want to give a big thanks
to our executive producers. Ken Johnson, John
Sturowski, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Belcombe,
Mickey Mathengian, Brendan Estergard, Nathaniel
Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Nick Abonto, Austin Wazolowski,
AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Adam Spies, and
Andrew Schunk for helping make this podcast
possible. And we'll talk to you guys next week.
Up up and away, true believers.