This is a Dynamike Network podcast. Hey everyone,
Johnny DC here at the top of the episode. With
the approaching holiday season, we're officially
underway with this year's holiday charity drive
in lead up to our charity dual episode in December,
which is going to be Alfred Pennyworth versus
Edwin Jarvis. This year, all donations will
be going once again to Pop Culture Classroom,
a nonprofit organization. that delivers high
quality, all-inclusive educational resources
to school districts, teachers, and community
organizations using comics, graphic novels,
and related pop culture media. Their mission
is to inspire a love of learning, increase
literacy, celebrate diversity, and build community
through the tools of popular culture and the
power of self-expression. To donate, visit our
official store through dynamicduel.com where
you'll find two donation options. and one of
your team Marvel. Or go directly to dynamicduel.com
slash donate DC, one word, or dynamicduel.com
slash donate Marvel, which are linked in our
show notes. We're making the charity drive a
competitive duel this year, except the only
stat is which side can donate the most. Everyone
who donates will receive a digital poster featuring
original arts of Alfred and Jarvis drawn New
Yorker style by me. One lucky random donor
will win a framed print of the Alfred vs. Jarvis
art that we'll announce during that December
duel episode. Which fanbase will be the most
charitable? We'll keep everyone posted as to
which team is winning as donations come in during
these upcoming episodes. On with the show!
Hi and welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast,
a weekly show where we review superhero films
and debate the superiority between Marvel and
DC by comparing their characters in stat-based
battle simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe. And I'm
his twin brother, Johnny DC. And in this episode,
we are going to review the latest Marvel Studios
film to hit theaters, The Marvels. It was a
pretty, pretty good time, I thought. I liked
it. I liked the movie. I went in with no expectations.
I was still underwhelmed. That makes you a hater,
because everybody literally felt the same way
about the Flash movie and Blue Beetle, and if
you can't be fair to this movie when you gave
those movies like four and a half stars, that
makes you a piece of crap. Geez, you don't
gotta say it like it is, Marge. Yeah, just saying
it as it is. We'll talk about the movie later
on this episode. Before that, we're gonna break
down the latest comic book movie news to come
out this past week, including the news that
Deadpool 3... Captain America 4, Blade, Thunderbolts,
and Venom 3 have all gotten new release dates,
and we're going to talk about the first official
teaser for the Dead Boy Detectives television
show. As always, we list our segment times
in our episode description, so feel free to
check out the show notes if you want to skip
ahead to a particular topic. As our listeners
may know, our duel simulator is so advanced
that it's gained sentience, and has named itself
the Artificial Lifeform for running extensive
duels, just a rather very intelligent simulator.
9000 or Alfred Jarvis 9000. He has a quick
message for our listeners. So listen up. Why
hello there. Do you love listening and chatting
about Marvel and DC? Then become a part of the
dynamic dual community on Patreon, where you
can choose from three tiers. The dynamic 2-0
tier lets you listen to this podcast without
ads, and gives you access to its Discord chat
group, where you can chat with Johnny DC and
Marvelous Joe. The Fantastic Four tier gives
you that and more with two bonus episodes each
month, including bloopers and top ten shows
where Johnny and Joe count down your favourite
Marvel and DC subjects. The X-Force tier makes
you an executive producer of Dynamic Duel,
where every month you help the hosts choose
what to review and who to fight against each
other. And finally, the Dynamite Podcast Network
tier allows aspiring podcasters to create their
own battle-focused show using this Monte Carlo
simulator.
Thanks AJ9K, and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast. Be sure guys to tune into the
Max Destruction Podcast, which is part of the
Dynamike Podcast Network this Wednesday, tomorrow.
where hosts Ken and Dustin are going to pit
Bruce Lee against Ip Man as portrayed by Donnie
Yen. Also tune in to the Syndrome World podcast
this Thursday to find out who would win in
an anime battle between Grey Fullbuster from
Fairy Tail and Aokiji from One Piece. Visit
dynamicpodcast.com or click the link in our
show notes to listen to all the shows in the
Dynamite Podcast Network. But with that out
of the way, quick to the no prize! A no-prize
is an award Marvel used to give out to fans.
Our version, the Dynamic Dual No Prize, is
a digital award we post on Instagram and in
our email newsletter for the person that we
feel gave the best answer to our question of
the week. Last week's question we asked, which
not currently existing MCU character would you
like to see get their own mini-series under
the Marvel Spotlight banner and why? And this
is coming off of the news that the Echo television
series on Disney Plus will be under a new Marvel
Spotlight banner that focuses on stories that
are disconnected from the larger MCU narrative.
Got a lot of great answers, let's go ahead
and run down our honorable mentions as well
as the no prize winner. Our first honorable
mention goes to Rick McGrew, who said, Hey guys,
Rick from the Retro Nomopod. The character
I would choose for a Marvel character not in
the MCU currently that would get their own
series would be Mr. Sinister. He's been involved
in a lot of major events and kind of always
been in the shadows. and he was even mentioned
kind of in New Mutants the movie, but he'd
be my pick, Mr. Sinister. Yeah, that's a great
answer. Mr. Sinister is a major X-Men villain
and with the X-Men characters kind of up and
coming or soon to come into the MCU, I think
it'd be a great idea to kind of explore some
of these characters within the Marvel Spotlight
banner before introducing them as threats in
the X-Men movies. Yeah, we haven't done a dual
episode yet with Mr. Sinister and that's a shame.
Yeah, that is a crime. Seven years! And how
do you do that without Mr. Sinister matchup?
Weird! I don't know. Who would he go up against
though? That's not my problem. That's the executive
producer's problem. Hahaha! Great answer, Rick.
Our next honorable mention goes to... Travis
Herndon, who said... Hey guys, Travis here.
So my pick would have to be KZarr. I know he's
a D-list hero, but I feel like you can do an
interesting story following him. him introducing
the Savage lands into the MCU as well as introducing
other characters like Moon Boy and Devil Dinosaur
into the MCU. I feel like there's a lot of
potential with him in bringing in something
as crazy as the Savage land lands into the
MCU finally will be an interesting world building
experience. So yeah. Yeah, Kezar is a great
idea for Marvel Spotlight Banner, especially
since his stories take place in the Savage
land, which is all the way down in Antarctica.
And really like. When is the MCU ever going
to go down and explore Antarctica? The continent
is largely, you know, isolated, and so therefore
the stories of the savage land could also be
largely isolated. I think it's a fantastic
answer, especially since it's kind of a way
to incorporate these like Jurassic Park type
elements with like the dinosaurs and the jungle
and everything into the MCU, which we haven't
really seen before. Yeah, we really haven't
seen that anywhere outside of Jurassic Park.
And I actually know who would be a perfect duel
matchup for Kezar if we ever did that duel.
Commandee. Yeah. Oh, for sure. Yeah, that's
perfect. Maybe one day we'll get around to
that. Obviously, Mr. Sinister would be a priority
over Kezar, but Kezar is a cool character.
It would be cool to even pair him up in like
a team duel alongside Shanna the She-Devil.
You know what's crazy though is that Dustin
Balcom gave this exact same answer of Kezar.
So apparently, Kaiser has a lot of fans out
there. We need to capitalize on that soon with
a duel. I'm all for it. Let's do it. Great answer,
Travis and Dustin. Our final honorable mention
goes to Luke Tucker, who said, Hey guys, this
is Luke. And I would like to see a Sentry miniseries
under the Marvel Spotlight banner. I think with
the darker themes and more mature tone that
it's setting up, we could really go into the
backstory of Robert Reynolds as a meth addict
who finds the golden Sentry serum and becomes
a superhero. who's kind of like Marvel's answer
to Superman. I think with him rumored to appear
in the Thunderbolts movie, it'd be a perfect
time to do this. All right, thanks guys. Finally,
someone we have done a duel with, right? We
recently did a duel with the Sentry against
General Zod, which was a pretty good episode.
I think this is a fantastic answer. The rumor
is that the Sentry is going to be the primary
villain of the Thunderbolts movie, as Luke said,
but the Sentry... really has a great enough
story that deserves its own project outside
of just being, you know, relegated to villain
status in another film. I think the Sentry is
a phenomenal, if not a perfect candidate for
a Marvel Spotlight banner series. Yeah, the
answers we've received so far, I think this
one has the most likelihood of actually happening
considering the rumors that he's in Thunderbolts.
Right. Yeah, I think they would actually be
doing the character of the
a substantial amount of time to his story, apart
from the Thunderbolts story. Cause right, in
the Thunderbolts movie, you want to see more
of like the team dynamic, not necessarily the
villain, maybe I could be wrong, but yeah, I
think a century mini series would be fantastic.
So great answer, Luke. We want to give a quick
shout out to Andrew Shunk and Nate Mantineo
for also leaving your answers. Although Andrew
Shunk was like, Marvel sucks. Let's do a Marvel
spotlight show for a DC character cause Marvel
sucks. And uh, Yeah, great answer. That was
not a great answer. But the winner of this week's
Snow Prize is Colby Hentges, who said, hey,
boys, Colby Hentges, I'd like to see Marvel
Spotlight in part fix Marvel's villain problem.
Give me a backstory. Give me the motivation.
Give me the raison d'etre. That way, when they
show up on the big screen at the end of some
movie, everybody already knows what's up. I
want Marvel Spotlight to give me Victor Von
Doom. Hell yes, bro. This is the perfect answer,
right? Victor Von Doom, Dr. Doom, one of the
greatest, if not the greatest, Marvel villain
in all of Marvel history. Absolutely has yet
to be done justice on the big screen for one,
but also has a fascinating backstory on his
own that should be explored in a project separate
from a Fantastic Four movie. Kind of like how
the Loki television series, You know, Loki's
such a fascinating character. He got his own
show. I think Dr. Doom is definitely worthy
of getting his own show. Yeah, Dr. Doom, and
actually, I think a lot of MCU villains would
be good enough to get their own series, which
would help their villain problem. I think that
the villain for the film we're gonna review
later on in this episode, the Marvel's Darben,
yeah, give her own thing. That way we learn
a little bit more about the backstory and lead
up to this film. Darben was only like an eight.
issues of the comic book, so I don't know if
she even has enough backstory to explore in
her own television show. I dunno, make it a
Hollis series then, I don't care. Just more.
Yeah, yeah. A Kree series, yeah, that could
work. But it wouldn't work as well as Doctor
Doom. Doctor Doom needs to have his own Marvel
spotlight series, enough said. So great answer,
Colby, for winning this week's No Prize. If
you, the listener, want a shot at winning your
own No Prize, stay tuned to later on this episode
when we'll be asking another Question of the
Week. And now that that's done, on to the news!
Alright this past week the SAG-AFTRA strike
with the studios ended, actors are allowed
to go back to work, but due to the length of
the strike, both the writer strike and the
actor strike, we have some new release dates
to report. A lot of things got pushed back
and I'm not happy about it. Damn studios. But
um, the Deadpool movie was the first victim.
The movie was supposed to come out on May 3rd.
It was supposed to open up the summer movie
season in 2024. It's been pushed back to the
middle of summer and will now come out on July
26th. This was my most anticipated upcoming
Marvel movie, so to see it get pushed back
like this is heartbreaking because I'm really
impatient and I don't want to wait an additional
few months but you know, such is the life of
a comic book movie fan. Am I right? I mean,
not a DC fan, Superman Legacy kept its release
date. Well, good for you, that's still not
coming out until 2025 so I'm not even thinking
about that right now. The July 26th release
date was originally held by Captain America
Brave New World. That movie got pushed back
to 2025 on Valentine's Day, February 14th. Another
movie to get pushed back into 2025 is The Thunderbolts,
which was originally going to come out around
Christmas time on December 20th, 2024. That's
now going to come out in the middle of the summer
of the next year on July 25th. And the final
casualty for Marvel Studios is Blade. Seemingly
this movie is never gonna come out. I think
this is like the fifth or sixth delay that it's
received, but the movie was originally gonna
come out on Valentine's Day 2025, and is now
coming out at the end of the year on November
7th, 2025. So that's all horrible news. In addition
to Marvel Studios, Sony also had to push back
their release of Venom 3, which was originally
gonna come out July 12th, 2024. but got pushed
back to the end of the year on November 8th,
2024. A lot of bullcrap for, you know, something
that I feel like could have been solved simply,
you know. But that being said, I don't have
any skin in the game. I don't know what I'm
talking about. Yeah, no, you don't. I'm actually
surprised to hear that some of those release
dates were relatively soon. Like Venom three,
I don't know. They had planned on releasing
that next summer. Yeah, just a few months after,
you know, Deadpool three, which was the soonest
movie. that was gonna come out that got pushed
back. I don't know what is now gonna open the
summer movie season. I don't know if anything's
gonna take that May 3rd place. Something will,
obviously, but it would have been nice to have
Deadpool there. These delays are like all too
common now ever since the days of COVID. And
I guess even before that, you know, these things
get delayed all the time. It's just always
difficult to report on. It just means that I'm
gonna be that much older when I do finally
get around to seeing the movie, you know? Yeah,
you're gonna be like 40 Jeez, almost. I'm not
even thinking about 2025 right now. You know,
the days are long, the years are short. Hopefully
these movies will be with us before we know
it. I think the biggest downer regarding this
news is just that this phase bore of Marvel
that it's going through is just going to go
on longer. You know, like get to Secret Wars
already. Restart this shit. Why don't you shut
the hell up? We are no longer in phase four.
We are in phase five. You don't know what the
hell you're talking about. Phase five. More
like phase. I got nothing. More like phase
dive or die. The day is dying. That's better.
No, that no, that doesn't work. Dragon try
to get some other time. All right. I guess DC
did have one delay. Creature Commandos was
supposed to come out in 2024, but I guess that
may get pushed back to 2025. I'm not sure if
that's official yet, but that's the rumor. But
in other DC television news. We got to our
first official teaser for the Dead Boy Detectives,
which is going to premiere on Netflix. Originally,
this was a show that was going to be made for
Max. But since it was not within the vision
of James Gunn and Peter Safran's new DC universe,
they pushed it to Netflix and they're making
it a part of the same universe as the Sandman
series, because the Dead Boy Detectives. written
by Neil Gaiman and they first debuted within
the Sandman comic so it makes sense. I'm actually
happy that it's going to be in the same universe
as the Sandman because the Sandman was freaking
amazing. I loved that series. I can't wait for
season two and I think the Dead Boy Detectives
will be a good holdover until we get that second
season. Of course, if you've been watching
the Doom Patrol, you're very familiar with the
Dead Boy Detectives. They appeared in season
two of that show. And I actually really liked
the episode. I thought they did a really good
job of interpreting the dead boy detectives
for the screen. I was hoping that they were
gonna stick with the same cast of characters,
and that may have been the original plan, but
it looks like they went a different route for
this Netflix show. Yeah, I knew nothing about
the dead boy detectives prior to that episode
on Doom Patrol season two. I thought they were
actually really compelling characters watching
that episode. But after watching this trailer,
I think the opposite. trailer sucked. It definitely
had a vibe of its own that really didn't make
it feel like it was set in the same world as
Sandman. It still feels quite a bit like Doom
Patrol, and I feel like this may almost be like
a replacement for that show's wackiness now
that the Doom Patrol is coming to an end with
its fourth and final season. I can't say I
really care too much for the actors they chose
for Charles and Edwin this time, but again,
this is just a teaser. It's a short one. a minute
and 20 seconds long, so maybe I'm judging prematurely.
We'll see. I guess my major gripe is that on
Doom Patrol, the characters look like how they
do in the comic books, because I looked up what
they look like in the comic books. One's blonde,
one's brunette, they have very different vibes
going on. But literally, the actors who play
the dead boy detectives in this Netflix series
could be twins. They look so much alike in
their faces, and it throws me off. That's fair.
I actually thought the very same thing the
first time I saw this. I was like, wait, which
one is Charles? Which one is Edwin? They look
way too similar to be in the same fucking show
together. That's really bad casting. I also
didn't care for the casting of Crystal Palace
either. Maybe it was just because she said
that the name Dead Boy Detectives was stupid.
And I was like, fuck you. No, it's not. Obviously,
it's the coolest name ever. The entire premise
is right there in the title, just like something
like Robocop, you know? It's a great name. Exactly.
Right. Plus, I think it's bad form just to
do that in the teaser for the show, where you're
supposed to be getting people pumped up about
it. And the character within the series is like,
oh, yeah, this is dumb. Like, don't do that.
Yeah, it doesn't do a great job of actually
selling the show, right? Not at all. What does
do a good job of selling the show is sort of
seeing like the ghost aspects of the characters,
like when they run through walls and stuff like
that. That's gonna be interesting. And you
know, the premise that they're running from
death is also pretty interesting. Although
I wonder if they're gonna go with death from
Sandman in this series. If it's part of the
Sandman universe, they kind of need to. Right,
oh, that's a great question. Yeah, we know
that death was played by Kirby Halle-Baptiste
in the Sandman series. If they go with someone
else, then that likely means that this show
is not actually in the Sandman series continuity,
right? Right, exactly. We'll see who they go
with. They do mention during the teaser that
this is not only part of the Sandman universe,
but also brought to you from the producers
of You and The Flight Attendant, which are both
fantastic shows. So I think that bodes really
well for the series. Allegedly fantastic, I've
never seen either of them. They're good. I've
seen both of them, they're great. I don't know
if we're going to be reviewing the series.
We'll talk to the executive producers about
it, and we'll let you guys know, I guess, as
we get closer to the show's release date. Yeah,
we don't actually have a release date for the
series yet, but I'm guessing it's coming sometime
early 2024. But in regards to this show of
characters set within the Sandman universe,
that brings us to our question of the week.
What other characters from the Sandman Universe
do you hope get their own series on Netflix?
Record your answer at dynamicduel.com by clicking
on the red microphone button in the bottom
right hand corner of the screen, which will
prompt you to leave us a voicemail. Your message
could be up to 30 seconds long, and don't forget
to leave your name in case we include you on
the podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer
and award that person a Dynamic Duel No Prize
that we'll post to Instagram and our email newsletter.
Be sure to answer before… November 25th. This
question of the week is actually running a little
bit longer because there won't be a question
of the week in the next episode considering
Jonathan is traveling for work. Right. So November
25th, that's your cutoff date for this question.
That gives everyone plenty of time to read
all the Sandman comic books, which you should
have done already because they're fantastic
and come up with some character ideas.
But that does it for all the news for this episode,
so let's go ahead and move on to the main event,
where we review the latest Marvel Studios theatrical
release, The Marvels.
Alright, The Marvels came out this past week,
directed and co-written by Nia DaCosta and
starring Brie Larson, Teyana Paris, and Iman
Vellani. The film is a sequel to the 2019 film
Captain Marvel, also starring Brie Larson as
the titular character, but you could also say
The Marvels is a sequel to the Secret Invasion
Disney Plus television series, the WandaVision
series, and the Ms. Marvel series. This movie
follows up a lot of other stories, and if you're
asking if it's necessary to have seen all of
these shows before watching the film, I'm gonna
say, kind of. You could probably skip Secret
Invasion, but to really feel like you're not
just jumping into the middle of a story, it's
probably better to have seen the rest of the
shows. That being said, this review is a spoiler
review for the Marvels, but we'll probably
also be dropping plot points from everything
else that the movie follows. So here's your
spoiler warning for the other stuff too. Again,
Wandavision, Secret Invasion, and Ms. Marvel.
Yeah, you got a lot of homework if you haven't
been keeping up with the MCU recently. Yeah,
I'm not gonna say the movie is impossible to
follow if you haven't seen this other stuff,
but I think you'll actually get a lot more enjoyment
out of it if you do. Kind of like a lot of
Marvel's other stuff that's heavily steeped
in continuity, right? But the number of projects
that this film follows is kind of the film's
main downfall, is it not? Like, Totally, The
Marvels tries to be as cohesive as it can, but
you know, like the juvenile humorous world
of Ms. Marvel is much different than like the
scientific sort of odd background of Monica
Rambeau's story in WandaVision, which was different
than the kind of cosmic level adventures of
Captain Marvel. You know, I won't say that the
film fails in wrangling this all together in
one package. I actually think that Nia DaCosta
did an admirable job of compiling it all in
one tone. But in terms of story, editing, and
overall... pace, I'd say the film wasn't as
successful. And this is like exacerbated by
the fact that, you know, the story of the movie
involves these characters jumping around and
teleporting all over the place from one corner
of the galaxy to the other. So it really gives
you this whiplash feeling that never really
leaves. Like even later on in the movie, I blinked
and suddenly the Marvels were in some sort
of like wheat field planet talking in one moment
and in the next they're like across the universe
toward Earth. between the actual swapping of
the characters, the space jumping, like warp
points factoring heavily into the story, and
all the references to backstories that hopefully
people have seen, you know, the story can feel
like a lot to keep up with. And this is coming
from me, a guy who I think has a pretty good
handle on the MCU as a whole. I can't imagine
how people who come into this movie fresh will
react, you know, it can't be easy. Yeah, I
honestly was wondering as I was watching the
movie in the theater, how many audience members
had seen everything and if any of them were
lost. My wife certainly was, my daughters certainly
were. Well that's because you're raising a DC
household and you need to be exposing them
to more Marvel stuff, I think, for, you know,
their own health. They watched Loki with me,
they actually liked Loki. They watched WandaVision,
I believe, but it was so long ago that they
really didn't remember much about it. I think
the biggest detriment to the film in regards
to all of this was the editing moves at a breakneck
pace, way too fast, I think, for its own good.
You know, the movie has the shortest runtime
out of any Marvel Studios movie to date at
just one hour and 45 minutes. I think if you
clocked that up closer to two hours, you would
have had a much more cohesive, understandable
narrative that felt less bonkers. Yeah, I definitely
think there was a lot of room to explore a lot
of things that they really just brushed over.
Like... Kamala Khan's eagerness to save Skrulls
and the realization that her hero was, you
know, a real person, you know, despite all of
her power, couldn't save everyone. You know,
I think they really could have explored that
more. I think they really could have set up
the film's villain a little bit more, maybe
with even like a pre-title sequence to the
story showing what they alluded to later on
in the film of Captain Marvel destroying the
Supreme Intelligence and things like that. Yeah,
particularly when it came to The villain of
the movie, Darben, a lot of her actions and
motivations were explained in retrospect. Right?
We had no idea what was going on with the jump
points until the three Marvel's ladies figured
it out. We didn't know what was happening. We
didn't know why she was doing all this until
we learned about the current state of Hala and
how it got that way. You know, the movie just
didn't do any favors for itself in terms of
how it structured the narrative, how it edited
it, and the pacing. Honestly, this film is sort
of exactly what I feel like a lot of audience
members are tired of when it comes to MCU films.
It just feels like it's just too much to keep
up with and it's a jumbled mess. I think this
film is actually going to hurt Marvel down
the line in terms of, you know, are people going
to be interested in future MCU films or just
feel like there's just too much homework? It's
a valid concern. I don't think the movie is
going to hurt the overall brand because all
that being said regarding the film's messy
structure, I actually had a lot of fun with
the movie more so than other recent Marvel
films like Ant-Man Quantumania and Guardians
of the Galaxy 3, though I will definitely say
that Guardians 3 was a better movie. A more
somber movie that had some really sad moments,
but obviously still a better movie. The Marvels
was like a bubblegum sort of film whose only
concern was to deliver a fun time, right? And
in that regard, I think it succeeded. The action
choreography was top notch. We saw some of the
best camera work since the fight scene in the
first Doctor Strange movie that happened in
Hong Kong where everything was going backwards.
I think the stunt team had the work cut out
for them and the opening action scene where
it was going between the three ladies at the
Khan home, out in space, and on the Saber space
station is probably some of the coolest stuff
you'll ever see from Marvel Studios. The swapping
gimmick was a great way to present superhero
action in a new and interesting way. Although
I'm still confused how that was set up. So essentially
their powers became entangled because Captain
Marvel and Monika Rambeau We're near a jump
point at the same time. And Kamala Khan is
using one half of the quantum band that caused
all the chaos to begin with. Oh, I mean, that's
all bullshit. You know, the science reasoning
behind the swapping, I think, is one of the
flimsiest things about the film. OK, good. It's
not just me then. Right. Monika Rambeau rationalized
it as quantum entanglement, but they already
used quantum entanglement in the Ant-Man and
the Wasp movie. Right. And in that movie, it
was a way for Michelle Pfeiffer's Janet Van
Dyne character to communicate telepathically
through Scott Lang's character. But here, it's
a physical teleportation, so apparently quantum
entanglement can result in all sort of manner
of effects in the MCU. But you know, it's hard
to be nitpicky about that because the whole
nature of superheroes in general requires a
suspension of disbelief, and the end result
of the swapping itself is fun enough that you
don't really want to question it, even though
it all makes no sense. But again, you know,
that's kind of like another thing that just
adds to the sort of messy feel to the film,
right? One of the best things I could say about
the movie overall is that I walked out of the
movie theater more excited for the future of
the MCU than any movie since Spider-Man No Way
Home. And that's largely because of, you know,
how the movie ended, the end scene as well as
the mid-credit scene. Those scenes alone almost
raised this rating up a half a star because
they were fantastic. I loved how Ms. Marvel
was inspired by her team up and took the initiative
to start recruiting a Young Avengers team.
You know, we've been waiting for that for years
now, and it was cool to see that finally take
effect, especially since she did it the exact
same way that Nick Fury did in the first Iron
Man movie. Almost line for line, but with her
own comedic twist. I thought that was great.
Seeing beasts in his true form on screen for
the first time gives me so much hope. for the
future of the X-Men and how they are portrayed
on screen. It's going to be hopefully so comic
book accurate just based on the look of Hank
McCoy, voiced by Kelsey Grammer from X-Men
The Last Stand. Honestly, I... Get out of here.
Don't even start. What are you going to say?
I mean, we've already seen someone from the
X-Men universe in a Marvel movie, in the whole
Multiverse of Madness film. We've already seen
Hawkeye. I don't get like all the hype over
these scenes. I mean, it's like Big Whoop. It's
just more of the same. You're building to this
half for how long? And it's like, OK, now that
we get a little more so more, how about you
just flip the switch and do it already? They
got to build up, man. They're building anticipation.
Yeah, we've seen Professor X before. And it
was cool that he was in his yellow chair, but
largely Professor X manifested in an expected
way, you know, portrayed by Patrick Stewart.
But this version of Beast wasn't just like.
you know, Kelsey Grammer in horrible prosthetics,
like it was an X-Men The Last Stand or in X-Men
First Class with Nicholas Holt or in Days of
Future Past. Like all that shit was horrible
looking. Like this beast in this movie was
perfection. It was perfection. Are you really
that excited over an underlight? Yes. Holy
shit. Yes. All right. That's right. I am that
excited. It's going to be great. I can't wait.
I guess binary was cool. That was cool. Yeah,
it was cool that they included Binary here.
Binary being one of the many aliases that Carol
Danvers has used over the years. It was interesting
to see Maria Rambeau take over that role. And
you know, she was actually Captain Marvel herself
in the Multiverse of Madness movie. So there
apparently are like a lot of universes out
there where Maria was the one that took the
fighter jet and had the light speed engine
Cosmic Cube incident from... Captain Marvel
movie. But speaking of things that I enjoyed
about the movie, one of the things I most enjoyed
were the characters. So let's go ahead and
talk more about them in our character breakdown.
Starting with Captain Marvel, aka Carol Danvers,
played by Brie Larson. Brie Larson did her best
work as the character in this movie. She wasn't
annoying like she was in Avengers Endgame, and
she wasn't a robot like she was for most of
the first Captain Marvel movie. I feel like
the character finally got to shine and be herself.
in the Marvels, which I think is fantastic because,
well, I'll admit that Brie Larson isn't perfect
for the role, I am rooting for her as Carol
Danvers because I think there's potential there.
I do think there's potential. I don't think
this film was her best work. You know, I thought
she conveyed more emotion in some of her many
post-credits scenes, you know, when she's talking
to like Shang-Chi or something like that. Yeah.
If this is Captain Marvel being her true self,
then her true self is boring as fuck. You're
boring as fuck. You know what the fuck. Fuck
you're talking about. What are you talking about?
What do you mean boring? Dude, yeah, she was
like the least interesting character in the
whole damn movie. I disagree with that statement.
Obviously the villain was the least interesting
character. I mean, they were like the same.
I like how in the film she went from a guilt-ridden
loner to rediscovering her more. personable,
likeable side through this new sisterhood that
gets established. I think Monica and Kamala
helped her become this lighter character that
maybe we can see more of if Brie Larson returns
to the role. Not only did she grow emotionally,
I think, in this movie, I think the plot device
of having to swap places with less experienced
heroes and kind of keep her on the back foot
in that regard, it made her more vulnerable
and humble and more interesting of a character
because Captain Marvel was, you know, too overpowered
from the get-go. The swapping definitely helped
alleviate that. I also thought that as I was
watching it, because you're right, she's billed
as Marvel's most powerful character. She freaking
tanked a headbutt from freaking Thanos in Endgame,
right? So yeah, I thought this actually was
a smart way to sort of not degrade her power,
but make it so that she can't just solve everything
so easily. Right, exactly. Which, you know,
was kind of a criticism of the first Captain
Marvel movie is that once she unlocked the
full- potential of her powers, she was essentially
unstoppable, right? The way they chose to go
about fixing that worked really well in an exciting
way. I do think there are some things they
inserted in this movie to make Brie Larson more
interesting as Captain Marvel that didn't quite
work, specifically the whole fucking singing
planet. Yeah, my theory is that they were kind
of going for like a Disney princess angle with
planet Aladdin and her princess role on that
planet. You know, she even got like a dress
and everything like that. I do have to say
I really liked her costume in this movie more
than in the Captain Marvel film. I thought
it was really well done. I liked her dress too,
you know, the Captain Marvel take on the dress
worked really well. I think a lot of girls will
appreciate the fashion choices made in this
movie. But if we're talking about the musical
scene in general, I mean, it was a joke, right?
It was played for laughs more than anything
else, which felt unnecessary because of that.
I mean, if it was a joke, it was a joke that
went on for way too long. Not really. Come
on. It was like two minutes. And I was just
watching it. I was like, I looked at my wife
and I was like, what the fuck is this? You know
what's gonna be a joke that's gonna go on for
two hours? Joker Follyado. Oh shit, I can't
say anything, can I? That's right. Joker Follyado
is gonna be a musical in its entirety. So, but
it's gonna be a good one. Yeah, okay. Let's
go ahead and move on to Photon, AKA Monica Rambeau,
played by Teyona Paris. Now, I call her Photon
only because the movie never really settled
on a superhero name for her, which was kind
of frustrating. Like, Ms. Marvel even named
a few of her aliases from the comics that she's
had, including Spectrum and Pulsar. Of course,
Monica was the original female Captain Marvel,
but right now she's going by Photon in the comics,
which is my favorite name for her, and I wish
they would have brought that up in the film.
But Teyana Paris, I think she's a more than
capable actor. I think she did a good job of
selling like the deep seated resentment she
had toward Carol for not returning like she
said she would. I think Teyana did a great
job with the action. And I thought she had some
funny moments too. She's really good with her
line delivery. Yeah, I thought she was fantastic.
I have like nothing bad to say about her. It
was a great performance. I think she's definitely,
you know, Avengers caliber material for whenever
they make the next Avengers film. She hopefully
is on that team. Yeah, she has a great power
set for that team too. Although for like the
average viewer, I feel like her power set isn't
as well defined as I would like it. You know,
in the movie, she says that she can see light,
if I remember correctly. But I'm like, that's
not really it. Her power is that she can emit
and become and absorb any form of energy on
the electromagnetic spectrum. You know, from
X-rays to visible light, to electricity, to
ultraviolet and infrared light. You know, I
like to see the MCU actually explicitly state
her powers as that, because I think it would
help audiences understand the character more.
That's actually very true. I was really wondering,
like, what the differences were between her
and Carol Danvers, like laser powers, like
the scene where Carol is surprised that Monaco
is able to shoot a laser to like solve this
problem on the ship. I was like, well, can you
have done that? Like, why did you need her
help to do this at all? Yeah. And the last bit
where she sacrifices herself. I don't know
what the fuck happened there. She absorbed all
the energy from the quantum bands and the photonic
energy from Kenta Marvel in order to have enough
power to seal the rift. But I think you're
right in that they didn't explain that very
well. Like it was a bunch of scientific mumbo
jumbo on behalf of Monica Rambeau's part. I
don't envy the actress at all for all the science
flux capacitor shit she had to say in this movie.
I did love Monica Rambeau's outfit, though.
I thought she had the best one. Yeah, I mean,
essentially it was just a Saber space station.
uniform but yeah it looks really cool. The whites
and blacks just popped for some reason. Let's
go ahead and move on to Miss Marvel aka Kamala
Khan who was played by Iman Valani. I really
liked Iman Valani as Kamala Khan in the Miss
Marvel television series. I think that was
a fantastic debut for this up-and-coming actress
and I really liked her in this movie. You know
in many ways she was the heart of the film and
the glue that really brought the team together
in such you know an innocent way born out of
just the love and admiration she had for these
other women. Yeah, no, I agree. She was my favorite
part of the whole movie. Like to me, I think
she was the star. I assumed that she would get
a little bit grating based on her appearances
in the trailers, but I found myself not bothered
by that too much. Maybe there are a few moments
where she was a little bit overexcited, but
considering the circumstances, I think she
kind of played it true to what the character
would do. No, the actress is just so endearing.
My daughter, Grace, who's 12 years old, she
loved Miss Marvel. Yeah, that was hands down
her favorite. of the three. I think it was a
lot of people's favorite for sure. And she
had some great moments. I like the moment with
the revelation about Carol visiting Monica's
mom, Maria, after Monica was blipped. When Kamala
hugged Monica and then when Carol joined, it
was the turning point for the team. It's when
they became a team. It was cool to see that.
It was cool seeing her prove herself and achieve
her dream going from an obscure Jersey City
hero to a legit superhero. That was a lot of
fun. Yeah. I definitely think that she was
a good foil in a way for Captain Marvel in that
Captain Marvel is a pretty cold character,
at least the way Brie Larson plays her. And
Iman Villani definitely is not. You're right.
She just has this exuberance and innocence and
excitement about her that just makes people
like the character. I would say that Brie Larson's
semi-cold depiction of Carol Danvers is not
without basis in the comics. Carol Danvers in
the comics is fairly straightforward. AKA boring
AF. Some of my favorite moments with Ms. Marvel
dealt with her awkwardness. You know, like
how her vision of her going twinsies with Captain
Marvel didn't quite play out like she thought
it would. She just brought a lot of humor to
the film. Yeah, like when we reviewed Ms. Marvel,
the show, I think I mentioned during that review
that I liked that series way more than I thought
I would. And I was really glad to see that her
personality survived intact for this movie.
Although I got to say, her family didn't translate
quite as well in the movie as it did in the
show. I would agree with that, totally. Actually,
a lot of the side characters in this movie
felt like they were television extras, right?
Including Kamala Khan's family, including the
extras on the Saber space station. They just
felt out of place. Right. Yeah. Like, I still
don't get why Kamala's family had to even go
up to the space station. Well, their home was
destroyed. But you're right. That doesn't necessarily
mean they have to go to a space station. Like
go to a fucking hotel or something. Exactly.
You know? Yeah. And like, why didn't they get
eaten by cats when everyone else did? Like probably
people who are more important and necessary
to the critical function of the space station
and everything. That's a valid point. They
had special privileges, I guess. Regarding Miss
Marvel, though, a really interesting question
came up while I was watching the movie. So in
the Miss Marvel TV series, you and I theorized
that. The bangle that Ms. Marvel received that
unlocked her powers was a Kree Negaband, which
in the comics were the weapons worn by the original
Captain Mar-Vell. And we ended up not being
too far off because the bangle actually turned
out to be a quantum band. And the Negabands
were the Krees' attempt to recreate the quantum
bands in the comics, but the quantum bands
are worn by the hero Quasar. who has the power
of energy construct generation, similar to
Green Lantern, which is why we picked Quasar
in a duel against Green Lantern on this podcast.
But I'm wondering, is Ms. Marvel with her energy
construct generation powers, the MCU's version
of Quasar? I mean, I think she has to be right
now, right? Not only does she have Green Lantern
powers, she has the literal quantum bands. Although
I guess Carol had one of them at the end as
well. I'm not sure why. They were like friendship
bracelets now or something. Yeah, they never
really got into that. I guess they just assumed
it was better to keep the quantum band separate
from each other. But now I totally think of
Ms. Marvel as Quasar. Which like, how do you
feel about that? Not great. You know, I think
a lot of people had issues with the depiction
of Ms. Marvel's powers translating from the
comics to the screen. You know, in the comics,
Ms. Marvel is a polymorph. She can stretch.
But in the show, it's her energy construct
form that stretches, which is certainly easier
to render using special effects than showing
her physical body stretching. But having her
generate these sapphire looking constructs
isn't true to the comics, right? Neither is
her being quasar. At the end of the day, I
think the more true things are to the comics,
the Although I guess the one argument you can
make that she's not the MCU's Quasar is that
her powers aren't derived from the Quantum
Bands. That's true. I mean, they only unlocked
her powers, but in the MCU, Ms. Marvel is a
mutant. But that's another thing, you know,
because in the comics, Ms. Marvel is an inhuman.
So, I don't know. I don't know. It's all strange,
but it did fascinate me to think that we have
witnessed the MCU's first iteration of the character
of Quasar. Let's go ahead and move on to Supremor.
aka Darben, played by Zowie Ashton. I'll start
off by saying Zowie Ashton wasn't the total
trainwreck I thought she'd be based on the trailers
for this movie. She wasn't as goofy as I thought
she'd be, I think her character had legit motivations
for the destruction she caused and for her
hatred of Captain Marvel. I think honestly the
worst thing you could say about the character
is that she was generic AF. Yeah. But I partially
blame that on the fact that, like I said earlier,
the character of Darben was only in 8 issues
of the comics back in the early 90s. Like we're
talking bottom of the F-less barrel here. And
so there wasn't much characterization to build
off of from the source material. I don't really
understand why Marvel Studios would do that,
why they would make Darben the villain when
there were so many other Kree characters they
could have gone with. Yeah, for sure. Like bring
back Jude Law, go with Jai Min Han Su. Why
not? Well, Jai Min Han Su was killed in the
first Guardians movie as- I mean, bring back
Jude Law. As Yon-Rogg? Yeah. Although, you know,
they called the character of Darben Supremor
in this movie. That was like her title. I'm
wondering why they just couldn't make the villain
of the movie Supremor from the comics, you know,
who is an android personification of the supreme
intelligence and is really well known among
Marvel Comics fans as the de facto ruler of
the Kree. Supremor is a badass. Like, like,
I think a better scenario for this movie would
have been that the supreme intelligence actually
wasn't destroyed by Carol. and during the time
it took for it to reboot itself, you know, the
Kree have their civil war and the devastation,
and then once Supremor reboots and then tries
to restore Hala to its former glory. Like,
wouldn't that have been a better angle considering
they already did some setup for the Supreme
Intelligence in the first Captain Marvel movie
with Annette Benning playing the character?
Yeah, absolutely. I really like Supremor as
a villain in the comics. Darben is not Supremor.
One of these days we'll get Supremor in a dual
episode. Yeah, maybe we could put Supreme War
up against like Brother Eye or something like
that. Eradicator. I don't know. I don't know
anything about Supreme War. That could work.
I do have to say that I was really confused
by Darbin's use of the Ronin Hammer. Like it
glowed purple as if it was powered by the Infinity
Stone, but it wasn't. Yeah, that was kind of
a bad visual effects call, right? So Ronin's
hammer is called the ultimate weapon, as you
know from our Ronin the Accuser versus Big
Barda duel episode that we did. Right. I thought
it was interesting how she paired it with the
quantum bands. I think the fact that she had
the quantum bands in this movie was a great
way to foil the energy-based powers of the Marvel's
characters, because what the quantum bands
can do in the comics is tap into any power source
in the entire universe. So the fact that she
was absorbing all of their energy blasts with
the quantum band made her a great threat to
the heroes. Let's go ahead and move on to the
final character in our character breakdown,
Nick Fury, played by Samuel L. Jackson. As always,
Sam Jackson defines the character of Nick Fury,
he is Nick Fury, but this Nick Fury was far
more laid back in this movie than I thought
he'd be considering the events of Secret Invasion.
At the end of that show, he and his wife, Vara,
went up into the Saber space station to begin
negotiating peace talks between the Kree and
the Skrulls, but things were left semi-unresolved
at the end of that show, and you never get
that sense here. No, yeah, absolutely. Like,
I thought- that his wife would have been a
character in this movie as a Skrull since they
were dealing with Skrulls in this movie. But
nope. It really just goes to show that like
Kevin Feige isn't in control of everything
in the way that we thought he was, at least
not in this new multiversal saga. There's just
more and more evidence for it. It does seem
like he's taking a few more vacations than
he should be, right? Yeah, what the heck? Also,
like Nick Fury's guilt that he couldn't find
the Skrulls a home was such a central theme
of the Secret Invasion television show. And
yet, the Skrulls' refuge on the planet Tarnax
in this movie seems pretty good, right? Like,
couldn't that be the Skrulls' home? Why couldn't
that be their home? What was the story with
planet Tarnax? We'll never know. For real, like
that's what I was wondering during this movie.
Like, why did all of the Skrulls have to come
to Earth in Secret Invasion? Why couldn't they
go to that planet? Yeah, it's a great question.
But that does for all the characters. Let's
go ahead and move into the story highlights.
Hey guys, it's Marvelous Joe here to remind
everyone that the holidays are approaching,
and now is the time to start getting gifts for
the friends and family in your life. And if
you're gonna shop for something cool and meaningful,
you may as well do it at the best deal you
can, right? That's why Dynamic Duel has teamed
up again with cufflinks.com to get you 20%
off everything in the entire site using the
code DUELE20 at checkout. We've partnered with
cufflinks.com before because They're awesome.
You know, the best way to describe them is
like, take geek culture and then make it fashion.
They have a plethora of Marvel and DC men's
accessories to choose from that let you rep
your fandom and still look like a million bucks.
Take for instance, this Iron Man cuff bracelet
I got from the site. Honestly, I never even
knew what a cuff bracelet was before I got it.
I've never worn a bracelet in my life. But
if you go to the site using the link in our
show notes, you'll see how badass this Iron
Man cuff bracelet is. It's just like something
Tony Stark would wear. It has a black plated
gunmetal base with gold Iron Man helmet accents
on the ends. It has a super sleek modern design.
And now you pretty much won't catch me without
it. So go to cufflinks.com, check out their
Marvel and DC stuff, or you know, Star Wars,
Harry Potter, they have it all. And shop for
the holidays using code dual20 at checkout.
I promise you, it'll be the coolest site you
visit all season. Thanks guys! Alright, a group
of Kree soldiers led by Supreme-Or Darben discover
the missing Quantum Band on a barren planet
in space. Wondering where the other one is?
We see it on Kamala Khan, Ms. Marvel, who fantasizes
about meeting her hero, Captain Marvel. I thought
it was a great intro to the character of Ms.
Marvel. That little animated segment they had
with her did a great job of setting up the backstory
as well as establishing the type of character
she is. Yeah, I definitely think they did a
great job setting up Ms. Marvel. Definitely
better than they did setting up Mono Karambo
for anyone who hadn't seen Wandavision. But
again, I still think the whole beginning of
this movie should have been the scene of Captain
Marvel destroying the Supreme Intelligence.
Right, yeah. To provide that context for the
story as a whole. Because this whole time we'd
been wondering like what the heck is Captain
Marvel doing out in space? You know, like she's
never on Earth to help out and it turns out,
you know, she's going to singing planets and
she's fucking up shit on Hala. Apparently too
busy to reignite Apparently, what do you think
of that reasoning for Ms. Marvel's absence
in general? I thought it was super lame. I did
not care for it. I thought it was okay. I mean,
the fact that she had great reason to be angry
at the Supreme Intelligence and destroy it
and allegedly free the people of Hala and then
kind of be mopey about it when the entire planet
went into chaos is kind of a big deal. I think
it was kind of a satisfying answer. Yeah, but
she wasn't just being mopey about it. She was
going off and... you know, singing, being a
princess. She had to be doing more than just
being mopey. She should have gone back and,
you know, taking care of her niece. That's true,
which is, you know, the whole reason for Monica's
resentment. But you know, Captain Marvel is
imperfect. I think they established that. I
think it makes her a little bit more human.
When the jump point above Earth starts going
haywire near the Saber space station, Nick Fury
has sword agent Monica Rambeau investigate.
while he and Captain Marvel track the source
of the anomaly to the planet where Supreme
War found the lost Quantum Band. The two women
make contact with the Haywire Jump Point energy
simultaneously, which causes them and Ms. Marvel
all to swap places through teleportation. Now
I know we discussed the whole nature of the
swapping thing is kind of bullshit, but I also
have questions like if Ms. Marvel was included
in the three-way swap because it was the Quantum
Band energy that created and then disrupted
the Jump Point. Why wasn't Darben also included
in their swap circle? She had the other quantum
band. That's a great question. That's a fantastic
question. I'm kind of dissatisfied with the
reasoning behind the swap, even though I was
satisfied with the effect it had on the film's
action. The three women struggle to come to
terms with their predicament as a fight with
Kree soldiers ensues in space on the Saber
space station and in the Kahn family home. When
the fight is over and the three return to the
original places. Monika and Fury visit Ms. Marvel
to discuss Monika's theory on quantum entanglement,
which is causing them to switch places anytime
they use their powers simultaneously. I think
I mentioned before I love this action scene.
I actually really got into it. I liked seeing
how all three of them kicked ass in their own
unique ways, especially Ms. Marvel. I thought
it was exciting to see her really come into
her own as a warrior. Yeah, I definitely think
she had the most interesting power of the three
and I was always excited to see how she was
going to use it As Captain Marvel investigates
peace talks between the Kree and Skrull empires
near a Skrull refuge on planet Tarnax, she inadvertently
swaps places with Monica and Ms. Marvel. Convinced
the talks are a trap due to Captain Marvel's
presence, Darben generates a jump point anomaly
using her quantum band paired with the Universal
Weapon that creates a vacuum that sucks up
the planet's atmosphere and destroys the Skrull
refuge. The three women save as many Skrulls
as they can. arranging for them to live on New
Asgard, led by Valkyrie on Earth. This was
a surprise. I didn't know Valkyrie was going
to make a cameo. Yeah, between Valkyrie's cameo
and Hawkeye's, this is almost like an A-Force
film. Yeah, that's kind of true. Question though,
in Secret Invasion, weren't the Skrulls and
all alien species on Earth deemed hostile by
President Ritzen? Like New Asgard on Earth is
not going to be a safe place for the Skrulls.
Also, I want to know how New Asgard... got control
of the Bifrost teleportation energy. That's
right, wasn't it destroyed? The Bifrost was
destroyed. The only thing that can wield the
Bifrost now is Thor's hammer Stormbreaker, which
is actually currently being wielded by Thor's
daughter, which is still a stupid concept. Oh,
love? Ugh, I'd already forgotten about her.
Why'd you remind me? Maybe she's dead and Thor
gave Stormbreaker to New Asgard and they can
use it to teleport now. Damn. Captain Marvel,
Monika, and Ms. Marvel deduced that it was
Darben's rupturing of the jump points that led
to their quantum entanglement, and that the
jump point instability is endangering the universe,
and that Darben is creating the anomalies to
bring resources to the devastated Kree homeworld
of Hala. The Marvels use scroll memory probe
technology to find Darben's next target, and
they train using their abilities in conjunction
with their swapping predicament. I really liked
the training montage. I thought that was a
lot of fun. Yeah, yeah, I agree. It was well
done. It was cool. The jump rope thing, I thought
was pretty creative and funny. Yeah, the whole
training montage, I thought was sufficiently
girly for the audience. Yeah, girly and fun.
I liked it. The Marvels travel to the planet
Aladdin to warn them of Darben's imminent arrival.
And it's revealed that Captain Marvel is actually
the princess there. The three fight the Kree
forces in an attempt to steal the villains
quantum band. But Darben discovers that Miss
Marvel has the other quantum band. and creates
a jump point anomaly that siphons the planet's
water. We already talked about the musical
scene, it was meant to be a joke, but probably
an unnecessary one, they were just trying to
be cute. I did like the conversation between
Monika and Kamala Khan as this was all happening
and they're just kind of commenting on the ridiculousness
of it all. But my favorite joke in the whole
movie actually also happens during the scene
during the fight with Darben when the villain
sees that Kamala has the other Quantum Band
and she's like, where did you get that? And
Kamala was like, my grandma sent it to me in
the mail. And that was fantastic. That's good.
That's the kind of humor I like from Marvel
movies, not the freaking sing along. Yeah,
yeah. Which, again, I guess I can't really see
anything about because of Joker Folly. I do.
So scratch. I said that I love all the singing.
It's great. Captain Marvel, Ms. Marvel and
Monica escaped the Kree forces and Carol reveals
that she was the one who caused the devastation
on Hala when she destroyed the Supreme Intelligence.
She figures that Darben is also acting out
of revenge against her, destroying the places
she holds dear. They travel to Earth to discover
Darben is attempting to steal the energy from
the sun next. When we got the flashback scene
when Captain Marvel destroyed the Supreme Intelligence,
I was trying to figure out when she did that
chronologically within the MCU timeline. Like,
I think it had to have happened sometime after
the first Guardians of the Galaxy movie, right?
Because like the Kree didn't seem like they
were in shambles there. and they made the peace
treaty with Xandar and the Nova Corps. Yeah.
Or maybe they signed the treaty because the
planet was kind of going into shambles and
they didn't have adequate resources to fight
the Novo war anymore. But I do wonder maybe
it happened post Avengers Endgame. Who knows?
I don't know. It would have been nice for them
to answer that question, though. The whole MCU
timeline is messed up anyway. It's broken.
Ever since the first fight. I know it. You're
right. No one does. I know it. I know. Except
for this scene. I have no idea when this happened.
That's the only thing. Captain Marvel, Ms.
Marvel, and Monica fight Darben and subdue her,
but the villain manages to steal Kamala's quantum
band. Meanwhile, the unstable jump point near
Earth damages a majority of the Saber space
station's escape pods, forcing the station's
crew to escape to Earth's surface by being
swallowed by flurking kittens that were laid
by Goose. I loved the flurking kittens, you
know, they didn't have much to do with the story
overall, but they were cute and the way they
were incorporated into the plot made me laugh,
so there you I thought it was super effing
random. It was like super convenient as well.
I hated everything about that. You're just
a sad, bitter person, old man. Well, why? Because
I don't like flerkens because you don't like
cute things like kittens swallowing people alive.
That shit's funny. I wonder if a lot of people
are confused in that when flerkens eat things,
they actually store it within a pocket dimension
inside of them. Like each flerkin has a little
black hole in their body. They don't necessarily
ingest it. which is why Goose was able to bring
back the Cosmic Cube after she had swallowed
it in the first Captain Marvel movie. The only
thing I found really funny about the Flurkins
was when Goose was cleaning himself and Nick
Fury was like, hey, stop that. And Goose was
just staring at him evilly, like mid-lick. I
was like, yeah, that's a cat. That's my cat.
I like the Flurkin eggs. Just the concept of
a cat-like creature laying eggs I thought was
funny. My least favorite part of the whole movie
happens during the scene when the escape pod
carrying the Khan family and Nick Fury crashes
onto Earth after falling from fucking space.
It literally crashes into the planet and no
one was hurt. The water was right there. They
could have landed in the water. Right. So dumb.
I saw that and I was like, fucking Marvel.
Whatever. Shut up. After being mortally wounded,
Darben destroys herself. by using the two quantum
bands to open a rift in space to another reality.
Monica reasons that absorbing the energy from
Captain Marvel and the quantum bands will let
her seal the rift and she gets stranded in
the other reality despite Captain Marvel trying
to save her. Can I just say that I thought
it was a cool element that the quantum bands
were what created all the jump points throughout
the Marvel Cinematic Universe? Yeah, that was
really cool and totally makes sense because
Quasar is able to jump through space using the
quantum bands in a manner similar to the jump
points in the Marvel universe. The jump points
themselves were always this unique things that
made their first appearance in Guardians of
the Galaxy Vol. 2 but had no basis in the source
material. You know, they were just something
that was out there that they ran with in subsequent
spacefaring movies in the MCU. Right. But to
kind of get their origin now and kind of get
an explanation of what the hell these things
are. where they came from, I thought was pretty
neat. Yeah, honestly, that's probably like my
favorite element of the entire movie was just
that single line that solidified that in canon.
I was like, dope, that's cool. Yeah, I'm just
a fan of the quantum bands in general from the
comics, they're cool. It was kind of a bummer
that Darben got mortally wounded because we
didn't really get to see her do much with the
quantum bands, but you know, tearing the rift
in space and time is a pretty epic way to go
out. I do have a quick question. What was it
that removed the quantum entanglement exactly?
It was the fact that they got ahold of both
quantum bands, I think. Don't ask me how, you
know, I don't understand the whole swapping
thing anyway. All right. Now, it just, you
know, confirmed my theory that it was all bullshit.
Captain Marvel travels to Hala and reignites
its sun, restoring the planet to full habitability,
and Miss Marvel starts recruiting a young Avengers
team, starting with Kate Bishop. Were you as
upset as I was that Captain Marvel didn't think
to reignite Hala's son on her own? Well. Yeah,
it was kind of like a selfless idea on Monica
Rambeau's part that you would have hoped a hero
like Carol Danvers would have had on her own.
Yeah. It didn't take much effort at all. Like
she was perfectly fine afterward. Yeah, she
should have done it a long time ago. It was
cool to see Haley Steinfeld in this last scene.
Yeah, I think I mentioned during our Hawkeye
review, or maybe it was Ms. Marvel, that the
female Hawkeye and Ms. Marvel's personalities
were very similar to each other. So I was kind
of concerned about how that would play out.
in something like a Young Avengers film or
series. But seeing the two characters quipped
back and forth has actually done pretty well,
I thought. Yeah, I can't wait for them to announce
the Young Avengers project whenever they get
around to it. Maybe they won't show up until
the next Avengers movie, who knows. But I assume
that we'll get a few more scenes with Aman Valani
recruiting other young characters. Yeah, it
was during that scene that Kamala mentioned
that someone had a son or something like that.
I didn't hear who. Daughter. Oh, Ant-Man. Oh,
OK, cool. In the mid-credits scene, Monica
wakes up in the alternate reality she was trapped
in a hospital bed. Next to her is her mom Maria
Rambeau aka the superhero binary and Dr. Hank
McCoy aka Beast. Great way to end the movie.
I actually think that this end credit scene
alone is going to bring a lot of people to
the theater to see the film even though you
know the movie isn't projected to do all that
great financially. So many people are going
to get excited by this end credit scene. Actually
that scene has already leaked online. So I think
a lot of people are just bootlugging it on
Twitter. Well, shit. Everybody stay off the
damn internet until you see this movie. That's
my suggestion. And if you've listened to this
review, I'm assuming that you have seen the
movie. But that does it for the movie. Overall,
the film is a mixed bag. On one hand, it's
all over the place. On the other hand, it's
really enjoyable. In a sense, it follows a
number of Marvel films and TV series. The movie
is structurally messy, but it provides a fun
time with lots to get excited about for the
MCU's future. I'm rating the film three and
a half stars, a fresh rating on Rotten Tomatoes.
Yeah, I guess I would give this a fresh rating
as well, just barely. But I think it deserves
it. I would definitely recommend it for people
on the fence, whether or not they've seen any
of the prior television shows in lead up to
this movie. I definitely think it could have
and should have been better than it was. But
I still really like the characters, if not the
story. Yeah, the movie's passable, which, you
know, I'm OK with. I think it was fine. I think
three and a half stars is certainly a more
honest rating than what you gave for Blue Beetle
and The Flash. I think everybody should give
Jonathan shit for giving The Flash four and
a half stars and Blue Beetle four. Because
I don't think Blue Beetle was better than this
movie. I think Jonathan's bias is showing.
Alright, maybe The Flash should not have been
four and a half stars. I could see four stars
for that because I've seen it a few times recently.
And I think I gave it four and a half just
because I got to see Christopher Reeve with
Superman again. So yeah, call it like... Immediately
post review bias as time has passed. I do think
that's four stars. Blue Beetle's four stars,
too, though. Like Blue Beetle was better than
the Marvels. If you say so, bro, if you say
so, I do say so. But that does it for this review,
guys. Let us know what you thought about the
movie by writing to us at dynamic, dual podcast
at gmail.com or by or by visiting us on Instagram
or X. You can find links to all of our accounts
by checking out our show notes or visiting
our website at dynamic duel dot com. And on
our site, you can also find a link to our Patreon
page where you can join our dynamic two tier
and chat with us and fellow listeners. Our
fantastic four tier, which gets you bonus content
each month, our X force tier that makes you
an executive producer of this podcast or our
newest tier that lets you join our dynamic
podcast network. If you can't join Patreon,
you could still support the show. by signing
up for our e-newsletter also at dynamicduel.com
so you'll never miss an episode. Please don't
forget to also visit our website to leave a
donation for Pop Culture Classroom which will
get you a digital poster of our upcoming charity
duel episode in December, Alfred Pennyworth
versus Edwin Jarvis. Our next episode is going
to be a duel. I know that Loki season two has
had its season finale by this point, but we're
actually gonna kick that review back a week
because Jonathan will be traveling for work.
So next episode is going to be in lead up to
the upcoming team duel of the Legion of Doom
versus the Masters of Evil. Therefore we are
pitting Enchantress versus Enchantress. DC's
Enchantress versus Marvel's Enchantress. Yeah,
this will be the first time we're pitting two
characters with the same name against each
other. And Marvel's Enchantress kind of ties
into Loki season two, given that Enchantress
is also an Asgardian like Loki. Yeah, I'm looking
forward to it. But that does it for this episode.
We want to give a big thanks to our executive
producers, Kent Johnson, John Strausky, Zachary
Hepburn, Dustin Balcom, Miggy Mathen-Geehan,
Brandon Estregard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yeaton,
Nick Abato, Austin Wasielowski, AJ Dunkerley,
Scott Camacho, Adam Spies, and Andrew Schunk
for helping make this podcast possible. And
we'll talk to you guys next week. Up up and
away, true believers.