This is a Dynamike Network podcast.
Hi and welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast,
a weekly show where we review superhero films
and debate the superiority between Marvel and
DC by comparing their characters and stat-based
battle simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe. And I'm
his twin brother Johnny DC. And Happy New Year
everyone! Yeah, welcome to 2024! Yeah, and this
year Jonathan and I will have had this podcast
running for a total of 8 years. Holy shit. 8
years, people. We started this show in 2016.
And holy crap, it's been going on a while. Like,
if you honestly told me that there were enough
Marvel and DC characters to put in these many
duels and this many Marvel and DC related media
to review, I would have told you to go fuck
yourself. Geez. All right. It's kind of a dream
come true, right? For comic book fans, 2023
may go down in history as the year that comic
book fatigue finally set in. But honestly, I'm
still enjoying most films. Yeah. Who's not
fatigued? This guy right here. I'm pointing
to myself because 2023 had a lot of great stuff
come out for Marvel and DC. And in this episode,
our annual Brothers Awards episode, we will
award the best that the company has produced.
Yeah, this is the eighth annual Brothers Award
episode. Of course, we named it the Brothers
Awards off of the DC versus Marvel comic book
and mini series that came out in the mid 90s,
which depicted two cosmic entity twin brothers
that each represented both Marvel and DC. So
we figured that the name of the award was fitting.
Yeah, and we represented those cosmic entities
as little statues that we award these films.
You could check out the images of these awards
on our Instagram. Little statues? I've always
imagined them as being like pretty big fucking
statues, dude. I thought they were like Oscar
sized, you know? No, no, we're thinking like
Statue of Liberty, bro. All right. Before we
get into our awards, we're going to break down
the latest comic book movie news that came
out this past week, of which there was none.
Partially because Jonathan and I are recording
this episode early, but also because, you know,
we're like in a dead zone in terms of movie
news. Yeah, it's pretty quiet during the holidays.
But, we do have a No Prize to award and a new
question of the week for you guys. As always,
we list our segment times in our episode description,
so feel free to check out the show notes if
you want to skip ahead to a particular topic.
Our artificially intelligent dual simulator
AJ9K has a quick message for our listeners
though, so listen up. Why hello there. Do you
love listening and chatting about Marvel and
DC? Then become a part of the dynamic dual community
on Patreon, where you can choose from three
tiers. The dynamic two-o tier lets you listen
to this podcast without ads and gives you access
to its discord chat group, where you can chat
with Johnny DC and Marvelous Joe. The Fantastic
Four tier gives you that and more with two bonus
episodes each month, including bloopers and
top ten shows where Johnny and Joe count down
your favourite Marvel and DC subjects. The
X-Force tier makes you an executive producer
of Dynamic Duel, where every month you help
the hosts choose what to review and who to fight
against each other. And finally, the Dynamite
Podcast Network tier allows aspiring podcasters
to create their own battle-focused show using
this Monte Carlo simulator.
Thanks AJ9K, and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast. Be sure to tune in to the Max
Destruction Podcast, which is part of the Dynamike
Podcast Network. which is currently on hiatus
for the holidays but will return soon with more
of your favorite action movie hero fights.
The Centro World podcast is a show that speculates
on fights between your favorite anime characters.
This week, host Zachary Hepburn will find out
who will win between Guts from Berserk against
Claire from Claymore. And the newest show in
the Dynamite Podcast Network, Console Combat,
hosts John and Dean find out who would win in
fights between your favorite video game characters.
In yesterday's episode... They speculated on
who would win between Joker from the Batman
Arkham games and Revolver Ocelot from the Metal
Gear games. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or click
on the link in our show notes to listen to all
of the shows in the Dynamike Podcast Network.
But with that out of the way, quick to the no
prize. A no prize is an award Marvel used to
give out to fans. Our version, the dynamic dual
no prize is a digital award we post on Instagram
and in our email newsletter. for the person
that we feel gave the best answer to our question
of the week. In last week's question, we asked,
which actor would you choose to recast Kang
in the MCU and why? Of course, that was coming
up with the news that Jonathan Majors was fired
as King of the Conqueror from Marvel. We got
three answers here. So, you know, two honorable
mentions and one no prize winner. Let's go ahead
and run them down. Our first honorable mention
goes to Chumnu, who said, Hello, if I could
recast Kang, I would probably recast. Busta
Rhymes because you know, he can portray like
a, what's it called, like a menacing type of
demeanor. And I just feel like he would fit
the role, you know, because Kang is very menacing
himself. So thank you for your time. Thank you
for listening. So Cham Ngu gave the answer
of Busta Rhymes. Honestly, I've only ever seen
Busta Rhymes in one movie and that was Halloween
Resurrection. And he was Fucking horrible in
that movie. This is a horrible answer. Everyone
knows that if you're gonna hire a rapper to
play King of the Conqueror, it's either gotta
be Ice Cube or Ice T. One of the ice guys. Not
vanilla ice. Fuck that guy. But I think Ice
T could pull it off. He kinda has a cool demeanor.
He's a little up there in age. So is Cube though.
They're all getting older. It's so sad. Or,
or, hear me out. You hire Coolio? And it turns
out that his character from the director's cut
of Daredevil was also Kang. He was a Kang variant.
Coolio's dead, bro. Oh no! Really? Yes! I didn't
know that! Dude. Whoops. I mean, we have AI
now. It's fine. You may as well said Tupac or
something. Jesus. Oh, fuck you. I know he's
dead. Anyway, let's go to move on to our next
honorable mention after that poor showing from
Jonathan here. Our next honorable mention goes
to Andrew Shunk, who said, Hey guys, Andrew
Shunk here. I would cast Christopher Judge for
Kang. So this is kind of a very dark horse,
but he's from the Stargate SG-1 series. He's
also the voice of Kratos from the God of War
series. I think it's something where he could
pull it off. Yeah, Christopher Judge had a
prominent role in the Stargate SG-1 series.
He's one of the other dimensional tough guys,
basically. I don't know. I never watched the
show, but I know of the character. He's kind
of like a interesting looking face. Yeah, he
was in The Dark Knight Rises, although it was
a very minor role. He was like assassin number
three or something like that. Interesting.
But I would say that he has an interesting look.
I guess he's a decent actor. I never really
watched the Stargate TV series. Yeah. But I
wonder if he's maybe not a big enough name
for Kang, someone who, you know, the MCU is
hindering their entire multiverse saga on.
I don't know. I mean, he has fan cred, I would
guess. But I just don't think he's that great
of an actor, though far be it for me to judge
anybody on a show that I have not seen. So
who knows? Did you know that Jason Momoa was
on one of the Star Gate shows? I did know that.
Yeah. He's on Stargate Atlantis. A precursor
of things to come. So great answer Andrew Shunk,
but the winner of this week's no prize is Travis
Herndon, who said, Hey guys, Travis here. So
my pick would have to be Chuck Woody Wooji.
I think he did an amazing job in Guardians
3 and I think he could pull off being Kang.
Now I know he's already played high evolutionary
before, but you can easily have it and not only
he stood the new variant, but you can even
have it at Kang. Kang was a different Kang variant
that just took a different path compared to
the other versions of Kang. So that's my pick.
Honestly, I don't love any of these answers,
but I do have to say that Chuck Woody Iwuji
is the best actor out of the bunch. That's
true. Yeah, that's why Travis Herndon wins this
award. Yeah, I didn't love any of the answers
either, but they were in fact answers. And yeah,
Chudwuki is really solid as he proved in the
Peacemaker television show and in Guardians
of the Galaxy Vol. 3. With the nature of the
multiverse, you can literally cast anybody and
say that they're just a variant. So, that's
why I don't hate this answer. But also, it would
be weird for the high evolutionary to be a
variant of Kang, I feel. Who knows, it may just
have been a variant who wasn't interested in
time, but more interested in biology. They can
make it work if they needed to. You know, rumors
are that Mads Mikkelsen, who played Kasellius
in the Doctor Strange movie, is being courted
for the role of Victor Von Doom. I also hate
that. Well the idea there, according to fan
theories, is that they would actually retcon
the character of Casselius so that it was an
alias for Victor Von Doom as he was studying
to be a sorcerer. You know, in the comics Victor
was learning magic as a way to circumvent death,
which is exactly what Casselius' motivations
were in Doctor Strange. And you know, he already
has the fucked up face because of what the
Dark Dimensions forces did to it, so it could
work. I take it back. that's actually kind
of brilliant. I don't hate it, honestly. Well,
if you had to recast Kang, who would you cast?
Well, I think the correct answer here was John
Boyega, who played Finn in the Star Wars sequel
trilogy. The guy who was done dirty in the Star
Wars franchise, and I think he deserves some
redemption in the Marvel universe. He has gone
on Twitter saying he's not interested in the
role, but I think for the right price, anybody
would be interested. Seriously, if I was coming
to Feige, I'd be like, what's the number? Just
tell me the number. Write it down, write it
down. I'll add a zero. As in I'll add a plus
sign and then zero. Geez, final offer. Anyway,
thanks to everyone who called in this week,
guys. Congrats to Travis Herndon for winning
this week's No Prize. If you the listener want
a shot at winning your own No Prize, stay tuned
to later on this episode when we'll be asking
another Question of the Week. And now that
that's done, on to the Question of the Week.
So now that Aquaman and The Last Kingdom has
been released, the DCEU has come to an end.
And we want to know, now that it's finished,
what would you say are the top three DCEU films
and why? Record your answer at dynamicduel.com
by clicking on the red microphone button in
the bottom right hand corner of the screen which
will prompt you to leave us a voicemail. Your
message could be up to 30 seconds long, and
don't forget to leave your name in case we
include you on the podcast. We'll pick our favorite
answer... and award that person a Dynamic Duel
No Prize that we'll post to Instagram and our
email newsletter. Be sure to answer before
January 6th.
But I think now we're ready to move on to the
main event of this episode, where we award
the best that has come out from Marvel in DC
in the year 2023. We're going to go ahead and
roll out the red and blue striped carpet. We're
going to get in our tuxes. Let's go ahead and
move into the 2023 Brothers Awards.
With all of the guests have made their way into
the auditorium where we're presenting the awards
of which there are 10 categories. Best trailer,
best original music, best new on-screen character,
best villain, best hero, best moment, best actress
and best actor, best series or special, and
finally best picture. There was so much media
to pour over for Marvel and DC both on the
small screen and the big screen. When it came
to Marvel specifically, the media that was
eligible that was released in 2023 are Ants
Man and the Wasp Quantumania, Guardians of
the Galaxy Vol. 3, Spider-Man Across the Spider-Verse,
Secret Invasion Season 1, Loki Season 2, The
Marvels, and What If Season 2.
Harley Quinn, a very problematic Valentine's
Day special, Legion of Superheroes, Shazam!
Fury of the Gods, Batman! The Doom that came
to Gotham, Titans Season 4, The Flash, Justice
League Warworld, Blue Beetle, My Adventures
with Superman Season 1, Harley Quinn Season
4, Doom Patrol Season 4, Merry Little Batman,
and Aquaman and the Lost Kingdom. Holy shit!
It's a lot. A spoiler warning, if you haven't
seen any of these movies or shows from the
past year, there is the potential that we will
spoil something for the nominees this episode.
Yeah, DC had way too much stuff come out this
year, like almost double the amount of Marvel's
projects. It was just too much because no one
cares about DC. Are we gonna have to throw
down on this stage? Is that what's gonna happen?
It depends on what I think of your words. But
let's go ahead and hear them, starting with
our first category. best trailer. Trailers
exist to get us excited for upcoming films and
television series. They are marketing material
that show us the tone and tease the story. If
they're done right, which they often are when
it comes to Marvel and DC projects, it gets
us fans all aboard the hype train. Yeah, these
trailers not only got fans boarded upon the
hype train, they also smashed barriers of doubt
and uncertainty to make everyone super excited.
At least until the films came out. Yeah, sometimes
the trailer is actually better than a movie.
Very true. But let me list the nominees for
best DC trailer this year. The nominees are
Aquaman and the Lost Kingdom official trailer.
If you lead, the Seven Kingdoms will follow.
Blue Beetle official trailer.
choice
The Flash official trailer 2. You wanna get
nuts? Let's get nuts.
Shazam! Fury of the Gods official trailer 2
It's a great list. I'm going to guess that your
ward is going to the Flash. The Akuma trailer
was also pretty good, but we got it so late
in the game that it was kind of lacking in
that aspect. But the Flash, I think, actually
got us really excited at the time it came out
because it gave us the best look into what looked
like a really exciting riff on the Flashpoint
story. And the winner is the Flash official
trailer 2. Called it. You guessed right. That
flash trailer, I mean, all of the trailers for
the flash were amazing, but that one specifically
got me super pumped because I had so many great
moments within it. It felt very Snyder in a
way to me, in a way that I tried to capture
emotion and just this awesome spectacle because
the visuals were pretty incredible. The score
was sweeping and heartfelt. And you can't top
the nostalgia factor of hearing Michael Keaton's
Bruce Wayne say, you want to get nuts? OK.
Let's get nuts. And the trailer was nuts. I
really like the shot where it was the two flashes
and Supergirl like coming at the camera as the
backdrop was like zooming out, you know. Yeah,
that was a neat effect. I also really like the
shot where Michael Keaton's Batman ejects from
the Batplane as it's like exploding in the air.
There was just a lot of exciting things to
get thrilled over. Yeah, yeah. There's also
the shot at the very end that closed out the
trailer where we see Batman diving through the
night sky. And the Batplane is in the distance
against the moon. What a beautiful shot. I was
so good. I was so unbelievably pumped for this
movie. For sure. Yeah, I mean, I think this
is maybe one of the instances where the trailer
actually was better than the movie, but you
know, a lot of people had a lot of different
feelings on the flash. Let's go to move on to
the Marvel best trailer. You're right, hold
on. Let's strike one. You had salt DC two more
times. We are throwing down on this stage.
I've been salted DC like 10 times already this
episode. Strike one. All right. I won't stand
for it.
one thing. What's that... time? Echo official
trailer You have so much pain in you
Someone's rage. Guardians of the Galaxy Vol.
3, new trailer.
ride.
The Marvels teaser trailer.
team. Oh no we're not a team.
I'm trying to think of which of those trailers
got me most pumped to see the show. I think
the Echo trailer is pretty intriguing in that
it's so very different from anything else that
we've received from the MCU television series
wise. But I think even more so than that, the
trailer that got me most excited to see a Marvel
film was Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 3. So
that's my guess. And the winner is... Echo.
official trailer. I mean, did I say Guardians
of the Galaxy? I'd gone with my first pick.
I said Echo. Ant-Man and the Wasp, Quantumania,
and Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 3 all had great
marketing ahead of those releases, but a lot
of it was kind of to be expected. We knew that
they were going to be fun, special effects
driven films, largely sticking to Marvel's brand.
I will say that the Marvel's teaser trailer
actually got me really excited for that movie,
and that was an instance where maybe the trailer
actually was better than the movie. Even more
than all of those other ones, Echo got me super
hyped because I was not looking forward to Echo
at all. And when that trailer came out and
we saw how brutal everything is, where we see
people like straight up shoot each other in
the face and you know, Kingpin beats a man to
death by punching him in the face. It was a
massive signal to fans that the brutality that
we were used to from the Netflix shows, specifically
the Daredevil Netflix show was returning. And
that is all the news I ever needed to hear.
Yeah, and thank goodness, holy cow, because
I was worried for a second when it came to
shows like Hawkeye and She-Hulk and what they
did with the Netflix characters. I'm really
glad to see that Marvel Studios is making a
course correction. Yeah, and the Echo show
comes out soon here, we'll be reviewing it in
just a few weeks. I'm looking forward to it,
mostly because of this trailer specifically.
Let's go ahead and move on to our next award,
which is Best Original Music. Now, this award
goes to the movie or show that had the best
overall musical original score. Music is a huge
factor in the quality of these films and television
shows. A great score can make a great movie
even greater, but it can even make a mediocre
movie even greater. And I feel like that's the
case for quite a few films. for Marvel and
DC this year. Yeah, given that both companies
had some mediocre films, but awesome scores
across the board. Let me run down the list of
my nominees for DC's Best Original Music. The
nominees are, Aquaman and The Lost Kingdom.
Blue Beetle.
The Flash.
Merry little Batman.
Those all had great scores. Merry Little Batman
was a very unique score. But I think you're
going to give the award to the Flash primarily
because of how it was able to incorporate so
many different themes from other DC heroes across
the decades, from the 1989 Batman to even Christopher
Reeve Superman. And the winner is. Blue Beetle.
So you are wrong. Largely because I was really
focusing on originality for this award. We had
recently heard Denny Elfman's Batman in the
Joss Whedon version of Justice League when that
came out in theaters. So it wasn't as exciting
or as nostalgic I think this time around. Unfortunately
I did really like the Flash score and I almost
gave it the award. But I decided ultimately
to go with Blue Beetle because it was a score
unlike anything we have heard before. And I
may be a little bit biased because of my Latin
heritage, but there was just something about
the music that I thought was incredibly moving
and touching and nostalgic. Not only that, but
I also really liked the music in the movie
that wasn't original. There were some timeless
mariachi classics like Sinti and Sabor a mi
from Los Panchos that just made the movie even
more moving for me. Yeah, I would describe
the Blue Beetle score as mostly electronic with
some like Latin Beats, some industrial stuff
a little bit too. It wasn't like a super sleek
score. It kind of had some heaviness to it,
you know? And it was also semi nostalgic in
that it kind of invoked 90s vibes with like
its synthetic electronic score, like you mentioned.
So yeah, I thought it was definitely the best
score of the year and a year with a lot of great
scores. Yeah, same goes for Marvel. Let me
go ahead and run down the nominees for best
Marvel original music. The nominees are Ant-Man
and the Wasp, Quantum Mania.
Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 3
Loki Season 2
Spider-Man across the Spider-Verse.
I'm going to go with Guardians of the Galaxy
only because I feel like James Gunn does a
really good job with music. Now of course he's
not the composer for that film, but I also
remember the music just being really moving
in that film in general. And the winner is
Loki Season 2. Well that of course was going
to be my second guess because I also really
like the music in Loki. I'm surprised your second
guess was in Spider-Man Across the Spider-Verse
because that movie nearly got this award. With
all the incredible music that was in that movie
between Gwen Stacy's drumming and visiting Spider-Man
India's world and Miles Morales' Latin feeling
theme, there was a lot to really like in the
Across the Spider-Verse soundtrack. However,
I'm kind of punting that award to maybe the
next movie in that franchise, Beyond the Spider-Verse,
and hopefully, you know, the score is equally
as good there. But for now, I want to give
the award to Loki Season 2. largely because
I think Natalie Holt did excellent work on
both seasons of this television series. You
know, for Loki season 1, that almost got the
music award too, but I ended up giving it to
WandaVision just because of the varied nature
of all the television themes that I thought
were done really well in that show. But Natalie
Holt's Loki score is so moving, so beautiful,
and very, very unique among the superhero genre.
With these really... ethereal synths and Nordic
feeling orchestral movements. It's just all
so well done. But I just remember one of the
things that moved me so much in the final episode
was the music. I think that music closed out
the show perfectly. I remember when Loki season
one came out, I had chosen that as my pick for
what I thought was going to get the Brothers
Award for Best Music that year. Like you said,
it didn't. So I'm really glad that it's winning
this year because it definitely deserves it.
The Loki score does a better job than I would
say most. comic book properties of setting the
tone. Absolutely. Let's go to move on to our
next award, which is best new on screen character.
Yeah, like we mentioned earlier on in the podcast,
if you had told us that comic book movies would
still be going strong for the most part, eight
years into this podcast, I would not have believed
you. The fact that we're still getting new
characters on screen is just a dream come true
for any comic book fan. Now, a lot of these
characters we've known and loved from the comics
for decades, but the fact that people are getting
to experience them for the first time on screen
is one of the true joys of being a fan. For
sure. Seeing new characters represented in live
action or animation is one of the most exciting
things about being a fan of the source material.
We had quite a few new characters for DC this
year, so let's find out who's the best. The
nominees are Blue Beetle from Blue Beetle.
Kordax from Aquaman and the Lost Kingdom.
Space Case from Doom Patrol Season 4.
Supergirl from The Flash.
Obviously this has got to go to Blue Beetle.
It's not even a question. I mean, all great
characters, but yeah. My guess is Blue Beetle.
Oh, you're so sure of yourself, huh? Yep. The
winner is... Blue Beetle from Blue Beetle. Of
course. Yeah, no, this one is probably a giveaway
because the character was just so unbelievably
well realized on screen. Of course, it also
doesn't hurt that of the nominees, he was the
only starring character. Yeah, Kordax and Space
Case had really minor roles, so did Supergirl
to a slightly lesser extent. But yeah, Blue
Beetle is probably one of the characters that
we never expected to actually get a movie despite
how cool he was. And to see him finally on the
screen and realize actually so well from the
comics. was a great feeling. I don't know if
I never expected it, but I definitely always
wanted it because I always thought the character
had the potential to be as popular as Spider-Man
because he is essentially in some regards DC's
Spider-Man. He just has a really cool look
about him. He's just a really cool character
with really cool powers. And it was great again
to see that realized on the big screen. Well,
there are a few new characters on Marvel side
as well. So let me go ahead and run down those
nominations. The nominees are High Evolutionary.
from Guardians of the Galaxy, Volume 3.
Lahori from What If Season 2.
Kang the Conqueror from Ant-Man and the Wasp,
Quantumania.
Spider-Man 2099 from Spider-Man Across the Spider-Verse.
Okay, I haven't finished What If Season 2 yet,
so I have no idea who that is, but I'm gonna
say that you went with Spider-Man 2099, because
I think they did a really good job adapting
that character. And the winner is... Kang the
Conqueror from Ant-Man and the Wasp Quantumania.
Gosh dang it! You're 0 for 3 so far. Some people
may say that Spider-Man 2099 is not a new on-screen
character because he made an appearance in the
Into the Spider-Verse movie, the first film
in that franchise. But it was an after credits
thing, so I don't think it was really a proper
introduction. I still consider him a new on-screen
character for Across the Spider-Verse. And
also, I don't actually think that was a solid
adaptation of the character from the comic
books. He was actually very different. Well,
I thought they improved upon him, honestly.
I- don't agree with that either. They did. They
did. Okay. He was a cool character, just a
slightly different version. But, Kang the Conqueror,
played by Jonathan Majors, and like this is
obviously going to be awkward awarding it given
that Jonathan Majors is no longer playing the
character. But, I thought he did fantastic in
the role. I thought Kang proved to be a great
threat for Ant-Man and the Wasp. And as a fan
of the character from the comics, I really
like this take on the character. Well, no, I,
you know. He would have been my choice if it
were not for the controversy surrounding the
character and sort of the bitter sweetness
that he's not returning to the role. Yeah, I
could totally see that. I do want to give a
shout out to Kihori from What If Season 2. She
is an original character that was introduced
in that season to Marvel, and what a great way
to kick off a character's origin. Let's go
ahead and move on to our next award, which is
Best Villain. Of course, the hero is only as
good as his villain. And if a movie or show
doesn't have an adequate enough threat, then
it's kind of a letdown, right? Villains can
really make or break a film. And these are
the best villains that appeared in 2023 that
we feel pose the greatest threat to our heroes.
Right. And of course, being a great hero means
overcoming great threats. You can't do that
if you have a crappy villain who should be menacing,
cunning and powerful. Yeah, that's a great
recipe to put heroes through the wringer. I'm
excited to hear who the best DC villains of
2023 are. The nominees are Black Manta from
Aquaman and The Lost Kingdom.
General Lane from My Adventures with Superman,
season one.
Yogg-Satha from Batman the Doom that came to
Gotham.
Joker from Merry Little Batman.
What an eclectic group of villains. Out of the
13 projects that you had to choose from, I
guess I'm a little bit surprised that these
are your nominees, although I can't offhand
name you better ones. I'm going to go with Black
Manta from Aquaman. That's my guess. And the
winner is... Yogg-Sattha from Batman, the doom
that came to Gotham. Wow. All right, I will
not lie. DC had a villain problem this year.
Of the 13 projects, it was really hard to come
up with a list of solid villains this year.
But once I broke down all of the threats that
the heroes faced, I don't think one was more
powerful, more evil, and more successful than
Yogg-Sotha from Batman the Doom that came to
Gotham. It was an animated film, fantastic
film, I loved the film, and I thought the villain
was next level. Yeah, Batman the Doom that
came to Gotham was an adaptation of a Mike Mignola
written Elseworlds series, very Hellboy-esque
in its approach to the character of Batman and
his rogues and allies. Well, it was a Lovecraftian
take on the Batman mythos. Yeah, and it was
fantastic. I remember loving that movie and
I do remember the tremendous ending that it
had. I don't really want to give it away here
because it was just too good to spoil. But yeah,
the villain was in some regards, successful.
and honestly could kick any other villains ass.
Like I'm sure your list of villains wouldn't
be able to hold a candle to Yogg-Sotha. Oh,
don't be so sure about that. Let me go ahead
and get into my list of Marvel villains. And
the nominees are Darben from the Marvels.
Gravik from Secret Invasion Season 1.
High Evolutionary from Guardians of the Galaxy
Vol. 3
King the Conqueror from Ant-Man and the Wasp,
Quantumania.
So the way this episode is cut, you probably
would not have heard me laughing after you
said Darben from the marvels, but I was like
hilariously because she was such a horrible
villain. I don't understand how she made it
on your list. So you definitely didn't choose
her. I'm going to guess. And I'm hesitant to
do so because I'm 0 for 3 for this movie so
far, I think. But Guardians of the Galaxy's
high evolutionary. And the winner is He became
the Conqueror from Ant-Man and the Wasp Quantumania.
Clearly, I have a James Gunn bias. And I keep
choosing Guardians of the Galaxy because I just
thought it was Marvel's best film this year.
And you don't agree, I guess. High Evolutionary
was a great villain. I hated that guy. Maybe
almost too much because I was really pissed
that they let him live. But also he was a little
bit annoying with how much he freaking yelled.
I did not love Chirwooki Uwuji's performance
in that film. But you know that I liked Jonathan
Majors as King of the Conqueror, who I think
also posed a similar level threat to the heroes.
Okay, I mean, that's fair. They were definitely
setting him up to be, of course, as we all know,
the big bad of Marvel's multiversal saga. And
I guess I'm hoping at some point he gets to
the level of Thanos. I just don't think he's
quite there yet. But I think for what they had
here, King was the best part about Quantumania.
I don't think you could say the same about the
other villains on my list, that the villain
was the best part. That's fair. Yeah, that's
absolutely fair. But also, King would not beat
the shit out of Yaksatha. So you're wrong. Yeah,
he would. He would go back in time to when
Yaksatha was a little baby and then choke him
out. Oh, my gosh. What a strike to bitch. Why
strike to ain't nobody dissing Yaksatha? He's
like a Lovecraftian god of chaos from when
he was a baby in another dimension outside of
King's like perception. There are no dimensions
outside of King's purview. Yes, yes there absolutely
are. Sorry. He's a three dimensional being
like you or me. Some would say he's a fourth
dimensional being. Oh, okay, well, fuck them
and you. Let's go to move on to our next award,
which is Best Hero. Stories have existed ever
since humans came up with language. Going all
the way back to the Sumerian times, you had
the hero of Gilgamesh taking on those primordial
deities. Heroes mean something to us as a species.
They go through the trials and tribulations
of life and teach us lessons that we don't
necessarily have to experience ourselves, but
love living vicariously through them. Yeah,
everybody loves a hero. Both Marvel and DC had
fantastic heroes that displayed all the tenets
of great protagonists like sacrifice, compassion,
responsibility, and yes, I think I pulled those
from Merry Little Batman. Well, let me break
down the best heroes for DC in 2023. The nominees
are Blue Beetle from Blue Beetle.
Flash from the Flash.
Little Batman from Merry Little Batman.
Superman from My Adventures with Superman season
one.
That's a solid list, I think any one of those
could take home the prize. But I'm gonna give
it to The Flash largely because of the unique
lesson that he learned within his movie specifically.
That's my guess. And the winner is... Superman
from My Adventures with Superman, Season 1.
Brung again! I'm actually a little bit surprised.
Is it because it was such a wholesome and new
version of Superman character? that but also
because I think they really captured the essence
of the character of Superman who is, I would
argue, the most heroic archetype that exists
within comic book heroes. He is selfless and
he protects the innocent no matter the cost.
We really saw aspects of the character in the
My Adventures with Superman show when he was
putting himself in front of bullets and lasers
to protect Lois without even knowing that he
was bulletproof or laser proof. It was such
a fantastic take on Superman. And as we mentioned
in that review, it's really kind of unfortunate
that they didn't use this take in live action.
For sure. Yeah, the My Adventures with Superman
cartoon was a great template for a live action
origin story for Superman and his supporting
cast. When it comes to other heroes from DC
this year, you know, Blue Beetle really didn't
have control of the Blue Beetle suit and become
heroic to the very end. The Flash committed
a, you know, arguably selfish act that kind
of... derailed the entire timeline. And little
Batman, you know, also a little selfish and
definitely disobedient. I thought Superman definitely
epitomized what it means to be a hero. Well,
let's go ahead and see who the best Marvel hero
of 2023 was. The nominees are Ant-Man from
Ant-Man and the Wasp, Quantumania.
Rocket Raccoon from Guardians of the Galaxy
Vol. 3
Loki from Loki Season 2.
Miles Morales from Spider-Man Across the Spider-Verse.
This is also a good list of heroes. You even
have a villain on your list. Interesting. I
think I'm going to go with Loki, mainly because
the way the show ended with Loki's arc from
villain to hero was so unbelievably well realized.
So yeah, Loki, that's my guess. And the winner
is Loki from Loki Season 2. About time! Finally
got one right. Damn! Yeah, no, I mean, you're
entirely right. All the reasons that you stated.
The arc that Loki went through from his unsuccessful
coup of Earth in the Avengers film, where we
saw that variant get arrested by the TVA, transformed
from a selfish ego maniac into the most selfless
hero. He basically gives up his entire life
to make sure that everyone else gets to live
by overseeing the new branching timelines in
the new Marvel multiverse. It was an incredible
journey from start to finish. Yeah, it was
unbelievably moving. I'm actually really glad
you're giving him the award because I wasn't
even considering him for some reason because
I always think of him as a villain. But yeah,
what he did in the show is absolutely heroic.
Yeah, his heroic journey was very different
from Superman's in My Adventure with Superman,
but no less so heroic. Great choice. Very happy
with that choice.
Let's go ahead and move on to our next award,
which is best moments. Now, these are the onscreen
moments from Marvel and DC television and film
that we think were the best, whether that means
most moving emotionally or most rousing in terms
of action and excitement or just something
that we thought was really cool. You know, cool
factor goes a long way for this award. Yeah,
saying that a movie scene had you on the edge
of your seat is kind of cliche, but these scenes
absolutely had me on the edge of mind. but were
also incredibly memorable, which is what I
would say is the main criteria for this award.
Here are my choices for DC's best moment. The
nominees are Aquaman vs Black Manta from Aquaman
and The Lost Kingdom.
Final Resolutions from Doom Patrol Season 4.
Hullway Fight from Blue Beetle.
Worlds collide from the Flash.
Oh, those are all great moments. I think the
one that really sucker punched me right in
the gut though, the one that I did not see coming
and the one that I still can't get over is
Final Resolutions from Doom Patrol Season 4.
That's my guess. The winner is... Final Resolutions
from Doom Patrol Season 4. I figured. So I almost
gave this award to Worlds Collide from the
Flash. But the more I see that scene, the more
sort of it feels out of place with the whole
movie in general, the more I notice just the
bad CG of it. I thought it was really cool
in theaters at the time, and I think it's one
of the reasons why I gave the film the high
score that I did. But reminiscing on all the
different moments from this past year, from
DC, the Doom Patrol finale was absolutely the
most moving. It was so- unbelievably bittersweet
to say goodbye to these characters and see how
they're going to live out the rest of their
lives, particularly when it came to the very
final scene of the show, which is Robotman
witnessing the life of his grandson and then
dying as a result of being so at peace with
that. How dare you bring that up again. Like,
oh, my heart, it's still broken. Yeah, I think
that one's going to stay with me for a while.
So there was no way I couldn't give Doom Patrol
that nod. It was a fantastic show, still one
of my favorite DC shows that I would recommend
to anyone. And holy cow if you haven't seen
it I'm so unbelievably sorry for spoiling it,
but definitely watch it, it's worth it. Totally
for sure. Let's go to move on to the best Marvel
moments. The nominees are, Entangled Wrangle
from The Marvels.
Escaping the Spider Society from Spider-Man
across the Spider-Verse.
Loki's Ascension from Loki Season 2.
Rockets Lament from Guardians of the Galaxy,
Volume 3.
Oh man, this is gonna be a hard choice. Um,
but I'm gonna go out on a limb and say you're
a big old softy like me and was really affected
by the cathartic closure of damn fine television
and go with Loki's Ascension. And the winner
is Loki's Ascension from Loki season two. Knew
it! I knew it! Yeah, great guess. I mean, Rocket's
Lament was moving, but in a very like depressing
way, right? It wasn't cathartic. Loki's ascension
at the end of Loki Season 2 though was cathartic.
It was so satisfying and jaw-dropping and honestly
unexpected when he started restoring the multiverse
and you know giving up everything to oversee
its existence. A damn fine culmination to the
character and both seasons of the series of
Loki. Really couldn't ask for more. Yeah no
I agree like the finale to Doom Patrol Season
4. the finale to Loki season 2 is definitely
a memorable one and probably more memorable
than any other MCU show that has come out.
I would agree, yeah for sure. Let's go ahead
and move on to our next award which is Best
Actress. There are quite a few actresses for
both Marvel and DC that really seem to embody
the character from the source material and yet
are also capable of making it their own for
the screen. Yeah, they not only embody the character,
they also elevate. their roles, I think, to
become something more than what's just lifted
off the page. There's some fantastic female
characters from the comics, and we want to celebrate
the actresses who brought those characters
to life in 2023. Let's find out the best from
DC. The nominees are Alice Lee as Lois Lane
in My Adventures with Superman Season 1.
Bruna Marcazzin as Jenny Cord in Blue Beetle
Michelle Gomez as Madame Rouge in Doom Patrol
Season 4.
Sasha Kaie as Supergirl from The Flash.
This is an okay list. Um, I think it was- That's
strike three, motherfucker. It's go time. I
think my guess would be Sasha Kaia as Supergirl
because although her role was small, I thought
it was impactful. Did you not hear me say it's
go time? It's fucking go time. Ready, ready?
That's me slapping you across the face. Punching
you, right here. Dude, you're already down
with the one slap. I just Will Smith'd you.
Clearly I was still punching afterwards, so
no. And the winner is... Sasha Kaia as Supergirl
in The Flash. Yeah, makes sense. I really wanted
to give it to one of the Doom Patrol actresses
because I think they're all great in that show.
It's one of the reasons why the show is so great,
I believe. Michelle Gomez was definitely the
highlight of this past season because she had
the largest role. And yet, she also came across
as slightly annoying. So ultimately, I decided
to go with Sasha Kaia as Supergirl from The
Flash just because of her acting ability. I
thought she did a fantastic job as the character.
I'm actually kind of sad that we won't get to
see more of this version of Supergirl, and
I really hope we get the chance to see Sacha
Kaeya in more work because she is extremely
talented. Yeah, in just the 10 or 15 minutes
or so that she was on the screen, she really
made her mark on the character of Supergirl,
I think. That will be highly influential, I
think, in subsequent depictions. Yeah, not only
did she have a really cool look in the movie,
but the way she emoted from sadness to rage
to bewilderment. She just did an amazing job.
For sure, yeah, I totally agree with this pick.
Let's go ahead and move on to the Marvel side
of things and find out who the best actress
there was. The nominees are Olivia Coleman
as Sonya Fallsworth in Secret Invasion, season
one.
Karen Gillan as Nebula in Guardians of the Galaxy
Vol. 3
Hailey Steinfeld as Gwen Stacy in Spider-Man
Across the Spider-Verse.
Iman Velani as Ms. Marvel in The Marvels.
Um, I think you're probably going to give this
award to Hayley Steinfeld for Across the Spider-Verse.
It was a voice role, but I thought she did fantastic
in it. And the winner is... Hayley Steinfeld
as Gwen Stacy in Spider-Man Across the Spider-Verse.
Right again! You're on a roll now, you were
struggling in the beginning. Um, yeah, you're
right. Hailey Steinfeld's performance in Across
the Spider-Verse as Spider-Gwen was very on
point. I thought she hit all the emotional
beats harder than she needed to. It was really
easy to empathize with her character from the
opening narration that she gave while she was
drumming to the end scenes when she is assembling
the team to rescue Miles. I thought it was actually
an improvement over her performance in the
first Spider-Verse movie. I feel like we really
got to know the character a whole lot better
in Across the Spider-Verse. Yeah, it did not
hurt that they gave her some really special
moments in this movie. Set in her own universe
with her own art style. But honestly, that
wouldn't have meant much if the voice performance
is not up to par. Yeah, for sure. I do want
to give a shout out to Iman Valani. from the
Marvels. I was heavily considering giving her
this award, largely because she was I think
the best part about the Marvels, which is surprising
considering you know she's a new actress. Yeah,
I agree. Fantastic job for her film debut.
Finally, Olivia Colman gets nominated for something
and doesn't win, right? I thought she was great
in the crown. Let's go to move into our next
category, which is best actor. Like the actresses,
the dudes also have a substantial task in bringing
these characters Not all of them do it well.
It is quite a feat, I think, to bring something
so fantastic to life. Oh yeah, absolutely.
But when they do get it right, there is no greater
joy to be had as a comic book fan. Let's go
ahead and hear who the best DC actors were this
year. The nominees are Ezra Miller as The Flash
and Young Barry in The Flash.
Jack Quaid as Superman in My Adventures with
Superman.
Michael Keaton as Batman in The Flash.
Shalomari Doinya, as Blue Beetle, in Blue Beetle.
I think between Jack Quaid and Ezra Miller,
surprisingly, I think I'm gonna go with Ezra
Miller. Despite the fact that he's kind of a
shithead in real life, I think he did a good
job portraying two different characters in The
Flash, so that's my guess. And the winner is...
Ezra Miller as The Flash and Young Barry in
The Flash. I feel like this is the year where
we're probably gonna get some shit for the awards
that we're handing out, considering we're handing
awards to Jonathan Majors and Ezra Miller. Yeah,
this was definitely a really poor year in terms
of actors for comic book adaptations, considering,
you know, we also had Amber Heard thrown into
the mix. People just really did not like a lot
of the actors that were in comic book movies
this year, Ezra Miller being one of them, you're
right. But despite how... crappy the guy is
in real life throwing chairs at people and stuff
like that. There's no denying the strong performance
he gave is not just one but two different characters,
actually three, in The Flash. Yeah, despite
the fact that I never thought he was quite suited
to the role, he was enjoyable in the movie
and I think he convincingly pulled off different
characters. Yeah, there's a lot of people who
don't think that, you know, he was right for
Barry Allen, and I could agree, but I also
see where Zack Snyder was coming from when casting
him. The Justice League was sort of a five-man
band kind of trope and he fit sort of the silly
character archetype that the team needed. Carrying
that into his solo movie, The Flash, I thought
he did a tremendous job acting against himself
and with Michael Keaton and everyone else in
the cast. Yeah, I'm hoping that both Ezra Miller
and Jonathan Majors are able to kind of redeem
themselves in real life so that way these awards
don't age poorly. Oh no, we're definitely gonna
get some shit for them. No one's gonna remember
these awards by the time Ezra Miller, Jonathan
Majors, and Amber Heard redeem themselves,
if ever. But I'm sticking to it. Sometimes as
a fan, you have to separate the art from the
artist if you're looking to get any sort of
enjoyment out of these films. Absolutely. Well,
let's go to move on to the best of Marvel's
actors this year. The nominees are... Bradley
Cooper as Rocket Raccoon in Guardians of the
Galaxy Vol. 3
Tom Hiddleston as Loki in Loki Season 2.
Jonathan Majors as Kang the Conqueror in Ant-Man
and the Wasp Quantumania.
Shamik Moore as Miles Morales in Spider-Man
Across the Spider-Verse.
Wow, this may be the hardest one to guess yet,
but I'm gonna take a swing and say Shemeek
Moore from Across the Spider-Verse. And the
winner is Tom Hiddleston as Loki in Loki Season
Two. Okay, I mean, that's fair. They all could
have won. Honestly, they were all great performances.
They were all fantastic performances. Again,
I think a lot of people are already aware,
we're huge fans of the arc that Loki had throughout
all of his appearances throughout the MCU and
how it culminated in the way it did at the end
of Loki season two. But Tom Hiddleston is a
phenomenal actor. He's honestly an Oscar worthy
actor. I think if he just got an Oscar
very technical, brilliant in his deliveries
and his choices that he makes. Absolutely.
Yeah, Tom Hiddleston just needs to do like a
master class and how to be a fucking badass
actor. But I loved Bradley Cooper as Rocket
Raccoon. I think that was his best performance
and it was just so moving from young Rocket
to although I don't think he voiced young Rocket
actually, but you know, Rocket's journey was
so incredible as well going from basically
this asshole raccoon to such a forgiving creature,
you know. for giving the high evolutionary
despite everything that he had gone through.
That's why he was also a nominee for best hero.
But yeah, the performance really enhanced that
arc. Same goes for Shamik Moore as Miles Morales.
And of course, Jonathan Majors was great as
Kang. I thought he was really menacing, but
I'm not about to give an award to a convicted
criminal. Okay. Strike four. I don't know what
happens in strike four. I'll tell you what happens,
we move on to the next award category, the
penultimate category, which is best series or
special. Essentially this category is like
the home media compared to the theatrical releases
for Marvel and DC, including both long form
content and shorter content from entire seasons
to one hour specials. Sort of, I mean, DC does
release direct to video stuff that is eligible
for the best picture category, but you're right,
for the most part, the series or special nominees
are mostly enjoyed from home. And honestly,
they're among my favorite projects. A lot of
it is long form content, serialized content,
which is very fitting given the source material
which also is serialized. I love long form
storytelling. Let me break down the nominees
for the best that DC brought this year. The
nominees are Doom Patrol Season 4.
Harley Quinn, season four.
My Adventures with Superman Season 1.
Titans Season 4
It's really gonna come down to My Adventures
with Superman season 1 and Doom Patrol season
4 because both were phenomenal. At the end though,
I think I'm gonna go with My Adventures with
Superman just because it was less uneven than
Doom Patrol season 4. And the winner is...
My Adventures with Superman season 1. I feel
like I'm kind of on a roll. I don't know, I'm
not counting. You were right in your reasoning
for why My Adventures with Superman beat out
Doom Patrol. As moving as the Doom Patrol was...
There were some problems with it. Problems
that did not exist for my adventures with Superman,
which was nearly perfect. I loved that series.
I loved the take that they took with the Superman
mythos. I loved the animated style that they
did as well. I never would have thought Superman
would have worked as a shonen anime, but it
absolutely does. They knocked it out of the
park and I can't wait for season two. I was
not looking forward to this show. I watched
it begrudgingly. And then I walked away super
thrilled that I did because I've never been
a fan of Superman really as a Marvel guy And
this show made me a fan which is hugely commendable
That's the biggest compliment the show could
ever receive the fact that it made marvelous
joe a fan of a dc character You guys heard
it here. Well, I mean, I still like every single
other marvel character more than superman,
but uh, Yeah, superman's pretty cool now I'm
debating whether or not to give you a strike
five. I definitely think that my praise of the
show is greater than the awards that you just
gave it. No, no, there's no award greater than
the Brothers Awards. We all know this. Let's
go to move on to Marvel and hear what the best
series for that were. The nominees are Loki
Season 2.
Secret Invasion Season 1
What if season two?
You only had three? Wait, what's the fourth
nominee? There is no fourth nominee. Holy shit,
Marvel sucked this year! Well, the obvious answer
is Loki Season 2. Even though I haven't finished
What If Season 2, I know it's not beating Loki.
And the winner is... Loki Season 2. I feel
like I'm on a roll. You're not though. Damn,
barely, barely. What if season two is fantastic?
I actually liked it more than what if season
one, but you're right, nothing touches Loki
season two. Of course, Secret Invasion is not
even part of the discussion. That was a huge
letdown when it absolutely should not have been.
Like the worst part about Secret Invasion is
that it did not live up to its potential. And
that's an even bigger crime in my book. Loki
season two, I think, surpassed its potential.
I think it told an incredible story, as we've
already discussed many times this episode. because
Loki has won a ton of awards and deservedly
so. Yeah, no, I agree. Loki has been my favorite
Marvel show out of everything that's been put
out on Disney Plus so far. And I'm really, really
glad that it went out on such a high note.
It's absolutely deserving of this award. I just
can't believe Marvel put out such little content
this year that you can't even come up with four
nominations. That is, wow, dropping the ball.
Yeah, I mean, Echo was supposed to come out
this year, but they punted it to January and
they didn't have any specials this year. So
yeah, I was stuck with three nominees. DC is
just crushing it, I guess. Let's go to move
on to our final award of the evening, which
is Best Picture for Marvel and DC. You know,
this is like the top tier award. Like with
the Oscars, everybody wants to know what the
best picture was of the year. Of course, this
is even more important because it pertains to
Marvel and DC, who never win Oscars for Best
Picture. But they're damn going to win a Brothers
Award. I mean, Black Panther and the Joker
received nominations for best picture. But yeah,
why does that matter when they could win a
brother's award? Exactly. Let's find out what
the best DC picture is for 2023. The nominees
are Batman, the doom that came to Gotham.
Blue Beetle.
The Flash.
Merry little Batman.
I'm surprised to see Merry Little Batman at
this list, but it was such a cute movie that
I guess it deserves to be here among the best.
I think it's kind of a toss-up between Blue
Beetle and The Flash, although the Doom that
came to Gotham was everything you would ever
want it to be. I'm gonna go with The Flash though,
I think you're gonna give Flash best picture.
That's my guess. The winner is... Blue Beetle.
Oh shit! Just lost your roll! Ha ha! Okay,
so originally I was giving it to The Flash because
for as much hate as it gets, I still think
that's a really good movie. When I first came
out of the theater after watching The Flash,
I was so ecstatic that I gave the film a 4.5
rating, which I admit now is probably too high.
I think it's a solid 4 film. I also gave Blue
Beetle a 4. And in rewatching these films now
that I own them, I have to say Blue Beetle,
in my opinion, is the better movie. I'm finally
glad to see you admit to your bias. Dude, I've
admitted to this before. Like, I give wrong
ratings all the time, more frequently than I'm
willing to admit. Like, the Joker got a wrong
rating from me. The Flash definitely did. But
Blue Beetle did not. It was a fantastic time
at the theater. It's why you go to the theater
to see these movies. but it was also a fantastic
adaptation of the character and one that I really
hope James Gunn continues in the DCU. I agree.
As far as Blue Beetle goes, I think there was
very little lacking in terms of what you would
want or expect from a Blue Beetle origin story
movie. I don't know if the same could be said
about the other nominees on this list. Like
when it comes to the Flash, I think what you
would want and expect is a more direct adaptation
of the Flash Point paradox story, but Blue
Beetle, they nailed. Oh, absolutely, absolutely.
I also loved the family themes that had, as
I mentioned earlier, the music was fantastic
and the CG that it had was the best hands down
that DC put out this year. I would totally agree
with that. Yeah, the movie looked incredible.
Unlike shots from The Flash or even Aquaman
and The Lost Kingdom. Right, the latter of
which wasn't even nominated for this award.
Same goes with Shazam Fury of the Gods. Well,
I don't think it'll be hard to guess what my
nominations were for Marvel. considering that
Marvel only had four full-length pictures come
out this year. So let me run down them. The
nominees are Ants Man and the Wasp, Quantumania.
Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 3
the Marvels.
Spider-Man across the Spider-Verse.
You're probably gonna give it to Across the
Spider-Verse, but man, I'm really, really hoping
you actually give it to Guardians of the Galaxy
Volume 3, because I think that was my personal
favorite Marvel film of the year. And the winner
is Guardians of the Galaxy Volume 3. Yes! James
Gunn wins, Joseph likes DC. I'm gonna count
that as a wrong guess, because I think you
actually guessed that I was gonna pick Spider-Man
on that one. No, I- So, Spider-Man Across the
Spider-Verse was incredible. I didn't get to
review that one because it came out the same
week that my little baby girl was born. That
movie will actually always hold a special place
in my heart because of that. But if I had gotten
the chance to review Spider-Man Across the
Spider-Verse with you and Spies, I would have
told you how much I loved it. It's actually
probably one of the best animated films I've
ever seen. But it's also just half a story.
Whereas Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 3... was
a culmination of a fantastic trilogy of films
and was entirely satisfying as an end to these
characters' journeys. Yeah, absolutely. I really
liked the Guardians of the Galaxy films and
I don't know, again, maybe I'm just a big softie,
but I really like the way that the arcs ended
for the characters that we had grown to love
in the MCU. Rocket Story was incredible. Star-Lord's
journey was fantastic. I'm really excited to
see where that goes in the future. I think it
would have been hard to conceive of a better
way to end that franchise than what James Gunn
did with Volume 3. Honestly, if we were giving
one Best Picture award for both Marvel and DC,
I would also give it to Guardians of the Galaxy
Volume 3. I thought it was better than any of
the movies that DC put out this year, and it
really makes me look forward to what James Gunn
can do in the DC universe. Well, Across the
Spider-Verse was also better than anything else
DC put out this year, so I mean, I think what
I just heard you say was that Marvel is better
than DC this year. So you admit it in 2023.
Yes. In the theater, Marvel was better than
DC. And I and I don't think you're going to
find anyone who disagrees with that. Honestly,
you heard it here first, folks. Jonathan likes
Marvel more than DC. I'm going to change your
name to read on the discord. He's
just wait till the next Brothers Awards. OK.
I guarantee you Joker Folly I do is gonna blow
anything that Marvel does out of the water.
2024 is the year of DC. Maybe the year where
DC embarrasses itself by producing a musical
that it had no right making. What is it with
Marvel fans and musicals? Musicals are not bad.
I just saw Wonka in the theater. I didn't know
it was going to be a musical. It was a musical.
It was fantastic. Musicals are not bad. Can
Joaquin Phoenix even sing? You know he was in
a band, right? No. Well, now you do. Who wasn't
in a band? You. That's true. But that brings
us to the end of this award show, guys. We
hope you had fun recounting the best that Marvel
and DC had to offer in the year 2023. Really
looking forward to 2024, kind of largely because
Marvel Studios is only putting out one theatrical
release, Deadpool 3, and Sony, oh God, is putting
out two movies with Madame Webb and Kraven
the Hunter. So. You might be right, Jonathan.
2024 might be the year of DC. I mean, I'm sure
Deadpool 3 is going to be amazing. I just don't
think it's going to be up to the same caliber
of film that Todd Phillips is going to make
with Joker Folly, I do. But of course, that's
the only theatrical release that DC is putting
out this upcoming year. I feel like we live
in fucking covid times. It's ridiculous. Freaking
actor and writer strikes, man. Yeah, those
strikes really delayed a lot. It's a real shame.
But luckily, there's a lot to enjoy on the
small screen. this year with television shows.
And direct-to-video animated features like
Justice League Crisis on Infinite Earths, Watchmen,
Aztec Batman, Creature Commandos, Kite Man
Hell Yeah, and Suicide Squad Isakai as well.
Not to mention The Penguin. Altogether we're
looking at about 10 DC projects to review in
2024. It's going to be Slim Pickens for Marvel,
it's unclear as to whether or not Agatha, Darkhold
Diaries is going to come out in 2024, same
thing with Eyes of Wakanda. your friendly neighborhood
Spider-Man and Marvel zombies, but we'll see.
Maybe even Ironheart is going to come out this
year. I know that Daredevil was pushed to 2025,
so the Brothers Awards might be a little bit
more predictable next December. I predict that
I'm going to beat your ass when it comes to
guessing what you're going to choose. I predict
I'm going to beat your ass. Period. For life.
That does it for this awards episode guys.
Let us know what you thought about it by writing
to us at dyna or by visiting us on Instagram
or X. You can find links to all of our accounts
by checking out our show notes or visiting
our website at dynamicduel.com. And on our site,
you could also find the link to our Patreon
page where you can join our dynamic 2.0 tier
and chat with us and fellow listeners. Our
fantastic 4 tier, which gets you bonus content
each month. Our X-Force tier that makes you
an executive producer of this podcast and our
newest tier that lets you join our Dynamike
podcast network. If you can't join Patreon,
you can still support the show by signing up
for our e-newsletter also at dynamicduel.com
so you'll never miss an episode. You can also
rate our show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser,
or on our website. Next week we are going to
review What If Season 2. I have good things
to say about it, so Jonathan, I hope you agree
when you watch it. We'll see, we'll see. But
that does it for this episode, we want to give
a big thanks to our executive producers Ken
Johnson. John Strausky, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin
Balcom, Miggy Mathengian, Brandon Estregard,
Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yaiten, Nick Kabonto,
Austin Wyselowski, AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho,
Adam Spies, and Andrew Schunk for helping make
this podcast possible. And we'd like to thank
all of you listeners out there for sticking
with us another year. We truly appreciate having
you guys check us out every week. We hope you
had a great new year, and here's to 2024. Up
up and away, true believers. and I give the
best AI award to Ava in Ex Machina. Hubba hubba.