This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
Hi and welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast,
a weekly show where we review superhero films
and debate the superiority between Marvel and
DC by comparing their characters in stat-based
battle simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe. And I'm
his twin brother Johnny DC. And this episode
guys, it's a big one. It's a big milestone team
duel episode, which we do every 25 episodes
or so. We're going to find out who would win
in a fight between the outsiders and X-Force.
The Outsiders is a badass DC group started by
Batman consisting of characters like Black
Lightning and Katana, and X-Force is a badass
Marvel group consisting of characters like
Cable and Deadpool. Yeah, they're borderline
street level teams, but they also have some
real powerhouses and some really cool characters.
Yeah, this particular team duel was determined
by our executive producers and... We've been
building toward it for a few months now, and
I'm really excited to see who's going to win
between these two groups. Of course, this isn't
the first team duel that we've done. We've done
lots of other team duels. I think we've done
like 11 of them now, including... Justice League
vs Avengers Titans vs X-Men Justice Society
vs Fantastic Four Suicide Squad vs Defenders
Justice League Dark vs The Midnight Suns Arkham
Asylum vs Sinister Six Young Justice vs Young
Avengers The Flash's Rogues vs The Brotherhood
of Mutants Doom Patrol vs Guardians of the Galaxy
We did a special last Halloween, Deceased vs
Marvel Zombies and the Legion of Doom vs. Masters
of Evil. If any of those strike your fancy,
definitely go check out our Team Duel episodes.
In addition to this episode, because, you know,
they're big ones. They're a lot of fun. A lot
of work goes into them. So much work. Yeah,
it's worth it, though. And we hope you guys
enjoy our four hundred and first episode. Episode
400 was actually our Suicide Squad Isekai review.
But before we get into that team duel, we're
going to go over the latest comic book movie
news to come out this past week, of which there
was just one news item, and that was that Marvel
television executive, Brad Winterbaum, has
confirmed that Nova will be a television series.
As always, we list our segment times in our
episode description, so feel free to check out
the show notes if you want to skip ahead to
a particular topic. Our artificially intelligent
duel simulator, AJ9K, has a quick message for
our listeners, so listen up. Why hello there,
do you want even more from this podcast? Then
become a part of the dynamic duel community
on Patreon, where you can choose from three
tiers. The dynamic two-oh tier gives you access
to our Discord chat server. The fantastic four
tier gives you two bonus episodes each month,
and the X-Force tier makes you an executive
producer of this show. Lastly, The DynaMic
Podcast Network tier lets you create your own
podcast using this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny
and Joe will help you develop your show, provide
graphic support and consultation, and get you
simulation results. Pitch the twins your ideas
via email at dynamicduelpodcast at gmail.com.
Check it out at patreon.com slash dynamicduel.
Pip pip cheerio. Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone
who supports the podcast. Be sure to tune into
the other shows in the DynaMic Podcast Network
this week. including Max Destruction, which
pits your favorite action heroes from film and
television against each other. This week, hosts
Scotty and Gilly are pitting Neo from The Matrix
against Gabriel Yulaw from The One. On the
Senjou World podcast, host Zachary Hepburn speculates
on fights between fan favorite anime and manga
characters. This Thursday, Zach will be finding
out who'd win between Toji Fushiguro from Jujutsu
Kaisen and Rock Lee from Naruto. On the Console
Combat podcast, hosts John and Dean find out
who would win in fights between popular video
game characters. In yesterday's episode, they
determined who would win between Craig Boone
from Fallout and Sniper Wolf from Metal Gear.
Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link
in our show notes to listen to all the shows
in the DynaMic Podcast Network. But with that
out of the way, quick, to the no prize! A no
prize is an award Marvel used to give out to
fans. Our version, the Dynamic Duel No Prize,
is a digital award that we posted on Instagram
for the person that we feel gave the best answer
to our question of the week. Last week we asked,
out of the 400 episodes we've done, what has
been your favorite episode of Dynamic Duel so
far, and why? And I thought we would get a
ton of answers. We got three. Which is disappointing,
but you know, I think we've asked this question
a few times already, so it makes sense that
we would get diminishing returns on it. We
got two honorable mentions and a no prize winner.
Our first honorable mention goes to Miggy Mathengian,
who said, Hey, what's up, guys? This is Miggy.
And my favorite episode of your guys's is the
Titans versus X-Men team duel. It just came
out at a time when I had finished catching
up on all of your backlog and I was listening
to episodes weekly. And the Titans are like
my favorite team and some of my favorite characters.
So it was just kind of that sweet spot. Also
the Batman review with the Spies Brothers, the
Batman movie with the Spies Brothers, the 60s
one, hilarious. Thanks guys. Yes, we have definitely
asked this question before and Mickey has responded
with those same answers. But just hearing his
choices again reminds me of how much fun I
have doing this podcast. It makes me feel like
we peaked years ago on this show. Totally.
His answers have not changed. That's true. We
keep putting out new episodes, but apparently
they're not getting any better than those I
mean it is the Titans and X-Men. Well, maybe
the X-Force episode will be better. We'll see.
Yeah, cause Outsiders is kind of Titans adjacent
and X-Force is X-Men adjacent. We'll see. No
pressure, no pressure. Thanks, Miggy, for your
answer. Our next honorable mention goes to Travis
Herndon, who said. What's up, DynamaDews? Travis
here, shout out to my other twins. So my answer
would have to be your video on Poison Ivy versus
Emma Frost's battle. That one to me was definitely
the funniest from you guys' back and forth.
You know how the fight was slowly going from
this actual fight to this hot and steamy, sexy
time and you guys had to be stopping yourselves
over and over again. So that had to be my pick,
the Poison Ivy vs Emma Frost. Yeah, that's embarrassing.
Really the only quasi-sexy thing that I remember
from that duel is when Poison Ivy cracked Emma
Frost's diamond form. And Jonathan said that
the crack was the crack of the ass. Ridiculous.
But yeah, Jonathan does that type of shit all
the time when it comes to the femme fatale duels
and he's working on it. He's trying to do better.
I literally cannot deny it because our patrons
have access to our blooper reels from when
we did like Catwoman versus Hellcat. I'm not
proud of it, but I am amused by it. Great answer,
Travis. But the winner of this week's snow prize
is. Kat Stevenson who said, Hi guys, it's Kat
again. And recently I went to the Seattle Museum
of Pop Culture where I got to see the Batman
and Robin suit. Seeing the Bat nipples in real
life made me realize that my favorite episode
is your Batman and Robin review. That movie
is absolutely bat shit crazy. And just getting
to listen to you guys rant about a horrible
movie is amazing. I love that episode and I
love you guys. Thank you so much. Thanks, Kat.
Yeah, this episode got the win largely because
I was just really surprised by the answer. I've
never heard this before. Actually, I remember
when we did that review of Batman and Robin,
we got some flack from some listeners who just
knew the movie was bad and didn't want to hear
a review on it. I guess not recognizing that,
you know, we're trying to review all the Marvel
and DC movies whether they're new or old. Good
or bad. Right. And holy cow, Batman and Robin.
is bad. Even revealing it, I'm like, this review
is way worse than I even remembered it being.
I'm glad someone liked the review because I
sure did not enjoy writing it. But the best
part about that whole experience was probably
recording our review and just cracking up. So
yeah, brought back some good memories. Thanks,
Kat Stevenson. Congrats on winning this week's
No Prize. If you the listener want a shot at
winning your own No Prize, stay tuned to later
on this episode when we'll be asking another
question of the week. And now that that's done.
On to the news!
This past week, Brad Winterbaum, who is the
Marvel Studios Head of Streaming, Television,
and Animation, guested on a podcast called the
Phase Zero Podcast. And on the show, Winterbaum
confirmed that Nova is getting a Disney Plus
television series. Now, I think a lot of us
have assumed that for quite a while or we've
known that. But what was interesting about
this reveal that Nova is going to be a television
show is that Brad Winterbaum described the
series as having shades of both Star Trek and
Battlestar Galactica, which both of those shows
are long running fan-loved sci-fi franchises.
So this can only mean good things for a Nova
series. Actually, you know what? I thought the
most interesting thing about that was, of course,
Marvel would be doing a Nova series after the
Green Lantern series was greenlit by Warner
Brothers. Because why wouldn't they? Because
they're a bunch of copiers. I'm sorry. The
Green Lantern series has been described as true
detective in space. whereas the Nova series
is being described as Star Trek and Battlestar
Galactica. Now which one of those other television
show comparisons seems more appropriate for
an intergalactic, spacefaring, peacekeeping
core out in the galaxy? You tell me. True Detective
or Star Trek? Now when you say appropriate,
do you mean like interesting? Because True Detective!
I mean both. True Detective. Dude, Star Trek?
Meets Battlestar Galactica. It's a big done
before. It's called Star Trek and Battlestar
Galactica. True Detection has been done before.
But now what? I have space, bro. OK, come on.
Oh, let's see Star Trek in space. I wonder what
that's like. Fucking awesome. That's what it's
like. Now, Brad Winterbaum said that it's going
to be an ensemble piece. So it looks like the
series is not just going to focus on one Nova
like Richard Ryder or maybe Sam Alexander.
It's going to focus on the entire Nova Corps
and perhaps what happens to them after Zandar
is destroyed. I would prefer the Nova Corps
and the Gromund Day to visit Earth, recruit
Richard Ryder, and then restart the Nova Corps.
I think that'd be a great premise. But really
the MCU is focusing more on the Nova Corps itself,
the entire team, as opposed to one individuel
Corps member. We saw in the first Guardians
of the Galaxy film where we were introduced
to the Corps on Zandar, how the Nova Corps were
more like a... police force than a group of
superheroes, you know, they didn't fly around
on their own. They flew around in Nova Corps
spaceships. And the way the Nova Force manifested
was like an energy force field linked between
their ships and stuff like that. It was really
fascinating. And it'll be really interesting
to see where they take that concept with this
Nova Corps series, especially considering that
Xandar has been destroyed. I'm actually not
surprised they're making it an ensemble considering
some of the cast members they've had. in the
Nova Corps and past movies like John C. Reilly
and Glenn Close. You know, if you could get
those actors to come back, maybe even for like
a brief appearance, that'd be pretty cool. But
also, I'm not surprised that it's an ensemble
because a lead character named Dick Ryder is
not for Disney+. You are the first person to
ever make that joke. I mean, I try. Now, Richard
Ryder is a great character. If you guys want
to learn more about him, definitely check out
our duel episode between him and Hal Jordan
Green Lantern. Actually, speaking of Green Lantern,
rumors are a swirling about who they are going
to cast as Hal Jordan. The list includes Josh
Brolin, Thanos himself, Matthew McConaughey,
Ewan McGregor, Chris Pine, and Timothy Olyphant.
And I gotta say, that's a solid lineup. I'd
be happy with any one of those. Yeah, I'd be
happy with any of those except for Josh Brolin,
I think. He just doesn't feel like Hal Jordan
to me. But it seems like they're going with
an older actor for Hal Jordan and a younger
actor for Jon Stewart. Yeah, yeah, that's their
plan, allegedly. But speaking of Nova and Green
Lantern, that brings us to our question of
the week.
Who would you cast as Richard Ryder in the Nova
series, and Hal Jordan and Jon Stewart in the
Green Lantern series? Record your answer at
dynamicduel.com by clicking on the red microphone
button in the bottom right hand corner of the
screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message can be up to 30 seconds
long, and don't forget to leave your name in
case we include you on the podcast. We'll pick
our favorite answer, and award that person
a dynamic duel no prize that we'll post to Instagram.
Be sure to answer before... September 14th.
Well that does it for all the news for this
episode, so let's go ahead and get into our
main event where we find out who'd win in a
fight between DC's The Outsiders and Marvel's
X-Force.
Alright, Outsiders vs X-Force. These are two
badass teams that I think are largely well
known for their respective fan bases. X-Force
is definitely well known even amongst non-comic
book readers because the team made a cameo appearance
on the Deadpool 2 movie. Yeah, and the Outsiders
had an entire season dedicated to them in the
Young Justice animated series from DC. Which
is not the same level of popularity as a theatrical
release. Nobody watches this cartoon that you're
talking about. The only people that would know
who the outsiders are actual DC comic book
fans, I think. Bitch, you don't know people's
lives? Show me the numbers. Prove me wrong.
Prove yourself right. The burden on proof is
on you, I think. I'm just gonna say that it
is. You have to prove me wrong. That's how it
works. We'll tell everybody out there who are
not quite familiar with who the outsiders are
their basic gist. The idea of the outsiders
is that they can do things and go places that
the Justice League cannot. And the X-Force
are kind of exactly the same when it comes to
the X-Men. Like the X-Force go out and do things
outside of the scope of your standard X-Men
mission. You know, they're often considered
outlaws for their more extreme, brutal methods.
You know, they're a product of the extreme
80s and 90s. They're also a product of the outsiders,
because the outsiders can first... and they
did all that stuff first. How do you know that
the Outsiders came first? Because the X-Force
came out in like the early 90s, I'm pretty sure,
and the Outsiders were around before Crysis.
Well X-Force came out in 1991. Okay, yeah, so
I'm right. Again it doesn't matter who came
out first, it matters who did it better. And
we're going to find out which team is better
in this episode, but to explain the methodology
behind our team duels, let's go to our sentient
duel simulator Alfred Jarvis 9000. Tell our
listeners how you go about determining a winner
in our team duel matchups. Yes, of course, sir.
The way I determine a winner between the two
teams is by running 1,000 Monte Carlo simulations
between every character on each team using
their statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation is
a probabilistic model used to determine outcomes
through random sampling. In this case, I randomize
the statistics along a normal distribution
as a way to simulate the many variables that
can occur during battle. The stat parameters
are based on the official Marvel power grid,
from which the DC characters' statistics are
extrapolated. Additional stat categories are
included such as range, damage potential, versatility
and perception, in order to create a more detailed
and accurate simulation. The results of the
49,000 simulations provide a percentage of wins
for each character on both teams. The team
with the higher average win rate is declared
the victor, as they have a higher probability
to win any given battle. In an equitable pairing,
neither team should win 100% of the matches.
The comic book stories have shown that there's
even a way for Batman to defeat Superman, so
the confidence rate of my method falls in line
with the precedents that have been established
in the source material. My mathematical simulations
are without subjectivity or bias. Feats are
not the sole consideration, nor are fan votes
tabulated for determination of the winner.
Thanks, Adrian, I'm K. Before we run the simulations
though, we like to break down each team's histories
and rosters before improvising a scenario on
how we imagine one of the thousands of simulations
we run would play out beat for beat. And it's
my turn to go first with the Marvel team's
backstory, so let me go ahead and tell you all
about X-Force. The origins of the X-Force team
are actually found within another group known
as the New Mutants, a team of young heroes
formed by Professor X when he mistakenly believed
his X-Men had perished. Though the Professor
was reluctant to form a new team, Xavier decided
that he could still mentor young mutants in
the use of their powers without sending them
into combat. However, combat found the young
team and the new mutants were in near constant
struggles against outside enemies and their
own inner demons despite Professor X's wishes.
You can learn more about Professor X and his
duel against the Chief and more about the X-Men
in their team duel against the Titans. Eventually,
the time traveling cyborg mutant soldier named
Cable took charge of the new mutants and restructured
it into a strike team that would take a more
proactive approach against threats against
mutant kind. More specifically, against threats
posed by Cable's clone named Strife, who had
formed a terrorist mutant group called the Mutant
Liberation Front. Cable took the young heroes
under his wing, radicalizing them in his more
extreme methods, which prompted several members
to leave. including Warlock, Wolfsbane, Richter,
and Sunspot, leaving only Cannonball and Boom
left on the team. This resulted in Cable recruiting
new members, Warpath, Shatterstar, Feral, and
Domino. Together they formed a new group that
Cable monocled X-Force, a group existing between
Professor X's pacifist ideals and Magneto's
hostile aggression. The team fought against
Genesis, a disciple of Apocalypse who hired
their mercenary Deadpool to attack X-Force.
They also battled Strife's Mutant Liberation
Front, Juggernaut and Black Tom Cassidy, the
Immortal Mutant Externals, the Parasitic Phalanx
Aliens, and even the International Espionage
Organization SHIELD after getting on their radar
for their brutal, uncompromising methods. In
their adventures, they brought on new recruits
including Siren, Caliban, Meltdown, Bedlam,
and Mirage. When Strife framed Cable for an
assassination attempt on Professor X, X-Force
found themselves without a mentor for a time.
They were taken under the guidance of the mutant
British spy, Pete Wisdom, but they disbanded
not long after. Eventually the cast of a mutant
reality TV show took the name X-Force for their
group, prompting the original team to confront
them and they changed their name to X-Statics.
Later the Scarlet Witch used her reality warping
powers during a psychotic break to remove most
of the world's mutant abilities in an event
known as M-Day. When Earth's first new mutant
was born, groups around the world raced to
find her, either seeking to protect, experiment
on, or destroy her. As part of the search,
Cyclops formed a strike force within the X-Men
team to find the child and protect her from
all threats, creating a new iteration of X-Force,
this time led by Wolverine and consisting of
X-23, Warpath, Caliban, and Hepzibah. Ultimately,
it was Cable acting on his own, who was able
to secure the child, naming her Hope Summers
and taking her into the future to protect her.
Cyclops retained X-Force as a secret black ops
team tasked with eliminating potential threats
to mutant kind, including William Stryker and
his purifiers, and Mr. Sinister and his marauders.
Archangel joined the team, and the group operated
out of his area estate in the Colorado Rocky
Mountains. They were also joined by Domino and
Deadpool when they were sent to the future
to help After saving the two and returning to
the present, the team relocated to an island
base off the coast of San Francisco. There,
X-Force fought against the mutant Succubus
Selene and her undead army, and later Bastion
and his battalion of Nimrod Sentinels. Eventually,
Cyclops determined the strike force was no longer
necessary, and he had X-Force disbanded. However,
Wolverine kept it going in secret, bringing
aboard Psylocke and Phantom X to the team.
They battled the resurrected Apocalypse and
his four horsemen, and the cybernetic Reavers,
during which the zombie cyborg soldier Deathlock
joined. They also opposed the evil psychic
entity known as the Shadow King, before Wolverine
revealed the group's existence to the X-Men,
and the X-Force disbanded once again. Is Deathlock
a mutant? He's not, but technically neither
is Deadpool. He's a mutate. So the X-Force team
is not just mutants exclusively, like Shatterstar
is not a mutant. Gotcha. He's an alien. Meanwhile,
Cable and Hope returned to the present, where
Cable's techno-organic virus was purged from
his system. With his psychic powers fully unleashed,
Cable began receiving precognitive visions of
the future, and he recruited a new X-Force
team to battle the threats that he foresaw,
including new members Hope, Colossus, and Forge.
Together, they stopped numerous threats such
as a public transmode virus infection, and
an alien invasion. However, since the team's
actions were preemptive, X-Force was branded
as terrorists and got on the radar of the Avengers
and had to fight the team to continue their
work. Simultaneously, the Black Ops X-Force
team, now known as the Uncanny X-Force, had
continued on, now led by Psylocke, and included
members such as Storm, Bishop, Spiral, and
Puck. One of Cable's premonitions led Hope to
perceive the Uncanny team as a threat, and
the two X-Forces fought. They eventually called
a truce, however, and Psylocke's team disbanded.
Eventually, Cable, still beset by his premonitions,
went after the mercenary Deadpool, who at the
time was being tested by the Time Variance Authority
as a potential agent. Cable stole a time harness
in an attempt to stop Deadpool from causing
a disaster and to fix his mind from the premonitions.
In the process, the time harness merged Cable
with various incarnations of himself across
the time stream, and Cable returned to the present.
back with his techno-organic virus, and without
his future premonitions. No longer tied to a
mission, the X-Force team disbanded. When Professor
X, Magneto, and other Mutant leaders developed
their own nation on the mutant island of Krakoa,
they found themselves still targeted by foreign
threats and decided to form a Krakoan intelligence
agency, a new special operations squad named
X-Force. You can learn more about Krakoa in
his duel episode against Danny the Street. This
new team was headed by Beast and included Sage,
Wolverine, Domino, Colossus, and Kid Omega,
with special equipment provided for their missions
by Forge. Together, they executed missions to
protect Krakoa's national interests, including
defending against the anti-Krakoan organization
known as Orcus. And that's their backstory
up until recently. For the 7-person X-Force
roster I'll be going with for this team duel,
because all of our team duels include 7 person
rosters. I wanted to pull from across the team's
long and varied history. First off, I chose
the founder of X-Force and its frequent leader,
Cable, who is a physical and psychic powerhouse.
I'm also going with one of the first recruits
of the original team, a founding member, and
one of the group's most frequent members, Domino,
my good luck wildcard. The strongman Warpath
is my third member, who is also an original
member of X-Force. The latter two that I just
mentioned were also members of the X-Force
Special Ops team, which is one of my personal
favorite incarnations of the group and where
I pulled from the remaining four members. This
includes Deadpool, who initially started out
as a mercenary adversary for the team but later
joined them, Archangel, who I consider my aerial
support as one of the only flyers on the group,
Psylocke, another psychic threat, and lastly
X23, who in the comic books is now going by
the code name Talon. which is a name I really
like for her, and that's what I'll be calling
her here instead of X23. Talon not only was
a member of the Special Ops Squad, but she's
also serving as a stand-in of sorts for her
father, and I put father in quotes, Wolverine,
and Wolverine has led several versions of X-Force,
but I already used him in the Titans versus
X-Men duel. So that's my roster. To reiterate,
the seven-member X-Force team that I'm going
with for this duel is Cable, Psylocke, Archangel,
Warpath, and X23, now known as Talon. And you
can learn all about their individuel histories
in their respective duel episodes. Basically,
this team is as badass as badass gets though.
It is pretty badass. Actually, there are a lot
of tie-ins in their backstory that reminded
me a lot of the Outsiders backstory. The teams
are maybe a little bit more similar than I
would have even thought. But let me get into
the Outsiders backstory. When Lucius Fox a
board member of Wayne Enterprises, was kidnapped
during a business trip in the fictional European
country of Markovia during the coup of the country's
monarchy, Batman insisted the Justice League
intervene, though he was rejected on the grounds
that the League's presence would be seen as
an involvement in a political conflict. Enraged,
Batman quit the League and enlisted the help
of Black Lightning to rescue Lucius abroad.
While posing as Lucius's brother, Black Lightning
developed a contact within the Markovian revolutionaries
named General Carnes, who worked with the villain
Baron Bedlam to kill King Victor Markov and
take over the country. Carnes was killed, however,
by the sword-wielding Kitana, who blamed him
for selling weapons that killed her family.
While Black Lightning was blamed and imprisoned
for the death of Carnes, Batman encountered
Halo, an amnesiac young woman seemingly a victim
of the war in Markovia that possessed energy
powers. and Markovia's chief royal scientist,
Dr. Helga Jace, was imbuing the country's prince,
Bran Markov, with geokinetic powers in order
to protect the crown. Metamorpho, an elemental
shapeshifter, was also in Markovia at the time,
seeking help from Dr. Jace to cure him of his
powers. After Prince Bryan, aka Geoforce, was
shot and left for dead, Batman, Halo, and Metamorpho
were all captured and imprisoned, though Katana
reappeared and helped rescue the heroes from
When GeoForce recovered, the heroes all managed
to work together to overthrow Baron Bedlam,
and rescue Lucius Fox to boot. Impressed by
their abilities and cooperation, Batman convinced
all of the heroes to join him in Gotham City
to train as a new, secret superteam capable
of covert missions that the Justice League were
incapable of performing. When Metamorpho wondered
aloud if a group of outsiders like them could
really be a team, it was GeoForce that determined
outsiders should be the team name. Batman led
the Outsiders in numerous missions against
villains such as Agent Orange, Meltdown, and
Cryonic Man. They clashed with the Teen Titans,
fought alongside the Justice League, and dealt
with personal struggles, including Kitana's
battle against the Yakuza, the betrayal and
death of Geoforce's sister Terra, Halo's abduction
by the extradimensional light beings known as
Articles, and the kidnapping of Sapphire Stag,
metamorphosed fiancee, on their wedding day.
After a space mission to stop the Cobra Cult
from taking over America, the outsiders traveled
to the subterranean kingdom known as Abyssa,
where Kitana's friend Emily Briggs discovered
her royal heritage and powers, taking on the
codename Looker, and becoming the latest member
to join the team. Eventually, Baron Bedlam
returned to Markovia and kidnapped Princess
Ilona, the fiancée of King Gregor Markov, Geoforce's
older brother. Batman withheld this information
from the team in the hopes that Geoforce would
remain in Gotham, and when the team found out,
Batman was ultimately forced off the team.
After receiving funding from the Kingdom of
Markovia, the Outsiders relocated from Gotham
to Los Angeles, establishing their secret headquarters
in an ocean research lab. After several adventures
and a number of scandals, the Outsiders reunited
with Batman to take on Eclipso. after which
they teamed up with Infinity Inc. after PsychoPirate
attempted to pose as Baron Bedlam in Takeover
Markovia. You can learn more about Eclipso and
PsychoPirate in their respective duels against
Malekith and Mastermind. Due to the team's continual
involvement in international affairs, particularly
in Markovia, the US government began hunting
the outsiders as enemies. It was during this
time that Dr. Helga Jace also betrayed the team,
revealed to be a sleeper agent of the robotic
manhunters. brainwashed Metamorpho into attacking
the team, though he was able to eventually
overcome her control and attacked her instead,
resulting in both his and Dr. Jace's death.
After Looker lost her powers, and Halo went
into a coma after battling the Manhunters,
and with the US government still after them,
the Outsiders decided to disband. The team
members later rejoined for the christening of
Geoforce's nephew, Prince Gregor II, and were
forced to team up again to defend the country
from an army of vampires, which killed an entire
village and placed the blame on the Outsiders,
making them international fugitives. During
this time, the Outsiders took on three new members,
the Sorcerer Faust, the Exosuit-Wearing Technocrat,
the Kryptonian Superman clone Eradicator, and
a man-beared thing named Wild. Ha ha ha. After
defeating the vampires in the Kingdom of Abyssah,
The Outsiders' names were cleared of wrongdoing,
and after some infighting, the teams split into
two factions, one led by Eradicator in Los
Angeles and the other led by Katana in New York.
Eradicator's team clashed with the Feiron Empire,
resulting in widespread destruction and internal
conflicts exacerbated by media distrust and
police intervention. The teams eventually reunited
after dealing with betrayal from Faust and
Wild, who they fought against in a hellish dimension.
Dr. Light and a clone of Terra later joined
the team, though it eventually disbanded. Following
the deaths of several Titans at the hands of
a mysterious android named Indigo, the Titans
team disbanded, leading Arsenal and Nightwing
to form a new incarnation of the Outsiders with
a metamorpho-revenant named Shift, an Amazon
named Grace, Black Lightning's daughter Thunder,
the daughter of Green Lantern Ellen Scott,
Jade, and the android Indigo. Sponsored by Wayne
Enterprises and operating from a Brooklyn bomb
shelter, the team took a proactive approach
to crime fighting by hunting known criminals.
After defeating the likes of the Joker and Brother
Blood, Huntress briefly joined the team along
with Black Lightning and Captain Marvel Jr.
Eventually, Indigo was revealed to be a traitor
and was actually Brainiac 8, leading to the
Outsiders and Titans teaming up to defeat her.
Kitana eventually joined the new team. proving
invaluable when her Soul Sword was able to
absorb and imprison the demon Sabacc. After
Black Lightning was framed for murder, Nightwing
and Red Hood led a failed breakout from Iron
Heights that resulted in numerous deaths. The
team faked their own deaths and continued operating
covertly with a new roster funded by Green
Arrow that now included Captain Boomerang, though
their existence was later exposed by the villainous
Dr. Sivana, and the team was captured by the
government organization Checkmate. who enlisted
them as covert operatives. When one mission
went awry, the team ended up being captured
and tortured in North Korea, forcing Batman
to intervene. Upon their rescue, Nightwing
stepped down as team leader and put Batman back
in charge of the outsiders. Batman's new roster
included Shazam, Martian Manhunter, Catwoman,
the Batgirl Cassandra Kane, and Green Arrow,
with Geoforce and Looker joining the ever-shifting
roster later on as well. When Batman seemingly
died, in his will he ordered Alfred Pennyworth
to assemble a new team of outsiders consisting
of Black Lightning, Creeper, Geoforce, Halo,
Kitana, Metamorpho, and Owlman, who together
worked to stop immortals known as the Insiders
from destroying the planet. After the Flashpoint
reset of DC's continuity, It was revealed that
Batman put together a secret team consisting
of Black Lightning, Metamorpho, Geoforce Kitana,
and Halo to investigate a mystery concerning
specific metals and their ties to the existence
of metahumans, though Black Lightning later
formed his own Outsiders team consisting of
Kitana, Cassandra Cain, and the new hero, Signal,
Gotham City's daytime protector. Now, for my
Outsiders roster, each member of which you
can learn more about in their respective duel
episodes, I will be going with the original
members of Black Lightning, Katana, Metamorpho,
Geoforce, and Halo as each of them have had
recurring memberships on the team throughout
its many incarnations. Noticeably absent on
this roster will be Batman, which seems strange
considering oftentimes the Outsiders comic
is titled Batman and the Outsiders, but it was
for that very reason that to me he felt more
like a benefactor of the group, an outsider
to the Outsiders as it were. And since to me
Batman is more of a Justice Leagueer, the executive
producers and I didn't have too many qualms
about leaving Kim off the team since he has
already been a part of one of our team duels.
Replacing Kim will be Cassandra Cain, aka Batgirl,
or Orphan, or Black Bat, who's been a member
of the team's more recent incarnations. And
lastly, since I didn't have room to include
Roy Harper, aka Arsenal, in our Titans vs X-Men
team duel, I knew I wanted to make sure he
was on the Outsiders, since he was a founder
of a prominent incarnation of the Super Team.
So that's Black Lightning, Kitana, Metamorpho,
Geoforce, Halo, Black Bat, and Arsenal. It's
really interesting how many similarities these
teams have, including the fact that we're substituting
some of the key members of these respective
teams with their young female proteges, including
Black Bat substituting in for Batman and Talon
X-23 substituting in for Wolverine. Yeah, I
also thought it was interesting that they both
had like split versions of the teams that like
battled each other for a bit. Yeah, it's really
strange when all these things start aligning
that you didn't expect to. You find out that
it's an even better idea than anybody even
knew. It's wild when, you know, Marvel essentially
just copies DC. They find all the different
ways in which that's the case. There are clearly
some things that happened in the outsiders
team after they happened to X-Force. So I don't
want to hear it.
Where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
DynaMic Podcast Network presents Console Combat,
where video game legends brawl every Monday.
Comic Book Titans smash every Tuesday, Max Destruction,
where TV and action heroes battle every Wednesday,
and Sendro World, where anime champions clash
every Thursday. Join us as we speculate on
the matches and armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge victorious.
Visit dynamicpodcast.com where we settle the
debate and settle the score.
But now that we got the team's histories and
rosters out of the way, let's speculate on
how one of the 1000 simulated matches will go.
The winner is determined by simulations, not
the speculation, but it's fun to imagine how
the fight could play out. AG and IK, what are
the rules of our speculation? Well, I should
say there are no rules, other than the teams
have no prior knowledge of the other going into
the fight. All they are aware of starting out
is that the other side is a threat that needs
to be eliminated. For the speculation, the
groups will begin approximately 50 meters apart
in a non-descript environment that will have
no bearing on the match itself, as no environmental
statistics are considered in my simulations.
The teams must earn victory on their own merit.
Alright then, let's get into it. The Outsiders
and X-Force meet on the battlefield. Who goes
first? Actually, Deadpool is going to start
off by signaling, time out! He's going to be
like, time out, time out! And he's going to
speak directly to our listeners, and he's going
to be like... You better get your white pants
on nerds, it's gonna get good. And he was like,
alright time in, we can commence with the fighting
now. Okay, before he even finishes that last
sentence though, Arsenal's just gonna shoot
him right in the head with an arrow. So Deadpool
is knocked out and he's gonna fall straight
to the ground. Alright, okay that's fine. Archangel
is gonna spread his metal wings and he's gonna
take into the sky and just rain down a shower
of razor feathers that's gonna slice into the
entire Outsiders team. and poison them with
a neurotoxin that paralyzes them. Ah, okay.
Uh, but Metamorpho, he's gonna stretch his hands
up and he's gonna transform his hands into
a metal shield that protects the outsiders from
those feathers. Okay, so the feathers stick
into Metamorpho's shield, which is his hand,
so the metal feathers are still gonna poison
him and seep into his system. Well, no, because
Metamorpho, he's actually immune to poisons
due to his, you know, composition and he could
reproduce the elemental makeup of whatever
he comes into contact with so in fact he's gonna
reproduce that neurotoxin in his body and become
a poisonous cloud that spreads across the X-Force
team paralyzing them. Okay I'm gonna say that
before Metamorphro can even spread himself out
over the X-Force team Cable's gonna reach out
with his telekinesis to grab this poison cloud
and dissipate him into the sky. So Metamorpho,
he's like in the upper atmosphere now and he's
gonna have to take some time to reconstitute
himself. Meanwhile, Talon, X23, she's gonna
scramble across the battlefield over to Katana
and she's gonna handspring kick her with her
foot claws, just slashing her across the chest.
No, because like in one smooth fluid motion,
Katana is gonna unsheath her sword and just
expertly deflect Talon's foot claws and then
she's gonna... transfer that momentum from
her defensive move into like a counter strike
that is going to slash Talon across her back.
Okay Talon's in pain but she's used to pain
okay and without missing a beat she's gonna
continue her claw fight against Katana's. Really
I assume neither of their blades would break
against each other considering Talon's blades
are adamantium and Katana's blade is magic.
Yeah her sword is unbreakable and it could basically
cut through anything. I'm guessing you're going
to say not adamantium. So yeah, Talon and Katana,
they're going to get it. Meanwhile, Geoforce,
he's going to use his Geokinesis to rip the
ground up into like a series of boulders. And
he's going to hurl those at Warpath, increasing
their gravity to just bury him. Well, no matter
how heavy these boulders are, they're still
made out of earth, right? And Warpath is super
durable and strong. So he's just going to punch
his way out from underneath these boulders.
And then he's going to pick one of them up.
and curl it over at Black Lightning to squashing
him. OK, force field. You know, Black Lightning
throws up his force field, which blocks against,
you know, metal and energy projectiles. So that
does literally nothing to. No, no, no. Boulder's
not made out of metal. It's made out of like
earth, like silicon, right? There's enough
metallic elements in the boulder for it to be
deflected. OK. Anyway, Domino is going to run
over to Deadpool and yank Arsenal's arrow out
of his brain. So Deadpool starts coming to
and he's like back from the dead, just like
Marvel Jesus. And Domino takes Arsenal's arrow
and she's going to hurl it like a dart right
at Black Bat. And the arrow is going to be
aided by Domino's luck powers. So it's just
going to bullseye Black Bat right in the face.
Well, no, because Black Bat, she could just
catch that arrow mid air because she has her
kinesthetic intuition ability. She could read
what Domino's doing and going to. No, no, no.
Luck powers supersede intuition. Okay, so even
though Black Bat tries to catch the arrow,
her bad luck is gonna lead to the arrow just
sticking right into her hand. Those luck powers
are the lamest thing. I hate it, but sure, okay.
Black Bat, you know, her hand gets pierced,
but she's gonna break the arrow off and, you
know, has a hand injury now, but she could
roll with it. Meanwhile, Halo, she's gonna turn
the color indigo and she's gonna put Deadpool.
into a energy field, a tractor beam, and she's
just gonna hurl him toward the horizon, just
away from the battlefield. Are you gonna let
him do anything during this match? I think,
in fact, he actually yells those exact words
as he disappears from view. He's gonna be like,
are you gonna let me do anything, Johnny DC,
you cock knocker? Nope. Meanwhile, Psylocke,
using her stealth, she's gonna sneak up behind
Geoforce, and she's gonna plunge her psychic
knife right into the back of his head. stunning
him. Okay, but Geoforce, he's not going to
be stunned for long because her hand gets knocked
away from Geoforce's head with a boxing glove
arrow from Arsenal's quiver, and he's going
to follow that up by firing two cryo arrows
like in quick succession at her feet, trapping
her in place. Big deal. She's going to break
out of the ice by shattering it with her telekinesis,
and then she's going to hurl a telepathic blade
at Arsenal, and you know, he's going to try
to because that's what he does, but he's not
going to know that her blade is psychic energy.
And so he's not going to be able to do anything
about it. And the psychic blade hits him and
he gets mentally knocked out. Meanwhile, Deadpool,
he's going to come back onto the scene with
Archangel who went to go get him. And Deadpool
is writing Archangel kind of like Sebastian
at the end of the never ending story. He's
going to be like, Falcor is wonderful. And he
leaps off of Archangel's back. You know, he's
going to do a superhero landing next to Black
Bat, and he's going to pull out his swords
and be like, Hello, Black Bat, I'm White Wade
Wilson. Is your power cultural appropriation?
Dude, he doesn't even know what race she is.
It doesn't matter. OK. I'm not going to lie.
Like Deadpool's body language is probably super
challenging for Black Bat to read. I imagine
he's pretty unpredictable. So she's disoriented.
And because of that, she's going to throw down
a pellet with knockout gas that just puts him
to sleep. All right. Once again, before he
gets to do anything, you're trying to take him
down. So Deadpool falls asleep. And as he's
dozing off, he's probably going to be like,
don't hurt me, Liam Neeson or something. Well,
by this point, Metamorpho has reconstituted
and, you know, seeing Katana and Talon battling.
He's gonna turn the lower half of his body into
a straight jacket that just wraps around Talon,
while the upper half of his body is still in
his standard form, except for his hands. He's
gonna turn those into mallets and he's just
gonna pummel Talon mercilessly. Okay, so Talon
is in a straight jacket and getting beat up,
but a straight jacket's not gonna cover her
legs. So while Metamorpho thinks he has her
restrained, she's just gonna kick her leg up
and slice off both of his hammer hands. with
her foot claws and then she escapes the straitjacket.
Meanwhile, Cable is gonna pull out his BFG.
You know what that stands for? Big Friendly
Giant. Stands for Big Fucking Gun, man. It's
a giant energy rifle and Cable's gonna use
it to shoot a hail of energy rounds at GeoForce,
just perforating the guy. Okay, well I mean,
how well does a BFG stand up against a BFV?
A big fucking volcano. That's what's gonna
erupt from the ground around Geoforce, blocking
Cable's blasts. And Geoforce, he's in the center
of this, like 30 foot tall mountain that shoots
him into the sky as it erupts. And from the
air, Geoforce is gonna bombard Cable with beams
of magma. So Geoforce creates a volcano that
shoots him up into the air? Yeah. That's pretty
cool. But if it's only 30 feet tall, that sounds
more like a little baby volcano than a big fucking
volcano. Whatever. But Cable's gonna throw
up a telekinetic shield to block the magma and
you know, the sky's Archangel's domain So that
was stupid like Geo Force is focused on burning
up Cable when all of a sudden he gets sliced
in half by Archangel's metal wings and Geo Force
is the first one out in this match. What? No,
I thought he was gonna be like my last one He's
like my most powerful guy Okay. Well, I do
have one question for you Do you know what happens
to an angel when it's struck by lightning?
It croaks. The same thing that happens to everything
else. Cause that's exactly what's gonna happen
to Archangel. Black Lightning, you know, he
saw what happened to Geoforce. And since Archangel's
wings are made of metal, he's like a great conductor
of electricity. So Black Lightning channels
this massive lightning bolt that just completely
fries Archangel to a crisp in the sky. So Archangel
is out as well. All right, okay. Well, I'm going
to say that the thunder from Black Lightning's
lightning bolt is going to wake up Deadpool
and Arsenal, who was, you know, knocked out
by Psylocke. And Deadpool sits up and he's going
to be like, where did that little baby volcano
come from? Oh, my God. Are those twin gold plated
desert eagles you're carrying? And he's going
to point at Arsenal's guns and Arsenal's going
to look down at his holster and he's going
to be like, uh, no. Well, Deadpool's like, I
need them for my collection. And he's going
to teleport over to Arsenal and right away slice
off his gun holster with his swords and knock
the guns up into the air. And Deadpool's going
to catch him and just pump Arsenal full of
lead. And then Deadpool's going to be like,
wait, these aren't gold. Okay. Well, as Deadpool
comes to that realization, the guns actually
get sliced in half, followed up by his own
decapitation, all thanks to Katana's soul taker
sword. So Deadpool's out of the match. Fine.
Meanwhile, Metamorpho, who just regrew his hands,
he hears a beeping sound. And he realizes that
a sticky explosive mine has been thrown onto
his back. And he's going to spin around and
see Domino is the one who threw the mine. And
with a smile, she's going to shoot right through
Metamorpho, hitting the explosive that stuck
to his back in this unbelievably lucky shot.
and the mine is gonna detonate with a sizable
explosion that just sends chunks of metamorpho
scattered across the battlefield. All right.
So, Halo sees this and goes on the offensive
against Domino. She turns yellow and flashes
at Domino, blinding her, which I believe negates
Domino's luck powers since they depend on her
vision, right? Right. So, bad luck for Domino,
Halo then turns red and just beams at giant
hole right through Domino's torso, taking her
out of the match. Good one. That was good. Well,
Warpath saw what Halo did, and he just throws
his vibranium knives like two tomahawks right
at Halo and the knives impale her and take
her out of this match, too. Yeah, no, the Halo
Warpath threw his knives at just dissipated
into blue light when the blades went through
her because there was a hologram created by
Halo. And that's when Black Bat She's going
to swoop in and stealthily land on Warpath's
shoulders. And before he could do anything,
she's going to be striking nerve points across
his body in rapid succession, just paralyzing
Kim and making him useless for the rest of
the match. OK, well, Psylocke sees this and
she jumps in and fights Black Bat, you know,
ninja versus ninja. And like maybe Black Bat
gets a few good hits in there. But suddenly.
Black Bat realizes she can't read Psylocke's
moves anymore because her mind is all fuzzy.
And that's because Psylocke telepathically clouds
her brain. And then she deals her coup de grace
with a telekinetic sword right through Black
Bat's torso. So Black Bat's gone. And you know
what? I'm not even angry. Black Bat went out
with honor, but not by Psylocke. Before Psylocke
could deal the final blow, Katana's Soul Sword
warned her of Black Bat's imminent death. And
so Katana, she moved really quick over to Black
Bat and made sure that she trapped Cassandra's
soul and her sword by delivering that killing
blow. And that's going to give Katana not only
Black Bat's kinesthetic intuition, but also
her martial arts mastery and knowledge of Psylocke's
psychic powers. And since Katana's sword can
block things that are immaterial, like psychic
blades, the two are just going to clash and
sword on sword action. But ultimately, with
Black Bat's aid, Katana's gonna come on top
and she's just gonna impale Psylocke with her
sword and steal her soul as well. That doesn't
make any sense. So Katana took out her own
teammate in order to get her teammates abilities.
It's like friendly seppuku, okay? But just
because Katana would be aware then that Psylocke
probably has psychic powers, that doesn't make
her immune to Psylocke's psychic attacks. Wha-
Katana can't be easily affected psychically
because the soul of her husband talks to her
all the time through the sword, you know, feeding
her information, and he'd warn her and tell
her how to move and dodge and parry and slash
and stuff if Psylocke tried to affect Katana
psychically, like through illusions or clouding
or anything like that. Uh, okay, alright. If
you say so. I do! I think that's a reach. Uh,
so suddenly Katana dies. because Cable lifts
her up by her neck with his metal tech arm
and just snaps the life out of her. Dude, she
would literally slice that metal arm right
the hell off before he could even do that. Not
if Cable telekinetically keeps her from swinging
that sword. Fuck! So she's out. Meanwhile, Talon
is going up against Halo. And Halo, you know,
she could probably block Talon's attacks with
her orange force field. But Cable has the ability
to... telepathically compel Halo to drop her
forcefield. And that's gonna leave her vulnerable
to Talon, who just rips Halo to shreds. No!
Okay, well, you know what's cool though? Both
of your guys that are left, Cable and Talon,
they have conductive metal throughout their
body. So while Cable is busy with Katana and
Halo, his metal arm just gets slammed with
millions of volts of electricity from Black
Lightning. who also is going to chain that
off of him to Talon. So both of them basically
get electrocuted to death. And bam, Black Lightning
emerges victorious. Oh, you think so? OK, right?
Well, Black Lightning thinks that he's won.
A little Deadpool emerges looking like a naked
troll doll with a mask on because his decapitated
head is regrowing his body. And like a weird
baby, he stumbles over to Cable's body. and
steals his time travel device and he uses it
to travel through time and the multiverse and
he's gonna pop back onto the battlefield the
moment he left with a whole legion of Deadpool
variants, the Deadpool core and Deadpool's gonna
lead them into battle he's gonna be like FOR
FREEDOM and they're gonna swarm black lightning
and just massacre the guy like it's not pretty
and then with the battle over Deadpool says
to our listeners those shit fucks down the
street never stood a chance and he does the
X salute and he's like X force match over.
Except that as he's doing the salute he's gonna
get clocked by Shift which is a sentient Metamorpho
remnant who was a part of the Outsiders for
a time and you know he turned his fist into
an anvil and just punches the lights out of
Deadpool and in fact actually with all the
scattered pieces of Metamorpho around the battlefield
there's an army of shifts just ready to take
on the Deadpool core. So good luck with that.
I'm going to say that Metamorpho was blown
up into two smaller pieces to actually form
an army of Metamorphos. Metamorpho has like
literally been vaporized multiple times and
he's always come back. So has Deadpool. Unless
you have like a magic sorcerer supreme Deadpool
because that's really the only way Metamorpho
can be taken out is magically. Then I think
this match would just basically go on forever.
I'm sorry to tell you one of the Deadpool variants
is the Sorcerer Supreme. So there you go. And
I think you're making that shit up. Well, we
could go ahead and leave the match there. Either
the Deadpool core beats this legion of Metamorphos
or the Metamorphos beat the Deadpool core.
We'll go ahead and input the stats on all these
characters, run the simulations and see which
team came out on top. AJ9K, hit it! Inputting
data, running calculations. Processing results.
Simulations complete. All right, this was a
great matchup. These teams are very, very close.
They were close thematically. They were close
in terms of their backstories, and they're
even close statistically. Cable was by far the
most powerful member out of either of these
groups. But the outsiders were no slouch either.
Black Lightning, Metamorpho, Geoforce, they
were all heavy hitters. Yeah, Geoforce was my
heaviest, followed closely behind by Metamorpho,
and Black Lightning was just under him. Yeah,
actually both Geoforce and Metamorpho won around
3 fourths of all of their matches, and Black
Lightning won about 3 fifths of his matches.
Cable, though, won like 4 out of 5 of all his
matches, but the rest of my guys didn't do
as well. Like, Deadpool, Psylocke, Archangel,
they all came out around the same statistically.
winning just about half of their matchups. My
second most powerful guy was actually Warpath,
who won a little bit over half of his matchups.
Yeah, not too many of my team members were
around that 50 percent mark. I had some that
were either like three fourths winning or one
fourth winning. So, you know, it varied quite
a bit. My weakest character by far, surprisingly,
was Kitana. Yeah, she's not impressive statistically,
is she? No, not even compared to some of your
weaker characters. She only won one fifth out
of every match, basically. Yeah, if you think
about it, Katana has the ability to steal your
soul if she kills you, right? But like, as
a superpower, that's kind of lame because you'd
be dead anyway, right? It was a power that
didn't help her in the stats, really. In terms
of the overall team stats, the biggest discrepancy
between these two teams was fighting skill.
and versatility. Like the outsiders were way
more versatile than the X-Force who are mainly
just you know like shoot and stab guys, but
X-Force was much more trained in hand-to-hand
combat than the outsiders. Which is wild because
I feel like I had the best fighter in Black
Bat. Yeah you had Black Bat and Katana, but
you also had Halo who really brought your team
down. Whereas everyone in X-Force is like an
expert fighter almost. X-Force also had the
edge in durability and strength but the outsiders
had the edge in damage level and range. So taking
all this into consideration, Jonathan, considering
how close things are, who do you see coming
out on top here? Well, it's definitely closer
than I thought it was going to be. I thought
the outsiders were totally going to stomp,
but I think the outsiders are still going to
come out ahead just barely. Instagram does
not agree with me. Apparently X-Force is the
more popular team. 62% of our poll takers sided
with Marvel for this team match. And I'm ready
to prove them all wrong. I don't know, they
sound pretty right to me, but let's go ahead
and find out. AJ9K, the results please. Here
you are, sir. Alright the winner between the
Outsiders and X-Force is... X-Force! Damn it!
Suck on that! X-Force wins! It was really damn
close though. Out of 1000 matches, X-Force
won 509. whereas the outsiders won 491, basically
a coin toss between these two teams. That is
shocking. Again, I did not think it was gonna
be this close. Me and the DC guys on Discord
were like, oh yeah, outsiders is totally gonna
take this one. Haha, Marvel's stupid. I mean,
Marvel's still stupid. But then who turned out
to be stupid, right? Is that what you're gonna
say? No. I am super pleased with these results.
I think X-Horse is just too badass of a team
to lose. to a bunch of nobodies like outsiders
like who the hell has ever heard of Halo? Not
me. Uh, I'm pretty sure more people have heard
of Halo than fucking Warpath. Warpath was in
X-Men Days of Future Past. Okay? All of my guys
on the X-Force team have been in movies. Oh,
and guess what? Halo has been in Young Justice
Outsiders. So that again, that's a fucking
cartoon that nobody's watched. Marvel's just
more popular. and they're stronger and in this
case just better overall. But not better looking
because you guys have Deadpool. Sure, but who
cares? He kicked ass this match. Who really
wins? DC. All right. You got to take what you
can get, I suppose. Oh, we will. We will. But
that does it for this team duel, guys. AJ and
IK, help close this out. Thanks for listening
to Dynamic duel. Visit the show's website at
dynamicduel.com and follow us on Instagram at
dynamicduelpodcast. You can support the show
on Patreon at patreon.com slash dynamicduel
and joining a tier that works for you, or by
rating and reviewing Dynamic duel on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, Podchaser or on our website. Don't
forget to listen to the other shows in the DynaMic
Podcast Network, including Max Destruction,
Senjow World and Console Combat. In our next
episode, we will be doing a review of Batman
Caped Crusader season one. It's an animated
series done by Bruce Tim that's currently on
Amazon Prime. I have not started watching it,
but you're going to hear all about what I think
about it in our next episode. But that does
it for this episode. We want to give a big
thanks to our executive producers, Ken Johnson,
John Sturowski, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Belcombe,
Miggye Mathagian. Brandon Estergard, Nathaniel
Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Austin Wazilowski, AJ
Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam
Spies, Andrew Schunk, Dean Molesky, Devin Davis,
Joseph Kirsting, and Josh Leiner for helping
to make this podcast possible. We'll talk to
you guys next week. Up up and away, true believers.
I wore my white pants for that episode, but
then I remembered it's after Labor Day and now
I'm just devastated.