Quick heads up at the top of the episode guys,
this month podchaser.com is teaming up with
World Central Kitchen to provide food supplies
for Ukraine as part of their Hashtag Chefs
for Ukraine initiative. This will provide meals
to individuals and families fleeing the current
crisis there. For every review of our podcast
or one of our episodes, Podchaser will donate
25 cents to World Central Kitchen. And another
25 cents. when Joseph and I respond to your
review, which we will do. So rate Dynamic Duel
at podchaser.com slash Dynamic Duel if you
haven't already. Or rate your favorite episodes.
We'll respond to you and together we'll help
fight world hunger and help those in need in
Ukraine. Again, that's podchaser.com slash
Dynamic Duel. On with the show!
Welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin brother Marvelous
Joe. In this episode, we will be reviewing
the long-delayed Morbius film produced by Sony
Pictures. Now, a lot of you may be surprised
in this upcoming review to hear that I actually
didn't hate it. Yeah, I went in with the lowest
of expectations and I was actually looking forward
to like hating on the film. But we'll get into
our thoughts later on in the episode. Before
that, we're going to break down the comic book
movie news from the past week. Of which there
is just one big movie related news item and
that is that Sharon Stone is going to play the
villain Victoria Kord in the Blue Beetle movie.
It was a pretty slow news week. It seemed like
all of the Hollywood news was about Will Smith
and like Ezra Miller. I mean the Ezra Miller
news does sort of affect the DCEU. but it wasn't
specific to the flash, so we're not really gonna
talk about it. As always, we list our segment
times in our episode description, so feel free
to check out the show notes if you wanna skip
ahead to a particular topic. And don't forget,
guys, to join us on Patreon, where we offer
ad-free episodes of the show via a custom RSS
feed, bonus content, including top 10 episodes
and bloopers, monthly live movie watch-alongs,
and access to our Discord chat server. Check
it out right after this episode at patreon.com
slash dynamicduel. linked in our show notes.
Our lowest tier is only $2 a month. But with
that out of the way, quick to the no prize.
A no prize is an award Marvel used to give out
up until the 90s to fans. Our version, the
dynamic dual no prize, is a digital award we
post on social media that Jonathan sometimes
draws for those who we feel gave the best answer
to our question of the week. That's fair. I
am very, very behind. like a month behind on
these No Prize illustrations. Just I want to
apologize to everyone who's won a No Prize in
the past month. I'm working on them. I have
some of the illustrations done, not all of them.
I'm trying to put all of them up all at once.
I think the listeners deserve to know why you're
so behind. So Joseph and I used to work together.
He recently abandoned me, so I have more responsibilities
at work. And just life in general, I got a
new house. I'm doing a lot of work on the house
on the weekends. It's I have less free time,
but that's not a good excuse. And I need to
get on those drawings. I know. I know. I'm
sorry, guys. You're right. It's not a good excuse.
I said that. I said that. Anyway, last week,
we asked the question, should the deleted scene
in The Batman with Joker have been in the movie?
or not and why. And of course this was related
to the deleted scene that Matt Reeves posted
to social media that we all got to see involving
the Joker and Batman in Arkham Asylum. We got
quite a few answers. Let's go through our list
of honorable mentions before we announce this
no prize winner. Our first honorable mention
goes to John Spies who said, Hi gentlemen,
Executive Producer John Spies here. Not only
should the deleted scene not have appeared
in the movie. But the whole Joker cameo was
completely unnecessary. It added nothing to
the story, only to add for fan service, and
to be honest, we're a little oversaturated
with the Joker right now. So honestly, he's
got a whole rogues gallery. Give us something
new. Do you think that the Joker was included
in the Batman movie as fan service? Oh yeah,
totally. I agree with John. I don't think there
was really any reason for him to be in the
movie and even the deleted scene. save for fanservice.
It is great to know that he exists in that
universe and I definitely would have been questioning
where's the Joker if he didn't appear in the
movie as a fan, but that being said I understand
it's there only for the fans and wasn't there
for the story. I've gone back and forth as to
whether or not this should be in the film and
you know acknowledging the fact that it is fanservice
is a pretty good reason. John of course is
the co-host of the Blast from Our Past podcast,
which he does with his brother Adam Spies.
Both John and Adam are actually going to be
guests on our podcast in just a couple of weeks.
You may remember them from our past episodes
like our X-Men Origins Wolverine review and
our review of the 1960s Batman movie with Adam
West. I love both of those episodes. I can't
wait to have these guys back on our show. Yeah,
it'll be a great time. Our next honorable mention
goes to Rick, who said... Hey guys, Rick here.
I think it was super necessary to pull such
an unnecessary scene from the movie. When I
say that, I don't mean I didn't like the character.
I loved his betrayal and take on the Joker.
I just don't think he did anything to really
move the story they were trying to tell along.
I think it was a very character saturated movie
already. And I think those characters did a
fantastic job of advancing the story they were
trying to tell. I hope to see him more. I hope
to see him in future movies. I just don't think
he belonged in this one and I'm glad they pulled
the scene. Yeah, I thought Barry Keegan did
a fantastic job as the Joker. I thought that
take on the Joker was really, really super
interesting. But again, it really didn't service
the story. Just like John said, what do you
think will come first? A sequel to the Batman
or a sequel to the Joker? Like, when do you
think we'll see this character again? Oh, snap.
That's a good question. I feel like a sequel
to the Joker will come up sooner because I feel
like Todd Phillips and Joaquin Phoenix have
been working on that for a while. Honestly,
though. I don't know if I need a sequel to
the Joker. In fact, I know I don't. I'm really
hoping we get to see a sequel to the Batman
and never see a sequel to the Joker. I think
that's a great standalone story. Just let that
one exist on its own. Yeah, I think I agree
with that for sure. Great answer, Rick. Our
final honorable mention goes to Jacob Bell,
who said. Hey guys, this is Jacob Bell. I may
have submitted this answer too late, but either
way, I think it should have been in the movie.
I think it was a great scene and I think ultimately
the reason it should have been in the movie
is because that kind of scene would have been
in the comics. Like if that movie was a comic
or whatever, that kind of scene would have been
in the comic absolutely and that's just how
the source material is so I think it should
have been in the movie. Yeah, I'm old enough
to remember back when they did like novelizations
of these comic book superhero films and they
would always have like extra scenes. They still
may make these books. I'm actually not sure.
But yeah, this feels like this scene would have
been in one of those stories, just one of those
extra scenes and definitely in a comic book,
because, you know, in comics, you're not limited
by time like you are in a film. You're limited
by page counts. Right. Exactly. But you're
also allowed to tell a really long story over
a span of a month over a year rather than just.
within a few hours. I did really like the scene
as I mentioned last week when we talked about
it. I thought it was a fantastic scene that
really did justice to the Joker and portrayed
him in a way that we haven't seen him in a really
long time on film. Just like literally the
smartest guy in the room and just like a total
psychological threat for Batman. Yeah thanks
Jacob Bell. A lot of great answers here. We
want to give big thanks to Wilfright, Bodhi,
Simone Bermudez and John Storosky for also taking
the time to visit our website. Click that record
button and leave your answer. But the no prize
for this week goes to Benjamin Alves who said
Hey John and Joe, so I think the Joker scene
should have been in the movie because like
it gave out too much of the story and it like,
I don't know, I feel like it would be better
if the Joker just wasn't in this movie or like
they teased it with um the Joker card like
in Batman Begins. Like, yeah, that's it. Bye
guys. Yeah, honestly, I think I would have
been happier with like a Joker tease, maybe
not the card, because we've already had that,
than the scene that we got in the movie. The
deleted scene, I agree with Benjamin, did reveal
too much of the story. Like the Joker gave away
that the Riddler's motive was vengeance before
we would have even known that, right? And the
fact that he was able to figure it out so quickly.
ahead of Batman just made Batman look like he
wasn't that smart. And that scene kind of took
away from what made the scene between Batman
and the Riddler so special in Arkham. Right,
right. Those scenes took place like in almost
literally the same location, right? So it's
hard not to compare both of them. And I really,
really liked Paul Dano's performance in that
scene. It was so haunting, so weird. But you
can also see the same thing about the Joker
scene. So it wouldn't quite make sense to have.
two kinds of scenes that were so similar in
the same movie. I do wish they would have taken
the Joker completely out of the film and just
saved him for later. And that's why Benjamin
Alvis gets this week's win. Yeah, congrats
Benjamin for winning this week's No Prize. If
you the listener want a shot at winning Giro
No Prize, stay tuned to later on this episode
when we'll be asking another question of the
week. And now that that's done, on to the news!
Okay, last week we learned that Sharon Stone
will be playing Victoria Cord, who I guess
is the villain in the upcoming Blue Beetle movie
that will be starring Sholo Maritwenya. I'm
really looking forward to this movie and I've
been wondering who the main villain was going
to be and I'm actually really surprised to hear
that it's an original character named Victoria
Cord. Now it sounds like she is related to the
character Ted Cord. You know, either his mother
or maybe his wife or something like that. Or
maybe a gender swap. It could be that too.
Yeah, they may be gender swapping Ted Kord into
Victoria Kord, which would be interesting.
I would also hate it, but it would be interesting.
Ted Kord, if you're not familiar with him,
is the second Blue Beetle, actually DC Comics'
first Blue Beetle, because Blue Beetle, of
course, is a legacy character that was taken
from Charlton Comics, which DC acquired in
the 80s. Yeah, Ted Kord's version of Blue Beetle
was like this inventor kind of gadgeteer type
character. He was the head of Kord Industries.
I'm wondering if Victoria is going to be the
head of Kord Industries in this upcoming movie.
And that's just speculation. But if that's
the case, I get heavy Catwoman movie vibes from
this casting, because of course, Sharon Stone
was the villain in the Catwoman movie with Halle
Berry. You know, but also she was probably
the best part of that movie in a way. I think
she's a fantastic actress. You know, I still
remember her from films like Basic Instinct.
Did you say Basic Instinct? Of course, who'd
forget that? No, but I do think she should be
working more than she is. I know she was almost
cast in a Marvel movie. Wasn't she almost going
to be cast as Janet Van Dyne? Yeah, before
Michelle Pfeiffer got the role. See, I would
have loved to have seen Sharon Stone over Michelle
Pfeiffer in that role, just so we could have.
Michael Douglas Sharon Stone reunion. But I
really hope Victoria Cord is like Ted Cord's
sister or something like that and maybe they're
both vying for the head of the company. Initially
when I heard about this casting I didn't know
her name was Victoria Cord. I automatically
thought that she was going to play the character
Ladama from the Blue Beetle comics. She's like
a mob boss, this urban legend like no one is
quite sure if she's real or not and she's into
the occult. That's right she was in the recent
Cat Omen hunted animated movie that we reviewed.
Right yep. was her. And you know, for all I
know, maybe that's secretly who Victoria Cord
is. Hopefully, let's not have a spoiler for
anyone. But we'll see. I don't actually know
any of Blue Beetle's rogues gallery. Like,
is there a character that you wish would have
been the villain of this instead of Victoria
Cord? I mean, ultimately, Jaime Reyes, his Blue
Beetle scarab, has alien origins from this
alien race known as the Reach. I imagine that
ultimately they will be the ultimate
occultism, Ladama will be involved with like,
I don't know, black market alien weaponry from
the Reach or something like that. And she wants
the scarab for herself. This is all speculation,
who knows. But yeah, the Reach would make sense
for the character. If Sharon Stone turns out
to not be like a version of Ladama and she actually
is a gender swapped version of Ted Kord, it
would be interesting to see like a female version
of the Blue Beetle character. But if Ted Kord
is in the movie, well, that just brings us to
our question of the week.
Who would you cast as Ted Kord in the Blue Beetle
movie? Record your answer at dynamicduel.com
by clicking on the red microphone button in
the bottom right-hand corner, which will prompt
you to leave us a voicemail. Your message could
be up to 30 seconds long, and don't forget
to leave your name in case we include you on
the podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer
and draw that person a Dynamic Duel No Prize
that we'll post to social media. Be sure to
answer before April 9th. But I think that does
it for all the news for this episode, so let's
go ahead and get into our main event. where
we review the latest Sony Pictures Spider-Man
Universe film, Morbius.
Okay, so Morbius came out this past week, finally,
after being delayed several times from its
initial July 2020 release date, largely due
to the COVID-19 pandemic. Like Venom and Venom
Let There Be Carnage, the film is part of Sony's
Spider-Man universe that is adjacent to the
MCU and indirectly associated with Spider-Man.
When the Morbius film was first announced,
I was bummed because, let's be real, Sony doesn't
know what they're doing. and they're only holding
onto the Spider-Man film rights to make money,
not because they care about these characters
or about making great movies. So in this film
kept getting pushed back. Honestly, I didn't
really care. And my anticipation for it was
nonexistent. Oh, yeah, dude, you think yours
was nonexistent. Mine was like beyond negative
nonexistent. Like if this film never came out,
I would have been thrilled. Like I would joke.
that the movie was gonna be amazing and make
trillions of dollars. And I was doing that ironically,
because honestly I didn't have any faith that
this film was gonna be good. My expectations
could not be lower unless I guess they were
yours. Right. But I think that was definitely
to the movie's benefit, because not only did
I find that the movie was not terrible, I thought
it was actually pretty decent, similar to how
I found the first Venom film or the new Mutants.
So despite what I thought the movie would be
and how many critics are coming down on it,
I would in fact recommend the movie if you
have even the slightest inclination to see it.
To me this is like a perfect streaming film,
like don't pay extra to see it at least. But
check it out on streaming if you want to waste
a couple of hours of your life. I mean also
check it out if you like vampire movies or
if you like Jared Leto or Matt Smith or great
visual effects or if you're a fan of Morbius
as a character. There are plenty of reasons.
to watch this movie. And if you haven't seen
it, I would suggest stop listening to this review
because we're going to be discussing spoilery
plot points from the movie, see the movie first,
then come back and compare your thoughts with
ours. Now I'm not going to say that this is
a great film by any means, but in this day
and age, it does seem like people will trash
something as a dumpster fire if it doesn't
absolutely blow them away. And I'm like, let's
be realistic. Quality is a spectrum. It's not
black or white. There are plenty of middling
films out there. that could be worth your time
depending on what your tastes are. Now Morbius
is not Avengers Infinity War, but it's not
Catwoman either. And I honestly think people
who know the character of Morbius in the comics
would be hard pressed to come up with a much
better film for him given his backstory. Honestly
this is probably almost as good of a Morbius
film as you're gonna get where it has a PG-13
rating and no Spider-Man involvement. Because
we both know changing either of those things
would have made this better. Yeah, totally.
I mean, I've seen so much hate online for this
movie. A lot of it for me, honestly. But after
having seen it, I don't get the hate from people
who have seen the movie, I guess. I mean, the
movie reminded me a lot of a superhero film
from when I was a kid, you know, in the 90s
and early 2000s. Just check your brain at the
door kind of entertainment, right? We get into
debates over the value of entertainment all
the time. To me it comes secondary to story,
but Marvel fans can't seem to get enough of
it. Which is why I'm wondering why so many Marvel
fans have turned on this film. Like what kind
of film were you expecting with a character
like Morbius? Well I mean, the movie does have
a lot of issues. We'll definitely talk about
them as we go through this review. I'll start
off by saying that the marketing of the film
was an utter shit show. Oh totally. Not only
did the trailers fail to get people excited
for the movie, they didn't adequately represent
the movie. A lot of what you've seen in the
trailers ended up on the cutting room floor,
including a lot of Jared Harris's role, Tyrese's
role, you know, there was no bionically enhanced
arm here, and the meeting between Morbius and
Michael Keaton's vulture, which I know a lot
of people were anticipating. Yeah, it really
makes you wonder what this movie would have
looked like if it came out before No Way Home.
Right, they may have resulted in a lot of the
changes here. Now, I try not to hold the marketing
of a film against the final product. But it's
clear that this movie got edited a lot. And
that may be a good thing after all, considering
the movie was actually better than the trailers
made it out to be. I'm guessing the studio
identified and removed some of the film's early
problems, which is good, but yeah, it's cut
up. And the movie is not long either because
of that. It's only about an hour and 44 minutes
and it moves at a pretty brisk pace. And in
a way, I would almost describe this film as
the anti-The Batman. where nothing lasts longer
than necessary. And I think a lot of people
that did not like the Batman will probably really
like this film. Well, I think a Venn diagram
of people who think that and also like ate paste
as a child is like a perfect circle. Ha ha
ha.
I guarantee you they do. Uh, no, I mean, I don't
think the movie is quite as dumb as you're
portraying it. You know, when I did a deep dive
of reading into the character of Morbius during
our duel episode where we pit him against Manbat,
I found that Morbius is one of Marvel's most,
if not the most tragic character because not
only has he experienced a lot of the tremendous
loss and unbearable circumstances that a lot
of heroes go through. Specifically, he was
like a good man and doctor who became a monster
compelled to kill. He can't control himself,
he can't cure himself, and because of his healing
factor, he can't die, not even from traditional
weapons due to his technically non-supernatural
status. So he lives as this pitiable soul in
the comics who tries to make the best of his
situation by combating evil. And I felt that
if this movie was going to be any good, it really
had to convey that tragic theme. of being forced
into essentially committing murder in order
to live. And while elements of that were here,
I think this film addressed the issue mostly
indirectly. The only innocent people he killed
were on the boat, and their innocence kind of
is up for speculation given that they were
mercenaries. Yeah, the film basically went out
of its way to tell you that, hey, these guys
probably deserve to die. Yeah. Yeah, they're
not good guys. But to the film's credit, it
did introduce some interesting devices to Morbius's
mythology. One of which was like the synthetic
blood. And that kind of served as like a ticking
time bomb in the movie, where once that temporary
solution had run its course, he would become
the uncontrollable murderer. But also in this
movie, if he didn't drink the synthetic blood
and he drank real blood, he would also become
uncontrollable, like go into this bloody drunken
rage. So it was tricky. And then of course,
in this film, he also developed a means of killing
vampires like himself with that iron rich anticoagulant,
which was pretty nice because he never came
up with that in the books. So while like this
wasn't quite the story of an uncontrollable
killer, it did bring some interesting ideas
to the table to sidestep that. And the consequences
of his failure still felt very real. I think
the film did a good job introducing what Morbius
would be like if things were taken to their
worst. You know, we had Milo as an example.
Yeah, absolutely. He was essentially what the
consequences would be. And it's just a cold,
ruthless killer. Morbius did not want to be
that. And though he has resorted to drinking
the blood of innocents in the comic books from
time to time, you know, he started out as a
Spider-Man villain after all, his whole arc
has always involved trying to prevent that.
He feels extreme guilt over those vampiric
actions. So at least they captured that in this
movie. But I think what surprised me most about
this film was the quality of its special effects,
actually. Because I didn't think they'd be
very good from the trailers. Specifically though,
in the quality of its body effects. The visual
effects that were around during the time of
Captain America, the first Avenger, we've gone
way past that. Because in that movie, like the
pre-serum Steve Rogers, sometimes looked like
Chris Evans disembodied head on a scrawny dude's
shoulders, you know? Wait, like Bobblehead?
Yeah, yeah, the scenes of like Jared Leto like
laying on the table in the freighter. That
was seamless. I was like, dang, like Jared Leto
must not have eaten for like a few months to
do that scene. You know, and he's done stuff
like that for roles, but it seems like he may
not have to do that ever again because the special
effects are so good here. They can make actors
bodies look like whatever they want to. He went
from an emaciated guy in the beginning to like
a male underwear model without really any suspension
of disbelief. Oh, yeah, totally. I think the
seamless and subtle way Morbius and Milo would
transform into their vampire forms was also
really impressive and kind of disturbing even.
Like Matt Smith's vampire face in particular
was the stuff of nightmares for me. Like so
much so that when the camera would linger on
it, I'd get uncomfortably creeped out. But also,
I think that's as far as the great special
effects went. I don't know if I would agree
with you in saying that this film's special
effects were that great. It was a little cartoonish.
I think they could have taken it a step further.
Well, I mean like when they weren't actively
flying around and smashing into things. I think
their look was really well done. Let's go ahead
and move into the character breakdown. Starting
with Michael Morbius who is played by Jared
Leto. And let me start off by saying I can't
stand Jared Leto. The guy is pretentious as
fuck. He almost ruined the concerts that I
went to at Red Rocks. I won't get into it, but
he was really drunk and made like the audience
sing all the words to his 30 seconds to Mars
songs. Yes, I don't have too much against the
guy. I feel like You've been hanging that over
his head for as long as I can remember. Honestly,
though, I thought he was perfect for this role.
I thought he did a fantastic job as Morbius.
Yeah, I mean, the guy can act no matter how
I feel about him. You know, outside of the
Joker, I should say. I think he's a fantastic
actor and, you know, he has the accolades to
prove it. From Rokuiem for a Dream and Dallas
Buyers Club. I was very satisfied with his
performance here, and I really liked him in
the role as much as I didn't want to. He just
has a very subtle acting technique that is pretty
effective, I think. I think it helps in the
fact that Jared Leto is a literal vampire, and
the fact that he's 50 years old and looks like
he's 29. Yeah, he's definitely been drinking
the blood of innocence or something like that.
Yes, yes. There's no other explanation. Now
in regards to the character, I think Morbius
is probably one of the easier characters to
get right in terms of motivation, because it's
very straightforward. You know, he develops...
the experimental bat treatment because he wants
to live essentially, and then he becomes a pseudo
vampire and fights evil because it's the only
way his conscience can tolerate his murderous
nature. Here it's more about stopping one evil,
in particular his best friend Milo, who took
the serum he developed and so he feels some
responsibility in stopping. So the main storyline
is easy to understand where he's coming from,
but at the end of the movie... It wasn't quite
clear what his plan was in regards to his thirst
now that the synthetic blood was ineffective,
or what his plan in general was, whether it
was to look for a new treatment, or become an
anti-hero, or what. Now yeah, the movie really
started and ended with Milo. Once that whole
arc was wrapped up, the movie ended pretty
abruptly. Yeah, for sure. I guess, ultimately,
he's joining the Sinister Six, but like, who
knows what their goals are outside of defeating
Spider-Man? who I'm not even sure exists within
this universe. Well, Morbius seemed to know
who he was. Yeah, he didn't question it. But
also he didn't really say anything to the vulture
at the end of the movie besides interesting.
Isn't this weird? It was a bizarre edit of like
a last minute reshoot or something, it was
bizarre. We'll probably talk more about the
end credit scenes later. But back to Morbius,
I thought the portrayal of his powers was interesting.
Like they substituted his enhanced senses in
the comics. with echolocation, which is not
a power that Morbius has in the source material,
even though it probably should be. You know,
in the books, he can smell things very acutely,
he can see in the dark and in various wavelengths,
but in the film, it was all about sound, which
gave him this radar sense, which I think totally
works thematically due to his bad nature. And
I think they probably should adopt that power
for him in the comics. Yeah, Marvel seems to
have pretty good synergy between their movies
and their comics. if they didn't go this route.
Yeah, I think it would be totally apt. And I
thought it was interesting how they portrayed
the echolocation visually in this movie, where
everything kind of moved with a smoke trail
and the things that he focused on seemingly
gave off like a sort of smoke signal. I thought
it was pretty neat and very unlike how Daredevil's
radar sense has been visually portrayed. I
didn't like the way this was portrayed. Just
making everything cloudy didn't make sense
to me because sound isn't really like a cloud.
I think they could have done it differently,
but at least it's different, you know, from
anything else we've seen. I think it didn't
100 percent click with me until like toward
the end of the movie when he was gliding through
the city to save Martine. And like he could
kind of sense her blood visually floating through
the air, like he was sensing it as the sound
waves bounced back to him. And that's how he
was perceiving it. It was almost like she smelled
or something like that, you know, like you
could smell her blood, maybe. Yeah, something
like that. The smoke kind of represented multiple
senses in that regard. In the movie posters
and stuff like that, we saw like these waves
emanating from him. I thought that would have
been cooler. Well, we did see that briefly
when he was first explaining his echolocation.
We saw like the sound waves go out and then
come back. They use this interesting visual
cue where his eyes got cloudy whenever he would
use echolocation. Oh, and his ears rippled too.
Yeah, they became like furry or something.
Gross. It's weird. I don't know if they needed
both of those visual cues, but, uh, cause the
ear thing was just kind of gross. It's like,
Ooh, my ears are tingling. I do like the way
this movie explained the science of his bat
serum. Cause like in the books, you know, it
was just like bat blood and electroshock, but
here he was like vampire bats evolved into
the only animals that feed entirely on blood
because of some kind of enzyme they have and
blah, blah. Yeah. I totally thought that the
science behind this movie, was much easier
to understand and accept than the science from
the comics. Yeah. I love the vampirism angle
that they took for this movie. It was really
well done, I thought. For some reason, I always
like when they mix science with the supernatural,
kind of like Blade kind of explained why vampires
need to drink blood and stuff like that. But
essentially in this movie, his treatment was
like a chimeric merge of human and bat cells
that made this feel more like the Island of
Dr. Moreau, but on a much more practical level.
Yeah, I love all the different adaptations
that they made to make the character more modern
and accessible. If it was like the instead
of being a stowaway on a ship, like he had to
go out and do this experiment in international
waters. I thought that was cool. Yeah. I love
the synthetic blood. That was really cool.
And I love the look of the synthetic blood,
like how it was blue. You know, it was like
this is the good stuff and the red stuff is
the danger stuff. Yeah, that's pretty cool.
Let's go to move on to Lucian, AKA Milo played
by Matt Smith. I thought Matt Smith. I didn't
know what to think about him before this movie,
because he had a very small part in the trailers,
but I thought he was a lot of fun here. I wasn't
expecting him to be any good at all, but he
turned out to be actually one of my favorite
parts of the movie. He almost saves this movie
with how sinister of a villain he is. Oh totally.
I knew he was probably going to be my favorite
part of the film going into it, and he absolutely
was. Yeah. I mean he killed a lot of people
here, and he did it with like this sense of
superiority and glee. So you could totally
see why he needed to be stopped. But the fact
that he and Morbius were best friends, almost
brothers since childhood, it threw an interesting
dramatic element in there. Yeah, they also
made him the benefactor of Morbius's research.
So it kind of threw another interesting twist
in there as to like who really owned the research
and was he entitled to that serum? Yeah, for
sure. It was a kind of relationship that you
don't see too much within these superhero stories.
Like even going back to when they were kids,
I think Morbius... first called him Milo as
like this way to detach from this new kid who
probably wasn't gonna live long as a friend,
you know? And the nickname stuck and towards
the end of the movie when Morbius finally killed
him at the end, Milo was like, you can't kill
me, you gave me my name, you know? I thought
that was kind of deep, you know? There was like
some palpable weight to the tragedy of it.
Yeah, you almost get the sense that Morbius
was like responsible for Milo's life in a way.
Yeah. He definitely promised to cure him and
to save him. So when that ends up going bad,
it's very heartbreaking that he had to take
Milo's life. Yeah. And I think that aspect,
you're right, did save the film and did add
some extra gravitas and some extra thematic
weight that the film otherwise would not have
had. It is hard to know why Milo turned evil
though, other than being corrupted by his newfound
power, which I think on its own is never a
great motivation. Well, it did explain that
he was perhaps bullied a bit more than Morbius
was in their childhood. He was upset his whole
life that he was not able to do what others
were able to do. He felt like, you know, others
were superior toward him or felt superior toward
him. And finally, he was able to do everything
everyone else could do and more, you know,
feel like what it's really like to be alive.
And I think he was just really taking out all
those years of resentment for people who were
able to do things that he couldn't do on Innocence.
Yeah, totally. I guess his goal in the film
was to torture Morbius. by killing the ones
he loved in order to convince him of their new,
like, primal nature. But it's hard to understand
what his plan was beyond that. I guess he wanted
him and Morbius to just rule over others as
seemingly more evolved beings or something.
That wasn't clear. And it is hard to know when
and how Milo took the serum though. Because
I don't remember a shot of him actually taking
one of the vials, do you? No. No, that was kind
of cheap, I felt. Actually really cheap. It
did make for a nice surprise though later on
in the movie. where he walks in with a bag
of blood and it's like, oh, that's nice, you
know, he's like helping his boy out with a
bag of blood. And then he walks out without
his cane and everything like that. That was
kind of like a shock. I was like, wait. You
actually thought that was a really well written
and well done reveal. Like once you understood
the significance of that cane, like it really
got you. Yeah, for sure. I do have to say that
like this kind of sold me on Matt Smith as
John Constantine. I can see that. With like
the trench coat and like the hair. And the
accent, I think it could work. He could totally
pull it off for sure. But he has that real
creepy bone structure about him too, you know?
I think that's why he'll be good in the Game
of Thrones spinoff. Right. What's interesting
about the Milo character is that in the comics,
Morbius's best friend was named Emil. And he
was a healthy kid, a neighborhood best friend,
who became a scientist just like Morbius to
try and save him. And you know, he helped him
administer his initial bat serum, and he was
the first person Morbius killed right after
turning into a vampire. In this movie, though,
Milo was like an amalgamation of Emil from
the books and Loxious Crown, who was a hydro-scientist
that became the villain Hunger, who was another
pseudo-vampire like Morbius. But turning Morbius'
friend into the main villain was, I thought,
a great change from the source material. I thought
it worked really well. Yeah, I like this more
than what you explained in your Morbius bio.
Yeah. Let's move on to Martine Bancroft, who
was played by Adria Arjona. I don't know if
I'm pronouncing that last name right. But I
don't think I've seen Adria in anything before,
but I thought she was perfectly fine here as
a Martine. She didn't really have much to do
in the story except assist Morbius. I feel
the movie dropped the ball on their romance.
Because you know in the books, Morbius and
Martine were actually engaged when Morbius first
took his bat serum. And here, they barely had
any romantic relationship except for like a
kiss late in the movie and then the kiss right
before she died, quote unquote died. I think
it would have been more tragic. when she died
in his arms and he drank her blood and everything,
if that romance had been better established.
Oh, absolutely. Like, why not make them romantic
partners right off the bat? I don't get that.
Maybe it's not professional? I don't know. I
don't know. I don't think I have too many qualms
about professionalism or ethics in this film,
you know? That's true. Plus, it's not like,
you know, a married couple can't be colleagues.
That's entirely true, yeah. That's totally
valid. In the comics, you know, Martine eventually
became more than just a pseudo-vampire. She
became a real vampire turned by Dracula and
Morbius had to stake her through the heart
despite loving her. So it'll be interesting
how they treat Morbius and Martine's relationship
going forward if the Morbius franchise continues.
I mean we'll definitely see the character again.
I wonder if we'll end up seeing another Morbius
movie again though. Yeah, who knows. We'll
see. There aren't too many other characters
to talk about in our character breakdown, but
let's go ahead and move on to Simon Stroud who
is played by Tyrese Gibson and Al Rodriguez
who is played by Al Madrigal. You know, the
FBI agents here were pretty generic, but at
least they seemed fairly competent as investigators.
Tyrese's character, Simon Stroud, I don't remember
him having a cybernetic arm in the Morbius comics
I read. I could be wrong, but I am really glad
that they cut that whole element from the film
since it seems like it would have essentially
been needless. Yeah, it seemed like they cut
a lot of him out. It definitely seemed like
there was a lot more to the character than what
we saw, even with like the scar across his
neck and stuff like that. It felt like there
was stuff missing for sure. Do you feel like
the movie suffered because that wasn't in the
film, though? No, not at all. Honestly, I'm
not even sure his character was necessary. I
think I liked Agent Al more. Yeah. And considering
there was like very little humor within the
film, I almost could have used a little bit
more of like a buddy dynamic between the two
investigators. Maybe. Finally, let's move on
to Dr. Emil Nicholas, who is played by Jared
Harris. Jared Harris, fucking brilliant actor.
completely wasted in this role, or rather in
this cut of the film. You know, the trailers
seem to imply that he was sort of a mentor to
Morbius, like advising him regarding the ethics
of his bat serum treatment, and then later on
influencing him to become a hero. But that
was all edited out here, and you know, he basically
just served as the father figure to these two
characters. But I don't think you needed an
actor of Jared Harris's caliber for what turned
into a pretty small and relatively unsubstantial
role. Right. His death was pretty tragic, although
I'm really wondering why Morbius didn't go into
a bloodlust when he came to rescue him. I'm
surprised he didn't drink his blood like he
did Martins, you know? It was so strange, like
his death scene was one of the rare instances
in which we actually saw blood in this movie.
For a vampire film, it was relatively bloodless.
Like I remember on the ship scene, there was
a part where Morbius straight up slashed this
dude across his throat. And the dude's like
going, oh, like... expecting there was gonna
be like blood squirting out in the special
effects or something like that. Nope. And maybe
there was practically, but you know, either
way they either cut it out or just didn't include
it. And he's like holding his throat and just
kind of like falling to the ground. No blood.
I thought it was kind of funny. I wouldn't
have minded if it was rated R. Like I think
if you're gonna do a villain movie like Morbius,
a character who does kill and a character that
is involved with blood, why not make it rated
R? Producer Avi Arad, he just likes those PG-13
dollars. Yeah, he's a douche. I think all vampire
movies should be rated R essentially, just like,
cause if you can't show the blood, you're getting
away from one of the main themes of vampires,
you know? Right. Yeah, totally. That does it
for the character breakdown, let's go ahead
and move on to the story highlights. Now the
film starts off in Costa Rica where we see Morbius
and a local team set up a trap for a shit ton
of vampire bats. Now I remember from the trailers
I thought this was like the process that would,
you know, turn them into a part bat creature,
but... No, it was just them capturing bats.
It was very dramatic for what it was though.
Oh, totally. I guess he cut his hand to like
wake them up. Yeah, so they could smell his
blood. It was all very ritualistic. You'd think
that they'd just grab some donated blood or
something to get the same effect, but. Or just
fucking wait for them to fly it out of the cave
at night. I don't know. I guess the pilot did
seem pretty spooked about staying there too
long. Yeah. From there, the film flashes back
to Greece when Morbius was a child staying at
the hospital. I thought it was an effective
flashback scene, like it really set up well
the relationship between him and Milo, aka
Lucian, and how much they cared about each other,
like how he wrote him that note, and then that
note meant everything to Lucian. We get a brief
scene of Morbius winning the Nobel Prize and
then turning it down, and at the hospital we
see that Morbius is testing out a serum with
bad DNA. He meets with Milo because the tests
are successful, and he goes and administers
it himself in international waters. on a ship
with a bunch of mercenaries. It was kind of
weird, like how all these mercenaries were just
walking around the ship with their guns and
everything like that. Like they were expecting
an attack of some sort to happen at any moment.
Yeah, were they like pirates? Yeah, it was strange.
Like that one mercenary guy who discovered
Morbius, like hanging up on the ceiling like
a bat, he walked in with like his gun drawn
and everything like that. I'm like, who are
you expecting to shoot in this situation? You
were working with a couple of doctors, like
the fuck? Well, they didn't even explain that
they were mercenaries until like after they
were all dead. I thought they were just like
crew members just carrying guns for some reason.
I was like, what? I thought there was some
kind of like security detail, which, you know,
they were. But yeah, strange. It was kind of
like a good monster movie kind of scene, though,
when he killed all those guys. I think it wanted
to be a good monster movie scene. It was fine
for what it was. So Morbius abandons the boat
by jumping into the water, and I guess. Swimming
to shore because he can swim faster than the
Coast Guard can pull them back to Long Island
Fucking swim. It's a long fucking swim for
sure, but you know, he's superhuman now I guess
so he knows he could pull it off. He looked
at himself in the mirror is like yeah, I can
make this swim I got this See these apps these
are made for swimming So he swims back to his
lab and then starts testing his symptoms he
finds that he has these superhuman powers and
he begins testing the limits of his thirst.
Milo pays him a visit and sees that Morbius
has essentially cured himself, although Morbius
sees it more as a curse. You often have to wonder
in movies like this, like why didn't Morbius
just tell Milo right off the bat, like, dude,
I'm drinking blood, it's not cool. I don't
want this for you also. Like he was so vague.
It's like, just be honest. Well, Milo already
knew that. He's the one that got him the blood
to drink when he had isolated himself in that
room. That's fair. That's fair. Milo knew what
he was getting into. He knew what he was going
to turn into. Maybe he even wanted that. He
just wanted those abs. He was like, yeah, I
had to drink blood, but also I could wash my
clothes on my stomach. There you go. I would
do it for those abs. Sure. Crazy. So the FBI
begins investigating the boat incident and
they deduce that Morbius was on the boat and
that he's probably involved. There's a scene
later where a nurse gets attacked in the hospital
hallway, which I thought was actually pretty
damn effective. It was definitely inspired by
David F. Sandberg's Lights Out movie. Oh yeah.
But it was good, it was creepy. It was the creepiest
scene in the movie, yeah. Did you jump? Oh,
hell yeah. Yeah. Did you jump? Hell no, hell
no. Shut up. You know you did. It was pretty
effective for sure. But Morbius gets captured
by the police after a brief chase. and Milo
visits him in jail and leaves a blood bag for
him and leaves his cane behind to signaling
to Morbius that he had also taken the serum
and doesn't need the cane anymore. Morbius
breaks out of jail to confront Milo about what
he had done and the two fight within the subway,
which I thought was a pretty good scene. Yeah,
honestly, it was a pretty cool scene. And by
this point in the film, I was still waiting
to hate Jared Leto. And I really recognized
at this point that like, hey, this movie isn't
as terrible as I thought it would have been.
Yeah, I think I realized that about halfway
through as well. Morbius flees their encounter
and meets up with Martin and tracks down a bunch
of counterfeiters to create a new secret lab
for himself. I thought that was kind of weird
because I don't think there's a whole lot of
similarities between the equipment used to counterfeit
hundred dollar bills and to create medical
serums. You know, like, yeah, I mean, the whole
thing with him even finding the counterfeiters,
like them showing up to the restaurant was extremely
convenient. Yeah. That and the fact that he
could use their equipment. Meanwhile, Milo goes
to a bar and gets into a bar fight and ends
up attacking his assailants as they left. The
investigators end up finding the footage and
release to the public that it's a different
vampire that is attacking everybody. Emil Nicholas
confronts Milo and ends up getting killed by
him. As he's dying, Emil calls Morbius, who
goes over and sees him die in his arms, and
realizes at that moment that Milo has also
killed Martine. So Milo's just killing everybody.
Yeah. I mean, the scene with the detectives
looking at the CCTV, I thought that kind of
resolved that whole arc a little premature.
Like you didn't really see those guys again.
Well, not until the end when they were chasing
Morbius and Milo as they were fighting in the
streets down in the sewers. But they weren't
necessary to the story. Right. After that point.
But, you know, we're like at the end of the
movie here, Morbius flies over to Martine and
kisses her. She bites his lip, which I thought
was kind of kinky. She ingests some of his blood
and then he drinks her blood and I guess that
whole process is what ends up turning her into
a vampire. I'm still wondering why she bit
his lip. Like why? Because she's into that shit,
you know, don't hate, don't hate. It's like,
oh I'm dying. I just gotta get some of that
flavor. She's passionate and kind of violent
and that would really hurt, I feel like. So
after he drinks her blood we get round two
of Morbius versus Milo. This time the fight
goes down into the sewers. After crashing through
a whole bunch of buildings and stuff like that.
I thought it was actually a pretty good fight
though, but Morbius ends up summoning this whole
army of bats again He can't do that in the
comics, but here he used them as almost like
this Telekinetic force to hold Milo down as
he injected him with like a vampire poison that
he created Yeah, this whole thing had me rolling
my eyes big-time. Why really like he controls
bats now he could Communicate with bats and
talk with bats well They kind of set that up
when he was like in his cylinder where the
bats were and he was like kind of bonding with
them Yeah, they're my brothers. I guess but
it is weird considering that Morbius had the
ability to control bats, but Milo didn't why
is that like I thought they had the same powers?
Yeah Oh, that's very valid like why do they
see Morbius as a brother, but not Milo but I
mean Milo had powers that Morbius didn't have
either like the whole like Scream shockwave
thing. Well Morbius didn't do that, but I think
he probably could have it was just like a using
the echolocation offensively Yeah, I think
so too. I do think that Morbius looked pretty
fucking badass though when he was controlling
those bats I just like the character design.
I feel like they were trying to rip off Batman
Of course, you would think that like why wouldn't
you think that? Batman used bats against his
enemies in Batman Begins and Morbius also used
the bats to cover his escape from the sewer
if you noticed Yeah, of course I noticed that.
I was like, okay. That's essentially the end
of the movie. We see him flying overhead and
we see that Martine is turning into a vampire.
I was legit surprised how this movie ended.
I was like, what? Like, that's it? I knew there
was some end credits scenes or mid credits scenes,
I should say, but I was like, wow, they like
really just closed the curtain on us. Yeah,
it was fairly abrupt. So it's like the fight
ended, he flew away, done, credits. Totally
anti the Batman. Yeah, there could have been
some resolution there for sure. Especially considering
how absolutely horrible these mid-credit scenes
were. The first one actually started out pretty
cool because we saw the rift in the sky from
Spider-Man No Way Home. And then Michael Keane
kind of like gets transported into a prison
cell. And his reaction to this is so fucking
bizarre. He's like, I hope the food's better
here. Like, really? That's your reaction to
getting transported to a new cell, a new universe
or something? Wouldn't you be like, What the
fuck? Where am I now? Where am I? I'm not supposed
to be here. Nothing like that. So weird. And
in the trailers, we know that there was a scene
where Morbius and the Vulture actually met while
being transported by police and they had a
conversation. They heavily edited that footage
just to show police taking him out of the cell
and putting him into a car as a news report
states that they don't know where this guy
came from. And since they have no record of
his crimes, they're going to let him go. I'm
like, OK. And then it ends. That was pointless.
But then there's another mid-credits scene
where it starts off basically kind of like a
car commercial and Morbius is driving through
the countryside and then he pulls over, gets
out of his car, and then the Vulture flies
over to him. Now I'm not sure how Adrian Toomes
managed to get a hold of this new wing suit,
considering it was the Tinkerer that made it
for him, but he has a new suit here and he
basically tells Morbius that he's not sure how
he got here, he thinks Spider-Man is involved,
but he thinks they should team up to do some
good. and do some good, it makes me wonder
if they're actually trying to make the Sinister
Six a group of good guys, or if quote, doing
some good, actually means something a little
bit more sinister. So little context. It was
a horrible end credit scene, like in a way that
doesn't even get me excited for what the future
holds. In concept, I am very interested in a
movie that would combine this version of Morbius
with Tom Hardy's Venom, and Michael Keaton's
Vulture. I think that would be a cool movie.
I don't know who else they would add to the
Sinister Six. other than Craven, who's gonna
have his own film that's coming up, and I have
no idea what they plan on doing with the group
as a whole, but at least it would be cool to
see the actors work together. Well, it's like,
yeah, I mean, they set up the Scorpion in Spider-Man
Homecoming. I don't think he would have traversed
the multiverse since he didn't know that Peter
Parker was Spider-Man the way that the Vulture
did. Even that was kind of weird. Like, it's
like, okay, you know who Spider-Man is. So
for some reason you're transported to another
universe? It's like some people slipped through
accidentally, kinda like how some other characters
slipped through into the MCU. I don't know,
like they did a really piss poor job of explaining
it. It was just really bad. But we'll see how
it all shapes up. I don't think that this franchise
is gonna die. I think they're gonna keep on
building this Sinister Six kind of team up and
try to bring in Spider-Man into the mix. But
that does it for this Morbius movie. I think
overall... I was surprised at how much I enjoyed
it. I did find it entertaining. There are a
lot of issues with the movie. It is by no means
horrible. It's by no means good. It's very much
in the middle. It's a middling film. And for
that, I give it three stars. Oh good, I was
so afraid you were gonna say like five stars
from my review of the Batman. I mean, the Batman
should have got three stars too, but you know.
Shut up. No, I think this was a perfect three
star film. The film is really basic and you
know, it was entertaining. It has very little
going for that beyond entertainment value.
Maybe that's not entirely fair because I actually
really did like the angle between Morbius and
Milo, but I don't think it was enough to warrant
a rating beyond three stars. Yeah. Ultimately,
it's one half star lower than like the first
Venom film or something like New Mutants or
Blade 2 or something like that, mainly because
it's obvious that this film was chopped up
in the editing process. And because of that,
there were some story issues and some general
awkwardness regarding the cut. And those other
movies didn't really have that as much. But
that does it for this review. Let us know what
you thought about Morbius by writing to us
at dynamicduelpodcast at gmail.com or by visiting
us on Facebook, Instagram or Twitter. You could
find the links to all of our accounts by checking
out our show notes or visiting our website,
dynamicduel.com. And on our site, you can also
find a link to our Patreon page where we offer
ad free episodes of this show via custom RSS
feed, bonus content, including top 10 episodes
and bloopers, monthly live movie watch alongs,
collectible pinsets and access to our Discord
server. Again, check it out right after this
episode at patreon.com slash dynamic duel linked
in our show notes. Our lowest tier is only $2
a month. Our next episode is episode 275 of
this podcast. For a while, you'll know that
every 25 episodes now, we are doing a big team
duel. And next episode is one of those team
duels. This time, we are pitting the Arkham
Asylum inmates against the Sinister Six. Perfect
timing with this Morbius review. Yeah, it's
almost like it was delayed to be just in time.
But no, we're talking about characters like
Joker vs. Green Goblin, Penguin vs. Vulture,
Bane vs. Craven the Hunter, and more. So definitely
tune in next week. It's going to be an awesome
time. It's our first villain team duel. Yeah,
it's going to be a blast. It's going to be awesome.
But that does it for this episode. We want
to give a big thanks to our executive producers,
John Spies, Ken Johnson, John Storosky, Zachary
Hepburn, Mitchell Phipps, Dustin Belcombe, and
Levi Yeaton for helping make this podcast possible.
And we'll talk to you guys next week. Up, up,
and away, true believers.