This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
Make Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we review
superhero films and debate the superiority
between Marvel and DC by comparing their characters
and stat-based battle simulations. I'm Johnny
DC. And I'm his twin brother, Marvelous Joe.
And welcome to the first episode of 2025. This
is our year, guys. This is our year. Year for
what? It's just our year. I don't know. It's
a saying. I don't know what it means. I thought
you were saying it's like Marvel's year. I
was like, what? Superman's coming out that too.
That too. Well, we're kicking off this year
with a Marvel review. At the very least, this
episode will be talking all about season three
of What If Marvel's animated series on Disney
Plus. Yeah, you know, the show's hit or miss.
But was season three more hit or more miss compared
to the other hit or miss seasons? We'll find
out later on in this episode. Before that, we're
going to break down the comic book movie news
from the past week, of which there was just
one news item. and that was that Jason Momoa
has been cast as Lobo in Supergirl Woman of
Tomorrow. As always we list our segment times
in our episode description so feel free to check
out the show notes if you want to skip ahead
to a particular topic. Guys our artificially
intelligent Duel simulator AJ9K has a quick
message for our listeners, so listen up. Why
hello there, do you want even more from this
podcast? Then become a part of the dynamic Duel
community on Patreon, where you can choose
from three tiers. The dynamic two-o tier gives
you access to our Discord chat server. The
fantastic four tier gives you two bonus episodes
each month, and the X-Force tier makes you
an executive producer of this show. Lastly,
The DynaMic Podcast Network tier lets you
create your own podcast using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and consultation,
and get you simulation results. Pitch the twins
your ideas via email at dynamicduelpodcast at
gmail.com. Check it out at patreon.com slash
dynamicduel. Pip pip cheerio. Thanks AJ9K and
thanks to everyone who supports the podcast.
Be sure to tune into the other shows in the
DynaMic Podcast Network this week. Including
Max Destruction, which pits your favorite action
heroes from film and television against each
other. This week hosts Scotty and Gilly are
finding out who would win between He-Man and
Lion-O. And I gotta say that's one I've been
looking forward to for a long time. Yeah, me
too. On the Sinjyo World podcast, host Zachary
Hepburn speculates on fights between fan favorite
anime and manga characters. Zach is off for
the next two weeks, but make sure to check
out his latest episode if you haven't already.
On the Console Combat Podcast hosts John and
Dean simulate battles between popular video
game characters. In yesterday's episode, they
reviewed the first season of Secret Level. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our
show notes to listen to all the shows in the
DynaMic Podcast Network. But with that out
of the way, quick to the note prize! A no prize
is an award Marvel used to give out to fans.
Our version, the Dynamic Duel No Prize, is a
digital award we post on Instagram for the
person that we feel gave the best answer to
our question of the week. Last week we asked
you guys, from 1 to 10, how excited has the
Friendly Neighborhood Spider-Man trailer made
you for the series, and why? And of course this
is coming off the back of the trailer that
was released last week for the upcoming Disney
Plus television show that's going to debut
at the end of January. We got only a few answers
this time. for this question, three of them
to be exact. So let's go down our two honorable
mentions as well as the no prize winner. The
first honorable mention goes to Travis Herndon,
who said. What's up dynamic dudes, Travis here.
Shout out to my evil twin. So all in all, this
trailer looks pretty good. I like the art style.
I love the designs. Me, I know a lot of people
are kind of iffy about the whole race swapping
of Norman Osborn, but hey, at least it makes
the waves make more sense for him now. Now
I'm giving it a chance and so far I'm going
to give it like an 8 out of 10. It gets me
hyped. It looks promising and I can't wait to
see more of it. You're not going to lie. The
rows of red and black hair in the comics never
quite made sense to me for Norman Osborn and
Harry Osborn, but interpreting them as cornrows
is kind of cool. Yeah, I actually like that
a lot. I think if you could race band anybody,
Norman Osborn would be a top contender. I'm
really excited to see how that plays out. But
I'm also excited to see that Travis is fairly
excited for the upcoming show because I need
to kind of latch on to that sort of excitement
and see if I could experience it vicariously
for myself being someone who's not as excited
for the friendly neighborhood Spider-Man show.
Because personally I put myself at maybe like
a four and a half or a five? I'd put myself
probably in that same spot. To me the most
exciting thing about this is seeing Peter Parker
in high school. Like on film... There's always
this rush to get him out of high school because
the actor keeps aging, but with animation,
you don't really run into that problem. Yeah,
that is definitely one of the more beloved
iterations of the characters, you know, young
Peter Parker. Well, great answer, Travis. Let's
move on to our next honorable mention, Mason
Thompson. Who said? What's up? If I had to
rate it from one to 10, I would rate it a solid
4.3 because I do not like the art style. I
don't like how it's mixing 3D with Hootie like
that one wish movie did and I don't like how
he has the future foundation suit like you guys
said. I do like how he has the like the web
shooters in a backpack though. I think there
have been some successful iterations of flat
three-dimensional art out there so I don't think
I would knock your friendly neighborhood Spider-Man
for its art style especially since it's evoking
those early Ditko drawn comics but like Mason
Thompson said we both had gripes about the future
foundation being his first superhero suit that
he gets after his homemade one. Although I will
say, luckily, according to some promo art that
was released last week, it does look like Spider-Man
does get his classic red and blue Spidey outfit
by the end of the season. So that news alone
actually gets me more excited for the show
because I guess I'm more of a stickler for Spider-Man's
look than I ever thought I was. It's one of
the reasons why I didn't like the Amazing Spider-Man
movie. The first one with Andrew Garfield.
So the purist in me is happy to see the character
don that suit. Thanks Mason Thompson for that
answer. But the winner of this week's snow prize
goes to Daniel Alonso. Who said, okay, I definitely
agree with Joe. It definitely should have been
a Tom Holland's origin of Spider-Man. Um, I'm
about a three out of 10 on this one. It kind
of looks like how DC makes shows. So I'm not
really too excited, but I'm probably still going
to check it out. I'm not sure yet. So Jonathan,
if you're wondering why he gave Daniel Alonso's
answer the no prize win, it's because even
while he's shitting on a Marvel show, he still
manages to also shit on DC. And I think that
is an admirable skill. I mean, I'm still confused
as to what he's talking about. Because like,
if it's a show that DC would make, it would
look good and he would be excited about it.
I cannot comprehend his answer. What DC show
is good? Name one. My Adventures with Superman.
Wrong. Batman kids crusader, suicide squad isekai,
Harley Quinn. Actually they're all pretty good.
I'm not gonna lie. That's what I thought. DC
puts out some pretty good animated shows as
well. No, I chose it because it's fun to dunk
on DC whether or not the claim is accurate
or not. Oh, okay. You're just jealous. Jealous
of all of DC's awesome animated shows. Quantity
is not quality, my friend. Quality? What quality?
What if season three? No, I'm talking about
like. X-Men 97, okay? Fuck you, Jonathan. Hahaha.
Moving on, congrats to Daniel Alonso for winning
this week's No Prize. If you, the listener,
want a shot at winning your own No Prize, stay
tuned to later on this episode when we'll be
asking another question of the week. And now
that that's done, on to the news.
Okay, so during interviews for his film Aquaman
The Lost Kingdom, Jason Momoa was doing press
rounds talking about the upcoming DC Universe,
saying that he hoped James Gunn, the head of
DC Studios, would give him a call regarding
the role of Lobo. Well, apparently he got the
call because he made a social media post announcing
that he has been cast as Lobo in the upcoming
Supergirl Woman of Tomorrow film. It's a role
he was pretty much born to play considering
the fact he looks and acts exactly like the
character from the comics. Of course, Jason
Momoa was Aquaman in the DCEU, a role that I
actually enjoyed him in, but anyone who says
he's not a better Lobo is kind of kidding themselves.
Well, I mean, he never fit into the Aquaman
mold according to what was set in the comic
books, right? I do think he was an interesting
adaptation for film. And I thought it was pretty
cool how they cast an actor, a Pacific Islander
descent to play Aquaman. That totally makes
sense. But you're right. You look at the dude
and he looks exactly like Lobo. As far as I'm
concerned, this is dream casting. And I think
he's totally up for it. Oh yeah, totally. He's
been talking for years how much he likes the
character of Lobo. So it was kind of surprising
when he was cast as Aquaman. There's a lot
of mixed reactions. when the first image of
him as Aquaman was released by Zack Snyder
and it said, like, unite the seven. It was an
early Justice League promo image. And, yeah,
everyone looked at that and I was like, oh,
look, it's Lobo. I wonder if we're going to
get some like Aquaman gags in the Supergirl
movie on behalf of Jason Momoa. I who are you
expecting? Aquaman. Right. Yeah, maybe. Lobo
is the character where you can kind of get
away with breaking the fourth wall, kind of
like Deadpool in that regard. So it might happen.
Who knows? If the character is done right, if
he's given a good enough part in the Supergirl
movie, I could totally see Jason Momoa headlining
his own Lobo movie in a style of film that's
very much in the same vein as Deadpool. Although
Jason Momoa isn't funny, so he'd have to have
good writers. Jason Momoa is funny? What are
you talking about? He was like partial comic
relief in Justice League. Look at the end of
Peacemaker. Yeah, you're right. You're right.
I think he's definitely funny enough and charismatic
enough to hold his own film or maybe appear
like in a Superman movie as a major character.
For all we know, maybe he makes a cameo in
the upcoming Superman movie. I would not be
surprised if he did. Like in a mid-credit scene
or something? Yeah, end-of-credit scene, mid-credit
scene. Loba has often appeared in animated
Superman projects such as Man of Tomorrow and
the Superman animated series. I think that's
actually how a lot of the general public are
familiar with the character. Of course, the
character of Lobo was not in the Supergirl Woman
of Tomorrow series, although I think he was
originally intended to be. I'm not sure what
role he's going to serve in the upcoming Supergirl
film starring Camille Alcock, but I actually
think the characters of Supergirl and Lobo
work pretty well together. So I'm excited for
this news a lot. Of course, the Supergirl film
does not come out until the summer of 2026,
so, you know, it's still a ways out. But like
I said, if we see Lobo maybe in an end credit
scene, Maybe we'll get an early look at the
character before we see him on screen. I'm really
hoping that audiences aren't too confused when
they see Jason Momoa not as Aquaman because
you know the first Aquaman movies were received
fairly decently. I'm not talking about critically
but just in terms of like box office performance.
The first Aquaman movie made over a billion
dollars and is still DC's highest grossing
film of all time I believe. I don't think audiences
will have too hard of a problem seeing Momoa
in the Lobo role considering that he's probably
going to be in heavy makeup. Right, yeah, like
white body paint and red eyes, the works. Hopefully,
fingers crossed. But speaking of past DCEU
actors returning for the DCU, that brings us
to our question of the week.
If you could recast any other DCEU actor in
a DCEU role, who would it be and why? I'm getting
real confused by all these DCE acronyms, man.
Well, if you're a Marvel fan, so I would expect
nothing less. Recording answer at dynamicduel.com
by clicking on the red microphone button in
the bottom right hand corner of the screen,
which will prompt you to leave us a voicemail.
Your message could be up to 30 seconds long.
And don't forget to leave your name in case
we include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer. and award that person a dynamic
Duel no prize that will post to Instagram. Be
sure to answer before January 11th.
So that does it for all of the news for this
episode. Let's go ahead and move on to the
main event in which we review the third season
of Marvel's and Disney Plus's What If series.
Alright, What If Season 3 is an animated series
on Disney+, directed by Brian Andrews and Stephen
Frank, written by Matthew Chauncey, and starring
many familiar names and voices from the live-action
Marvel Cinematic Universe. Based on the What
If comic books, the show explores the multiverse
with a series of anthological tales told from
the perspective of Uwatu the Watcher, who is
the cosmic entity that oversees the events happening
in each episode. Each story is set up with
a question of what if that explores how a change
in the primary MCU timeline would affect continuity,
and each episode unfolds the universal effects
from that change. Season 3 is the final season
of this animated series, and over these past
few years, this show has been hit or miss in
regards to the quality of the stories it tells,
though I would say there have been many more
hits than misses. We found that season 1 focused
more on its overarching narrative of the multiversal
guardians to the detriment of its indiviDuel
stories. focused more on its indiviDuel stories
and succeeded more because of that. Season 3
also focuses more on its indiviDuel stories,
saving its greater arc of Uwatu and the Watchers
for the final episodes. And you'd think that
would make it as good as season 2, but unfortunately
you'd be wrong. With that said, here's your
spoiler warning for what if season 3 and probably
season 1 and 2 as well will be discussing plot
points from the entire series and revealing
fun Definitely better discovered by watching
the show and not listening to two nerds talk
about it. Yeah, honestly, I'm really torn on
this season because well, I think some of its
episodes pose the absolute worst What if scenarios?
I also think the closing episodes were incredible.
Oh for sure Yeah, the season ends with a bang
not a whimper. They did a really good job on
closing out the season in a way that may make
you look at season 3 as a whole with rose tinted
glasses, but we're going to break down each
episode piece by piece and figure out what was
good and what was bad. The showrunner stated
that the What If series is ending because the
MCU's multiversal saga is going to start wrapping
up here, but that's not going to happen until
2027 with the Avengers Secret Wars film. So
my big takeaway from season 3 already knowing
that the show avoided the pitfalls of season
20 episodes into the series, for some reason
it seems like the writers were beginning to
run on fumes. All three seasons have had some
great premises that introduced lasting characters
like Captain Carter, Doctor Strange Supreme,
Nova Prime Nebula, and K'Hori. But season 3
overall seemed to lack that same enthusiasm,
that magic that comes when you ask a simple
question that unlocks a universe of wonders.
That's not to say that season 3 didn't have
great ideas like Hulkazilla. or the Western
Legend of the Ten Rings. It's just that it
seemed like there were fewer of them in this
season. I don't like either of those premises.
Hulkzilla, dumb. Western Shang-Chi, dumb. You're
fucking wrong, bro. What? Those were both fantastic,
and I'm gonna slap the shit out of you next
time I see you. I freaking fell asleep for
the Shang-Chi one, absolutely. That was one
of the better episodes this season, and history
will judge you harshly. Okay, fine, come at
me, bro. Come at me, history. Okay, all right.
Just wait. Next time I see you on the street.
Overall, I'd say that out of the nine episodes
in season one, I enjoyed about six of them.
And for season two's nine episodes, I enjoyed
actually eight of them. There was only one episode
that I didn't really like out of season two.
And for this season, out of the eight episodes,
I'd say I only enjoyed about five of the stories.
So like totaling it all up, 19 out of 25. is
not too bad for the series overall, which is
why I said the show has more hits than misses.
And I gotta say, despite that track record,
I'm gonna miss What If? I'm really sad that
the series is ending because even when the
episodes weren't firing, the show still always
had the potential to be jaw-dropping amazing.
And I think that was the best thing about it.
Yeah, the question of What If? and the premise
of What If? is 100% all about potential. I just
think that they never really asked more interesting
questions. Like Howard the Duck and Darcy having
an egg? Who cares? It was nice to get Howard
the Duck content out there. This is the most
that we ever got of the character. But we'll
break down that episode once we get to our story
breakdown. But specifically regarding season
three, I do appreciate that the writers ventured
further outside the world of the original Avengers
to include newer characters because the main
detriment to the MCU as a whole currently.
is that it's less cohesive than it's ever been.
You know, throughout the entire Infinity Saga,
it was easy to keep track of everything and
everything felt more intertwined. Whereas nowadays,
there are so many random projects and nothing
is really connected. And it's so disparate
that it's hard for people to stay on top of
everything. Right. Yeah, absolutely. Like the
ten rings from Shang-Chi that cliffhanger has
not tied into, you know, Atlantis, which is
not tied into the Eternals. which is not tied
into, you know, secret invasion and the scrolls
and everything like that. Right, right. It's
like, what am I supposed to be following here?
Exactly. Yeah. You know, a lot of the Phase
Four and Five characters have yet to be revisited.
So it was really nice to hear from those actors
like Simu Liu, who plays Shang-Chi, Oscar Isaac,
who plays Moon Knight, and Kamel Najiani, who
plays Kingo from The Eternals, and Tionna Paris.
It was really nice to get this next generation
of Marvel characters and actors in the mix.
Yeah, if anything, just to remind audiences
that they exist, just in case you forgot about
them, which one will be in the Avengers? Who
knows? Find out, keep watching. If there's
one thing about this season that I actually
really liked over past seasons, and I thought
was an improvement, was the animation style.
Now I know it's largely the same as what we've
had before, but there were moments in this season,
particularly towards the end, where they were
able to use lighting in a way that they haven't
done before. And I thought it went a long way
in showing actually just how interesting this
animation style is. For sure. Yes, cinematography
is a term that's largely applied to live action
content, but it also applies to animation as
well. I think that's easy to overlook. But the
cinematography of this show, episode to episode,
is spellbinding. Everything looks so gorgeous,
which is no surprise because the show is produced
by Marvel who is owned by Disney who produces
some of the greatest animated content the world
has ever known. But to review what if overall
is really difficult because each story in itself
is its own tale. So let's go ahead and get into
our episode breakdown. Episode 1 was called
What If The Hulk Fought The Mech Avengers? It
stars Anthony Mackie as Sam Wilson, Mark Ruffalo
as Bruce Banner, Teona Paris as Monica
David Harbor as Alexei Shostakov, Simu Liu as
Shang-Chi, and Oscar Isaac as Mark Spector.
In the episode, Bruce Banner becomes friends
with Sam Wilson, who counsels him in his trauma
support group. An accidental Hulk transformation
leads to Banner trying to separate the Hulk
from himself using gamma radiation. However,
the experiment manifests a powerful radioactive
monster called Apex that is capable of growing
in size and spawning kaiju monsters. Tony Stark
develops mecha-sized Hulkbuster suits for the
Avengers, and though the original team falls
to the Kaiju in battle, the surviving heroes
win the Gamma War. However, ten years later,
the beasts return, prompting Sam Wilson as Captain
America and Photon to investigate the radioactive
anomaly in the Arctic. There they find the Apex
still alive and leading a massive Kaiju army.
Photon and Winter Soldier learn the location
of Bruce Banner, believing he's the key to
stopping the Kaiju. Captain America visits him
in the Astra Islands to convince him to join
the fight. Banner refuses, but provides Sam
with a plugin he wrote for the mech suit's
interface called the Mighty Avenger Protocol
that will allow the Avengers to combine their
strength. The merger proves effective in defeating
many of the kaiju, but the apex still proves
to be too strong for them. Banner arrives on
the scene with a nuclear gamma bomb that he
detonates. The Hulk absorbs the full blast.
permanently transforming him into Mega Hulk,
who uses his gamma breath to disintegrate the
apex monster. Mega Hulk acknowledges his friend
Sam, proving that Banner's mind is still somewhere
inside the creature, and he leads the remaining
Kaiju into the sea, to the Astra Islands. I
heard you diss on this episode a few minutes
ago. And I'm here to reiterate that you are
wrong. I thought this was a fantastic homage
to the Godzilla stories and mecha stories like
Gundam, Evangelion and Pacific Rim. To me,
the whole thing felt very gimmicky. It was like
Power Rangers meets Godzilla, which sounds
cool. But the whole time, I was just wondering
how the hell was this Apex Hulk created? Like,
why is it a separate being from Bruce Banner's
Hulk? It was Bruce's attempt to separate himself
from the Hulk, but We don't know how gamma radiation
works. You know, it created the Hulk. I think
it's entirely plausible that instead of separating
the two beings, it would separate another yet
more monstrous creature. I really liked the
great camera work in this episode, especially
like that split screen style that they would
do that made the show feel like Voltron or
Power Rangers. That was a lot of fun. And it
really served to highlight the cool wide cast
of characters that they got for this episode.
You know, I mentioned before it was really
cool to see people like Oscar Isaac back in
the role. you know, despite how small that
role may be for this episode. What'd you think
of this Avengers lineup? Like is this the new
official lineup that you would like to see on
the silver screen? No, but I thought it was
a great representation of international characters,
you know, really taking that global approach.
You had Nakia from Wakanda. You had the Red
Guardian and Malia Vostokov from Russia. You
had Moon Knight who was in this very like Egyptian
type armor. You had Shang-Chi representing
Southeast Asia. It was pretty fascinating stuff.
I thought that was all really cool to get that
international feel. I guess in that regard,
it was more like Pacific Rim than anything
else. Exactly. I liked the lineup. I'd actually
be really happy if this was the Avengers lineup
going forward, but maybe replace Nikiya with
Shuri's Black Panther. That'd be dope. Yeah,
and maybe toss in Namor or something like that
in there. Have a Talokhan-style suit of armor
made out of vibranium. Hell yeah! I'm still
really offended that you didn't like this episode.
I don't think you've given a good enough reason
to not like it. I mean, seeing Hulk turn into
Godzilla and then using that gamma breath to
melt the apex, I thought was fantastic. It
was such a good homage. I don't even know if
I have a good reason for why I didn't like
it. I just remember watching the shows. Well
then shut the hell up. Okay? I think I was
just upset that I had to watch another season
of What If? And I was like, ugh, okay. Maybe
try to step up as a critic then, you know? Just
because you have to watch a show doesn't mean
that you should go in hating it. Okay? This
was a great premise. I thought it was one of
the better executed what if premises that the
series has ever done actually. You might be
right. Maybe I'll rewatch this episode specifically
and I'll completely change my mind. Because
on paper actually it does sound interesting.
Yeah, I think you need to do that. And also
slap yourself on behalf of everybody else out
there who is listening to this and wish you
would. I don't know about slapping myself, but
I'll watch it. Let's go ahead and move on to
episode 2, which is called What If Agatha Went
to Hollywood? It stars Catherine Hahn as Agatha
Harkness, Kumail Nanjiani as Kingo, Dominic
Cooper as Howard Stark, and James Darcy as
Edwin Jarvis. The story of the episode is, in
her quest for power, Agatha Harkness learns
of the celestial Tiamat growing in the Earth's
core and plans to siphon its power. During
the Golden Age of Hollywood, she becomes an
actress who convinces her director Howard Stark
to add star power to the motion picture by hiring
the famous Bollywood actor Kingo. of the Eternals.
Kingo arrives at the set in Hollywood and performs
a large dance number with Agatha. He reveals
during their scene that he knows about her plan
to harness celestial power and attacks her.
Agatha defends herself using the other Eternals
powers, revealing that she has already siphoned
those abilities and that Kingo is last on her
list. She convinces him of her heroic intent
and his own humanist tendencies, getting him
to agree to transfer his power to her. Arishem
signals his arrival to Earth and Agatha and
Kingo get Stark to shoot the finale at the
Griffith Observatory where they perform the
ritual. Agatha absorbs Tiamat's power and becomes
a celestial as Arishem arrives and the two fight.
She uses magic to restrain Arishem and defeats
him, absorbing his power as well. Agatha then
reveals her deception, that she was seeking
power all along and not to save the world. But
Kingo convinces her that she could bring about
more change as an actress. than as a celestial.
Agatha relinquishes her power, and she and
Kingo attend the world premiere of their movie
Cosmic Queen as more celestials arrive on Earth.
This episode fucking sucked, man. As beautiful
as it looked and as well as it evoked the golden
age of Hollywood with fantastic art deco style,
I really hated the story. Yeah, the whole story
kind of felt like it was two concepts merged
into one. I feel like writers were like...
Oh, I really want to do like a Kingo Bollywood
dance episode. And now the writers were like,
oh, what if Agatha absorbed the power of a celestial?
And at the end, they were just like, oh, fuck
it, combine them. Yeah, I'm not entirely sure
that the worlds of Agatha's witchcraft and
the Eternals really vibed as well as they thought
it would. But the biggest problem I have with
the episode was when Kingo convinced Agatha
to relinquish the power of the celestials,
because I don't think that was in character.
for Agatha. I think Agatha is and always has
been someone who seeks out and craves ultimate
power. And I think during that turn, Kingo
forgot the simple fact that Agatha is not actually
an actress. You know, she came to Hollywood
as part of her ruse. So for Kingo to convince
Agatha that they were the same, you know, insecure
actors looking to show the world they were big
and that she didn't need her celestial power
and that she only needed to be famous, like
that was such a weird self-absorbed perspective,
as if being an actor was the most important
thing a person could become, like more important
than a world creating life-generating celestial.
Like the narcissism to that idea was astounding
to me. Yeah, only Hollywood could have come
up with something as ridiculous as stardom
being something greater than a god. Exactly,
which is weird because it's not like this episode
was written by actors, but it certainly felt
like it. was. And in that regard, yeah, the
episode just felt too self-serving. And, you
know, like if you want to give an homage to
classic Hollywood, you got to look at WandaVision.
I think that show did it way better than this
episode of What If did. That said, I do think
the episode was aware of how ridiculous it
was being. Sure, yeah, it was meta in that regard,
but that doesn't do anything for me. Like you
look at Kingo too, you know, Kingo was convinced
to betray Arasham. because Agatha promised
him a three-picture deal. It kind of makes the
character of Kingo pretty petty. Yeah, I guess
if we're gonna talk about things I liked about
the episode in addition to the visual style,
I also did like Howard Stark in the episode
because like he's often seen as a parallel
to Howard Hughes, but in this episode, he seemed
more like an Orson Welles type. I thought that
was pretty clever. Yeah, it was like Orson Welles
or maybe even like Walt Disney. I did think
that Dominic Cooper gave a great voice performance
as like a classic Hollywood director type.
Oh yeah, he does that old timey voice really
well, which we saw in Captain America, the
first Avenger. I forgot that I'm rating each
of these episodes as we're talking about them.
I would rate episode two, what if Agatha went
to Hollywood, two and a half out of five stars.
Didn't really like it, but I would rate the
first episode, what if Hulk fought the Mech
Avengers four out of five. I don't even want
to give my ratings now because I feel like
my- rating for the first one is probably going
to be very different from yours. But yeah,
I would agree with episode two's rating. Episode
three was called What If the Red Guardian Stopped
the Winter Soldier? It stars David Harbour as
Alexei Shostakov, Sebastian Stan as Bucky Barnes,
Laurence Fishburne as Bill Foster, and America
Ferrera as Ranger Alessandre Morales. Wait,
what? Really? Yeah. Why? I don't know. In the
episode In Early Nineties Russia, Alexei Shostakov,
the Red Guardian, ignores his orders from the
Red Room to become a sleeper agent in Ohio
with the young Natasha Romanoff. Instead, he
shadows the Winter Soldier on his mission to
acquire Howard Stark's newly created Super Soldier
Serum in New York. Alexei prevents Bucky from
killing the Starks, and the two fight. When
the police and S.H.I.E.L.D. arrive on the scene,
the two flee and receive notice from the Red
Room that due to their failure, they are on
their own for extraction. Shield agent Bill
Foster investigates the scene and stops Alexi
and Bucky at a traffic stop while on their way
to Las Vegas. Bill Foster gives chase, turning
into Goliath, but the pair drive their car off
a cliff to escape. Alexi and Bucky survive
and mend their wounds by breaking into a veterinary
hospital where Alexi tries to get Bucky to
remember his past. The pair arrives in Vegas
where they meet with a Rook, an American informant
who leaked the Super Soldier Serum's existence
to Russia, who turns out to be Obadiah Stane.
Alexei is saddened to learn that the Rook is
a capitalist, and Obadiah attempts to shoot
them before Bucky knocks him out the window
of his penthouse hotel room. Goliath and S.H.I.E.L.D.
arrive on the scene and chase Alexei and Bucky
to a construction site. There, Hydra handler
Vasiliy Karpov tries to get the Winter Soldier
back under control, but S.H.I.E.L.D., Alexei,
and Bucky team up to take him out. Ultimately,
the Winter Soldier is captured and taken back
to the Red Room. but Alexei defects and retires
as a gym teacher before Bill Foster recruits
him into SHIELD and he becomes a member of the
original Avengers. Now on paper, I don't think
that episode sounded too bad, but in execution,
the Red Guardian was so fucking dumb that this
episode was really hard to get through. He was
kind of like a Soviet flag waving communist
poster boy but with the IQ of a kindergartener.
It was bad. Yeah, his whole shtick got. real
old, real quick. From his opening scene with
Drakov in the red room, like the way he's yelling
at him, like he's not acting like a real character,
he's acting like a cartoon character. And yes,
I understand that this is a cartoon. And yes,
the character is still a little bit goofy in
live action, but not to this extent. They went
way over the top here in a way that made me
kind of hate the episode. Like every line out
of David Harbour's mouth, like smash the capitalist
pigs and like you gotta seize the means of production
and it just, it didn't work. I don't understand
why the Red Guardian didn't want Bucky to kill
the Starks. I'm guessing it's because he fancied
himself a hero who doesn't kill, but that doesn't
seem quite in keeping with the character that
I know from live action. At least Bucky Barnes
as the Winter Soldier was solid. I gotta say
that Sebastian Stan's voice performance in season
3 far and away was better than his appearances
in season 1. He's really grown as a voice actor.
evoked classic films like Party Thor was a riff
on risky business. You had Nebula joining the
Nova Corps as a kind of tribute to Blade Runner.
Yeah, that was cool. They even parody Die Hard
with the Christmas episode from season two that
I thought was really good. That's right. Here
it seemed like they were trying to pay homage
to Thelma and Louise evading the police and,
you know, driving their car off of a cliff and
everything like that. But god, this was just
such a piss poor tribute to that movie. If I
have to say a good thing about the episode,
I did think it was neat that the Russian intelligence
regarding Bucky's mission came from Obadiah
Stane. I do think that it makes sense that he
would be the one to have Howard killed considering,
you know, he tried to kill Tony Stark in Iron
Man 1 in a similarly underhanded way. I like
to think of Obadiah Stane as the Rook as like
main MCU sacred timeline canon, because we
never really know where Hydra got that intel
from. that Howard Stark had recreated the Super
Soldier Serum, I totally think it makes sense
that Obadiah Stane would have sold him out.
Yeah, I liked that too. I didn't even realize
initially that was Obadiah Stane. It took me
a while, but once I did, I was like, oh yeah,
that's awesome. There's one character in this
episode who worked with Bill Foster. They called
her Ranger Morales. She's actually a character
from the comic books named Alessandre Morales,
who was a SHIELD agent. I don't know why they
adapted her as a Ranger in this episode, but
I thought that was at least a cool Easter egg.
I don't understand why they cast America for
her to voice her. I wonder if that signals
that she'll be playing the role in live action
as well. Yeah, maybe she'll be playing a shield
agent in the future in the MCU. That'd be pretty
cool. I give episode three two out of five
stars. It was actually one of my least favorite.
What if episodes that they produced? Oh, wow.
That's lower than I would have given. I think
I would have given it like. two and a half,
maybe just a half star higher. Why would you
give it a 2.5? You fucking hate bathos more
than I do. And yet this entire episode was the
definition of that. Doesn't make any sense.
That's true, I don't know. Let's go to move
on to episode four, which was called What If
Howard the Duck Got Hitched. It stars Kat Dennings
as Darcy Lewis, Seth Green as Howard the Duck,
Samuel L. Jackson as Nick Fury, Tom Hiddleston
as Loki, Clark Gregg as Phil Coulson, Michael
Rooker as Yondu Udanta, and Josh Brolin as Thanos.
This episode is a sequel to the What If Thor
Were an Only Child episode from season 1. In
it, Darcy and Howard the Duck meet after one
of Party Thor's celebrations in Las Vegas and
they go out for nachos, falling in love and
getting hitched. They have a baby egg raising
it in their New York apartment where they're
served an invitation to one of the Grandmasters
intergalactic cruises. There, the egg is taken
for childcare while Howard and Darcy are invited
to brunch. Upon realizing that their child
is going to be served as brunch, Yondu the Ravager
crashes the scene, stealing the egg to take
it to the Collector on nowhere. Howard and Darcy
steal a ship and en route contact Nick Fury
of SHIELD for help. On nowhere, Yondu meets
the sorcerer Kyselius, who zealots captured
the Collector in order to get the egg. Yondu
reveals that other parties expressed interest
in the egg, including the Dark Elves and Zeus,
but Kyselius incapacitates him. Howard and
Darcy infiltrate a dark ritual trying to use
the egg to birth Dormammu. However, S.H.I.E.L.D.
intervenes and acquires the egg, losing it in
the ensuing chaos, allowing Howard and Darcy
to escape with their egg and hide out on Jotunheim.
Loki is eager to help, but King Loffi wants
to use the egg as a weapon. The frost giants,
S.H.I.E.L.D., the Olympians, the dark elves,
the zealots, and Thanos' black order all converge
on the scene, all fighting for the egg. Amidst
the chaos, the egg radiates a cosmic energy
that incapacitates everyone but Howard and
Darcy and hatches, revealing a baby human-avian
hybrid that they name Bertie. They take Bertie
back home and put her to bed. Now let's address
the elephant in the room here with this episode.
In that a woman and a humanoid duck had a baby.
You know, Howard the Duck has had romantic
tension with human women like Beverly Switzler,
who was in the comics and even in the Howard
the Duck movie. His stories have always tiptoed
that line without ever explicitly venturing
into human animal relations territory. And I
don't know if it's just my mind, or maybe it's
just the paradigm shift of seeing Howard as
a dad, but like I had trouble getting over
the idea of Darcy banging Howard. Like I just
kept wondering, how would that even work? Am
I the only one? No, absolutely. I was thinking
the whole time I was watching this episode,
like really they decided to base an entire episode.
of Howard the Duck's implied coupling with
Leah Thompson in his movie. That's ridiculous.
Yeah, I mean, it was also implied in the comic
book, so it wasn't just in the movie. But it
raises questions. Ducks have corkscrew-shaped
dongs, right? And Darcy was in labor and she
gave birth to this egg, like the size of the
egg would have just left her whole downstairs
totally demolished. So I'm thinking it had
to be a Caesarian birth at least, you know?
And I came to the following conclusion. The
Howard the Duck movie taught us that females
on Duckworld have human-like chests, right?
Like they totally show duck boobs in that movie
even though ducks aren't mammals and they wouldn't
have memory glands. So maybe the ducks of Duckworld
evolved to have more mammalian-like sex organs
despite remaining avian in an appearance. I
don't necessarily think it's out of bounds
to say that Howard maybe doesn't have a corkscrew
dong. Maybe it's more like a human-like feather
dong or something like that. But then I remembered
that if Darcy gave birth to an egg, as the
female, she would be the one to produce the
egg. But human ova do not have hard shells.
So at that point I was like, fuck, I do not
understand any of this. And I flipped my office
table. So I will say that you thought about
Howard the Duck's dick way more than I did.
But everything you're saying is valid. I just
don't get it, man. I don't get how it would
work. I just don't understand. But, you know,
trying to get past that, this episode was another
silly one. It was really hard to go back to
back with the silly episodes, but I wanted
to give this episode a little bit more leeway
due to the fact that Howard the Duck stories
from the comics are a little bit more silly
by their very nature. Yeah, well, the two stars,
both Howard the Duck and Darcy, are pretty much
comedic relief, I would say. So I'm more forgiving
of this episode being goofy than I was of the
last one for sure. Yeah. I mean, there were
some jokes that just didn't land for me. Like
when Ebony Ma was saying that the Black Order
is on Jotunheim for a company retreat because
they have a group on. I was like, what the
fuck is going on here? But bad jokes aside,
I tried to give the episode. a little bit more
grace in terms of the cringe worthiness on display
here. I did like the theme of new parenting,
being a new parent myself as the father of a
one-year-old. I can appreciate that. But there
was also like another part of me that was like,
why is that baby sleeping with a blanket in
its crib? Like it's just born, like get that
blanket out of there. They shouldn't be sleeping
with blankets until they're one. You notice
stuff like that in movies all the time when
you're a new parent. There was something sweet
about Darcy and Howard's relationship. They
just seemed really comfortable together. And
it seemed like they were great parents concerning
what Bertie became, which we find out later
on in the series. I didn't even care for that
payoff. Like, who cares by the end of it? I'm
like, I don't know anything about this character.
Why is it that important to me? I thought Bertie
was fine. I think conceptually, she's pretty
cool as a character, especially because she
kind of looks like Lea Thompson's Beverly Switzler
from the 80s movie. Well, that's one of the
problems I actually had with it. She was just
way too 80s, I hate 80s style. What? Yeah. Dude,
you're so wrong.
fantasies collide and heroes clash, one podcast
network rises above the rest. Prepare yourself
for the ultimate showdowns in comic books, video
games, movies, and anime. The Dynomic Podcast
Network presents Console Combat, where video
game legends brawl every Monday. Comic Book
Titans smash every Tuesday. Max Destruction,
where TV and action heroes battle every Wednesday.
And Sendro World, where anime champions clash
every Thursday. Join us as we speculate on
the matches and, armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge victorious.
Visit dynamicpodcast.com where we settle the
debate and settle the score.
Let's move on to episode 5, which was called
What If The Emergence Destroyed The Earth.
It stars Dominique Thorne as Riri Williams,
Emily Van Camp as Sharon Carter, Tessa Thompson
as Valkyrie, and Jason Isaacs as The Eminence.
On a post-apocalyptic Earth that was ripped
apart by the celestial Tiamat's emergence from
the planet's core, Mysterio takes control of
humanity's last vestiges using Tony Stark's
drones and his own holographic illusions. Riri
Williams tries to create a weaponized suit of
armor using the technology available to her,
but is captured by Vision, who has been commandeered
by Mysterio. She is rescued by the Alliance,
the last remaining force united against Mysterio
composed of heroes such as Wong, Okoye, Valkyrie,
and Ying Nan. Riri is taken to the Alliance's
base to complete her weapon when Vision attacks.
She is able to complete her weapon just in time,
using it to defeat Vision, then uses his components
to become a human-synthesoid hybrid to infiltrate
Mysterio's tech systems. Alongside the Alliance,
Riri attacks Mysterio's base, able to see through
his illusions. However, her suit malfunctions
and she falls victim to Mysterio's trap. He
reveals that he too is a tech hybrid, having
uploaded his network's nanites into his body,
allowing him to control his illusions with
his mind.
so he needs Vision's components to keep him
alive. He attempts to extract Riri's synthzoid
pieces from her, but with the Watcher's prompting,
she pulls them back to herself and phases through
Mysterio, assimilating his internal nanite network.
Having defeated the villain and dismantled
his federation, Riri projects the Avengers logo
to Earth's remaining survivors, giving them
hope. Meanwhile, three Watchers known as the
Eminence, the Incarnate, and the Executioner
witness Uatu's prompting of Riri, pleased by
his interference. I liked the premise of this
episode. The concept of Tiamat's early emergence
was solid, and I think it makes sense that
someone like Riri, if she was a survivor, would
prove to be a vital asset to the rest of humanity
given her technological prowess. I think the
episode had promised that it largely lived
up to. The one thing that I would have changed
that would have made it better was the use
of more prominent hero and villain characters.
Like, Mysterio was an interesting choice for
the leader of the Federation, but it also seems
a little unlike his character to take such
a commanding role. Like the character's accomplishment
in this episode is probably greater than anything
Mysterio has ever done in the comics. I wouldn't
have been surprised if his role was someone
more like Dr. Doom or Norman Osborn or even
like the Kingpin that had taken over what remained
of Earth, but I consider this like a step up
for Mysterio. Not that I want to disparage
him, because I do like Mysterio. Yeah, I think
Mysterio is one of the more interesting villains
in the MCU as a whole, so I was actually glad
to see him return here. As a master of illusion,
he is hands down the best candidate to have
done the things that the character did in this
episode. I also liked the fact that they adapted
his cancer arc in the comics into this, like
he was a sick dyke man who was trying to prove
himself in a way, except instead of cancer,
they went with nanites. Yeah, his look... in
this episode was very similar to the look that
he had in the Guardian Devil story arc in the
comic books. You're right though, for what
this part required in this story, Mysterio was
the best candidate. I also think that Mysterio,
he's had some pretty impressive feats in the
comics, you know? He was the only one from
the main universe to go into the ultimate universe,
if I'm not mistaken. Yeah. So I think this
is in keeping with some of the more impressive
things he's done. He never like took over Earth
1610 though. No, but the guy is a technological
powerhouse. Yeah, I do think that having Wong
Ying Nan Okoye and Valkyrie as the last surviving
heroes was a little bit weak for this episode.
Like, Dan, you couldn't even squeeze in like
a bee lister in there. It was very random.
I felt like, oh, this was the cast you could
afford. OK. Yeah, I would have liked to have
a stronger supporting cast for Riri Williams.
I got the overall impression that what if season
three was supposed to come out? after the Ironheart
series given that we had Riri's inclusion in
this episode and the Hood's inclusion in the
next episode. Yeah, that makes sense because
Ironheart, the series has been pushed back,
I think a number of times. Right, right. After
seeing this episode though, I'm really looking
forward to the Ironheart series. I hope that
show really portrays Riri as like adaptable
and smart as she was in this episode. I actually
really liked the Ironheart vision hybrid that
she became. That was pretty cool. That was
pretty sweet. I rate episode 5 3.5 stars out
of 5. I thought it was pretty good. Oh, and
I don't think I mentioned my rating for the
last episode too. The Howard the Duck episode,
I gave 3 out of 5. Let's move on to episode
6, which was called What If 1872. It stars
Simu Liu as Shang-Chi, slash Ten Rings. Hailey
Steinfeld gave the voice of Kate Bishop Hawkeye.
Wyatt Russell was in the episode as John Walker.
and Walton Goggins played Sonny Birch. In the
days of the Old West, a group of gunslingers
signal for the legendary fighter, Shang-Chi,
known to them as the Ten Rings for his unique
calling card. Partnered with the crack shot
Kate Bishop, known as Hawkeye, Shang-Chi takes
out the gunslingers. He gets John Walker to
give him the location of the Hood, a mysterious
villain abducting the Chinese immigrants building
the region's rail lines who had taken Shang-Chi's
sister, Sha Ling. Walker's info leads Shang-Chi
and Hawkeye to a town which they find decimated,
with only a young boy named Kui-Jun-Fan left
remaining. The boy tells them the town was
attacked by the Hood, who left on a ghost train.
Shang-Chi, Hawkeye, and Jun-Fan head the train
off at the pass, discovering that it hovers
off the ground using stolen Stark tech. They
find the missing railroad workers under a trance,
hypnotized by Sonny Birch, using a special
musical pocket watch. Jun Fan escapes Sunny's
men, but they capture the boy and nearly throw
him off the train, prompting the watcher's interference.
The train arrives at the station where the
hood waits and reveals to be Cha Ling herself,
who is using the cloak's dark power to help
enslave an army to fight for her vision of the
country. She and Shang-Chi battle as Hawkeye
is put under Sunny Birch's trance. Jun Fan rings
the train's bell ten times to snap Hawkeye
and the prisoners out of their trances. and
Shang-Chi decides that fighting his sister
is not the answer. Just as Chao Ling is about
to deliver the killing blow, Hawkeye shoots
and kills her, ending the Hood's threat. Shang-Chi
and Hawkeye watch as the Chinese immigrants
celebrate, listening to Jun-Fan, referred to
as the Iron Fist, re-enact the story of their
adventure. The pair rise off into the sunset
as Uwatu the Watcher is confronted by his peers
for his meddling. They attack him, resulting
in shards breaking from their observational
plane and hurling into the multiverse. I thought
this was a fantastic episode. I really love
how they were able to incorporate characters
like Shang-Chi and Hawkeye in this old west
setting, and even tossing in references to characters
that haven't shown up in the MCU yet, like
the Hood and Iron Fist. And they even fit in
actual history, like the Chinese workers' mistreatment
during the transcontinental railroad construction.
It was just really well done, really well realized
in a way that fit neatly together like a puzzle
piece, it just made sense. I- I completely
disagree. I did not like this episode. It was
one of the most random episodes, I think, of
the entire series so far. And I understand that
the watcher kind of set up that was on the
far reaches of the multiverse, and therefore
it was going to be a little bit more random.
But there are a lot of things I didn't understand,
like the Walt Goggins pocket watch. What the
hell was that about? The iron fist connection.
I didn't actually even make that connection.
I guess that's interesting. Definitely interested
in seeing. Iron Fist make an appearance in
the MCU at some point, hopefully at Shang-Chi's
sequel. But also, like, why Kate Bishop and
Shang-Chi to begin with? Like I didn't understand
the connection there whatsoever. As far as
Hawkeye goes, Hawkeye totally makes sense as
a Western character, plus the story itself
draws a lot of parallels to the film True Grit,
of which Hailey Steinfeld made her debut performance
as an actress. So one, they're playing that
up. casting Kayleigh Steinfeld in this role
and to Hawkeye it just makes sense as an old
west character being a crack shot. I think
it makes a lot of sense that she would pair
up with Shang-Chi. Tossing in Sunny Birch I
think makes a lot of sense considering the actor
Walton Goggins has been in a lot of westerns
and he said that he got his pocket watch from
Russia which I think was a tie-in to the hydra
conditioning using the code words to brainwash
the Winter Soldier but in this case it was
a song that was doing it. They needed something
auditory so that Jun Fan can interrupt it with
the 10 rings of the bell. OK, well, I mean,
some of those explanations are just like meta
rationalities. So I guess these sort of work.
Did it explain where Shang-Chi's sister got
the hood from? Yeah, she got it from a villain
who was already exploiting Chinese workers
at the time. She killed him and took the hood
from him. I don't know. The episode was too
different from the MCU for my liking. Who cares
about that? What do you mean, too different
from the MCU? The show's called fucking What
If. Yeah, but this was more different than
other episodes. No, it wasn't. They just changed
the time period. And in regards to Iron Fist,
now there have been multiple Iron Fists throughout
history in the comic books, dating back centuries.
And there was an Iron Fist that was around in
the mid 19th century named Jun Fan, who actually
traveled to America during the days of the Old
West. That was the character that they were
incorporating in this episode. It was a really
nice call out to the comics. He was actually
the Iron Fist before Orson Randall, who eventually
passed his mantle down to Danny Rand. So really,
really cool stuff. For that, I rate the episode
four stars out of five. Episode seven was called,
What If The Watcher Disappeared? It starred
Hailey Atwell as Peggy Carter, Jason Isaacs
as The Eminence, Devri Jacobs as Kihori, Allison
Sealy-Smith as Aurora Monroe, Natasha Lyonne
as Bertie. Karen Gillan as Nebula, Taika Waititi
as Korg, and Ross Marquand as Infinity Ultron.
Following the events of What If Nebula Joined
the Nova Corps from Season 2, the monstrous
Hydra Champion tears into the dimension, threatening
Xandar. Captain Carter and her team of multiversal
guardians including K'Hori, Birdie, and Storm
the Goddess of Thunder arrive on the scene
and by propelling Captain Carter like a bullet
through the monster's head, they defeat it.
After the battle, the group discover the shards
deducing the Watcher is in trouble. They attempt
to get to the 5th dimension to help Uatu, first
using the shard's energies to augment their
ship, then using another shard to augment Storm's
hammer Mjolnir using a spell. Unsure of how
to use their final shard, the team remembers
that Infinity Ultron once breached the barrier
into the 5th dimension so they make a plan to
capture and reprogram him. Knowing the mission
would be too dangerous for her friends, Peggy
journeys alone. and finds Infinity Ultron living
in solitude in the universe he destroyed. The
other Guardians realize Peggy's actions and
go to rescue her, finding only Infinity Ultron
and Peggy's broken shield. Ultron recounts
to them that Peggy was attacked and taken by
one of the Watchers. He tells them that after
spending eons alone in his universe, he's realized
that emptiness is not the same as peace, and
agrees to help the Guardians in their mission
to the fifth dimension. He uses the last shard
to gain fifth dimensional power. and pilots
their ship into the Watcher's observational
plane. I thought this was a pretty decent episode
as a first parter. I thought there was a lot
of good set up here. I thought the action was
pretty top notch, including the battle against
the Hydra champion. I thought it was really
nice revisiting Nebula and Xandar from season
two. And most of all, I thought it was really
cool to see the variant of Storm that was the
goddess of thunder. Voiced by the same actress
that voices Storm in X-Men 97. I liked this
episode. I liked these last two episodes. a
lot, particularly when it came to the action
and just the premise itself. I thought the mythology
of the Watchers, it was really, really interesting.
The most interesting thing to come out of this
entire what if series, all three seasons. That
said, I do wish that they would have had a more
familiar cast of characters to aid the Watcher
in this final battle. Two of them are original.
One of them I thought was kind of cheap and
just turning Storm into a Thor. variant, I don't
think Storm should be a Thor variant. I think
that's kind of a disservice to Storm. Why? Because
she is not Thor, they are separate characters.
I just wish they would have maybe just gone
with Storm. No, I mean, considering that the
characters are both masters of the elements,
I thought it made total sense to have her as
a variant of Thor in this episode. I thought
that was really badass. I didn't think that.
I think a lot of people thought that too. I
know a lot of people who actually questioned
whether Storm was a variant of Thor and to me
that's I don't like that. Whether she's a variant
of Thor or whether she's a variant of herself
I think it works either way. I definitely don't
think it does a disservice to either of the
characters. I do agree that it would have been
cool if the Multiversal Guardians included more
characters from the series past. It was nice
to have Khori back. It was interesting to have
Bertie in the mix here. Like what if they did
really Williams slash Vision like that would
have been cool. That would have been cool.
And also tossing like a novo prime nebula in
there as well. It's almost like a multiversal
a-force in that regard. Yeah, yeah. I really
liked the opening to this episode where they
switched perspectives from Uwatu to the imminence
where he was like, a watcher must never ask
what if, you know, I thought that was pretty
cool. Yeah, the opening to the series, I never
skipped it because I just loved the narration
by Jeffrey Wright. The whole premise that it
sets up about time and space and things like
that. leading up to the whole question of what
if, it's a fantastic setup. And then to twist
it near the end like this, I thought was also
pretty cool. It was very meta in this very enjoyable
way. Did you notice that Peggy's multiversal
ship in this episode looked a lot like King
of the Conqueror ship from Ant-Man and the
Wasp quantumania? No. Oh yeah, like the sphere?
No, it's like a clamshell type thing. I didn't
notice that. That's cool. Yeah, that was a pretty
cool Easter egg. I also really liked Infinity
Ultron's Revelation. toward the end of the episode
that life must exist for peace to exist? Well,
the philosophical ideas posited in this episode
and the next episode I thought were very profound,
probably more profound than they needed to be.
And I definitely was not expecting that from
this series considering we also got some very,
very silly episodes. Oh yeah, the show definitely
veered wildly back and forth between being profound
and being goofy as hell. In all, I give episode
7 3.5 stars out of 5. I thought it was really
good. a great setup. I thought you would have
given it a higher rating than that. I thought
this was like at least a four. It was good,
but it didn't have enough payoff. It all came
in the next episode, which I thought was the
best of the season. That was episode eight titled
What If What If. In a flashback scene, the
Eminence shows Uwatu the multiverse and has
him take the oath, making him a watcher and
instructing him to make only observations, not
judgments. Uwatu wonders what if the Eminence
was wrong about him. but is told that what if
isn't a relevant question. In the present,
Uwatu makes his case to the other Watchers that
his actions were for the betterment of the
multiverse. Captain Carter is brought before
the Watchers as well, convincing Uwatu that
though a Watcher is supposed to be no one, everyone
is someone. Infinity Ultron arrives with the
Guardians and attacks the Watchers, allowing
Peggy and Uwatu to escape. The Watchers destroy
Infinity Ultron as the team plots a course for
Strange Supreme's universe. But they're knocked
from the fifth dimension. onto a barren planet.
Though the Guardians attack the Watchers, their
efforts are useless and the team is nearly killed,
prompting Gawatu to instruct them to take the
Watcher's oath and granting them his powers.
As Watchers, they attack the Eminence, the
Incarnate, and the Executioner in an all-out
battle. In an effort to win, the trio merge
and begin erasing Peggy,
Peggy musters the strength to sacrifice herself,
pushing the Watchers into Strange Supreme's
universe where the Watchers have no power. With
the Eminence defeated, Uatu reveals to him
what he's learned, that what something is, is
not the same as what it means. Mourning Peggy,
Kihori, Birdie, and Storm join the Watcher on
the observational plane to watch over the multiverse.
I loved this episode. I thought it was enjoyable
not only from an action and spectacle perspective
from which it delivered in spades. But I think,
you know, the episode was also philosophically
profound. There were some deep lessons and real
heroic struggles going on. I'm really curious
as to how the mythology of the Watchers matches
what's in the comics. It's a little bit different.
Like, Iwatu doesn't watch from the observational
plane. He watches from the blue area of the
moon. So they play a little bit looser with
the mythology of the Watchers overall. But
the essence is there. And also, like, I've never
seen a Watcher throw down like the Watchers
threw down in this episode. Holy shit, man.
They were badass. Dude, so this battle between
the Watchers and the Guardians of the Multiverse
may just be the most epic battle to ever happen
in any on-screen superhero project ever. It
would be up there, for sure. Absolutely. Just
in terms of epicness? Yeah, you might be right.
I mean, but the What If series has always had
epic action. You take a look at the Guardians
of the Multiverse against Infinity Ultron from
the first season. And then you have Khori and
Captain Carter against Strange Supreme in the
second season where they were using all of those
cool universe destroying artifacts against
him and stuff. But yeah, I think this episode
was the best of the lot. and just kind of melted
my face from all the awesomeness that it had
to show. Like even towards the end, how cool
the watchers were and how they were able to
manipulate space, time and everything like
that. The way they played with physics in this
episode I thought was really cool. It was really
fascinating when they joined back to back to
back and became like one being spinning around
almost like the living tribunal. It was really
abstract in concept and so interestingly rendered
on the screen. Oh man, and the stakes. Holy
cow, like erasing them from every multiverse.
That was wild. And yeah, the final battle, the
fact that they cracked a planet in half. I
was just watching this and I was just like taking
notes for like a future duel episode because
it's just how cool it was. Yeah, I felt like
we were put to shame in terms of how cosmic
level fights go. Oh yeah. Right, because we've
speculated on duels between cosmic level characters
and I don't think they've been nearly as interesting
as what we saw on the screen here. Absolutely
not. Like I could only aspire to get as awesome
as this final battle was in our Duel speculations
We got a separate game up. I have to ask why
are there multiple watchers? Like if there's
only one multiverse in the comic books who watch
who looks over earth 616 So they just never
explained that in this show No, the function
is a little bit different of the watchers here
I'm assuming that they have a whole lot of watchers
looking after a whole lot of different parts
of the multiverse I found it interesting that
the other two Watchers also had titles. I knew
that there was the Eminence, but I didn't know
that there was also the Executioner and what
else? The Incarnate. That's weird. I can't off
the top of my head think about the significance
of those three names for those characters. Well
in the books, I believe the Watcher that everyone
else reports to is just simply known as the
One, and they kind of like deposit all their
knowledge there. But I like the names of the
Eminence, the Executioner, and incarnate. I
think it makes them sound pretty badass. It's
almost like one is a creator, one is a preserver,
and one is a destroyer. Kind of like Hindu mythology.
That's pretty cool. Yeah. But essentially,
they almost played like God. And the philosophical
questions in this episode almost border on
the theological because it's essentially asking,
well, why does God allow bad things to happen?
And in that regard, Uatu is almost like a Lucifer
type character. where he's rebelling against
the higher order. Yeah, you're right. I didn't
even really think about that. That's pretty
interesting. The concepts of like to preserve
something when only needs to observe it, that
was fascinating. There was a statement posited
by one of the watchers that to essentially
be able to see something from all sides, you
cannot have a side. And Watu's response was,
but things have changed. I didn't think there
was a good answer at all. I don't understand
like. What changed? I didn't think they explained
that well enough. No, they definitely could
have dedicated, you know, an entire season toward
the philosophical questions that were raised
during this episode, I think, and really get
into Uatu's mindset of why he chose to do the
things that he did. Besides the fact that, you
know, everyone is special and injustices need
to be righted. But I think for the purposes
of this episode, that was enough explanation
for me. I still think I'm on the side of the
eminence and his buddies. because I don't think
Watu put up a good enough debate, but no, yeah,
it was still a fantastic episode, just for
going harder on the philosophy than it needed
to. Yeah, I gotta say I'm on the side of Watu.
I think injustices need to be righted, and I
think if you don't think that, then you're
not a very good superhero candidate, Jonathan.
No, I think that sometimes you do just need
to observe things, that not all injustices can
be righted, and not everything that you see
as an injustice is an injustice. because if
you look down the line, maybe it all turns
out for the better in the end anyway. Maybe
if you look at the very end of things, things
are good. You know, we can't always see the
consequences of correcting certain things that
you feel like you need to be corrected. Superheroes
are guilty sometimes of playing God, and I
think it's hard to know where that line is before
you cross it. Uatu, you know, definitely has
the eyes of a watcher, so you can kind of see
everything. So maybe he did know. But I don't
understand then why he was disagreeing with
people who also had his power. Because they
weren't looking closely like he was probably.
I don't know, they explore these ideas, I remember
in the Captain Marvel comic book series back
when Genisvel, who is the son of Marvel, was
in the role. And he gained cosmic awareness
and he basically was driven insane by questions
like these. Whether or not to save one person
or whether or not to save a whole planet of
people. And the effects. that resulted from
his actions and he could see everything and
he ended up destroying the entire universe and
then recreating it basically. It was a really
interesting read but I don't want to drive myself
crazy thinking about some of these answers.
One of the coolest things I thought about this
episode was at the very end when the Watchers
kind of like signing off, we got to see multiversal
variants of characters like Riri Williams as
the Punisher, he had like Thanos as Wolverine,
a Samurai Ghost That was all really cool to
see. It makes me want the show to go on forever.
Yeah, I would have loved to have seen some
of those episodes rather than some of the episodes
we got in this season. Absolutely. But that's
the end of the show overall. The episodes in
this season were pretty typical of the series
as a whole in that they were hit or miss. There
were some episodes that I really didn't like
this season. There were some episodes that I
absolutely loved. And I think when the show
is doing well, it's really playing up to its
potential. And when it's not. it's really squandering
that potential. And yeah, though I'd say the
show did squander its own potential somewhat
here in this season due to its hit or miss nature,
I think it ends with a bang, not a whimper,
due to its spectacular action and meaningful
themes. I'm gonna give this season three and
a half stars, a fresh rating on Rotten Tomatoes.
Again, I liked five out of the eight episodes
here. Overall, I still think season two was
the best. Yeah, I think season two had the
best questions, but like I said earlier, I also
think that the best episodes of the series
as a whole were the final two of season three,
but I get it. I'd be interested in hearing
what the listeners think, so be sure to reach
out to us guys on Discord if you're a patron,
or on Instagram. But that does it for this review.
AJ9K helped close us out. Thanks for listening
to Dynamic Duel. Visit the show's website at
dynamicDuel.com and follow us on Instagram
at dynamicDuelpodcast. You can support the show
on Patreon at patreon.com slash dynamicDuel
and joining a tier that works for you, or by
rating and reviewing Dynamic Duel on Apple
Podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser or on our website.
Don't forget to listen to the other shows in
the DynaMic Podcast Network, including Max
Destruction, Senjoh World and Console Combat.
In our next episode, as a tie into this review,
we will be doing a duel between the monitor
and the watcher. Yeah, I didn't know how we
were going to do this duel with the watcher
prior to seeing the final episode of What If
Season 3, but now I'm totally game for it.
It's going to be fucking epic as hell, hopefully.
So look forward to that next week. That does
it for this episode. We want to give a big thanks
to our executive producers, Ken Johnson, John
Strosky, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Balcom.
If everyone is someone, then someone is everyone.
But if no one is everyone, and no one is also
no one, then someone is also no one, therefore
your mama.