This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
Welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin brother Marvelous
Joe. And in this episode- Incoming. Whoa, what's
going on AJ9K? Incoming transmission from Diamondback
at Console Combat. File name man vmonster.afd.
Duel input re-initiated. new fighter selection,
Godzilla vs Ultraman. Okay that's weird, so
it seems like our initial episode idea has been
scrapped due to this glitch and we are now
going to bring you the matchup of Godzilla vs
Ultraman. Crazy! And since this glitch is coming
from Console Combat, we bet that you can probably
check out the first part of this duel matchup
over on their podcast. We're just going to be
continuing the battle here. Before that, we're
going to break down the comic book movie news
from the past week, of which there was none!
But we did miss a news item from two weeks ago,
and that was the third trailer for Suicide
Squad, Isekai. That's right, folks, this entire
episode is brought to you from the Isle of
Japan! Hai! As always, we list our segment times
in our episode description, so feel free to
check out the show notes if you want to skip
ahead to a particular topic. Our artificially
intelligent duel simulator, AJ-9K, has a quick
message for our listeners, so listen up. Why
hello there. Do you love listening and chatting
about Marvel and DC? Then become a part of
the dynamic duel community on Patreon, where
you can choose from three tiers. The dynamic
2-0 tier lets you listen to this podcast without
ads and gives you access to its Discord chat
group, where you can chat with Johnny DC and
Marvelous Joe. The fantastic four tier gives
you that and more with two bonus episodes each
month, including bloopers and top 10 shows
where Johnny and Joe count down your favorite
Marvel and DC subjects. The X-Force tier makes
you an executive producer of Dynamic Duel, where
every month you help the hosts choose what
to review and who to fight against each other.
And finally, the DynaMic Podcast Network tier
allows aspiring podcasters to create their own
battle-focused show using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and consultation,
and get you simulation results to announce on
your show. Pitch the twins your show via email
at dyna
them on social media. Check it out at patreon.com
slash dynamic duel. Pip pip cheerio. Thanks
AJ9K and thanks to everyone who supports the
podcast. Guys be sure to check out the rest
of the shows in the DynaMic Podcast Network,
especially this week because you will be getting
four times the Godzilla versus Ultraman goodness.
As we just stated, you'll get the first part
of this battle in console combat. This episode
is just continuing what they started, so be
sure to check out console combat. followed by
Max Destruction tomorrow, and then Senjoworld
on Thursday for the conclusion. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com
or click on the link in our show notes to listen
to all of the shows in the DynaMic Podcast
Network. But with that out of the way, quick
to the No Prize! A No Prize is an award Marvel
used to give out to fans. Our version, the
Dynamic Duel No Prize, is a digital award we
post on Instagram for the person that we feel
gave the best answer to our question of the
week. Last week we asked, what song do you
hope to hear in Joker Follyadoo and what character
would sing it? Now this is coming off of the
news that the Joker sequel movie is going to
be a jukebox musical with popular pop songs
in it. It was a disappointing news item but
it gave us some great answers that we're going
to break down now. We got a lot of them. We're
going to give you the three honorable mentions
as well as the no prize winner. Our first honorable
mention goes to Christian Rubito who said.
Hey, this is Christian Urbito. I'm going to
submit the answer of Break Stuff by Lynn Biscuit,
because that's kind of how I feel when I learned
that this movie was going to be a musical.
The first movie is one of my favorite DC movies
ever. And to hear this is extremely disappointing.
And to the fact of who can sing it, I guess
everyone together. So it can really pack a
punch. Yeah, thanks, all. I mean, it's all about
the he said, she said bullshit. I hope you
know that Joker packs his chainsaw, and they'll
skin your ass raw. Weren't those the days when
like Limp Bizkit was like, OK to like? Yeah.
Oh, man, they were huge back in the day. And
I don't know what happened. They just sucked,
I guess. I don't know about that. I still like
I really still like the song that they did for
Mission Impossible. But break stuff. That's
an inspired choice. I can't say that I see that
working too well within the tone that Todd
Phillips has established with the first Joker
movie. But then again, this seems to be a departure
from that anyway. Right, I mean, and plus, you
know, the Joker's an angry guy and Break Stuff
is like the ultimate angry song. So, great answer,
Christian. Our next honorable mention goes
to Andrew Shunk, who said, Hey guys, Andrew
Shunk here. I would have to say Mad World,
the Gary Jules version that was in Donnie Darko,
would be great for this movie. I would have
Harley Quinn sing it and it could even be a
duet. but start with Harley Quinn singing.
Feeling kind of funny, feeling kind of sad.
The dreams in which I'm dying are the best
I've ever had. I think those depressing lyrics
totally fit fine with the themes of the Joker.
Yeah, he mentioned that he would want to hear
the Gary Jules version, which is a great version.
But of course, that is a cover of a song originally
done by Tears for Fears. And I think that one
would actually work pretty well within the period
piece type of film that is the Joker. And also,
I believe Harley Quinn first debuted in an episode
of Batman the Animated Series that was called
Mad Love. Well, it wasn't her debut, but it
was an award-winning episode that went into
her origin. I see, I see. Mad World, Mad Love.
They could change it up to Mad Love. Yeah,
totally. Great answer, Andrew. Our final honorable
mention goes to Waldo. Found him! Who said?
Hey guys, this is Waldo. Longtime listener,
first time caller. I feel like It's an obvious
answer, but I just have to say it. Lady Gaga
needs to sing Joker Face. I mean, it's right
there. If they don't do it, that is an intentionally
missed opportunity. Mama, Mama Joker Face,
Mama Joker Face, Mama, Mama. Yeah, you know
she doesn't repeat Poker Face that second time,
right? Did you know that? I only just learned
that she says Fucker Face in this song. That's
crazy. Kids, listen to that on the radio. No,
but taking poker face and trying to get into
Joker face is very on the nose for a film starring
Lady Gaga. Probably too on the nose for the
film, but I did like your creative twist on
the song to make it Joker face. I wonder what
she'll mean when she goes, can't read my can't
read my no, he can't read my Joker face. It
means she's just wearing too much makeup, I
guess. Great answers. Everyone, we want to
give a quick shout out to Colby Hentges, John
Storosky, Mitchell Smoothie and Scott Camacho
for also taking the time to visit our website
and drop us an answer. Appreciate it guys.
But the winner of this week's No Prize goes
to Lizzie Dyer Arnie, who said, Cause I'm a
picker, I'm a grinner, I'm a lover, and I'm
a sinner. Playing my music in the sun. I'm
a joker, I'm a smoker, I'm a midnight toker.
Shoulda want to hurt no one.
The Joker by the Steve Miller band. Thanks.
Yeah. Great job. There we go. Great job. Well
done. Great answer, by the way. Actually, when
we first asked this question, I told Jonathan
that I was hoping someone would answer with
The Joker by the Steve Miller band because
that's like, you know, that's the obvious answer.
It's set right in that time period too. And
it just seems spot on. Great job Lizzie for
giving us that great rendition. That was awesome.
As is the song. I totally remember jamming out
to that song on Guitar Hero back when that
was a thing. Yeah I hated doing vocals for that
song. You know what part like whistles it's
like whoo whoo. Great answer Lizzie. Thanks
for being a great sport. You win this week's
no prize. If you the listener want a shot at
winning your own no prize, stay tuned to later
on this episode when we'll be asking another
question of the week. And now that that's done,
on to the news.
Okay, so a couple of weeks ago we got the third
trailer for the anime series, Suicide Squad
Isakai, along with a release date for the premiere
of the show in Japan at least. We have no word
when it's gonna arrive in America yet, but at
least we know in Japan it will be debuting
this July. I imagine it's not gonna come to
America until they localize it and do dubs
for the voice track, but who knows, we'll see.
I wouldn't watch that anyway, I'm gonna watch
the subs. Hell yeah, subs before dubs. The trailer
starts off with this romantic kind of scene
between Harley Quinn and the Joker, who looks
pretty awesome. Way cooler than the Jared Leto
version. He still has tattoos, but the tattoo
is like of a smile on his face rather than
like damaged. Yeah, these tattoos actually make
sense. Right, yeah. A lot of this film looks
heavily inspired by both Suicide Squad films
and it's just pretty much dripping with style.
but it also doesn't hurt that it has a pretty
catchy J-pop song going on in the background.
The trailer definitely seems to be promoting
the song, which I guess is called Go-Getters
by Maury Kaliope. Never heard of that artist,
but it's pretty cool. I thought you were a
big J-pop fan, Jon. K-pop, bro! K-pop! Don't
be racist! I bet you so many new listeners
are surprised that you listen to K-pop, and
so many older listeners are not surprised at
all considering how little you know about music.
That's why it's because he listens to K-pop.
Just because you spend a year living in Korea.
It's catchy. It's catchy. But no, it looks
like eventually Harley Quinn gets separated
from the Joker and she's taken with other members
of the Suicide Squad to the world of Isekai,
which I guess is connected to the DC world
through a portal of some sort. And they're there
to put a stop between a war between a kingdom
and an empire, it looks like. Is it just me
or is the plot to this thing look extremely
vague? Like we've gotten three trailers for
this and I don't think we've gotten any new
information on what the story actually is, besides
the fact that they go into this other realm.
I don't know. It feels very much like a Japanese
anime teaser to me. You know, at the end of
most anime episodes, they'll tease the next
episode and I have no idea what the hell they're
teasing, to be honest. I'm like, well, that's
pretty crazy. Is that really the continuation
of the story? All right, sure. This definitely
feels like that. But it's cool just to see
the cast of characters that they have. As we've
seen in previous trailers, they're bringing
Harley Quinn, Deadshot, King Shark, Peacemaker,
Rick Flag. But this is the first time we get
to see Diablo, from the first Suicide Squad
movie, the one that controls fire. Although
this time they're giving him a like Michael
Jackson kind of vibe. Yeah, that's weird. I
think it's kind of cool. Another thing that
caught me off guard here is that it's almost
like they're breaking the fourth wall. because
you have the Joker talking about like, oh,
this is just a really long intro to the show.
And then Diablo later on is like, oh, they
miscast us. It's kind of interesting. I wonder
if they'll actually play into that. Do you
think it's strange mixing the world of Suicide
Squad with like this medieval fantasy setting?
Yeah, and that's partially why I'm here for
it. Like it's gonna be really, really interesting
and something you probably haven't seen before,
especially with these characters. By the end
of the trailer, we see that Harley Quinn really
just wants to return home. to her lover, the
Joker, and she's definitely like the standout
character of this trailer, of all the trailers
really. It looks like she's the main character
of the show. It looks like there's a lot of
romantic elements at play, not just between
the Joker and Harley Quinn, but I don't know,
just the setting of the world that they venture
into seems highly romanticized. Yeah, that's
fair. And also very Shinto in a way, or at least
like Eastern folklore with like giant boars
and stuff like that. I really hope that this
gets released in the US this year. I'm not
holding my breath. Even if they don't localize
it, I would still love to find a way to watch
the Japanese subtitled version. But given the
fact that this series is an anime, that brings
us to our question of the week.
What is your favorite anime? And why? And it
doesn't have to be just Marvel or DC. I'm just
curious. Yeah, record your answer at dynamicduel.com
by clicking on the red microphone button in
the bottom right-hand corner of the screen,
which will prompt you to leave us a voicemail.
Your message could be up to 30 seconds long,
and don't forget to leave your name in case
we include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a Dynamic
Duel No Prize that we'll post to Instagram.
Be sure to answer before April 6th.
That does it for all the news for this episode.
Now let's go ahead and move on to the main
event, where we find out who is going to win
in a fight between the DC Comics version of
Godzilla and the Marvel Comics version of Ultraman.
Okay, so I'm not sure why our network's AI simulators
have decided to glitch this April Fool's week
and give us all Godzilla vs. Ultraman duels,
but I'm here for it because the rights to Godzilla
are partially owned by Legendary Pictures, who
teams up with Warner Brothers to make some
pretty awesome Godzilla movies. And they've
even done some comics published by DC, also
owned by Warner Brothers. Yeah, and actually
Marvel Comics has produced three Ultraman miniseries,
which have come out recently, I think starting
in 2020. So Ultraman is a Marvel Comics character
of sorts. What a coincidence! Who would have
thought? Crazy! It's almost like we all got
together and brainstormed which characters could
work across all of our different podcasts in
our network. Yeah, because there are video game
versions of Godzilla and Ultraman. There are
comic versions that we're going over. There
are movie versions, obviously, and anime versions.
So this is pretty exciting. Yeah, can't wait
to find out who's gonna win between Godzilla
and Ultraman, but to explain the methodology
behind our duels, let's go to our sentient
duel simulator, Alfred Jarvis 9000. AJ and INK
tell our listeners how you go about determining
a winner in our duel matchups. Yes, of course,
sir. The way I determine a winner between the
contestants is by running 1000 Monte Carlo simulations
using the characters' statistics. A Monte Carlo
simulation is a probabilistic model used to
determine outcomes through random sampling.
In this case... I randomize the statistics along
a normal distribution as a way to simulate
the many variables that can occur during battle.
The stat parameters are based on the official
Marvel power grid from which the DC characters'
statistics are extrapolated. Additional stat
categories are included such as range, damage
potential, versatility and perception in order
to create a more detailed and accurate simulation.
The results of the 1000 simulations provide
a percentage of wins for each character. Contestant
with the higher percentage is declared the
victor as they have a higher probability to
win any given battle. In an equitable pairing,
neither character should win 100% of the matches.
The comic book stories have shown that there's
even a way for Batman to defeat Superman, so
the confidence rate of my method falls in line
with the precedents that have been established
in the source material. My mathematical simulations
are without subjectivity or bias. Feats are
not the sole consideration, nor are fan votes
tabulated for determination of the winner. Thanks
AJ9K! Before we run the simulations though,
we like to break down each character's comic
book histories and abilities before improvising
a scenario on how we imagine one of the 1000
simulations would play out, beat for beat.
And I believe it's my turn to go first with
the DC character's backstory, the DC version
of Godzilla, which is the Monsterverse version.
Now in 1980 Tokyo, a young Ishiro Serizawa,
played by Ken Watanabe on screen, met with his
father Eiji, who confided in Ashiro about his
secret job, beginning his tale in Hiroshima
in 1945 after the atomic bombing. Amidst the
devastation, Eiji, then a sailor in the Japanese
Navy, searched for his wife and newborn son
Ashiro, but was only able to find Ashiro. Eiji
immediately afterward witnessed a mysterious
and massive creature flying in the area. and
suspected it had something to do with the bombing.
While Ashiro was cared for by his grandparents,
Eiji continued serving in the Japanese Navy.
One year after the bombing, Eiji's naval unit
was dispatched to aid an American vessel stranded
on a small Pacific island. Encountering the
same terrifying creature that Eiji saw a year
prior, Eiji's unit and the American crew were
all killed, save for Eiji and one American
survivor. Lee Shaw. Impressed by Eiji's rescue,
Shaw recruited him for the US government, leading
Eiji to join Monarch, a secret military unit
tasked with combating massive unidentified
terrestrial organisms, or MUTOs for short. The
MUTO creature, later dubbed a Shinobura by
Eiji, continued annual attacks around the Pacific,
each time drawing attention to another mythical
creature dubbed Gojira. which only AEG ever
glimpsed and believed existed. In 1953, Monarch
discovered a giant Shinomura cell, proving the
Mudo was actually an organized swarm of smaller
creatures and allowed AEG to theorize about
its connection to Gojira, believing both they
and other Mudos hailed from a prehistoric time
when the Earth was much more radioactive. The
Shinomura destroyed Monarch's headquarters soon
after. and Eiji, believing Gojira had protected
them from the Shinomura prior, was tasked with
fighting this Godzilla. The following year,
on Matata Island, Eiji witnessed that there
were actually two Shinomuras, prior to them
merging in order to fight Godzilla, who had
caught up to them. Using his atomic breath,
Godzilla managed to re-divide the two monsters
and kill one of them.
who witnessed the tail end of the Mudo fight.
Seeking to spare Godzilla from Monarch's plan
to destroy him and the Shinomura with a nuclear
bomb, Eiji confronted Monarch's head general
and pleaded for a peaceful resolution, though
he ultimately witnessed the bombing of both
on Bikini Island, disguised as nuclear testing.
The result was the confirmation of the Shinomura's
death and the presumption of Godzilla's. he
assured his son Ishiro that Godzilla was still
alive. Eiji died one year later, and during
his funeral, Ishiro was approached by Shaw
to join Monarch. That story was told in the
comic Godzilla Awakening, a prequel to the
2014 film Godzilla, which, along with Kong Skull
Island, kicked off Warner Brothers and Legendary
Pictures Monsterverse film series, which includes
the events from Godzilla, King of Monsters,
Godzilla vs. Kong, the TV series Monarch Legacy
of Monsters, and the newly released film Godzilla
Kong, The New Empire. Also in the canon are
prequel comic series published not by DC, but
by Legendary Comics, namely Godzilla Aftershock,
Godzilla Dominion, and Godzilla Kong The Hunted.
But recently, both Godzilla and Kong have also
appeared in the pages of DC Comics in versus
Godzilla versus Kong seven part miniseries of
which only the first six issues have been released
as of this recording. Spoiler warning if you
haven't read it yet. In this alternate timeline
tale the Legion of Doom unleashed Titano, a
skyscraper sized gorilla in Metropolis as a
distraction for them to invade the Forges of
Solitude and steal the Mother Box stored there.
When they accidentally set off an alarm the
Justice League arrived and battled the Legion,
during which time Toy Man stole the Dreamstone
and the Mother Box was triggered, sending the
Legion to Skull Island in the Monsterverse.
After Toy Man was berated by Lex Luthor over
his fascination with the Titan-designated Mudos
that he observed while in a Monarch base, Toy
Man made a wish using the Dreamstone that all
of the monsters could come back with them to
their universe. While proposing marriage to
Lois Lane atop the Daily Planet, Clark Kent
witnessed the emergence of Godzilla in Metropolis,
and the two battled while other titans, a giant
Cthulhu-like spider Cilla in Central City, the
gigantic bat Kamizots in Gotham, and the colossal
mammoth Behemoth on Themyscira also appear.
His allies Hawk Girl Shazam, Supergirl, and
Atom Smasher managed to bring the monster down
together, causing Godzilla to flee into the
ocean. Meanwhile, as heroes bring down the
Titans and the other cities, Wonder Woman brought
Green Arrow to Skull Island, which mysteriously
appeared in the ocean as he'd volunteered to
investigate. There, he found King Kong battling
hordes of other monsters to prevent them from
escaping the island. After being subdued by
Supergirl, Conk helped Green Arrow fend off
the League of Assassins, who also arrived on
the island to investigate and managed to escape
with one of the fallen Skullcrawler monsters.
Superman, seemingly dead, was placed in a stasis
pod on the Justice League satellite headquarters,
while the League reviewed footage of the Legion's
attack on the Fortress of Solitude to determine
what caused the Titans to emerge. As Lex Luthor
plotted a way to control the Titans to his
end, the League traveled into the ocean to help
Aquaman defend Atlantis from the giant sea
monster Tiamat, only for Godzilla to come to
their aid, just as Aquaman also unleashed the
Kraken. Though Godzilla and the League defeated
the Titan, the Kraken was able to help Aquaman
chain Godzilla in the Kraken's own shackles
within a massive abyss. With help from Lois
Lane, The League learned about Monarch and was
able to access their files concerning each
of the Titans as they grouped and assessed all
of the threats, including Les Luthor finding
and taking control of Mecha-Godzilla, Ras Al
Ghul bringing a Skullcrawler back to life in
a Lazarus pit, and Gorilla Grodd manipulating
King Kong by taking mental control over Supergirl.
Behemoth, Scylla, and Tiamat joined Mecha-Godzilla
and the Legion in Metropolis to battle the
Justice League. alongside a giant Batman robot
that Batman had built, a mini Batplane sidekick
bot controlled by Nightwing and Damien, and
the human Green Lantern Corps members who formed
a giant green robot of their own named Robo.
When Gorilla Grodd and his Gorilla City army
joined the fray with Supergirl and King Kong
under his control, he and Kong successfully
destroyed Robo and he even managed to kill the
Green Lantern Guy Gardener. Despite Beast Boy
trying to even the odds by transforming into
a King Kong sized gorilla, he was easily taken
out by Supergirl, who was brought under control
once the Justice League defeated Grodd, bringing
Kong to the side of the good guys, only then
for Russell Gould's Skullcrawler army to arrive.
As hope seemed to vanish, Superman finally awoke
from his stasis chamber and dove into the depths
of the ocean to free Godzilla. And we'll see
how this story concludes in issue number 7.
due out on April 16th. Powers-wise, the Monsterverse
version of Godzilla is 120 meters of brute
strength, able to destroy skyscrapers and battleships
with a wave of his tail, which is serrated
all the way up his spine. He has sharp claws
and teeth, and he's durable enough to survive
a nearly direct hit from a 15-megaton hydrogen
nuclear bomb, though it does take some time,
sometimes years, for him to fully regenerate.
depending on how heavy the damage is and how
much radiation he's able to feed on. He's essentially
immortal, having survived since prehistoric
times. Speaking of radiation feeding, Godzilla
can absorb radiation, allowing him to emit
his signature radioactive energy beam, known
as Atomic Breath. If overloaded with radiation,
Godzilla is able to temporarily emit waves in
all directions of destructive nuclear energy.
His amphibious nature allows him to breathe
both on land and underwater, and he has enhanced
senses, able to hear and smell other monsters
across continents and oceans. He's much faster
in the water than he is on land, admittedly,
and in the comics, he was susceptible to Shazam's
magic lightning bolts. But besides that, the
guy is basically indestructible, and Ultraman
is going down. Uh, Ultraman eats kaiju like
Godzilla for breakfast. I just want you to
know that. Oh, really? Yeah. The king of monsters.
I think not. How tall is Godzilla again? 120
meters. It's one of the tallest forms of Godzilla.
Oh, wow. That's that's pretty big. All right.
Well, let me go. Tell you how fucked you are
by going through Ultraman's bio. OK. All right.
This is the Marvel Comics version of Ultraman
by the way. The character has been around since
the 1950s, but he was recently rebooted in the
Marvel Comics series in 2020. There have been
three mini-series to come out including The
Rise of Ultraman, The Trials of Ultraman, and
The Mystery of the Ultra-7. There are going
to be more produced later including a crossover
between Ultraman and the Marvel Super Heroes
universe, but let me go ahead and tell you
about the character's backstory.
a sentient alien race discovered the existence
of kaiju, extra-dimensional monsters that feed
off of negative emotions that were mysteriously
invading reality from beyond the unknown. The
aliens learned that the fear the kaiju caused
would create a cyclical loop of negative emotions
that would in turn bring more kaiju into the
universe. To stop the monsters, the sentient
alien race had to transcend beyond their normal
state. evolving past negative emotions and
becoming powerful beings of peace, compassion,
and justice. They became Ultra, and used their
privilege to travel the universe and defend
other lifeforms against the Kaiju. In 1954,
mankind became aware that Kaiju were invading
Earth. An international joint effort was created
to study and protect the world from the Kaiju,
known as the United Science Patrol, or USP
for short. Twelve years later, in 1966, a pilot
for the USP named Dan Moroboshi was investigating
an approaching anomaly from space that was actually
a spaceship belonging to one of the Ultra Aliens
who was coming to Earth to assist the planet
against the Kaiju. The jet and the Ultra's
ship collided, presumably killing each pilot.
Though the wreckage from the alien ship was
too advanced for the USP to understand, They
were able to reverse engineer some of its technology
for use in Earth's battle against the Kaiju.
This included the invention of Keirei's, a
weapon's energy that was subsequently used to
fight Kaiju and shoot down any subsequent spaceships
sent by the Ultra. Throughout the decades, the
USP was able to use this technology to fend
off the Kaiju and keep their existence largely
a secret from the world at large. However,
one day in 2010's Japan, a teenager named Shin
Hayata, and his friend Kiki Fujii stumbled
upon a kaiju monster who attacked them. They
were rescued from being eaten by a USP agent
who stepped in to save them. Managing to escape
the incident and avoid having their memories
erased, Shin and Kiki became obsessed with their
knowledge of the kaiju and the USP, whom they
refer to as the Ultimate Sneaky People. They
used their knowledge over the years to find
a way to track the kaiju via their energy signature,
and eventually as young adults, they tried
to join the USP. While Kiki passed their recruitment
exam, Shin did not due to his inability to
put aside his own convictions and follow orders.
Kiki went to work studying the Keirei technology
at the USP and was eventually pulled into the
field alongside one Captain Muramatsu. The
two were rescued from a kaiju ambush by Shin,
who built his own Keirei blaster and followed
them. Though he was admonished for his unsanctioned
actions, Captain Muramasa trusted Shin enough
to bring him on his and Kiki's next assignment,
which was to investigate the crash site of
a downed Ultra spaceship. The captain ordered
Shin to fire on the Ultra emerging from the
wreckage, which he did reluctantly. As the alien
began dying, Shin ignored orders to stay back
and sympathetically approached the being, making
contact and merging with the Ultra in order
to save its life. The merging process rendered
Shin comatose for 19 hours. During that time,
Kiki researched the 1966 crash incident to try
and understand what was happening to Shin.
This led her to the remote cabin of Dr. Yamamoto,
a scientist who was discharged from the USP
for arguing against the use of K-Ray technology.
During their meeting, they were attacked by
a Kaiju monster. Shin was able to find Kiki
in time with help from Captain Muramata and
transformed into Ultraman for the first time,
defeating the creature. Transforming back,
Shin and Kiki learned from Dr. Yamamoto that
their K-rays were not disintegration beams
as they previously thought, but rather teleportation
energy that would transport the kaiju to an
unstable pocket dimension called Limbo. With
the vast number of kaiju that the USP had sent
there over the decades, Limbo was starting to
break down, threatening to release every monster
ever sent there back on Earth. One such creature,
a giant lizard named Bemular, did manage to
break through the dimensional barrier. Shin
had to transform back into Ultraman and defeated
the creature by growing to his normal, giant
size and fighting it. Now working with the
USP, Shin and Kiki convinced the director that
the best course of action to avoid all the
kaiju in Limbo spilling onto Earth simultaneously
was to slowly allow kaiju through the dimensional
barrier in a controlled manner. This let Ultraman
handle the kaiju crisis around the world methodically.
as he took on creatures big and small, the largest
ones typically hiding at the bottom of the
ocean. As the general public became aware of
the Kaiju's existence via Ultraman's battles,
one former USP robotic scientist named Kato
had a protégé that started developing Mecha
Kaiju as a means to convince people that the
USP were untrustworthy. Ultraman defeated the
Mechas, though public distrust in the organization
remained. This included Shin's father himself.
resulting in Shin revealing to his dad that
the kaiju were indeed real and that he was
Ultraman. However, Shin's father did not trust
his son with the aliens power, revealing that
he blamed him for the death of his younger brother
Jiro, who was killed accompanying Shin and
Kiki on one of their kaiju hunts as teenagers.
Ultraman sympathized with Shin stating that
he had lost a brother too named Ultra-7, the
Ultra who had crashed with the USP jet back
in 1966. In that crash, the pilot Moroboshi
and Ultra-7 were revealed to have been sent
into Limbo where they merged. After spending
decades fighting an endless battle against
the Kaiju that were being sent there by the
USP, Ultra-7 eventually became corrupted by
the violence. When Ultra-7 arrived back on Earth
through the weakened dimensional barrier, he
went into a frenzy, attacking both Kaiju and
Ultraman, who tried to reason with him and
eventually subdued him. As it turned out, Ultra
7 first came to Earth in the 1960s as he had
gained evidence that the reason Kaiju were appearing
on the planet was due to an external influence,
an evil presence that had embedded itself within
the USP. This led to Shin, Kiki, Ultraman,
Ultra 7, and Jack who was a new combined mecha
version of Ultraman created by the roboticist
Kato and piloted by his teenage children. They
all formed a team called the Ultra Guard. to
combat the USP's corruption. And that's Ultraman's
backstory in Marvel. Powers-wise, Ultraman
possesses enhanced physical abilities due to
his transcendent alien nature. This includes
increased strength in excess of 100 tons, flight
speed up to Mach 5, increased durability, and
increased agility. He can grow in size to a
height of 40 meters or 131 feet tall. He also
has a variety of energy weapons, including this
Spacium Beam, which he can fire when forming
his arms into the shape of a plus sign, and
the Ultra Slash, which is an energy buzzsaw
that he can throw out by moving his right arm
in a tomahawk motion. He is a master in his
judo-esque ultra fighting style, and can see
across the electromagnetic spectrum. Lastly,
Ultraman is highly intelligent and logical,
able to adapt and process battle strategy on
the fly, with help from the also intelligent
Shin Hayata in his mind. His one weakness is
that Shin can only remain in the Ultraman form
for three minutes before he has to revert back
to Shin due to the weakened state of the Ultra
during their merging process. Wow, that's sad.
That's pretty lame, yeah. But three minutes
is all this guy needs. So you're telling me
this guy goes up against shrimpy 40 meter tall
Kaiju's? I mean, Ultraman can grow taller than
that too. Oh yeah? Yeah. Are you sure? Well...
He's never done that in the Marvel Comics version,
so I can't say that with 100% certainty, but
at the very least, he's going to be a third
the height of Godzilla. This is going to be
fun.
fantasies collide and heroes clash, one podcast
network rises above the rest. Prepare yourself
for the ultimate showdowns in comic books, video
games, movies, and anime. The DynaMic Podcast
Network presents Console Combat, where video
game legends brawl every Monday. Comic Book
Titans smash every Tuesday. Max Destruction,
where TV and action heroes battle every Wednesday.
And Sendro World, where anime champions clash
every Thursday. Join us as we speculate on
the matches and armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge victorious.
Visit dynamicpodcast.com, where we settle the
debate and settle the score.
But now that we've got the histories and abilities
out of the way, let's speculate on how one
of the 1000 simulated matches will go. The winner
is determined by simulations, not the speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how this fight could
play out. AJ9K, what are the rules of our speculation?
For the speculation, the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a non-descript
environment that will have no bearing on the
match itself, as no environmental statistics
are considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. Alright
then let's get into it. Godzilla and Ultraman
meet! Woah! What's happening here? Wow! Alright,
so like in a fiery explosion, the characters
just teleported into our non-environment setting.
where I guess the fight continues from yesterday's
episode of the console combat podcast. So now
that they're here, who's going to go first?
Well, I got to say, you know, the DC Comics
version of Godzilla is just so much taller than
Ultraman. He's just going to straight up stomp
Ultraman into the ground, just stepping on him.
It's not going to be that easy, which shows
how smart Godzilla is. Like Marvel's Ultraman
might only be a third of the size of Godzilla,
but he's still incredibly strong, so strong.
that he's gonna catch Godzilla's foot as it
tries to stomp on him, then he's gonna do this
incredible judo slam, throwing the kaiju down
onto the ground and creates this massive Godzilla-shaped
crater. Okay, well you just paced Godzilla
off now. You can see it in his emotive monster-verse
face. So while he's on the ground, Godzilla's
gonna sweep his long tail and smack it right
into Ultraman, sending him flying toward the
horizon. Okay, but like... Ultraman can fly,
so yeah, he gets smacked to the horizon, but
he just comes racing back into the battle at
Mach 5 and just rockets his fist right into
Godzilla's jaw at five times the speed of sound.
And that's just gonna shatter all of Godzilla's
teeth. So now we just have Toothless Godzilla,
just gums. Uh, no, I'm gonna say Ultraman rocketed
his fist right into Godzilla's bite. So Ultraman's
trapped in Godzilla's jaws. And while Ultraman
is locked there, That's when Godzilla's back
dorsal plates began to glow blue, and he's
just gonna fry Ultraman with his atomic breath
point blank. No, I mean, that takes a while,
right? So Godzilla never gets a chance. Because,
like, Ultraman, yeah, his arm is trapped in
Godzilla's teeth, but with his other arm, he's
gonna send out an Ultra Slash, and that energy
buzzsaw thing is just gonna rip right into Godzilla's
neck, just severing his ability to use his
atomic breath. about that it's definitely gonna
hurt Godzilla you know and cause him to drop
Ultraman and by drop I mean drop kick like Spartan
style and that's when Godzilla is gonna let
out this deafening roar that's just gonna stun
Ultraman long enough to get body slammed by
Godzilla like Godzilla is just gonna drop right
on top of him and stay on top of him for you
know whatever time remains in
Yeah, Shin's time limit is probably coming up
in his Ultraman form. So yeah, he has to do
something drastic. So he summons all of his
might to lift Godzilla's fat ass off of him,
and then he's gonna handspring back onto his
feet, and then he's gonna do his space-ium
beam technique, you know, forming his forearms
into a plus sign, which unleashes this devastating
energy blast that is just gonna disintegrate
Godzilla. Okay, but like in the time it takes
Ultraman... to do this jutsu dance move with
his arms, you know, that's the same amount
of time it takes Godzilla to counter with a
beam of his atomic breath, causing the two
energies to collide and form a massive explosion.
Whoa, whoa, what's happening? They're being
sucked into another vortex. And they're gone.
AJ 9K, status report, please. Reading anomaly
energy signature. The combatants are traversing
via interdimensional portal to the Max Destruction
podcast. Estimated time of arrival tomorrow.
Okay, well, I guess we'll figure out what happens
with these two characters tomorrow on the Max
Destruction podcast Just before the characters
left though. I was able to glance at their stats
and the comic versions are pretty impressive
specimens Yeah, they definitely both have a
lot going for each other They're both incredibly
destructive characters able to level whole cities
in their battles, but You know, Godzilla is
just so insanely strong and durable. Although
you can't discount Ultraman's agility and his
fighting skill and his intellect. You know,
Godzilla is a big dumb comparatively. Yeah,
but Godzilla did get the edge when it came to
perception because he's able to sense monsters
from an entire continent away. Who needs perception
when you have speed? You know, Ultraman's faster
than Godzilla. Who needs speed? We've got fucking
atomic breath. It'll be interesting to see
who wins when we finally get the results of
this match on Thursday on the Senjoworld podcast.
So if you guys want to know who wins, be sure
to continue on with the DynaMic Podcast Network.
Tomorrow you get to hear hosts Ken and Scotty
talk about movie versions of the two characters
fighting and on Thursday, host Zach is going
to be breaking down really powerful anime versions
of the characters. You do not want to miss it.
And again, don't miss out on yesterday's episode
on console combat where they talked about the
video game versions of Godzilla and Ultraman.
But that does it for this duel guys, let us
know what you thought about our speculation
by writing to us at dyna or by visiting us on
Instagram, which you can find a link to on
our show notes, or by visiting our website at
dynamicduel.com. And on our site you can also
find a link to our Patreon page, where you can
join our dynamic2o tier and chat with us and
fellow listeners. our Fantastic Four tier, which
gets you bonus content each month, our X-Force
tier that makes you an executive producer of
this podcast, or our newest tier that lets
you join our DynaMic Podcast Network. Hey guys,
please don't forget to rate the show on Apple
Podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser, or on our website.
But that does it for this episode. We want
to give a big thanks to our executive producers,
Ken Johnson, John Swarovski, Zachary Hepburn,
Dustin Balcom, Maggie Mathengian, Brandon Essergard,
Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Austin Wazilovsky, AJ
Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Adam Spies, Andrew
Schunk, and Dean Molesky for helping make this
podcast possible. And we'll talk to you guys
next week. Up up and away, true believers.
I'm disrespectful to dirt. Can you see that
I'm serious? Get out of my way all of you.
This is no place for loafers. Join me or die.
Can you do any less? For lucky best wash, use
Mr. Sparkle.