This is a Dynamike Network podcast.
Hi and welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast,
a weekly show where we review superhero films
and debate the superiority between Marvel and
DC by comparing their characters in stat-based
battle simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe. And I'm
his twin brother Johnny DC. And in this episode
we are going to review season one of My Adventures
with Superman. which is an animated television
series that debuted on Cartoon Network and Max.
It was 10 episodes long and it was pretty good.
Can't wait to talk about it later on this episode.
Before that, we're going to break down the
latest comic book movie news to come out this
past week, of which we got news about some
release date changes for Marvel shows on Disney+.
As always, we list our segment times in our
episode description, so feel free to check out
the show notes if you want to skip ahead to
a particular topic. As our listeners may know,
our dual simulator is so advanced that it's
gained sentience, and it's named itself the
artificial life form for running extensive
duels, just a rather very intelligent Simulator
9000 or Alfred Jarvis 9000. Here's a quick
message for our listeners, so listen up. Why
hello there. Do you love listening and chatting
about Marvel and DC? Then become a part of the
dynamic dual community on Patreon, where you
can choose from three tiers. The dynamic two-o
tier lets you listen to this podcast without
ads and gives you access to its discord chat
group, where you can chat with Johnny DC and
Marvelous Joe. The Fantastic Four tier gives
you that and more with two bonus episodes each
month, including bloopers and top ten shows
where Johnny and Joe count down your favourite
Marvel and DC subjects. The X-Force tier makes
you an executive producer of Dynamic Duel,
where every month you help the hosts choose
what to review and who to fight against each
other. And finally, the Dynamite Podcast Network
tier allows aspiring podcasters to create their
own battle-focused show using this Monte Carlo
simulator.
Thanks AJ9K, and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast. Be sure to tune into the Max Destruction
podcast, which is part of the Dynamike Podcast
Network, to witness the bare-knuckle across
film and television. This week on Wednesday
September 6th, you can learn who would win
in a battle between B.A. Baracus from the A-Team
against Action Jackson. Also, anime fans tune
into Senjou World, another Dynamite Network
show featuring your favorite anime characters
that drops episodes on Thursday. If you tune
in this week, you'll find out who'd win in
a fight between Tire Harabelle from Bleach and
Hoshigaki Kasami from Naruto. I am horrible
at pronouncing these names. Damn it, Zach. But
no, I'm actually blown away by your character
selection. I don't know who these characters
are half the time, but it's always fascinating
to learn about these anime characters in the
show. Yeah, totally. Makes me want to watch
all of the shows if only I had time. Visit dynamicpodcast.com
or click on the link in our show notes to listen
to all the shows in our network. But with that
out of the way, quick to the no prize. A no
prize is an award Marvel used to give out to
fans. Our version, the Dynamic Duel No Prize,
is a digital award we post on Instagram and
in our email newsletter for the person that
we feel gave the best answer to our question
of the week. Last week we asked you guys to
pitch us your perfect Marvel vs. DC video game
and to tell us what it would be like. We only
got two eligible answers. To be fair, we are
recording this episode early due to Labor Day
weekend. Right, right. But still, that's not
a whole lot of participation. For what I thought
was a pretty interesting question, like just
describe the most awesome Marvel versus DC
video game you can think of. Yeah, like Rampage,
but with Lestaro or Fing Feng Fum. That's just
off the top of my head, guys. Fucking bejeweled
blitz, but it's Marvel versus DC. I don't know
how you would do that, but you can imagine it'd
be pretty awesome. It would be Infinity Stones
and Green Lantern Rings. Boom, off the top of
my head, it just happens. It's that easy, guys,
to call in. We did get pretty solid answers
for the two answers we did get, so let's go
ahead and run down our honorable mention and
the no prize winner. Our first honorable mention
goes to Colby Hentges. Who said? Okay, I've
never actually heard of Skullgirls, but I looked
it up and it looks pretty interesting. Basically,
the premise of the game is you're a bunch of
goth schoolgirls that are fighting against each
other that have like magic powers. The gameplay
style is very much in the vein of Marvel vs.
Capcom, but like way more insane. And you can
choose any combination of up to three fighters
per matchup, kind of like how in Marvel vs.
Capcom, you select two fighters and they fight
back to back or you can switch off in between
them during the course of the fight. It looks
like a pretty damn cool game. It would be incredible
to have a Marvel vs. DC video game like this.
Yeah, with the appeal really being that you
don't have to select just one character to fight
with. but up to three or maybe more for this
game. Like give me the entire seven roster member
Justice League to fight with. That'd be dope.
I would do it. I'd play the shit out of the
game. I do love how you're comparing it to
Marvel versus Capcom though, instead of just
Street Fighter. Just say Street Fighter. Well,
I always thought of Marvel versus Capcom as
being a much more over the top, crazy video
game than Street Fighter. Although, you know,
Street Fighter has gotten pretty over the top
as well over the years. But yeah, they're both
great games. Great answer Colby! We do have
to give a shout out to Christopher Menotti who
recorded an answer, but he described a Arkham-style
nightcrawler video game with no DC element to
it. So it didn't qualify unfortunately, but
thank you for taking the time to record your
answer. The winner of this week's No Prize
though is Matt Lamb. Who said? Yeah considering
Ed Boon made comments regarding a Marvel vs
DC video game last week and... Ed Boon is the
head of NetherRealm Studios, who makes the
Mortal Kombat and Injustice video games. It
seems most likely that if this game were going
to be made, it would be in that same Mortal
Kombat style. And they're great games. Yeah,
they're fantastic. I love NetherRealm storytelling.
You know, they created Injustice, which is
just fantastic. They also have incredible character
designs. They've gotten much better at that
than they have in the past, I feel. So I would
love to see them render all of the Marvel and
DC characters that they would have on their
rosters. It would be insanely cool. And brutal
AF. It's freaking Netherrealm. Right, right.
If I'm being honest, I actually do like the
Mortal Kombat renders more than Capcom's, which
tend to be a little bit cartoony, you know,
like in the Street Fighter vein. Right. Mortal
Kombat approaches the characters almost like
if they were live action movie costumes, you
know? Right. And I think that'd be really cool
to see in a video game for Marvel and DC. I
think they'd have to brighten up their palette
a bit because a lot of their games feel like
very dark. Mm hmm. But yeah, it could totally
work. I think it would be fantastic. Now, I
know Matt Lamb said that the characters wouldn't
have fatalities, but special finishers. But
screw that. What would Batman's fatality be?
He would just run your ass over with the Batmobile.
That's pretty good. What about Spider-Man?
Spider-Man's Mortal Kombat fatality, he would
totally like Mark of Kane. your shit up. Like
he'd stick his hand onto your face and then
just rip your face right off. Oh damn. And
then he'd web up your entire body and then web
swing you and slam you into the ground until
you're just like bag of mush. I will accept
that. Great answer, Matlam. Congrats for winning
this week's no prize. If you, the listener,
want a shot at winning your own no prize, stay
tuned to later on in this episode where we'll
be asking another question of the week. And
now that that's done, on to the news.
Alright this past week we heard from the Hollywood
Reporter that Marvel is shuffling their TV
calendar setting new dates for The Agatha Show,
Echo, X-Men 97, and What If. Initially we were
supposed to get all of these shows this year
in 2023, considering it's already September
it seemed highly unlikely that this was all
going to happen this year, especially due to
the ongoing writers and actor strikes. Disney
Plus is still going to release Loki Season
2 this year starting on October 6th. But the
first show to get pushed back was What If,
which is now going to debut around Christmas
time of this year, so the very end of the year.
Echo was originally supposed to drop in November,
all the episodes were going to drop at the
same time, but that got pushed to January of
2024. The animated series X-Men 97, which is
going to be a continuation of the classic 1990
series from Fox, that's going to come out sometime
early 2024, around springtime. And then finally...
Agatha Coven of Chaos has been renamed to Agatha
Darkhold Diaries, and it's going to drop in
the fall season of 2024. It's crazy because
the Agatha show was originally named House of
Harkness, then it got renamed to Coven of Chaos,
and now it's called Darkhold Diaries. It's like
pick a name, holy shit. Seriously. But I do
think that like right around Halloween time
is a perfect time to drop an Agatha television
series. Do you like the name Darkhold Diaries?
I mean, sure, it works just like the rest of
them work. I think they all were fine. I liked
Covenant of Chaos, I'm not gonna lie. Yeah,
I liked that one too. But considering that we
now have a show dropping early 2024 in Echo,
spring 2024 in X-Men 97 and autumn 2024. in
Agatha, Darkhold Diaries, it makes me think
that other shows that have been filmed or partially
filmed such as Ironheart, Daredevil Born Again,
and Wonder Man are all getting pushed into 2025.
Which is possibly a good thing. I know there's
a lot of concern going around that Marvel is
producing too much content that people aren't
able to keep up with and therefore are kind
of losing interest in. And so I think the aim
is to focus on the quality and make sure that
release dates are staggered to hold audience
interest. Yeah, I think it's a smart move. Bob
Iger pretty much admitted that there was too
much Marvel content on Disney+. This gives them
some breathing room to kind of reevaluate what
they want to do with each series and make sure
it's a little bit more cohesive, I think, going
forward, hopefully. But speaking of all these
shows, in particular X-Men 97, that brings
us to our question of the week.
90s kids, what was your favorite Marvel or DC
cartoon from the 90s and why? Basically, if
you're listening to this and you were born after
the 90s, you can still answer but also you're
too young. You're just too young. You're too
young. Be older, because we're looking for
90s cartoons. It was the best era for Marvel
and DC cartoons, in my humble opinion. Yeah,
I think it was definitely like the Renaissance
after shows like Super Friends and stuff like
that, you know? Yeah. Record your answer at
dynamicduel.com by clicking on the red microphone
button in the bottom right hand corner of the
screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long, and don't forget to leave your name in
case we include you on the podcast. We'll pick
our favorite answer and award that person a
Dynamic Duel No Prize that we'll post to Instagram
and our email newsletter. Be sure to answer
before September 9th.
But I think that does it for all the news for
this episode, so let's go ahead and move into
our main event, where we review the DC animated
series on Cartoon Network and Max, My Adventures
with Superman, Season 1.
Adventures with Superman is a 10-episode animated
series made for Cartoon Network's Adult Swim
programming block and the Mac streaming platform
by the series' showrunners Jake Wyatt, Brandon
Kloffer, and Josie Campbell. The series explores
Clark Kent's early career as both a journalist
for the Daily Planet and as the superhero Superman,
as well as the burgeoning relationship with
his colleague Lois Lane. It was a fantastic
series. that modernizes Superman in a way that
has never been done before. I definitely recommend
watching it. It's available on Max once again.
Please watch it before listening any further
to this spoiler review. Yeah, even as a Marvel
fan, I highly recommend this series. It actually
turned out better than expected when the executive
producers requested that we review the show.
I was kind of a whiny bitch about it. I didn't
want to do it. I feel like we've seen this story
done well before in the Smallville television
series and even in animated form recently with
the Man of Tomorrow movie. But this show ended
up blowing all my expectations away and when
I first started watching it I was like, what's
this cartoony shit? By the time I was done,
I considered it one of the best interpretations
of Superman's origin story that has existed.
Way better than Man of Tomorrow, honestly.
Oh, absolutely. Yeah, no question. Like you,
when this cartoon was first announced... I
can't say I was looking forward to it, and I
was also surprised when it was decided that
we were going to review it, because we don't
usually review Cartoon Network shows. You know,
considering the fact that the episodes were
dropping on Macs shortly after their Cartoon
Network debut, and because the episode count
was relatively short, we figured we'd review
it, and I'm really glad we did, because like
you mentioned, the show was way better than
I thought it would be, and it's definitely a
far cry from the character that we've seen
on the big screen for the past decade, I would
say. When My Adventures with Superman was first
announced in early 2021, based off the title,
I was under the impression that it was a series
that focused on Lois Lane specifically, and
you know, like her perspective regarding Superman
and life in Metropolis. Right away, I assumed
I wasn't the target demographic, and you know,
I'd probably watch it with my daughters, but
probably wouldn't enjoy it. I was totally wrong.
I enjoyed the shit out of the show, because
I forgot how much I could relate. to the romantic
side of the Superman story, which is an element
that has been there since the very beginning
of the character's introduction since 1938.
Jerry Siegel, one of the creators of Superman,
said that one of the inspirations for Clark
Kent as an alter ego was because he had crushes
on girls who didn't even know he existed, and
he thought to himself, what if, secretly, he
was really great? What if he was super? The
love triangle of sorts that stemmed from Clark
Kent loving Lois Lane, but Lois Lane loving
Superman, was this tragic component that allowed
readers to connect with these otherwise perfect
characters. And it's a component that was noticeably
lacking in Zack Snyder's take on the character,
or from any other medium other than maybe Smallville
for decades. I would argue that this show nails
the romantic aspect between Superman and Lois
than any film or television series in history
because of the novel approach they take with
the Clark Kent alter ego. His awkwardness in
this show isn't necessarily an act like it
was for the Christopher Reeve version of the
character. It's often been debated amongst
comic readers whether Clark Kent should be an
act, and in this show we see that Clark Kent
and Superman are essentially the same person.
It's just that Clark Kent is clumsy, due to
having to control and hide his powers at all
times, which is difficult to do when his attention
is on a pretty girl like Lois. I'm not usually
one for romantic media, I'll admit that. I
think my tastes as a hyper-masculine dude is
pretty much in the vein of, you know, I like
to see the action aspect of these superheroes.
The romantic side never really interested me.
But You know, I think that Superman actually
has one of the most interesting romantic angles
out of all superheroes in general. Yeah, I mean,
his romantic relationships, and I guess not
just that, his relationships in general are
the source of his vulnerability, right? And
plus, like, Superman's really only loved one
girl for the most part. I think he's had some
a few other romantic interests in his history,
but for the most part, Lois is Superman's girl
ever since the 1940s, you know. Whereas I think
most other male superheroes have quite a number
of romantic interests, like another prime example
is Spider-Man, but he's had Gwen Stacy, Mary
Jane, Felicia Hardy, you know? Spider-Man's
a ho! It's much more wholesome, I think, with
the Superman-Lowes relationship. Absolutely,
yeah. Now, there was a lot of length, but that
was in high school. You know, since becoming
an adult, Superman is primarily a wood woman
man. Now, the show is so well written. And the
chemistry between the characters of Superman
and Lois is so well realized that even though
Lois discovers Clark Kent as Superman less
than halfway through the series, it doesn't
ruin the dramatic flow and tension between
the characters. And it even helps address a
criticism many have levied at the writers of
Lois Lane for decades in that if she's such
an intelligent investigative journalist, why
didn't she deduce that Clark Kent was Superman
early on? Here, she does. and in a more believable
and natural way than, say, Amy Adams' version
of the character. The way the showrunners approached
the relationship between Clark and Lois wasn't
the only novel aspect of the show, however,
the most blatant being the anime animation style.
We saw shades of the anime style in the DC
animated movie universe that began with the
Justice League the Flashpoint Paradox animated
film, but My Adventures with Superman is, for
the most part, a shounen anime in terms of
both animation and story style. Shounen animes
are geared toward teenage boys and include
tropes such as growing in power like leveling
up, having a romantic rival, themes of teamwork,
and the power of friendship, many of which are
found in this show. I love that for almost
every villain that Superman went up against,
Lois and Jimmy were on the sidelines figuring
out how to help Superman, whether it was pushing
buttons on a crate or- you know, finding the
off switch for a high tech panic room. Yeah,
the anime art style was pretty well done here.
I never knew how well suited the character of
Superman was to the anime style until I saw
it, and it works really damn well. Yeah, there's
a lot of visual anime tropes on the show as
well. You know, such as Superman sparking with
electricity like Goku or the Majoko style transformation
into a super suit. The teaser for the next episode
at the very end of the one you're watching.
And you know, overall the fast action and exaggerated
facial expressions. I don't watch a lot of
anime, but I do know that some of my favorites,
like Neon Genesis Evangelion, My Hero Academia
and Sword Art Online, would be considered shounen.
And recognizing some of those anime tropes,
both story and visual, was part of the fun of
watching the show. I never would have thought
like you that Superman would have worked in
that style. But he totally did. For sure. And
going back to the romantic angle, I think for
some reason, the anime art style does a really
good job of expressing that sort of like shy,
flirtatious behavior between characters. Yeah.
You know, with like the blush cheeks and everything
like that, it just worked really well in selling
their romantic back and forth in an endearing
way. Yeah, totally. Japanese shounen don't
really shy away from romance in the same way
that I think Western cartoons geared towards
young men do. It was like, oh, they love each
other. I was like, he likes her, oh no. No,
my daughter loved this series as well. She's
12 years old. She's in middle school. She watched
the new episodes before I did. She was like
really into it. Girls love anime, I found.
Yeah. And I think a large part of it has to
do with, yeah, they don't shy away from things
like romance. Now, as a Superman fan, one of
the things I loved most about this show was
the approach it took with Superman's origin
and how it resulted week to week. and a who's
who of supervillains from DC Comics. In a similar
way to how Kryptonite was responsible for creating
many of Superman's villains in the Smallville
television series, in this show, many of them
are powered by repurposed Kryptonian technology.
Superman doesn't realize this until the very
end of the season, so he doesn't have that same
guilt that Clark did in Smallville, but I'm
sure that's coming next season. Some people
got tired of the Kryptonite villain of the
week, Shtick, from Smallville. But since my
adventures with Superman was only 10 episodes,
I didn't feel that aspect overstayed its welcome.
And it helped story-wise in coming up with
a simple solution for why all of these superpowered
beings emerged for Superman to fight. We got
to see Livewire, Silver Banshee, Mist, Rough
House, Dr. Ivo, Parasite, Heatwave, Deathstroke,
Mixi Spidlic, Amanda Waller, Lex Luthor, Omac
Robots, General Lane and even Matsumura Mala
and the Brain. At the very end, we even get
teases of Brainiac and Zod. None of these characters
get much character development and it shouldn't
work because of that, but it somehow does because
of the way all of the villains get their powers
and because the show is so focused on Superman
and his friends. Yeah, I think the tech aspect
goes a long way in making the show feel modern.
as well. A lot of the bad guys almost seem like
Iron Man or something like that, you know?
But it doesn't feel untrue to the characters
themselves. Like Livewire, I think she was
actually a villain introduced in the Superman
animated series from the 90s. But her origin
here I think is actually better than the one
they introduced in that old cartoon. And you're
right, it was fun going like, oh, that's Livewire.
Oh, that's Deathstroke. It's funny how like,
I was so ready to write off the show in the
beginning. Because I thought that was lame.
I was like, what the fuck are they doing? Like
reinventing all these characters. And I was
like, this is just some else world's bullshit.
But by the end I was like, man, this would
be a great angle for a film adaptation, honestly.
Oh man, don't even get me started. Like I liked
this show so much that it actually got me a
little depressed by how good it was. Because
like most DC animations, I don't understand
why Warner Brothers couldn't adapt this approach
for live action, you know? Like each of these
episodes were only 22 minutes long. This could
have easily been a pair of films, maybe even
a trilogy. And that would have been amazing.
Like whatever James Gunn is doing with the Superman
legacy film, the bar has been set for how well
you could introduce Superman already right now.
It does have its work cut out for it in telling
Superman's early years better than this show
did. Right. Exactly. And it's been said that,
you know, it's not focusing on Superman's early
years as Superman. but it is supposed to focus
on his early years in Metropolis with Lois Lane
and stuff like that. So, I don't know. Maybe
he could go like the Superman birthright route
in that regard, but we'll see, I guess. For
my money, this was a better modern adaptation
of the character of Superman than the Man of
Steel movie, which I thought was an interesting,
you know, alien sci-fi approach to the character.
You know, I love Man of Steel. It's one of my
favorite DC movies, and I would agree with
you. That's why I'm depressed. But moving on
to the character breakdown, there's really
only three main characters to talk about. Of
course, starting with Superman, aka Clark Kent,
he was voiced by Jack Quaid, who's the son of
Meg Ryan and Dennis Quaid, and is probably
best well known for playing Huey and the boys.
It's a lighter, more comedic take on Superman,
but I thought Jack nailed this version of the
character. I've never heard or seen- Superman
to be this expressive on screen. Oh, he was
incredible. I didn't even know that was him,
and now I'm kind of blown away by that. Yeah,
yeah, I didn't realize it was him either. He's
pretty talented. Now, the show asks numerous
times, who is Superman? Superman asks himself
that question. As we see each of Superman's
powers activate during the course of the show,
he learns that he's a hero who simply does what
he can to help others. A good example of this
is when he steps in front of Lois. to shield
her from a barrage of lasers without thinking,
without even knowing that he was invulnerable
to them. Superman being a hero isn't the most
shocking answer to the question of who he is.
The bigger shock comes from the angle they
took in showing us that not only are some supermen
across the multiverse seemingly evil, but they
also make us believe for a time that
Yeah, there's an aspect to the show that was
kind of reminiscent of the invincible comic
book series and animated show on Amazon, where
they portrayed the Kryptonians almost like
Viltrumites, where like they're these super
powerful beings. And I think Jor-El in this
show can almost be seen as an analog to invincible's
father Omniman. I thought that was really fascinating,
even though we know that Jor-El is ultimately
going to be a good guy. But then you have Zod
at the end. Right. Yeah, so cool. I can't wait
for season two. And I think that's a testament
to just how good this show is. I spoke earlier
about how like this show does a better job
of bringing the character into modern times
while making him feel like Superman. Yes, like
a young classic version of Superman in the modern
day. And they never thought that they would
be able to do that as successfully as they did
here. I think that's really why I was so happy
with the show by the end of it, because it proved
that it could be done. Right. Like Henry Cavill's
Superman was a little bit dark for some people's
tastes. He was a little bit brooding. You cannot
say that about this animated version of Superman.
Should have been live action. Damn it. Moving
on to Lois Lane, she was voiced by Alice Lee,
a singer and actress from Zoe's Extraordinary
Playlist and never saw the show. Alice is of
Korean descent and her version of Lois Lane
is also of Korean descent. And I believe this
is the first time we've ever seen the character
depicted that way. And I don't mind it. You
know, they also race-bent Jimmy Olsen to match
his voice actor. We'll talk about that character
in a bit. But I think matching the ethnicity
of the voice actor best suited for the role
is admirable. And I have to say, I loved the
voice work for Lois Lane and Jimmy Olsen. Oh
yeah, they did a perfect job. Now Lois's arc
really revolves around her relationship with
her father. She disdains him for keeping secrets
from her growing up about his classified work
and her mother's cancer. and she struggles
to find success in part due to feelings of neglect
from him ignoring her growing up. I think it
was brilliant that they made her father, General
Lane, the primary villain. I thought it was
going to be like Lex Luthor or maybe Brainiac,
but having it be General Lane added a whole
other layer of conflict to the relationship
between Superman and Lois. I mean, who didn't
see that coming, but also, yeah, brilliant idea.
I mean, I didn't initially until we actually
saw him. I was like, oh shit. Nice. I did kind
of roll my eyes when we learned that there
was a multiversal league of Lois Lanes because
we've seen that done so many times by this
point, like Council of Ricks, Council of Reed
Richards, you know. But after a while, I realized
it was a clever way to not only add further
tension to Superman and Lois's relationship
and introduce Kryptonite, but also to qualm
any haters who may have an issue with this
adaptation of the world of Superman or even
like the race bending by saying that this is
its own thing. It's its own world. Your classic
Superman world still exists, but this is our
interpretation and our stamp. There's a little
bit of the manic pixie dream girl characterization
here, especially in the early episodes for Lois
Lane. But Lois Lane is kind of like the OG
manic pixie dream girl. She's always been this
like borderline insane woman who will always
be impulsive and go out and do the dangerous
thing. Right. And that's also an anime trope.
you know, the wild impulsive anime girl. And
I really liked how they kind of blended that
characterization into this version of Lois Lane.
For sure. Yeah, she was really well done. As
was Jimmy Olsen. He was voiced by Ishmael Saheed.
And I have to say, I haven't enjoyed Jimmy
Olsen this much in a long while. It's always
been hard to sincerely say that Jimmy Olsen
is Superman's best pal in the comics, because
he's always been like this dimwitted and somewhat
annoying peon of sorts. But here they made Clark
and Jimmy bros, like equals, who were friends
even before they arrived at the Daily Planet.
And on top of that, they made Jimmy a conspiracy
theorist vlogger, which was a brilliant way
to add tension to him and Clark. Yeah, at first
I thought it was just like this random character
trait that was done for... Comedic Relief and
I was prepared to be really annoyed by Jimmy
Olsen actually. And then I kind of saw how
all the pieces fell together as Clark always
found himself nervous around Jimmy because
Clark is an alien, you know? Right. So it was
pretty interesting. Again, you know, there's
an anime trope of like the Comedic Relief character
that this version of Jimmy Olsen fell squarely
into. But the way that the show was able to
fill those molds while still staying true to
the Superman mythos was just brilliant. Yeah.
I mean, tropes and cliches. exist for a reason,
and when they're well done, they're really well
done. Now I don't know how I feel about the
reveal that Jimmy recognized that Clark was
an alien early on as roommates, but I guess
it makes sense considering they were living
together, and it also shows how true of a friend
Jimmy was in that as a vlogger about aliens,
he wouldn't expose Clark as one. Like, if that
isn't the sign of a true friend, I don't know
what is. My impression is that It was his realization
that Clark was like a super strong alien guy
that manifested his whole conspiratorial nature
to begin with. Oh interesting, maybe. He's like,
holy crap this guy's like superhuman, the fantastical
must exist and I must learn all about it. I
love that, that's great. Let's move on to the
story highlights.
In episode 1, titled Adventures of a Normal
Man, part 1, in Smallville, Kansas, a young
Clark Kent awakens the power of flight and strength
to save a woman and her baby from a car accident.
Years later, in Metropolis, Clark and his roommate
Jimmy Olsen, a photography student and alien
conspiracy theorist, start their first day as
interns for the Daily Planet. Assigned to senior
intern Lois Lane, she deceives them into helping
her investigate a military-grade technology
theft. With a lead from Flip Johnson's News
Kid Legion, the trio finds the thieves loading
military robots at the docks. The thieves' leader,
Leslie Willis, unleashes a robot to attack
them. Clark gets out of view and returns in
disguise to destroy it. As Willis activates
the remaining robots to battle Clark, Lois successfully
deactivates them while he awakens his super
speed to destroy the final robot. Despite their
efforts, Editor-in-Chief Perry White refuses
to publish the story based on Jimmy's blurry
photos without real proof of the new metahuman
that Lois dubbed Superman. Once the trio become
friends, Lois invites the boys to help her
get an exclusive interview with Superman. Now,
I'll admit this first episode I did not love
when it came to the wacky, you know, Jimmy Olsen
hijinks, the manic characterization of Lois,
and like the kids' newspaper brigade or whatever.
I was like, God. I didn't... why are we reviewing
this? Like, I would have rather have reviewed
the live-action Superman and Lois television
series is what I thought to myself. Or something
like that, you know? Because I've heard that's
good. But to the show's credit, as the show
progresses, it gets more serious along the
way. Which I think resulted in nice growth for
the characters. Yeah, true. Like you, I wasn't
thrilled by this first episode. Like, I didn't
think it was the greatest adaptation ever for
Superman. I didn't really feel that way until
maybe episode three or four. But episode 2
was pretty good. That was titled Adventures
of a Normal Man, part 2. While Lois doggedly
follows up on the robot theft for a lead to
Superman, Clark returns to Smallville to investigate
his past and understand his new powers. Digging
up the space pod that delivered him to Earth,
Clark activates an alien hologram and sees visions
of an alien planet amid a space war being destroyed.
After Clark gains new alien clothing from this,
His mother, Martha, adds a belt and shorts
to complete the look. Meanwhile, Willis is hunted
by the organization she stole the robot technology
from, Task Force X, and arranges a meeting with
leading agent Slade Wilson, aka Deathstroke.
When Willis threatens to detonate explosives
across the city sewers if they continue hunting
her, Lois and Jimmy's surprise interruption
turns the meeting into a scramble for the Willis
reveals her electrical super suit to fight Deathstroke
until Superman arrives to subdue her. Deathstroke
damages her suit's power crystal, leading Superman
to destroy it after it gives him another vision
of the space war. Though Jimmy's clear photos
convince Perry to publish the story, he gives
the byline to uninvolved staff reporters. Later,
Deathstroke tortures Willis, now Livewire,
at a black site for information about Superman.
I've seen a lot of flack online for the transformation
scene in this episode, and I really feel like
early on when the show's first episodes were
coming out, there was a lot of antagonism towards
it. But I am happy to see more and more people
admit that they liked the series online. Well,
I mean, it just made sense for the context
of the scene, right? Clark activating the ship
for the first time and going down into it and
seeing partial visions of the Kryptonian story.
and getting a suit from that, I think, worked
really well. And yeah, it's kind of a funny
anime cliche for the characters to suit up
in this overtly grandiose fashion. But considering
it only happened once in the season and it
had that context to go with it, I thought it
was spot on. Yeah, I don't even think it was
that over the top either. It literally only
lasted five seconds, maybe not even that long.
Yeah, I do love the fact that Martha helped
contribute to the suit in some way, because
in the comics she did. You know, she helped
him make it and design it. Yeah. So that was
cool. It really only took me up until this episode
to start getting into the show. Once you kind
of saw what they did with LiveWire, something
kind of like clicked for me and I understood
what they were going with in terms of bringing
in the larger DC universe. Right, yeah. We've
begun to episode three titled, My Interview
with Superman. While Lois attempts to interview
Superman, Clark struggles to figure out how
to help her while protecting his secret identity.
However, the interns must also contend with
the Daily Planet's established Scoop Troop
reporters, who perry-credited for their Superman
story. Specifically, Steve Lombard, Kent Grant,
and Ronnie Troop. Meanwhile, Myst and his friend
Ruff House use technology they obtained from
Livewire to break his sister, Chauvan McDougal,
out of prison and equip her with sonic tech
to rebuild their small time crew, Intergang.
Despite Clark's misgivings, the interns impersonate
the Scoop Troop to investigate Chauvin, now
Silver Banshee, discovering a clue to Intergang's
next heist. When Intergang attempts to rob the
Metropolitan City Bank, their ice cannon's
power crystal malfunctions and begins to freeze
everything in proximity. Seeing Lois and Jimmy
in danger, Superman awakens his heat vision
and destroys the crystal, granting him a vision
of an invading robot army. While Deathstroke's
organization secretly takes the defeated Intergang
members into Superman accepts Lois' interview
and discloses that he is still figuring himself
out, but is committed to saving people. However,
to his dismay, Lois later tells Clark that
she suspects Superman is lying. Now, when I
first saw Intergang pop up here, I was guessing
that the main villain was going to be Darkseid
and that this was apocalyptic tech, but that
turned out to not be the case. Right, because
traditionally, Intergang is supplied with new
God technology, right? I do like the way they
kind of flipped it here so that it was Kryptonian
tech, though. I think it still worked. Yeah,
I agree. I also think it's interesting how
crystals power Kryptonian tech. You know, Sunstone
is a thing in the comics. We saw that in the
Superman movie as well, where like all the architecture
and stuff is created from crystals. So it was
nice that they found a way to incorporate crystals
and even kryptonite as a crystal into Superman's
mythos. Yeah, when Superman destroyed the ice
crystal with his heat vision, that's when I
recognized the shonen tropes of him like leveling
up to face new challenges throughout the course
of each episode. I thought that was really neat.
It's really interesting. It's still not entirely
clear how his new powers were unlocked. He kind
of just like sparked with electricity and then
boom, had a new power. But I thought it was
cool and I thought it worked. I have a feeling
maybe Jor-El was kind of keeping tabs on his
son. and would unlock new powers as he needed
them. Episode four was titled, Let's Go to Ivo
Tower, You Say. Perry assigns the interns to
cover the Amazotech Gala held by CEO Dr. Anthony
Ivo. Lois is snubbed by the attendees for her
invasive questions, while Clark stumbles upon
an argument between Ivo and his chairman, Curtis,
regarding the board of directors voting out
Ivo. Ejected by Ivo's security, Lois sneaks
Clark back inside. They open up to each other
before discovering a secret room with technology
that connects Ivo to Livewire and Intergang.
An angered Ivo demonstrates the Parasite 1.0
armor and attempts to kill Chairman Curtis.
Clark becomes Superman to save Curtis, while
Ivo traps the attendees in the Amazo Panic Room
to make them witness him overpowering Superman.
Realizing the armor absorbs energy from his
attacks, Superman stops fighting Ivo directly,
as Lois and Jimmy deactivate the panic room.
With the suit depowered, Superman removes it
from Ivo, who became deformed due to the suit's
side effects. With Ivo under EMT care, the
interns return to find the secret room empty.
Lois kisses Clark, considering the night a
date night. Later, after submitting her expose
on Ivo, Lois finds a torn tabloid article involving
Kansas' miracle sightings in Clark's coat. After
reworking her evidence board, Lois concludes
that Clark is Superman. Now, Ivo was the one
villain, I think, that they really didn't do
justice, or I should say Parasite. Professor
Ivo in the comics, of course, is a mad scientist
of sorts, who is responsible for the creation
of villainous robots such as Amazo. Parasite
is his own villain. For some reason, they decided
to merge the two here, and I really didn't
care for the character design. I don't understand
why it needed a tail, of all things. It was
weird. Yeah, Parasite has never traditionally
been depicted as a tech- I mean, a lot of Superman's
villains are not tech-based, although you could
rationalize a lot of their abilities as tech-oriented.
Take, for example, Silver Banshee, which I thought
was well done. Parasite, I'm not quite so sure,
successfully makes the transition over to tech-villain.
Although, you know, the whole power-draining
aspect of it made sense for me, but- the weird
like tail and insectoid elements of the armor
didn't quite make sense. I also thought that
they really played a little bit probably too
heavily off of Tony Stark for Ivo making Kim
like this, you know, celebrity CEO on Playboy.
I don't know, I think they could have done a
better job, although I do appreciate the effort
I suppose. By this episode with Alex making
an appearance, you know, Ivo's like scientist
assistant, I totally thought that the main bad
guy the season was going to be Lex Luthor.
What are your thoughts on the show kind of like
positioning Lex Luthor as more of a secondary
villain type? I don't mind it, honestly. Like,
if you want to build up Lex Luthor as a major
antagonist over a season or two, that's fine
by me. Like, give next season to General Zod,
maybe have Lex Luthor help defeat him in some
way, but become bald in the process and then
have him be like the main villain by season
three. That's, that's fine. Yeah, I think that
totally works. I assume that they're going to
have Alex take over his former boss's company,
essentially. He's going to take over Amazotech
and turn it into LexCorp. Or LexTech, one of
those. Episode five was titled, You Will Believe
a Man Can Lie. Hoping to confess his burgeoning
feelings for Lois, Clark asks for her help in
developing a story about the stolen military
technology spreading throughout Metropolis and
a mysterious individual kidnapping anyone using
it. However, she sees it as an opportunity to
expose him as Superman. Using an old dispatch
scanner, she chases down Superman as he foils
various crimes before eventually meeting him
after he defeats Heatwave, another criminal
empowered by the stolen technology. While Superman
is distracted, Heatwave escapes, believing he
is behind recent kidnappings of Intergang members
who have used the high-tech weaponry. After
Superman drops off Lois at the Daily Planet
to keep her safe, He reconfronts Heatwave and
discovers the true culprit behind the abducted
criminals is an armored Deathstroke aided by
similar robots that Livewire used. Their subsequent
fight soon endangers civilians, leading to Deathstroke's
superiors, the General and Amanda Waller, ordering
him to withdraw so Superman can save them. After
returning to Lois, she forces Clark to reveal
his secret identity to her and is left distraught.
that Clark and Lois fail to attend a pre-planned
camping trip to investigate Bigfoot sightings
with him. He goes alone, but a large gorilla
kidnaps him. I thought this was a pretty good
episode, both action-wise and drama-wise. I
was actually surprised by the amount of drama
they were able to milk out of the whole Superman
Clark can't reveal to Lois Lane. Right. Yeah,
this is one of my favorite episodes. There's
often criticism that, you know, Lois Lane should
know that Superman... is Clark Kent because
Superman is just Clark Kent without glasses.
But I think this episode does a decent job of
sort of showing that Lewis doesn't really get
the best looks at Superman. He's never around
enough for her to interact with him the way
that she wants to. I mean, that all depends
on what version of Lewis you're talking about,
though, because, like, if you look at Richard
Donner's movie, they had a whole like date
night interviewed together. So she got a pretty
good look then. Margot Kidder should have known
better. It's fair. Well, she did figure it out
in Superman 2 on her own. That's true. To be
fair. Episode 6 was entitled, My Adventures
with Mad Science. After failing to locate Jimmy,
Clark reaches out to Lois for help. Despite
still being mad at him, she agrees. Scouring
the woods, the pair find an abandoned military
installation called Area 52. But upon crossing
the fence, Clark's powers falter due to the
area being exposed to red before they are chased
by OMAC robots. Meanwhile, inside Area 52, Jimmy
meets and befriends the gorilla Matsumala and
his partner, the Brain. The pair reveal they
originally worked for Project Cadmus, a branch
of Task Force X that focused on developing futuristic
technology, before the latter organization
betrayed them and raided Area 52. Ever since,
the Brain and Mala have been attempting to
create a wormhole to access other dimensions
where they will be accepted. Eventually, breaching
Area 52, Clark and Lois reconcile with each
other and Jimmy, who reveals he knew of Clark's
secret identity all along, before joining Brain
and Mala in defeating the Omacs. Successfully
opening their wormhole, the Brain warns Clark
that Task Force X is after him before leaving
with Mala. Concurrently, the General recruits
Ivo to help him use Cadmus' technology to kill
Superman. This is one of the lesser episodes,
in my opinion, largely because of the characters
of Munchier Mala and the brain. I know them
as Doom Patrol villains from the Brotherhood
of Evil. Right. And they weren't very evil in
this reality. Well, no, I think a lot of the
villains that were under the hands of Grant
Morrison were reinterpreted in a way that made
them less evil than they were prior, I would
say. Like, you know, he's the one who made
Munsir Mala and the Brain lovers to begin with.
Which just struck me as really weird in this
show. Yeah, especially considering that the
Brain was a scientist that helped give Munsir
Mala the gorilla his genius. And then fell in
love with him, which seems like a weird case
of bestiality going on. Like, was he fucking
that gorilla the whole time? I hope not. I
don't know if we want to- He better not be.
Yeah, like I didn't feel like comfortable with
some of the implications of this episode. There's
definitely like a breach of ethics there somewhere.
Anyway, yeah, I didn't love what they did with
the Brain and Mansuramala. They're Doom Patrol
villains again, so I'm not sure why they were
here in this episode. There are other villains
from Project Cadmus that I think could have
worked here just as well. Can you explain why
the area was doused in red solar radiation?
Because I guess I didn't quite get that part.
Or like why there were booby traps around as
the omacs were chasing Lois and Clark through
the jungle. Well the booby traps were set up
to protect Mansuramala and the brain from Task
Force X should they ever return to the base
of Area 52. I don't know what the red solar
radiation thing was about, I also didn't catch
that. Again, I don't think it was a great episode
because of unexplained things like that. I did
think the OMAX were cool, and I was actually
surprised to see them so soon after watching
Blue Beetle. Yeah, they're like everywhere
now. Episode 7 was titled Kiss Fallen Portal.
After Clark shows Lois and Jimmy his spaceship
and clarifies his incomplete alien origin, Clark
and Lois plan their first date. However, he
is interrupted by Mr. Mixy Espitalik, a multiversal
imp who deceives him into helping him steal
a recorder from a museum on Earth-1. revealing
Clark is from the planet Krypton in the process.
Meanwhile, Lois and Jimmy are recruited by the
Multiversal League of Lois Lanes to help them
stop Mixi-Spitalik and Clark. Suspicious of
their intentions, Lois searches their files,
stumbling onto the redacted File X. Upon finding
them, the League attacks Clark, while Mixi-Spitalik
hijacks the League's vessel and travels to their
headquarters with the Recorder and Lois' help.
As she steals the original File X, Myxiospidulix
retrieves his hat, regains his full strength,
and causes chaos until Superman distracts him,
allowing Lois to depower him and Jimmy to restrain
him. While the League arrests Myxiospidulix,
Jimmy's counterpart, Jelana, secretly brings
the interns back to their native Earth-12, where
Clark and Lois finish their date. Following
this, she opens File X and finds recordings
of evil alternate universe Superman and a sample
of Kryptonite. that the League used to injure
him. I actually really like this interpretation
of Myxias Spedulic, and I never know if I'm
pronouncing that correctly. Well, that's how
they pronounced it in the show. Yeah, it was
very different from other iterations of the
character that I've seen. Typically he's portrayed
as like this impish looking character, but
here he definitely had like mystic alien influences.
I thought he was more like a feline genie,
which kind of made sense to me. Considering
that fifth dimensional imps in DC comics are
often interpreted as genies like the Thunderbolt
I liked it the hat didn't make sense, but I
liked it No, yeah, and the fact that he got
his powers from his hat I thought was a little
bit convenient But no there were a lot of great
references in this episode to alternate animated
universe Superman that I appreciated I don't
think you guys power from his hat. I just think
he wasn't whole without his hat. Okay. Yeah
episode 8 was titled Zero Day Part 1. The General
uses shock collars to forcibly recruit Livewire,
Intergang, and Heatwave into assisting Deathstroke
and Ivo in capturing Superman. Meanwhile, after
developing Superhearing and sensing everyone
in the city crying for help, Clark runs himself
ragged helping everyone and soon becomes sleep
deprived and weakened. When Gotham Gazette journalist
Vicki Vale arrives to cover his activities,
Lois is starstruck to meet her. only to be disappointed
when Vail runs a biased story defaming Superman
as a menace to gain a promotion. Superman saves
an invisible Mist from being hit by a truck,
but causes an accident, turning public opinion
against him. Mist says Task Force X kidnapped
Silver Banshee, and Superman offers to rescue
her, only to be led into a trap and attacked
by the group. Though he holds his own despite
his weakened state, Superman is eventually
knocked out by Ivo, via his upgraded parasite
armor and livewire. The General stops Ivo from
killing Superman as he wants to interrogate
him, Mr. Egress luring Superman into the trap
as Lois and Jimmy rush to the scene but arrive
to see the group carry Superman away. And this
was cool, like this was a way to introduce the
Suicide Squad without actually naming them
as such. Just repurposing all of the villains
that they showcased throughout the season,
I thought was pretty well done. Yeah, and seeing
Superman going up against all of them was a
lot of fun to watch. It's like that video game
that's never coming out. Suicide Squad killed
the Justice League. Right, right. The angle
they took for this episode where his super
hearing kind of creates this vulnerability in
that he struggles with being everywhere at
once and therefore doesn't sleep and therefore
is less effective playing upon people's fears
that are being stirred by this new biased reporter.
It all works really well together. The show
can be really well written at times. Most times,
I would say. Yeah, I agree. Yeah. Episode nine
was Zero Day, part two. In flashbacks to Zero
Day, the general, Waller and their forces were
attacked by an alien army led by a Superman
like figure codenamed Nemesis Omega before
a mysterious event forced the army back into
a retreat that left their technology behind.
In the present. The News Kid Legion helps Lois
and Jimmy search for Superman, while the General
interrogates him for information on Zero Day.
From Superman's anguished reaction, the General
doubts his connection to it, while a displeased
Waller secretly helps the prisoners escape,
during which Livewire electrocutes Deathstroke's
right eye. A vengeful Ivo attacks Superman,
but inadvertently frees him. Flip from the News
Kid Legion eventually finds Superman, and takes
him to safety. Clark believes he was sent to
Earth to destroy it, but Lois assures him otherwise.
Upon learning Ivo is siphoning the power grid
and going on a Kaiju rampage through the city,
Lois and Jimmy use social media to petition
Metropolis's citizens to turn off their power,
weakening Ivo so Superman can use his newly
awakened x-ray vision to locate and remove
Ivo from the suit. As Superman and Lois declare
their love, Jimmy finds File X. On Checkmate's
behalf, Waller demotes the General and gives
him Ivo's last invention, the Omega Cannon,
with orders to kill Superman. And again, I didn't
love Ivo in this episode. The whole Kaiju parasite
thing was recently done in Superman Man of Tomorrow.
So it wasn't like novel to see it done again.
No, it was pretty cool how Superman's newly
gained ability of X-ray vision assisted in
Parasite's defeat though. That was cool. Yeah,
I agree with that. I actually thought this
was the season finale. I knew that there was
10 episodes, but for some reason I was like,
oh, it must be a mistake. I think there's actually
only nine. So I was surprised and pleased to
see that there was episode 10, because I thought
episode 10 was great. Episode 10 was called
Hearts of the Fathers. After having nightmares
about Zero Day. Clark is promoted, along with
Lois and Jimmy, to full reporters for their
article on Ivo's defeat. They have Thanksgiving
dinner with Clark's parents, and Lois invites
her father, Sam Lane, revealed to be the General,
though he fails to recognize Clark. In private,
Clark finds File X and the Kryptonite Shard,
which hurts him. His space pod reacts to the
Kryptonite, and releases a signal that prompts
an invasion similar to Zero Day. Superman and
Sam battle the invaders, with Jimmy learning
the kryptonite hurts them as well. Superman
takes the kryptonite and, despite being weakened,
uses it to destroy the mothership, halting the
invasion. A hologram of his father helps return
him to Earth. Sam prepares to kill him, but
Lois pleads for his life and reminds him that
he just saved them, causing him to leave. Jimmy
reveals he sold his social media platform,
Flamebird. to the daily planet for over 5 million
dollars and is now rich. On a distant world,
a robot seemingly brainiac informs his Kryptonian
master about the halted invasion. His master,
seemingly General Zod, says that the rebellious
world will soon kneel.
All around well done. The action of this episode
was fantastic. When he started throwing down
in that spaceship corridor with those robots,
right? I was like, kick their asses, Superman.
Superman gets his own hallway fight scene. Yeah,
I mean, the action overall is not really comparable
to some of the better anime action I've seen.
I think that could have actually been done
better in the season, but I did really enjoy
seeing Superman throw down with all these robots.
That's what the character is good for. You know,
these larger than life fights. Exactly. Yeah.
Superman has battles that no other superhero
really can have. It's top tier for sure. I
also loved seeing Jor-El like help his son fight
alongside him in the hallway, just like short
circuiting all those robots by zapping through
them as a hologram. I was like, you go, Jor-El,
you go. I wasn't quite sure why Jor-El's recognition
of the Kryptonite initiated a Kryptonian invasion,
but I am super interested in seeing why all
of that happens the way it happens in season
two, when we get reintroduced to characters
like Brainiac and General Zod, and get the
whole missing side of the story there. Exactly,
yeah, for sure. It almost seems like the ship
woke up in a response to the kryptonite for
some reason, and there wasn't much that Jor-El
could do about it. I'm not sure. I did love
the final line of Jimmy Olsen when he was like,
oh yeah, I'm rich now. My mouth went open just
like everyone else's around the table, just
like, what? What? It's definitely a fun angle
for Jimmy Olsen, I think. For sure. Really
interested in seeing where that goes. Yeah,
I'm interested in seeing where all of it goes
because this series is just so refreshing as
a DC fan and a Superman fan in particular.
It modernizes the character in a way that, again,
I didn't think could ever be done. It was this
perfect blend of anime action and romance and
the show's sleek character designs and charming
animation just successfully modernized Superman
and his friends. so well that I'm giving this
season 4.5 out of 5 stars, a fresh rating on
Rotten Tomatoes. Yeah, I have to agree with
the 4.5 star rating. I wasn't going that way
at the beginning of the season, but one of
the most impressive things about the show is
how it managed to turn me. My mind on what
it was completely changed from beginning to
end. Like, at the start, I was like, this is
like some kid's show, you know? I thought the
characterizations were too and the universe
was too unrecognizable. But the characters really
grew throughout the season, and I think the
universe that they built here came to be one
of the more compelling iterations of the Superman
story ever. I agree. To me it was near perfect.
I think the worst thing you could say about
it is that the show doesn't do the best job
of adapting lesser known Superman villains,
but they are lesser known Superman villains.
You know, it's not like they botched Zod or
Brainiac or Bizarro or something like that,
you know. These are Livewire and Heatwave.
So I didn't mind the creative liberty they took
with the characters. And overall, fantastic
show. Yeah, I hope the show does well because
I think that this version of Superman will
be to the 2020s that Smallville's Clark Kent
was to the early 2000s. I hope so. I hope so
because Smallville was insanely popular. And
I hope for all the people who were maybe thinking
about this show the same way we were going into
it, that it was, you know, just this kiddie
show. Take the time to watch this and really
find something to admire like we did. But that
does it for this review. Let us know what you
thought about season one by writing to us at
dynamicduelpodcast at gmail.com or by visiting
us on Instagram or X. You can find links to
all of our accounts by checking out our show
notes or visiting our website at dynamicduel.com.
And on our site, you can also find a link to
our Patreon page where you could join our Dynamic
Duo tier and chat with us and fellow listeners.
Our Fantastic Four tier, which gets you bonus
content each month. Our X-Force tier that makes
you an executive producer of the podcast. Or
our newest tier that lets you join our Dynamike
Podcast Network. If you can't join Patreon,
you can still support the show by signing up
for our e-newsletter also at dynamicduel.com.
Or you could also rate the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, Podchaser, and Facebook. or on our
website. Our next episode is going to be a duel
episode and lead up to our big team duel event
between Doom Patrol and Guardians of the Galaxy.
That'll be in two weeks, but next week we're
going to find out who'd win in a fight between
Dorothy Spinner and Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur.
Yeah, this is going to be a pretty interesting
match. The story of Dorothy Spinner is pretty
tragic. I don't know much about Moon Girl and
Devil Dinosaur, but I'm definitely interested
in seeing them throw down. But that does it
for this episode, we want to give a big thanks
to our executive producers Ken Johnson, John
Sturowski, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Balcom,
Miggy Mathangian, Brandon Estergard, Nathaniel
Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Nick Abonto, Austin Wazilovski,
AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, and Adam Spies
for helping make this podcast possible. And
we'll talk to you guys next week. Up up and
away, true believers. Save me, Pooper Man.