This is a Dynamike Network podcast.
Welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin brother, Marvelous
Joe. And in this episode, we are doing a duel
between the characters Dorothy Spinner from
The Doom Patrol and Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur.
This is the final duel in lead up to our big
team duel next episode. where we're gonna pit
the teams of Doom Patrol and Guardians of the
Galaxy against each other. Yeah, Dorothy Spinner
and Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur are both little
girl superheroes with big monsters as backup,
basically. It'll be a lot of fun to break down
these characters. Moon Girl has a fantastic
backstory that I was really glad to dive into,
so can't wait to talk all about her and figure
out who the heck's gonna win this matchup later
on this episode. Before that, we're gonna break
down the comic book movie news to come out in
the past week. of which there isn't much due
to the ongoing strikes. There was like a 45
second Loki season 2 teaser, so we're going
to talk about that. Yeah and this episode is
actually sponsored by the Chronicle AI card
game that Jonathan and I invented. That's right,
we are sponsoring our own episode because we
can. it's our podcast. So we're going to talk
a little bit about the card game that Jonathan
and I made. As always, we list our segment times
in our episode description, so feel free to
check out the show notes if you want to skip
ahead to a particular topic. As our listeners
may know, our duel simulator is so advanced
that it's gained sentience and has named itself
the artificial life form for running extensive
duels, just a rather very intelligent simulator
9000, or Alfred Jarvis 9000. Here's a quick
message for our listeners, so listen up. Why
hello there. Do you love listening and chatting
about Marvel and DC? Then become a part of
the dynamic dual community on Patreon where
you can choose from three tiers. The dynamic
2-0 tier lets you listen to this podcast without
ads and gives you access to its Discord chat
group where you can chat with Johnny DC and
Marvelous Joe. The Fantastic Four tier gives
you that and more with two bonus episodes each
month, including bloopers and top ten shows
where Johnny and Joe count down your favourite
Marvel and DC subjects. The X-Force tier makes
you an executive producer of Dynamic Duel, where
every month you help the host choose what to
review and who to fight against each other.
And finally, the Dynamite Podcast Network tier
allows aspiring podcasters to create their own
battle-focused show using this Monte Carlo
simulator.
graphic support and consultation and get you
simulation results to announce on your show.
Pitch the twins your show via email at dynamicduelpodcast
at gmail.com or by reaching out to them on
social media. Check it out at patreon.com slash
dynamic duel. Pip pip cheerio. Thanks, J9K,
and thanks to everyone who supports the podcast.
Be sure to tune into the Max Destruction podcast
this Wednesday, where Ken and Dustin find out
who'd win in a fight between John Matrix from
the Commando Movie. versus Robocop.
A No Prize is an award Marvel used to give out
to fans. Our version, the Dynamic Dual No Prize,
is a digital award we post on Instagram and
in our email newsletter for the person that
we feel gave the best answer to our question
of the week. We got a lot of great answers
this time. I think a total of eight people called
in. Unfortunately, we can only pick four answers
and there were only really four answers to give
because the question last week was... What
was your favorite Marvel or DC cartoon from
the 90s and why? I think the answers will be
pretty obvious, but it'll be interesting to
see which one comes out on top. Our first honorable
mention goes to Dustin Balcom, who said, Hey,
dynamic duelist Dustin Balcom here and I am
jumping in right away to get my answer because
I'm not going to let these DC robots come out
and just say Batman the animated series because
it is good, but my gosh grow personality. The
real answer is the 90s Spider-Man cartoon because
it was just perfection. And that's all I got
to say. That's right, Jonathan. Anyone who thinks
that Batman the Animated Series was the best
cartoon of the 90s basically has no personality,
according to Dustin. And he's right. The best
cartoon is actually Spider-Man, which was a
fantastic adaptation of the comic books. It
introduced kids to a whole bunch of other Marvel
superheroes. There were a lot of crossovers
in that show. Killer opening theme song. and
the show gave us the first example of the Spider-Verse.
I dunno, sounds kinda boring to me. What? Yeah.
I mean, big whoop. You know you watched that
shit. I did, it was good I guess. Travis Herndon
and Lizzie Dyer Arnie also gave the answer
of the 90's Spider-Man cartoon. But Colby Hentges
gave this answer. Hey boys, Colby Hentges.
I know these are usually opinion questions and
there's no right or wrong answer, but this
week is different. If you don't pick Batman,
the animated series, you're wrong. It's still
some of the best telling of some of Batman's
best stories. Kevin Conroy is Batman. Mark
Hamill is Joker. It's the best. B-Taz or bust.
Now, Joseph, I've got to ask you, would you
rather be boring or wrong? Uh, I'd rather be
wrong, I guess. That's fine. You rag about
everything, so it makes sense. I love how passionate
this week's answers are for this question.
How the DC guys have no personality and how
the Marvel guys are just wrong. But they are
because the Batman animated series is so good
with the music, with the voice work, even with
the character adaptations. And so influential
in terms of what came after it for DC. You
mean like the Superman show, Justice League?
Exactly. And even beyond that with the DC animated
movie universe films. Yeah, the legacy of the
show is pretty lasting, I'll admit that. We
want to give a shout out to Ezra Garcia who
also gave the answer of Batman the Animated
series. Our final honorable mention goes to
Scott Camacho who said, Johnny please do not
change the color of my name. But when it comes
to this category, I'm going to have to side
with Marvel, mainly the X-Men series.
banger of a soundtrack you cannot get any more
than the X-Men. Come on! That's right! Even
a DC fan can admit that the X-Men animated series
in the 90s was the best cartoon at that time.
Scotty mentioned the opening theme, which is
still the best theme in all of cartoons. His
brother, Gilly Macho, also gave the same answer
and made great points that... The show pretty
much defined the 90s as far as superheroes go
and it was highly influential in getting the
X-Men movie made which in turn probably helped
kickstart the MCU. So you know the influence
of the Batman animated series is one thing but
I think the influence of the X-Men animated
series was even greater and you know it's coming
back on Disney Plus next year. I don't see
Batman the animated series coming back. Well
they're trying to do it with Batman Kid Crusader.
I don't know what that is. It's Bruce Timm's
new Batman cartoon. Come on, keep up. Why would
I keep up with that? It's DC. Because DC's better.
Duh. Not according to Scotty. You know, I'm
going to have to change him to Team Red on the
Discord from Team Blue. Scotty, let's strike
one. Strike one, my friend. Thanks to everyone
for sending in your answer. But the winner
of this week's No Prize is Brandon Estegard,
who said, I barely make the cut off of a 90s
skit. I'm also going with a show that barely
makes a cut and that's Batman Beyond. I don't
think there's a wrong answer to this question,
but what sets Batman above the rest is it doesn't
have to rely on storylines from the comics and
can still establish amazing episodes. It was
a fresh and creative take on Batman with the
updated style from the OG animated series.
Yes, Spider-Man, Batman the animated series,
the X-Men animated series were all great, but
when you think of Batman Beyond, it was almost
like an amalgamation of everything that made
those other shows. Phenomenal I guess you could
say that because you know it had the cool animation
style from Batman the animated series as Brandon
mentioned But it also had you know the killer
soundtrack like the Marvel cartoons did and
more mature plots and adult themes and things
like that You know yeah, absolutely That was
a DC cartoon that I think even Marvel fans
have to admit was insanely cool It was almost
like the Marvel version of Batman right the
fuck yeah, I'm just gonna put that out there
Well, I'm not agreeing with that Now, for as
good as Batman Beyond was, I think X-Men actually
was the clear winner for this question. However,
Brandon was the only person to give the answer
Batman Beyond, and he got points for originality
with this one, since we don't usually like to
let people share No Prizes, you know? Right.
Congrats, Brandon! You win this week's No Prize.
If you, the listener, want a shot at winning
your own No Prize, stay tuned to later on in
this episode when we'll be asking another Question
of the Week. And now that that's done... Onto
the news!
Alright, there's not much news this past week
when it comes from Marvel and DC, but we did
get a teaser of sorts for the upcoming Loki
Season 2 on Disney+, which is strange because
we already got a full-on trailer for the show,
so it's kind of weird to get a 45 second teaser
after the trailer. Usually that's flipped around.
But we did get some pretty interesting new
shots of what's going down. in Loki season 2
starting October 6th. Like we said with the
trailer, this all looks phenomenal. The cinematography
and the visual effects are movie level. In
some cases, it looks even better than how the
movie looks, especially when it comes to the
set design and stuff. The teaser basically introduces
the concept that Loki is being pulled through
space and time involuntarily. He meets up with
Sylvie. who appears is hiding out in like McDonald's
in the 1970s after the events of season one
where she killed He Who Remains and kickstarted
the multiverse. She still has the really bad
haircut, but Loki and Sylvie join forces here,
going up against Victor Timely, who we get some
new shots of Jonathan Majors playing the character.
We also see Rhona Renslayer from season one,
who in the comics is King of the Conquerors'
romantic interest. She appears to be in Victor
Timely's timeline, and she's holding this futuristic
laser gun type device. Yeah, it makes me wonder
whose side she's on. Like, is she gonna try
and stop Kang, or is she gonna try and stop
Loki? That's a great question. My inclination
is that she's on Kang's side, and she's probably
his only ally, especially since she was such
a firm believer in the TVA and its mission,
even after she realized that the leaders of
the TVA were just lifeless automatons. True,
yeah, true. I mean, for a teaser, it definitely
teases. I don't know if I mentioned this in
our review of the latest trailer that came
out, but Loki was my favorite thing to come
out of the post-Endgame era of the Marvel universe,
next to Shang-Chi. So I'm really looking forward
to this, really intrigued by the marketing
that they're putting out for it, even if it's
just a 45-second teaser. Yeah, I'm also super
excited. We have less than a month before this
show comes out, and perhaps we'll get another
full-length trailer before that time, but we'll
see. That does it for the news for this episode.
Jonathan and I want to briefly remind listeners
that we created a card game for all you card
gamers and tabletop gamers out there and board
gamers. Jonathan and I have a deck building
card game that we developed over the span of
10 years or so and we've been told that it's
really fun and we played it and we think it's
really fun. So if you guys are into that kind
of stuff at all, check it at all. visit ChronicleAIgame.com,
which we will link in the show notes, and check
out the card game. Jonathan and I put a lot
of work into it and would appreciate any and
all support you guys can give in that capacity.
We do have a Marvel vs. DC version of this
card game exclusive to patrons. So whether or
not you get the Chronicle AI version of the
game, which is robot themed, or the Marvel vs.
DC version of the game, which we called Infinity
Crisis, let us know if you pick it up. and what
you think about it. We'd love for you to play
it. We think it's great, and we think you'll
think the same. Speaking of card games, that
brings us to our question of the week.
So all the gamers out there, what is your favorite
non-video game, for Marvel or DC, and why?
You know, such as board games, card games, tabletop
games, anything physical like that you've played.
Yeah, Jonathan and I are big fans of board games
and stuff like that, so largely this question
is to help inform me, I think, about some of
the things that are out there that I may not
know about that I would love to check out. So
record your answer at dynamicduel.com by clicking
on the red microphone button in the bottom right
hand corner of the screen. which will prompt
you to leave us a voicemail. Your message could
be up to 30 seconds long and don't forget to
leave your name in case we include you on the
podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer and
award that person a Dynamic Duel No prize that
we'll post to Instagram and our email newsletter.
Be sure to answer before September 16th.
That does it for the news portion of this episode.
Now let's move on to the main event, where
we find out who's gonna win in a match between
the Doom Patrol's Dorothy Spinner against Moon
Girl and Devil Dinosaur.
Okay, Dorothy Spinner against Moon Girl and
Devil Dinosaur. Of course, you'll be familiar
with Dorothy Spinner if you've seen any of the
HBO Max Doom Patrol series, or I guess it's
just Max now. Phenomenal series. If you haven't
watched it, I definitely recommend it, especially
season two, the season that Dorothy Spinner
is featured in. Yeah, Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur
actually have their own show too on the Disney
Kids channel and on Disney Plus, which is actually
incredible for a character that just came out
in 2016. I think to go from non-existence when
this podcast started to having a full-on show
of their own is a real testament to how cool
the characters of Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur
are. I highly recommend the cartoon. It is
for kids, but it is highly inspired visually
by the Spider-Verse films. It's not... 3D animated,
it's 2D, but there's a lot of cool stuff in
there that's very comic book-y. That's cool.
Is it Moon Girl or Devil Dinosaur or both that
were created in 2016? Well, Devil Dinosaur
dates back to the 1960s as a creation of Jack
Kirby. Moon Girl was created much more recently,
and I go into that a little bit in my history.
In addition to the shows, you know, also check
out the comics. The Doom Patrol comics are very
highly recommended, especially the run by Grant
Morrison. And I have to say, in my research
for this episode, I had a whole lot of fun
going back, reading the first two arcs for Moon
Girl and Devil Dinosaur. Nice, well, let's
get into it. To explain the methodology behind
our duels, let's go to our sentient duel simulator,
Alfred Jarvis 9000. AJ9K, tell our listeners
how you go about determining a winner in our
duel matchups. Yes, of course, sir. The way
I determine a winner between the contestants
is by running 1000 Monte Carlo simulations using
the characters statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation
is a probabilistic model used to determine outcomes
through random sampling. In this case, I randomise
the statistics along a normal distribution as
a way to simulate the many variables that can
occur during battle. The stat parameters are
based on the official Marvel power grid from
which the DC characters' statistics are extrapolated.
Additional stat categories are included such
as range, damage potential, versatility and
perception in order to create a more detailed
and accurate simulation. The results of the
1000 simulations provide a percentage of wins
for each character. The contestant with the
higher percentage is declared the victor, as
they have a higher probability to win any given
battle. In an equitable pairing, neither character
should win 100% of the matches. The comic book
stories have shown that there's even a way
for Batman to defeat Superman, so the confidence
rate of my method falls in line with the precedents
that have been established in the source material.
My mathematical simulations are without subjectivity
or bias. Feats are not the sole consideration,
nor are fan votes tabulated for determination
of the winner. Thanks AJ9K! Before we run the
simulations though, we like to break down each
character's histories and abilities before improvising
a scenario on how we imagine one of the 1000
simulations would play out B for B. And I believe
it's my turn to go first with the DC character's
backstory, so let me tell you all about Dorothy
Spinner. Her backstory is a little bit of a
downer, but here it is. Dorothy Spinner was
born with an ape-like facial disfiguration
and hairy limbs, resulting in her birth mother
giving her up for adoption while Dorothy was
still an infant. Adopted by the Spinner family,
Dorothy was raised as an only child on a farm
in rural Kansas. With many in the community
repulsed by Dorothy's appearance and due to
excessive bullying from other children, the
Spinners isolated Dorothy on their farm, which
occupied much of the Spinner's As a result of
her loneliness and isolation, Dorothy developed
imaginary friends, which she was unknowingly
able to bring to life due to her psychic mind.
Her friends taught her to read and write and
told her stories, such as The Wizard of Oz,
which Dorothy enjoyed. One day, while picking
flowers outside, Dorothy was accosted by a
young boy named Bernard
When Dorothy made her way back to her barn to
find that Bernard had hung her cat, she wished
that Bernard was dead. It was at this point
that the Candlemaker emerged from her mind,
a being capable of granting wishes. After making
the wish to the Candlemaker, Bernard was found
in a field the next morning by his friends,
crucified and disemboweled. At the funeral,
Dorothy vowed to never make another wish from
the Candlemaker again and buried him deep in
her mind. At age 11, Dorothy began being frightened
by the stories that her imaginary friends were
telling her. Old, sinister fairy tales from
the Brothers Grimm and Hans Christian Andersen.
When three imaginary family members tried to
get Dorothy to wear red shoes, they reminded
Dorothy of a fairy tale about a girl who couldn't
stop dancing until her legs were chopped off.
Dorothy told them that she had something to
show them behind the barn, at which point Dorothy
shot and killed them with an imaginary gun.
A few years later, A battle between a team
of superhero outcasts known as the Doom Patrol
and the Lord of Chaos named Pytheia spilled
onto the Spinner farm. Home alone, Dorothy got
swept up into the battle and helped the superhero
team defeat Pytheia when the others seemingly
died in the pandemonium. Dorothy was made an
honorary member of the Doom Patrol and was shocked
when they called her their friend. After realizing
that their daughter had psychic powers, the
Spinners called Dr. Niles Calder. aka the Chief,
who you can learn more about in our Chief vs.
Professor X duel episode. The Chief agreed
to help care for Dorothy and brought her to
the Doom Patrol's new headquarters, the Secret
Sanctuary in Happy Harbor, Rhode Island, a former
base of the Justice League which contained
a vault of souvenirs from past Justice League
battles. One of those souvenirs was the Materiopticon,
formerly wielded by the villain Dr. Destiny
and Dream of the Endless before him. the latter
of whom you can learn more about in our Sandman
vs. Mephisto duel episode. Due to the Materiopticon's
ability to turn dreams into reality, Dorothy's
imaginary family, Damal, Darling Come Home,
and Flying Robert, came back to life and attacked
Dorothy for killing them, still trying to get
her to wear the red shoes. Realizing the red
shoes symbolized Dorothy's fear of menstruation,
the Doom Patrol's
empowering the Materiopticon, which robbed the
imaginary beings of much of their strength.
Before they vanished, Dorothy accepted the red
shoes and her own womanhood, realizing the
shoes were ruby slippers after all and that
she was at home with the Doom Patrol. When
the team relocated their headquarters onto Danny
the Street, who you can learn more about in
our Danny the Street vs. Kerkoa episode, Dorothy
and new Doom Patrol member Flexmantello were
kidnapped by an organization- known as the Men
from Nowhere, who imprisoned them in the sub-subbasement
of the Pentagon known as the Ant Farm in order
to harness their psychic power to summon an
all-powerful entity known as the Telephone Avatar.
Although Flex Mantello managed to weaken the
Telephone Avatar by flexing a muscle that turned
the Pentagon into a circle, Flex and Dorothy
would have been killed were it not for Dorothy
wishing for the Candlemaker to save her and
her friends before passing out. When she awoke,
She saw the telephone avatar hanging from the
ceiling. With the Candlemaker constantly intruding
into Dorothy's thoughts afterward, asking her
for wishes, Dorothy confessed to Joshua what
the Candlemaker had done before she collapsed
from mental exhaustion. When Joshua went to
the Chief for help, the Chief shot and killed
Joshua for interrupting him. When Dorothy came
to and found Joshua dead, the Candlemaker emerged
and asked Dorothy if she wished that Joshua
were alive. When she said that she did, the
Candlemaker resurrected Joshua, only to kill
him immediately afterward, to Dorothy's horror.
Having gained enough power from Dorothy's wishes
to emerge into the world fully formed, the
Candlemaker decapitated the Chief and destroyed
Robotman's human brain before attacking the
world's soul in New York City, causing people
to go insane. After learning that the Candlemaker
was really an ancient malevolent entity, that
used Dorothy's psychic powers to emerge into
the physical plane, the Doom Patrol eventually
defeated Candlemaker, with Dorothy delivering
the killing blow by blowing out the Candlemaker's
final flame. The Doom Patrol disbanded afterward,
forcing Dorothy to enter the real world and
get an apartment. Having to deal with continual
harassment from onlookers whenever she had to
leave the house, Dorothy was also bombarded
by African spirits who kept asking her to join
their world. Dorothy created an imaginary version
of the Doom Patrol to comfort her, though she
was encouraged by the scientist William Magnus,
who you can learn more about in our Metal Men
vs. Colossus duel episode, to overcome her
fear of the real world. After being attacked
by spirit-possessed mannequins at a shopping
mall, Dorothy was saved by Robot Man, who you
can learn more about in our Robot Man vs. Think
episode. The two of them helped reform the Doom
Patrol, though Dorothy found herself depressed,
and due to her inexperience and frequent inability
to contribute to the team as much as she wanted.
After befriending a magical doll named Charlie,
who she later learned was possessed by the
spirit of a rabbi, Dorothy helped Charlie reform
the Holy Grail with the power of her imagination,
and Charlie's spirit departed, his mission completed.
Alone again, Dorothy was taken on a camping
trip by robot man and fellow Doom Patrol member
named Coagula. to let her know that her adoptive
father had died in a wheat-thresher accident
and that they found her biological mother,
who was going to meet them soon. Upon realizing
that she was being asked to leave the Doom
Patrol in order to live a normal life with her
mom, Dorothy unleashed a psychic explosion
in a fit of immense rejection that killed Quagula,
destroyed Robotman, and put herself into a
coma. After a new Doom Patrol team formed, Its
version of Robotman eventually realized that
he was an imaginary version created by Dorothy
in her vegetative state. When the real, newly
assembled Robotman realized what was going on,
he visited Dorothy in the hospital and made
the traumatic decision to take her off of life
support, and Dorothy soon died. And she remains
dead in post-Flashpoint continuity, though Robotman
keeps a photo of the two of them and visits
her grave every week. Powers-wise, Dorothy is
a powerful yet somewhat unstable psychic, capable
of bringing her imaginary friends to life, sometimes
unwillingly. As a young girl, many of her imaginary
friends manifest as symbols of her emotions,
often fear or as character interpretations
from stories she's read or heard, and occasionally
as recreations of people she knows. This includes
but is not limited to... Pretty Miss Dot? who
has lipsticks for fingers that can shoot fire,
paddle the sky, a swirling mass of hands holding
paddles, hearts of ice, a woman made of ice
that can freeze things, dark as the morning,
a shadow creature with a giant fanged mouth,
cowboy doll book face, a gun wielding cowboy
made of dolls with a book for a face, and Spinner,
a superhero adult version of Dorothy, who's
a member of the imagined team, the Doom Force.
and can manifest the nightmares of her opponents.
That's Dorothy Spinner. That was a lot darker
than I thought it was going to be and very much
a downer. It is like the exact opposite of
the Moongirl Devil Dinosaur backstory, which
is largely pretty fun and cute and yeah, not
at all what Dorothy Spinner's story is. Yeah,
it's probably like the most depressing backstory
of any DC character I've ever done a bio for
in the span of this podcast. So let's cheer
up everyone with Moongirl's backstory. Yeah,
I'm glad I'm going second here. Here's the
backstory for Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur.
In prehistoric times, in an alternate dimension
existed Dinosaur World, a planet where dinosaurs
lived alongside the Neanderthal tribes of early
humans. Within a region of active volcanoes
called the Valley of Flame, the most aggressive
hominid tribe called the Killer Folk dominated
other less hostile tribes such as the Small
Folk. When a group of Killer Folk came across
a female Tyrannosaurus rex-like dinosaur and
her young, they attacked and killed the mother
and two of her children. They offered the third
young dinosaur as a sacrifice to their volcano
god by burning it alive with the fire from
their torches. The beast nearly died, but was
rescued by a boy from the Small Folk tribe
who witnessed the massacre. The Neanderthal
child's name was Moonboy. as he was the only
member of his tribe who was brave enough to
go out at night. He saw that the flames had
turned the dinosaur's scales a fiery red, and
the boy took care of it, naming him Devil.
Moonboy and Devil Dinosaur formed a close bond,
and together they fought and defeated the Killer
Folk tribe, claiming the Valley of Flame for
the small folk and protecting the lands from
other dinosaurs and monsters. Meanwhile, universes
away, An autistic 9-year-old girl named Lunela
Lafayette grew up on the Lower East Side of
Manhattan. Brilliant but shy and mocked for
her awkwardness, Lunela acquired the nickname
Moon Girl due to her constant daydreaming about
strange gadgets and inventions. When the inhuman
hero Black Bolt released the Terranian mists
into Earth's atmosphere during a battle with
Thanos, Lunela believed she could use her intelligence
to help contain the gases. were afraid that
pterogene exposure would transform them as
the substance was used by the inhuman race as
a catalyst to change them into their superpowered
forms. Inhumans were descendants of a group
of early mankind that were experimented on
by the alien race, the Kree, to serve as their
soldiers. Hundreds, if not thousands of people
on Earth unknowingly had inhuman genetics and
were being altered due to the pterogene clouds
now in the air. You can learn more about pterogenesis
the Inhumans and their King Black Bolt in our
Shazam vs Black Bolt dual episode. Lunela believed
the solution to the Terran clouds lay in alien
Kree science, so she built a device to help
her locate any Kree technology on Earth in
order to study it. This led her underneath the
Brooklyn Bridge where she found a Kree device
called an Omni-Wave Projector that was capable
of opening portals between time and space.
Meanwhile, universes away, Moon Boy happened
upon another Omni-Wave projector that had landed
on Dinosaur World that was being worshipped
by the Killer Folk tribe, who called it their
Night Stone. The Killer Folk caught Moon Boy
with the device and beat him to death, when
suddenly both projectors activated simultaneously,
opening a portal between Earth and Dinosaur
World. A group of Killer Folk entered the portal
and began terrorizing the people of present-day
Manhattan, but they were followed by Devil Dinosaur,
who sought to avenge Moonboy's death. Devil
Dinosaur saved Lunela from the Killer Folk,
who had fled their encounter, and she explained
to the semi-intelligent beast that she needed
his help to get the Omni-Wave Projector from
the Neanderthals in order to save humanity.
Before they could act, however, Devil Dinosaur
was captured and imprisoned in a secret facility.
Finding her courage, Lunela resolved to rescue
her friend and equipped a series of homemade
gadgets and a suit After hacking into a government
database to find the dinosaur's whereabouts,
she snuck away from home and broke into the
secret facility, using her gadgets to break
Devil from his high-tech cage. Together, the
duo tracked the Killer Folk to a Manhattan rooftop
where they defeated the Neanderthal group and
recovered the Omni-Wave Projector. However,
immediately after their victory, the Terran
Cloud descended upon Lunella, causing her to
undergo teragenesis and encasing her in a giant
egg. Devil Dinosaur carried the egg containing
Lunela to safety at her secret lab underneath
her elementary school. When she hatched, Lunela
could not immediately tell what the Terrigen
had changed about her. However, later at school,
she discovered that she would involuntarily
switch minds with Devil Dinosaur, who was back
at the lab, whenever she experienced strong
emotions such as anger or hunger, and spontaneously
during a full moon. Keeping her crime fighting
a secret from her parents as much as possible,
Lunella was eventually discovered by scientist
Amadeus Cho, who administered a test developed
by Bruce Banner called the Brain Omnicompetence
Examiner. It was determined that Lunella was
probably the most intelligent mind on Earth,
scoring higher than other scientific minds such
as Mr. Fantastic. The villain Dr. Doom took
offense to this news and attacked Lunella, but
with help from the superhuman community, including
Dr. Strange, the X-Men, and Ironheart, She and
Devil Dinosaur were able to defeat the Doombot
army. At one point, the inhuman hero Ms. Marvel
recruited Lunella and Devil Dinosaur to help
in the war between the Inhumans and the X-Men,
which was caused by the toxic nature of the
Terrigan mists to mutants. Lunella used her
knowledge of Kree technology to help the X-Men
scientist Forge miniaturize a version of a machine
he designed that would compress the Terrigan
gases into a solid state and incinerate it.
You can learn more about Forge in our Mr. Terrific
vs. Forge dual episode. Later, Lunella received
a distress call from space and built a spacecraft
so she and Devil Dinosaur could answer it. During
the adventure, her omni-wave projector malfunctioned
and the pair ended up back in time on Dinosaur
World, Devil's home planet. There they found
Moonboy at the time he discovered the omni-wave
projector and they were able to prevent him
from being beaten by the Killer Folk. Knowing
that Devil was back home with his true owner,
Lunella decided that leaving him with Moonboy
was the right thing to do. She said goodbye,
and though Devil Dinosaur protested, she tearfully
told him she didn't want him anymore and used
the projector to travel back to Earth alone.
Sad and isolated, Lunella ended up joining
the Thing, Human Torch, and the robot Herbie
in a new version of the Fantastic Four, as
Mr. Fantastic and Invisible Woman were off with
their children recreating the multiverse. You
can learn more about that in our Justice Society
vs. Fantastic Four dual episode. Eventually,
Lunella used Herbie to open a dimensional portal
to bring Devil Dinosaur back to Earth to help
in a fight against the Super Skrull, and the
two were reunited. Lunella admitted she was
wrong for leaving Kim, Devil forgave her, and
the two went back to fighting crime on their
own. This included helping Doctor Strange rescue
a boy kidnapped by the villain Nightmare, assisting
Spider-Man against a Goblin foe, and solving
an unsolvable riddle for Thor that was posed
by his brother Loki. The latter adventure revealing
that Devil was worthy of wielding Mjolnir and
it transformed him into the Thunder Lizard.
On a family trip to the country of Wakanda,
Lunela's parents discovered her secret alter
ego as Moon Girl. They banned her from continuing
to fight crime with her dinosaur pet, though
they later compromised as long as Lunela visited
with a therapist once a week. At that time,
she formed a support group for fellow newly
powered adolescent inhumans called the Support
Alliance Derby for Sensationally Abled Kids,
or SADSACS for short. And that's her backstory.
Powers-wise, Moon Girl has the inhuman power
to temporarily swap her consciousness with Devil
Dinosaur, her crime-fighting partner. This
process is triggered involuntarily, caused by
heightened emotional states and the Fool Moon.
She has an exceptionally high intellect. stated
to likely be the smartest person on Earth,
and has built a vast array of homemade gadgets
for her crime fighting activities. This includes,
but is not limited to, spectrum scanning goggles,
spring loaded boxing gloves, rocket powered
roller skates, a helicopter backpack, a plunger
tipped taser gun, sneeze powder grenades, a
flashlight flash bang, and so many other toys
in her utility belt. She can invent nearly
anything she puts her gifted mind to, physically
through engineering, or digitally through computer
programming. Devil Dinosaur is a physically
and mentally enhanced Tyrannosaurus Rex-like
dinosaur via genetic mutation awakened when
he was set aflame as a youngling. He has increased
durability and strength, able to lift around
25 tons, and his scaly hide is immune to heat
and strong enough to be bulletproof. Devil Dinosaur's
fangs, claws, and his sense of smell are razor
sharp, and he can track nearly anyone by their
scent. He has human level reasoning abilities
and can fully understand moon girl's commands.
That's moon girl in devil dinosaur. Wait, so
when devil dinosaur takes over moon girl's body,
is she just like this snarling creature who's
like always hungry? Yeah, she looks quite feral
actually. It's kind of funny when it happens.
Interesting. And her friends are aware of what's
going on or they aren't? No, she just gets
further ostracized for being weird when she
swaps minds with devil dinosaur during school
time. That's funny. That's cute. What a cute
character. Yeah, and she freaking lives at
the end. Yeah, that's because Marvel is for
little kids, bro. OK. All right. DC is for
the adults. Sad adults, but adults nonetheless.
I mean, what adult isn't sad?
So now that we got the characters' histories
and abilities out of the way, let's speculate
on how one of the 1000 simulated matches will
go. The winner is determined by simulations,
not the speculation, but it's fun to imagine
how the fight could play out. Alfred Jarvis
9000, what are the rules of our speculation?
Well, I should say there are no rules, other
than the characters have no prior knowledge
of the other going into the fight. All they
are aware of starting out is that the other
character is a threat that needs to be eliminated.
For the speculation... contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the
match itself as no environmental statistics
are considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. Alright
then let's get into it! Dorothy Spinner and
Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur meet on the battlefield.
Who goes first? Honestly this is kind of hard
because I don't think either character would
attack the other really like they'd probably
commiserate and want to be but that's too bad
because the purpose of the podcast is to see
who would win in no holds barred action. So
we're gonna make these children fight, damn
it. All right, I figured that once Dorothy
sees Devil Dinosaur, she's gonna freak out and
probably summon Pretty Miss Dot, who's kind
of her go-to when she's in danger. So this weird
entity wearing a helmet with lips. and curlers
and lipstick fingers flies toward Devil Dinosaur
and begins blasting him with fire. Alright,
well that does nothing. Devil Dinosaur is immune
to fire, so all this attack is gonna do is
just piss him off. So he's infuriated and he's
gonna roar real loud and then he's just gonna
chomp down on Pretty Mistat with his razor sharp
teeth. Meanwhile, Moon Girl is gonna roller
skate over to Dorothy and just knock her the
hell out with a spring-loaded boxing glove.
Yeah, except that now Dorothy is emotionally
traumatized by having seen Pretty Miss Dot
just die like that. So while Moon Girl was approaching
Dorothy, she's going to conjure several more
entities. And we'll go with Paddle the Sky for
Moon Girl and Heart of Ice for Devil Dinosaur,
since Fire didn't do anything to him. So not
only does Moon Girl's boxing glove get knocked
out of the way, she also gets paddled numerous
times by Paddle the Sky. And Devil Dinosaur
is now encased in ice. Remind, what do Paddle
of the Sky and Heart of Ice look like? Paddle
of the Sky is literally a spinning vortex of
hands holding wooden paddles. And Heart of
Ice is just a woman made of ice. Okay. Uh, not
gonna lie, I don't think Moon Girl would be
well equipped for all this weirdness. But she's
gonna evade the paddles by activating her spring-loaded
roller skates to launch herself into the air.
And then she's going to switch on her helicopter
backpack. So she's flying through the air. And
as this paddle creature is chasing her, Moon
Girl is going to pilot over toward Devil Dinosaur.
And then she's going to quickly zip out of
the way so that paddle guy crashes into Devil
Dinosaur, who's in the ice. And basically,
the paddles are going to break Devil Dinosaur
out of his ice casing. So now that Devil Dinosaur
is free. He's just gonna tackle paddle the sky
out of the sky and just eviscerate it turning
those paddles into Splinters I hope you choke
on them And while that's happening moon girl
is gonna whip out a hairdryer That she outfitted
as a flamethrower and she's just gonna melt
the ice lady to a puddle Dude keep killing Dorothy's
imaginary friends. See what happens. She's
got some weird ass friends, you know Even you've
got insoles for her. Wow, wow, she can't catch
a break, can she? Dude, these friends are objectively
weird. I don't think anybody would deny them.
Literally one of them is made out of paddles.
Come on. And while Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur
are taking care of them, Dorothy's gonna be
like, oh no, my friends. And that is when Moon
Girl, she's gonna pull out a can of soda that
she shakes and then hurls over to Dorothy like
a grenade and the can. is going to explode and
just drench Dorothy in this sticky adhesive
that Moon Girl invented. Okay, the can, it's
going to explode way before it reaches Dorothy
because Cowboy doll Bookface is going to shoot
it right out of the sky when it's right over
Devil Dinosaur just drenching him in the adhesive
instead. So Devil is stuck to the ground and
Cowboy is just going to keep shooting at Moon
Girl. All right, well, Moon Girl is going to
dive behind Devil Dinosaur. and use him as cover
since she knows that he's bulletproof. And
then to get him free of the adhesive, she's
gonna pour a soda can of anti-adhesive on him
and then hop on Devil's back as he gets up and
just straight up charges Cowboy Dollface and
whips his tail right through him, book face.
Whatever. But his tail whip is gonna cause
the Cowboy to explode into a thousand doll parts.
So he's gone. And without missing a beat, like
after that tailwhip, Moon Girl is going to spring
off of Devil Dinosaur's back and she's going
to shoot a taser plunger at Dorothy that sticks
to Dorothy's head and it's going to send like
10,000 volts of electricity through her brain.
Just shutting it down. Well, OK, Dorothy's
knocked out, but she doesn't need to be conscious
for her imaginary friends to manifest or protect
her. You know, so as Moon Girl is about to land.
She lands on Honey Pie, which is a beehive
with tree branches for limbs and a honeypot
for a head. So Honey Pie has Moon Girl in this
bear hug, essentially, and Moon Girl's being
squeezed and stung as she's pressed up against
this pissed off beehive. And meanwhile, Spinner,
the adult version of Dorothy, is going to appear
and manifest Devil Dinosaur's greatest fear,
which is... I don't know, an army of the killer
folk tribesmen who are all gonna rush and attack
Devil Dinosaur. I mean, Devil Dinosaur eats
killer folk for breakfast, alright? So he's
gonna tear through them to rescue Moon Girl
from this beehive guy. Honey pie. Yeah, yeah,
he's gonna grab honey pie in his T-Rex claws
and just freaking body slam that thing causing
it to drop Moon Girl who's gonna helicopter
away to safety. And as she's flying away...
She's gonna pull out of her backpack a version
of Professor X's Cerebro device that in the
comics she once calibrated to detect magic
beings. So she's gonna be recalibrating it again.
Where is she pulling this stuff out from? Her
backpack? Okay. Well, I mean, Spinner is still
around. So she's gonna appear into Moon Girl's
mind and manifest Moon Girl's greatest fear,
which is, I don't know, what's Moon Girl's
greatest fear? Uh, I... I don't know, an F on
a test or something? Big whoop. Moon Girl wearing
the recalibrated Cerebro is gonna deduce that
Dorothy's friends are psychic manifestations.
So she's gonna pull out a bullhorn that emanates
a frequency that disrupts psychic energies.
And Moon Girl's gonna use this invention to
just dissipate Spinner. Okay, all right, so.
Dorothy is going to wake up to see Spinner dissipate.
And all of a sudden, she hears the Candlemaker
whispering in her mind, asking her to make a
wish. And she's going to wish that this match
was over. And that's what's going to happen.
Devil Dinosaur, he'll eat Moon Girl. And he
himself is going to burst into eldritch flames
that just melt his bodily tissue like Raiders
of the Lost Ark style, just leaving this dinosaur
skeleton. Match over. What? I don't get it.
Was Devil Dinosaur possessed or something? I
don't even know what happened there. No, like
he was more like driven insane by the Candlemaker.
And it caused him to eat Moon Girl? Yep. I
say that like even before Dorothy hears the
Candlemaker like whispering in her ear and
then, you know, she makes the wish and all that
weirdness happens, that would take a while.
So before that, Devil Dinosaur just straight
up stomps Dorothy with his big old dinosaur
foot. planning and then he's gonna let out a
big victory roar like the T-Rex did at the
end of the Jurassic Park movie. I don't think
that hearing make a wish and then making a
wish would take all that long. I mean it's not
quicker than a foot dropping on you so I don't
know but we could go ahead and leave the match
there either Dorothy makes her wish and the
candle maker causes moon girl and devil dinosaur
to destroy themselves or Dorothy doesn't have
a chance to make the wish because she's a pancake.
Let's go ahead and find out which of these
scenarios happens by inputting the stats for
these characters and running 1000 simulations.
We'll be right back with the winner. Hey G9K,
hit it! Inputting data. Running calculations.
Processing results. Simulations complete. I
hate to see these two characters go up against
each other. It would have been more fun, I think,
to do a speculation where they become best
friends and hang out together, you know? Right?
It was kind of interesting just coming up with
the stats. We kind of realized that both of
these characters' powers are essentially the
power of imagination. Like they're highly, highly
versatile. Right, because Moon Girl can basically
engineer anything she imagines, and Dorothy
Spinner can manifest it. So that was pretty
cool. We treated this matchup like a two versus
two character matchup, like a mini team duel,
which we've done before in episodes like Cloak
and Dagger versus the Wonder Twins, or North
Star and Aurora versus Hawk and Dove. Yeah,
or like Daughters of the Demon versus Daughters
of the Dragon. Yeah, we've done a few 2v2 matches
before. In this case, we counted the individual
stats for Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur, as well
as Dorothy Spinner on her own, and kind of
an amalgamation of her imaginary friends, wherein
we averaged the stats of all of her imaginary
friends and treated it as kind of like this
composite being. Yeah, which was not easy.
No, it was pretty difficult to come up with
that average for the imaginary friends, but
in the end we ended up getting win rates for
each one of the characters. Dorothy Spinner
was by far the weakest. Yes, Dorothy Spinner
is hands down the weakest character I've ever
done a duel with. I felt bad for her as I was
entering these stats in. But, her imaginary
friend creatures were actually really powerful,
more powerful than either Moon Girl or Devil
Dinosaur on their own. And- kind of wiped the
floor with both of them individually, winning
three quarters of all of its matches. And what
was really interesting was that Moon Girl actually
had better stats than Devil Dinosaur. Right.
Just due to her heightened intelligence and
versatility with all the inventions and stuff
like that. Devil Dinosaur is strong and can
do damage, but otherwise, you know, he's not
that impressive statistically, considering
he's kind of a one trick pony and not that bright.
He's a dinosaur. It's kind of interesting because
a lot of Dorothy's imaginary friends were also
one trick ponies. But then you have someone
like the candle maker who isn't technically
an imaginary friend, but we still kind of counted
him in the composite considering the fact that
he was a manifestation from Dorothy's mind.
And the guy could almost do anything. You can
make wishes come true, essentially. Yeah, he
definitely skewed that average. But was it enough?
What do you think, Joseph? I think there's
an interesting balance here. between how weak
Dorothy is, but how strong her imaginary friends
are. And then Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur are
somewhere in between that power spectrum. So
I think the matchup is gonna be close. I do
think that the scales are ultimately gonna
tip toward Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur though.
So we did a poll on Instagram and 64% of those
who voted, voted in favor of Moon Girl and Devil
Dinosaur. Do you think it's gonna be over or
under that? I think it's going to be under that.
I think it's going to be a closer match. But
that was definitely a popularity contest poll.
We even had some people ask us like, who the
heck is Dorothy Spinner? To which case, I got
to say, read and or watch Doom Patrol because
it's awesome. You have to watch Doom Patrol
on Max. It's a great show. And its final season
is wrapping up here soon. But let's find out
who won. AJ 9K, the results, please. Hey, you
are, sir. The winner of the matchup between
Dorothy Spinner and Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur
is Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur. Hell yeah.
I was hoping to see that coming. I was hoping
she'd win this one. It was close. Moon Girl
and Devil Dinosaur won 57.1% of the matches
or 571 out of 1000 compared to Dorothy Spinner
and her imaginary friend who only won 42.9.
So that was pretty close. If you had asked me
leading into this. Whether or not I thought
Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur even stood a chance
against Dorothy Spinner, I would have said
you're out of your mind. Well, it's really all
about Moon Girl's intelligence, right? Considering
that she is likely the most intelligent person
in the Marvel universe, she has a lot going
for her. Probably more than you ever realized.
Way more than Dorothy Spinner, I think. It's
not down to the intelligence. You know what
it's down to? What? The fucking system, man.
The fucking system. What? Yeah, it's like there's
no way that Dorothy Spinner would go into this
match with only one imaginary friend, but it's
way too complicated to pit two characters against
like 20. Well, that's why we had the composite
imaginary friend. It's not good enough. It's
not good enough. The system's broken. I think
it sounds pretty accurate myself. But, you
know, anytime Marvel wins. It always sounds
highly accurate to me. It does make me wonder
though, how we're gonna run the stats for next
week's team duel between Doom Patrol and Guardians
of the Galaxy if we count Dorothy Spinner as
multiple beings. I don't know if we can actually.
We might have to do a composite of her as well
with the imaginary friend. That'll be interesting.
That will be interesting. We'll have to figure
that out. Considering those seven versus seven,
matrices simulations take a long time to run.
Yeah, ton of time. Even two versus two takes
a while. Yeah. I hope you feel bad. I hope you
feel bad for Dorothy Spinner. She's had a hard
life and you don't make it any easier. Well,
geez, I do feel bad for her as a character,
but also, you know, Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur
deserve this win. So there you go. All right.
I guess if you can live with that guilt. That
does it for this duel. Let us know what you
thought about the results by writing to us at
dynamicduelpodcast at gmail.com or by visiting
us on Instagram or X. You can find links to
all of our accounts by checking out our show
notes or visiting our website at dynamicduel.com.
And on our site you can also find a link to
our Patreon page where you can join our Dynamic
2.0 tier and chat with us and fellow listeners,
our Fantastic Four tier which gets you bonus
content each month, our X-Force tier that makes
you an executive producer of this podcast, or
our newest tier that lets you join our Dynamite
Podcast Network. If you can't join Patreon,
you can still support our show by signing up
for our e-newsletter. also at dynamicduel.com.
Or you can also rate the show on Apple podcasts,
Spotify, Podchaser, or on our website. As we
mentioned earlier, our next episode is going
to be episode 350, a big team duel between the
Doom Patrol and the Guardians of the Galaxy.
Can I wait for that? Doom Patrol is going down
and it is gonna be very satisfying. I just
imagine it's going to be like the most bizarre
team duel that we've ever had. I guarantee
it. For sure, for sure. But that does it for
this episode, we want to give a big thanks
to our executive producers Ken Johnson, John
Strausky, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Balcom, Mickey
Mathen-Geehan, Brandon Estregard, Nathaniel
Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Nick Abonto, Austin Wisselowski,
AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, and Adam Spies
for helping make this podcast possible. And
we'll talk to you guys next week. Up up and
away, true believers. This episode was sponsored
by the card game, Chronicle AI. Get it at chronicleaigame.com.