This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
You have to pay for expedited shipping and no
one wants that. Visit dynamicduel.com and navigate
to the store to see the sweater or visit the
link in our show notes. Remember that 10% of
all proceeds in the months of November and December
will go to Stand Up to Cancer. And don't forget
if you're a patron of ours, you get 15% off
of our store for the months of November and
December. So support the show, support A Great
Cause, and get yourself or your family the
coolest Dynamic Duel merch for the holidays
this season. Not all heroes wear capes. Sometimes
they just buy really cool podcast merch. Again,
visit dynamicduel.com and click the store button.
On with the show.
duel Podcast, a weekly show where we review
superhero films and debate the superiority
between Marvel and DC by comparing their characters
in stat-based battle simulations. I'm Johnny
DC. And I'm his twin brother, Marvelous Joe.
And in this episode, we are reviewing season
one of Agatha, All Along. It's Marvel Television's
latest Disney Plus exclusive series that I
did not think I was going to enjoy, but damn
did I. Yet. It was really good, I can't wait
to talk about it later on this episode. Before
that, we're gonna break down the latest comic
book movie news to come out this past week,
of which we have two new trailers coming out
of Brazil's D23, and that was the Captain America
Brave New World official trailer and the Thunderbolts
D23 special look. So basically, this is an all
Marvel episode, this is in fact the third week
in which there is no DC news. So Jonathan, tell
me, why are you still a DC fan? Not gonna lie,
it's pretty hard right now. Um, after the Joker
just being so disappointed by that and not
really having too much to get excited for besides
Superman legacy. I need something. I need something.
Well, we are going to be reviewing the Penguin
next week. That's fair. People have said that's
really good. I haven't even watched a single
episode of it, but I can't wait to. Now that
I finished Agatha all along, I could do that.
As always guys, we list our segment times in
the episode description, so feel free to check
out the show notes if you want to skip ahead
to a particular topic. Our artificially intelligent
duel simulator AJ9K has a quick message for
our listeners, so listen up. Why hello there,
do you want even more from this podcast? Then
become a part of the dynamic duel community
on Patreon, where you can choose from three
tiers. The dynamic two-oh tier gives you access
to our Discord chat server. The fantastic four
tier gives you two bonus episodes each month,
and the X-Force tier makes you an executive
producer of this show. Lastly, the DynaMic
Podcast Network tier lets you create your own
podcast using this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny
and Joe will help you develop your show, provide
graphic support and consultation, and get you
simulation results. Pitch the twins your ideas
via email at dynamicduelpodcast at gmail.com.
Check it out at patreon.com slash dynamicduel.
Pip pip cheerio. Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone
who supports the podcast. Be sure to tune into
the other shows on the Dino Mike Podcast Network
this week, including Max Destruction, which
pits your favorite action heroes from film and
television against each other. This week, hosts
Scotty and Gilly are reviewing Who Framed Roger
Rabbit. On the Senjo World podcast, host Zachary
Hepburn speculates on fights between fan favorite
anime and manga characters. Zach is currently
abroad right now, so the show is momentarily
on hiatus. On the Console Combat podcast, hosts
John and Dean simulate battles between popular
video game characters. In yesterday's episode,
they find out who would win between Duke Nukem
and Sirius Sam. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or
click on the link in our show notes to listen
to all the shows in the DynaMic Podcast Network.
But with that out of the way, quick to the No
Prize! The No Prize is an award Marvel used
to give out to fans. Our version, the Dynamic
Duel No Prize, is a digital award we post on
Instagram for the person that we feel gave the
best answer to our question of the week. Last
week we asked you guys, out of Marvel Television's
upcoming projects revealed in the sizzle reel
that was released a couple weeks ago, Which
one gets you the most excited and why? And
this is coming off of the video that Marvel
put out that showed their 2025 Marvel television
and Marvel animation projects. We got a total
of two answers for this. It looks like you
guys are not very excited about what Marvel
television has to offer. I don't think that's
the case. I think maybe it was just a boring
question because people will be like, I'm obviously
excited for Daredevil. Like, obviously, like
next question. So that's probably our bad,
but. We do have a no prize winner to announce.
We did get an answer from Mason Thompson, but
it was not understandable due to the whispering,
bro. So if you call us, make sure that we can
understand you if the whole thing's gonna be
whispering. You don't have to keep us a secret,
it's fine, we're cool. Like people like us.
The winner of this week's no prize goes to
CJ Craft, who said? Hey guys, CJ Craft here.
Out of all the shit Marvel listed, I think
my favorite piece of shit has to be- Yeah, damn,
see?
a chance to introduce even new characters that
aren't in the comics that could become big
figures later.
Sorry about the shit jokes. I left out loud
when I first listened to this message because
I had forgotten that I was like, out of all
the shit that Marvel's putting out and you're
like, you're right, it is shit. But no, Eyes
of Wakanda is something that we didn't really
get a good look at until the sizzle reel came
out a couple of weeks ago that Marvel released.
And we had commented that it looks very unlike
anything else that Marvel Studios has produced.
It doesn't look like, you know, the What If
series or X-Men 97. It almost looks like a
Clone Wars style cartoon with that type of 3D
character animation. It looks really fascinating,
especially the content of the show, which is
going to give us a look at Black Panthers from
the past. Basically exploring Wakanda's rich
history and mythology. Yeah, honestly, the
MCU I feel like has created a version of Wakanda
that is cooler than anything I've ever personally
read in the comics. I'm not sure if you feel
the same way. But it'll be cool to see how
that culture has evolved into what it is in
the movies today. Yeah, Ryan Coogler and Marvel
Studios did such fantastic world building, both
in the original Black Panther film and its
sequel, Wakanda Forever. So it's nice to be
able to consistently revisit it, you know,
every few years. I think it's necessary just
as this piece of modern pop culture mythology.
It's unfortunate that the show is only going
to be four episodes, because I feel like we
could get a... a whole 10 episode series out
of that, but it's only going to be four episodes
and I'm sure they're going to be fantastic.
Do you think we'll get a chance to see more
of Namor? Ooh, that's a great question. I don't
know. I know that we're going to see Iron Fist.
Not the Danny Rand version, but like a historical
version of the Kun Lun warrior. Oh man, please
tie that into Shang-Chi. In fact, if they want
to include the Mandarin in there somewhere,
that'd be cool too. I'm totally fine with that.
That would be totally awesome. The show comes
out on August 6th, so we have a ways to wait
before we see it, but yeah, totally excited
for Eyes of Wakanda. So thanks CJ for calling
in with that answer, and congrats on winning
this week's No Prize. If you the listener want
a shot at winning your own No Prize, stay tuned
to later on this episode when we'll be asking
another Question of the Week. And now that
that's done, on to the news!
Alright, last week was the big D23 Brazil event,
which is a fan event held for fans down in
South America, and we got not only the official
trailer for Captain America Brave New World,
but we also got like an extended scene and new
trailer for the Thunderbolts film which was
called a D23 Brazil special look. They're both
on YouTube if you want to go check them out
because I'm excited to talk about them. First
off, the Captain America Brave New World trailer
was really cool, not for necessarily what it
showed because I don't know if it showed it.
too many new surprises compared to what the
teaser showed us. But I think stylistically,
this is one of the most interesting trailers
that Marvel has ever put out. It is very different
from any other trailer that Marvel has ever
done. You're right. It took itself very, very
seriously. Like there were no wisecracking jokes
here. There is barely even any music. And I
actually really liked that about this trailer.
Yeah, there were like a lot of ticking clocks
and stuff like that. Just really ratcheting
up the tension. It is a tense trailer. I wonder
if the movie is actually going to be as tense
as this preview is portraying it, but like
we didn't get like the standard Marvel Studios
branding or anything. It was just white on
black titles, which I thought was an interesting
departure for any Marvel Studios film. They're
really trying to make it look like something
unique here, something more akin to, you know,
the previous Captain America movies like Winter
Soldier and Civil War, but like ratcheted up
to 11. Like, I feel like they're selling this
as the end-all-be-all political action thriller.
Yeah, I noticed that about the branding as well.
It actually caught me off guard as I was watching
the trailer. I was like, wait, that's not the
Marvel font. What's going on here? They did
this, like interesting split screen effect for
most of the trailer. We were getting two simultaneous
shots on the left hand side of the screen and
the right hand side, which was an interesting
way to kind of keep diverting your attention.
But it kind of gave me Hulk 2003 film vibes
for the split screen effect. But at least it
made sense here. the way they did it. It wasn't
quite as clumsy as how that film did it back
in the day. Well, I love that movie, so I'm
not complaining. I don't think that'll be in
this movie. I think that's way too far of a
departure for Marvel's standard way of filming
things. But I think as far as a trailer goes,
it's pretty innovative. There were quite a few
major action shots that were shown here that
we haven't seen elsewhere. One of them was a
little bit weird because it was Sam Wilson's
Captain America. landing among a group of enemy
soldiers, like really, really fast, like fast
enough to break his legs. And then all of a
sudden, you know, the sonic boom from his landing
knocks them all back. Now, I can understand
Sam flying fast enough to breach the sound
barrier. But what I can't understand is him
basically crashing into the ground at that
speed and just being fine with it in the same
way that Iron Man would. Iron Man, at least
you can rationalize that his armor has some
kind of like inertial dampener to protect him.
But it's hard to make that same rationalization
for Captain America who's not wearing the same
armor. Right, yeah, he'd have to be wearing
like Vibranium boots or something like that,
which isn't outside the realm of possibility.
I guess not, I mean, he does have Vibranium
wings that were gifted to him by Wakanda, which
we saw in the Falcon and the Winter Soldier
television series. So you're right, it might
not be out of the realm of possibility, it
was kind of a badass line where he lands and
he looks at all the soldiers and he's like,
wait for it, and then the Sonic Boom comes.
That was pretty cool. Sam does have some pretty
fantastic moments here. Especially when we see
him in an aerial dogfight with a bunch of other
airplanes who fire missiles at him And he takes
all the missiles out with his shield that was
really badass and of course at the end of the
trailer we see him go up against Red Hulk and
Red Hulk freaking throws a flaming car at the
guy and Sam does a flip over it and slices
the car in half with his wings. I got chills.
That was awesome Yeah, I didn't realize his
wings were that sharp, but sure Sam's so cool
with the wings, I think that's the main appeal
that I get from watching these trailers. I hope
that the story is as compelling as they're
portraying it to be, but even if it doesn't
quite live up to my high expectations already,
I know at least we're gonna get some really
badass, quintessential, iconic Sam Wilson Captain
America action beats. The Captain America movies
have always been pretty good, so I'm not worried
at all. I think this is gonna be really good.
Well, we'll find out in just a few months.
The movie comes out on February 14th, Valentine's
Day. So, yeah, take your significant other
to go see Captain America and have a good time.
Yeah, no one's going to do that. It's not a
date movie. It's totally a date movie. Is it,
though? Every girl wants their guy to take
them to a Marvel Studios film. Trust me, bro.
It's a sure thing if you do. No, it's the farthest
thing from that, actually. Like who's Sam's
love interest in this? At least I know, man.
At least even Steve Rogers had a love interest.
Maybe it's the Sabra chick, the Israeli fighter
that they kind of retconned into being a member
of the Red Room program in the film. Maybe,
I don't know. Those two probably hook up in
the film, I bet you. Anyway, with that said,
that brings us to our question of the week.
What would you say is the best Marvel or DC
film to watch on Valentine's Day with your
significant other and why? And I'm not talking
about like new releases that come out in the
theaters. I'm talking about like you and your
SO are like sitting on the couch. You pop in
a Marvel or DC movie on Valentine's Day. What
is it and why? Record your answer at dynamicduel.com
by clicking on the red microphone button in
the bottom right hand corner of the screen,
which will prompt you to leave us a voicemail.
Your message could be up to 30 seconds long
and don't forget to leave your name in case
we include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a dynamic
duel no prize that we'll post to Instagram.
Be sure to answer before November 16th. Moving
on to the Thunderbolts D23 Brazil special look.
This was such a badass preview for the Thunderbolts
movie. Just what I thought I couldn't be more
excited for the movie. We get this extended
look at an action scene where The Thunderbolts
are riding in Red Guardian's limo, escaping
from an armored convoy, and the Winter Soldier
shows up and basically just fucking annihilates
the entire convoy in spectacular style, straight
out of like a Terminator movie. It is so damn
cool. Even Red Guardian himself is like, oh,
it's the Winter Soldier. He's so cool. It looks
hilarious. It looks action packed. I loved
everything about that scene. Yeah, I love how
the Red limo they were driving was like Red
Guardian's own personal, like Red Guardian mobile.
Yeah. I like how one of the defensive maneuver
switches he clicked on was basically just like
mood lighting in the backseat with Genuine's
My Pony playing. That was actually a pretty
good comedic beat. But there was some other
great music in this trailer. We got Possum Kingdom
by the Toadies and that's following the previous
trailers whereas My Mind by the Pixies. So like
Thunderbolts is just firing on all cylinders
when it comes to the music in these previews.
I mean, are you surprised? Because like the
Suicide Squad films had amazing soundtracks.
What does the Suicide Squad have shit to do
with shit? Again, this is basically Marvel's
Suicide Squad, so I'm saying they're, you know,
trying to really live up to that. I think you're
just way off base here, and I think you need
to shut your mouth about the Suicide Squad as
it pertains to the Thunderbolts. Okay? Oh,
that's cute. You think you could tell me what
to do.
As Possum Kingdom is playing, we get some cool
beats, just basically showing the... quirky
attitude of the Thunderbolts cast of characters.
I really like Yelena Belova. Like Florence
Pugh has really stood out as this truly hilarious
deadpan character out of the Black Widow film.
Her Yelena is awesome. I just like how she could
tell a character like the Contessa to eat shit,
you know? Just that delivery alone was perfection.
Yeah, her deliveries and David Harbour's line
deliveries as the Red Guardian, also like perfect
comedic timing. Actually, a lot of the cast
was pretty comedic, even John Walker. Which
was surprising. Yeah. I really love when Red
Guardian asks Bucky, like, what kind of super
soldier serum he got. He was like, I don't
know, the regular kind, the Hydra kind. And
he's like, ooh, Hydra. So fancy. So good. Another
great gag from the trailers is how they're underselling
the sentry by just calling him Bob and just
making him look like this regular guy who shows
up wearing scrubs. You know, it's just so unassuming.
And I hope it's a surprise for a lot of audiences
just how powerful he ends up being as the Sentry.
I don't know why, but for the first time in
this trailer, I finally understood why people
are saying that this is actually going to be
like the Avengers and that's the whole reason
for the asterisk. Because Yelena bought Avengers
Tower, so she's probably making her own Avengers
team. So while she dubs them the Avengers, you
know, Alexi is calling them something different.
Yeah, Red Guardian is calling them the Thunderbolts
and he thinks it's a really cool name. No one
else thinks that though, which is also pretty
damn funny. Really can't wait for this movie.
It comes out May 2nd, just a few months after
Captain America Brave New World.
That does it for all the Marvel shit from this
episode. Now let's go ahead and move on to
the main event, I guess, which is more Marvel
shit. Our review of Marvel Television's Disney
Plus exclusive series, Agatha, all along.
Alright, Agatha All Along was created by Jack
Schafer, the same creator behind WandaVision.
The show serves as a direct sequel to that 2021
series and it stars Kathryn Hahn, Joe Locke,
and Aubrey Plaza. It was released around the
Halloween season this year and I thought it
did a fantastic job continuing the spooky vibes
established in Marvel's other Halloween projects.
like the Halloween episode of Wandavision, the
Werewolf by Night special presentation, and
the upcoming Marvel Zombie show set to release
around Halloween of 2025. Agatha all along
serves as a strong backstory for Agatha Harkness,
as well as a strong introduction for Wiccan,
aka Billy Maximoff, an original member of the
Young Avengers team. If you want to learn more
about either Agatha or Wiccan, feel free to
listen to our duel episodes that feature those
characters. It's not necessary to know the comics
backstories, but I do feel that you get more
out of these shows and films when you see how
they compare to the source material. I will
say that Agatha all along has made the character
Agatha more prominent and interesting character
than she ever was in the comics. And I really
had a lot of fun with this series. I think
it was an even better show than it needed to
be considering Agatha is a lesser character
from the books. And there are some like truly
pause worthy twists in the show. in that the
twist happens and you pause it and you're like,
what? And for those who haven't watched the
series, I got to say, don't spoil anything for
yourself by continuing to listen to the spoiler
review. I recommend the show. Trust me, it's
worth watching if you're even the slightest
bit interested in the MCU. So there's your spoiler
warning. Yeah, the thing I like most about
this series actually is how unpredictable it
was like. The show just gets better and better
as each episode progresses. And with all the
twists and turns that end up being revealed
toward the end, it actually gives a pretty solid
rewatchability factor. Yeah, yeah, the twists,
man. I mean, like WandaVision had some great
twists, you know, like with the revelations
of what was happening to Westview, who Agnes
was, things like that here. You know, there
were great twists involving Billy and who he
was and what he could do with chaos magic,
apparently. But. I think the best twist that
made my mouth hang open for a solid hour was
the revelation of what the Witch's Road actually
was. We spent this entire show thinking it
was one thing, only to realize that it was just
a song. Like a little children's song that
Agatha's son would sing to pass the time as
they spent their lives as wanderers. It was
like the most innocent, pure, simple thing that
in time became a legend. which in turn was
used for something so sinister, which in turn
manifested into something so fantastic and
magical. I think the show's concept of the Witch's
Road is cool, you know, like manifesting the
hero's journey as a sort of Wizard of Oz meets
Cabin in the Woods type setting, but the show's
origin and evolution of the Witch's Road, I
think- It was pure brilliance. Oh, that was
amazing. It was a fantastic reveal and it really
endeared me to the character of Agatha Harkness.
Oh for sure, yeah. The twists though, they also
come with some caveats. I think some of this
cleverness is also where the show stumbles.
Like the idea of the road complete with its
lethal trials requiring complex potion making,
spell casting, spiritual warfare, tarot reading,
and botanomancy? You know, that's a solid concept,
right? They're all great challenges that require
skill and they have fatal consequences. So the
stakes are there. But the road reconceived
as an accidental manifestation of chaos magic
from a kid who's, you know, like a relative
newcomer to the world of witchcraft. That's
a little bit harder to swallow. Like at one
point, Jennifer Kale, the witch played by Sashir
Zamata, hallucinates that she's being drowned
by a doctor she used to work with. And when
you look back on it, you're like, but. The
road isn't real, it's just Billy's manifestation.
So that's kind of weird what's going on there.
Same thing goes for Alice seeing her mother
kill herself. And I don't think the drama surrounding
the road would hold up to much scrutiny. Like
don't think about it too hard, otherwise you'll
be like, wait. And I'm pretty sure any question
regarding the road can be answered with, because
it's magic, stupid. But I'm not positive the
show would do as well on a rewatch because
of that. There's bound to be, I think, some
plot holes or more general weirdness derived
from some of these twists. I disagree. Because
of the revelation that the whole thing was
created by Wiccan, because he's psychic. He
could read people's minds. So it made sense
to me that the road was able to tap into that
to learn people's greatest fears. So you think
that somehow Billy's subconscious was able to
divine the correct manner of laying out a tarot
deck? Well, I think his subconscious created
the entire thing. So absolutely. Sure. I mean,
yeah, again, I think that answer is in line
with because it's magic. Stupid. I think it's
slightly better than that. Well, I'll have you
rewatch the show then and then see if there's
any strangeness that comes out of the whole
concept there. You don't know my life. Maybe
I will. Maybe I will rewatch it. Actually, I'm
going to watch the penguins. I'm not. I do
plan on rewatching Agatha all along, probably
next Halloween season, because my wife really
enjoyed it, too. I think one of the biggest
appeals for me was the impression that I got
while watching it that everyone involved, from
the cast, to the writers, to the set designers,
the wardrobe team, the musical team, they all
just had a blast making it. The project really
seems like a director's dream, juggling these
multifaceted characters, putting them on a
roller coaster journey, transforming the look
of each trial with beautifully designed practical
sets and costumes and watching it all unfold.
The show is varied. in a way that few other
Marvel projects can be. And I found myself transported
in a way that can only really be described
as movie magic. Like forget that the show actually
dealt with fantasy magic. I'm talking about
the transport of nature of well-made fun cinema.
Oh, this thing was unbelievably well-made.
The cinematography, fantastic. Like it was movie
quality. Yeah, especially when you're going
from settings like the opening scene. that's
based off a crime drama. It felt like you were
watching an episode of The Killing as they stumble
upon the body. And then, you know, you go to
like the little big lies type setting of the
coastal home to the Friday the 13th style of
the cabin. I thought it was all fantastic. It
does feel like a dream project. Yeah, absolutely.
There were more amazing shots in this series
than there are in most Marvel movies, I would
say. I agree with you, but also try to be respectful.
No, no, it will not be, I refuse. I have to
imagine that the show creator Jack Schaeffer
was pleased with the end result of her vision,
which I think was more successfully executed
here than in Wandavision, which I had some
frustrations with if you remember from that
review. But Jack Schaeffer truly has a knack,
I'll say, for writing series that aren't bound
to one style or genre. Like we saw in Wandavision,
where many of those episodes recreated classic
sitcoms across the decades. And we saw it here
with Agatha all along with things like the opening
scene, like I mentioned, or how the road would
manifest each trial as a new setting. In another
comparison to WandaVision, Agatha all along,
I think, also did a great job of balancing these
wide emotional turns, going from depressingly
sad scenes of loss and grief to horrific and
unsettling moments to laugh out loud comedy.
It was just well balanced all around. Oh, 100%.
Yeah, the story was just incredible. for this
series. I really, really enjoyed the story.
I found it entertaining all the way through,
particularly with the escape room type challenges
for each episode. That was so brilliant. Yeah,
it was fun to try to figure out what clues there
were in the room and then seeing them solve
it and what they got to do. They felt just right
in terms of difficulty level and the skill
that it would take to actually pass the trial.
Yeah, and in regards to that, I also really
liked the lore that they developed for witches
in this show. Like for there to be a protection
witch that, you know, is symbolized by fire
and a potion witch that symbolized by water,
a divination witch that's symbolized by air
and a green witch that's symbolized by, you
know, plants and stuff like that. Freaking is
this like Avatar? This is cool. What did you
think of the actual song, The Ballad of the
Witch's Road? It was cool. I liked the different
versions of it. It's catchy, as was Agatha Lalong
in WandaVision. Yeah, I got to say, even now,
during this review in the back of my head, I'm
thinking down, down the road, down the way.
It's just on repeat in my head. It's an earworm.
I especially like the chant version, but, you
know, the rocking out protection spell version
was also pretty good. That was pretty fucking
cheesy. Not going to lie. But I don't like it.
It's fine. I liked it. I liked it because it
was a spell that they were casting. It was a
song that served as a means of protection for
her daughter. I liked that other things were
going on as they were just really cheesing
it up. You know, like that demon monster curse
thing that was terrifying. Yeah, that was pretty
scary. And again, the lore behind that song
and how that developed, like who did you say
wrote this? Jack Schaeffer. This Jack Schaeffer
guy, he needs to do more Marvel stuff. Jack
Schaeffer is a chick, bro. Jacqueline. Oh, shit.
But let's go ahead and talk about the characters
that she developed for the show in our character
breakdown. Starting with Agatha Harkness, played
by Catherine Han. On the very first episode,
I wasn't quite sure if Catherine Han was phoning
in a weak performance, or if she was a good
enough actress to act like she was phoning
in a weak performance. And luckily, right when
she broke out of her spell by the end of the
episode, I realized it was the latter. She was
fantastic in the show and as Agatha, I think
she's been able to really showcase the full
range of her acting prowess in tackling drama,
comedy, horror, action, like in her opening
fight against Rio. And she can go from scenery
chewing rage to the subtleness, sadness in her
eyes, to hysterical laughter. It's really a
beast of a role that I think any actress would
cherish and I think Han nailed it in a way
that few other actors could. I will admit I
did not actually care for her performance for
a majority of the series. I thought she was
like hamming it up way more than any of the
other actors were. But in hindsight, that may
just be because she was aware of more of what
was going on than other actors were. So she
was trying to play along with them as it were.
Yeah, totally. From the get-go, she realized
that this was a sham manifestation basically.
So I think all of the information definitely
informed her performance. I am convinced that
she's going to get Emmy nominated again for
this role just like she did in Wandavision.
I would not be surprised if that happened. Agatha's
journey in this show was mostly about her acquisition
of power as it has been for centuries. You know,
she started out in the 17th century as a young
witch studying black magic for which her mom's
coven tried to kill her. And she went down
this really dark path, even apparently communing
with the entity of death, which seems pretty
damn dark. But her emotional arc really began
with the birth and death of her son Nicholas,
who awakened this caring side of Agatha that
she had never really experienced before, a
side that was just utterly decimated when her
son passed away tragically by her side. From
there, we saw her choose to live only for herself,
reverting to her main aim of amassing power
and studying dark magic. She even acquired the
Darkhold we know at some point, and she was
a good villain in WandaVision, interesting protagonist
here in that once again we get to see her open
up a bit again when she encounters Billy Maximoff
who reminds her of and she perhaps initially
believes to be her son Nicholas. You know, it's
a very vulnerable time for her not just emotionally
but also physically because she's powerless
and she has enemies that are coming for her.
So the audience connects with her in that regard
but she also shatters that connection with
her callous disregard for the
Whereas the viewer you're equal parts interested
and repulsed and amused by and feel sorry for
her throughout the course of the show. But in
the very end, she finally settles into the
mentor role that she's always served in the
comics. And I think it was such a fun and fascinating
journey to see her get to that point, being
the mentor. Absolutely. Like I said earlier,
I didn't really care for the character of Agatha
until the final episode. when we learned about
her past and saw what she has become. It was
a fantastic character arc. I actually really,
really like her arc. But I also think that because
of the nature of her character throughout the
series, Catherine Hunn was really fortunate
to have a strong supporting cast to really
pick up the slack where the story didn't need
the character. Yeah, it was a great ensemble
cast, fantastic. One of the best ensemble casts
I think you can get for a series about a coven
of witches, honestly. But also great in the
cast was Wiccan, aka Billy Maximoff played
by Joe Locke. I knew nothing of Joe Locke before
the show. I had heard good things about him
from the Netflix show Heartstopper, and I got
the impression a lot of people were happy with
his casting as Billy Maximoff. But I remember
not being that happy. Like in a very shallow
manner, I'm ashamed to admit. I thought he didn't
look anything like the child actor who played
him in WandaVision and Doctor Strange and the
Multiverse of Madness. I feel like such a fucking
asshole now, not only because Joe Locke is a
wonderfully charismatic actor who I thought
did an exceptional job in the role, but also
because the show itself did such an incredible
job in rationalizing how Billy came back and
why he looks different now. Oh, yeah, absolutely.
I love the way they rationalized how Billy came
to be this William guy, because it's really
confusing in the comics, I feel like. And it's
still a little complex here, but I think a
little bit less confusing. Yeah, in the comics,
basically. Billy and Tommy were manifestations
of magic that ended up being shards of Mephisto,
the devil's soul. And when he pulled them back
into himself, you know, they ended up dying,
but they got reincarnated, you know, years
later and raised by different families. Here
is a little bit more interesting in that the
reincarnation happens to William Kaplan the
moment he dies. Stan And he dies the same moment
that Billy essentially dies. Ben Right, exactly.
Really well done. I think a lot of fans of
the Wiccan character will be pleased with how
this all panned out. I'll say in regards to
my initial reactions to his casting, I don't
think that the marketing of Agatha all along
did Joe Locke any favors, but I am happy to
say that I would be thrilled to see more Wiccan
in the MCU, hopefully in an upcoming Young Avengers
film or series. Oh yeah, I would agree with
the marketing for the show. I definitely felt
like it was outside my demographic. I was not
looking forward to watching or reviewing the
show, I would say, but I'm really glad I did.
Because honestly... I liked it more than WandaVision.
I liked it more than a lot of other MCU shows.
Yeah, I think I liked it about as much as Loki
season two. I think I liked it more than that.
Really? Oh, that's surprising actually. Yeah.
Back to Wiccan, his arc here had almost as
many twists and turns as Agatha's did. First
he's William Kaplan celebrating his Bar Mitzvah,
then he dies, coming back as Billy, but he's
amnesiac. We see his journey to Agatha, his
unconscious use of chaos magic to create the
Witch's Road. all to reach out and find his
twin brother Tommy, which I thought was a really
touching journey for him. And I'd like to think,
Jonathan, that if we both died and you reincarnated
that you'd risk your life to find and reincarnate
my soul too, right? Right? I mean, I think I
would move on eventually. You piece of shit.
Consider your ass haunted. Nah, okay, fine with
that actually. We'll be like brother voodoo.
Yeah, that'd be cool actually. That'd be cool.
But thematically, yeah, Billy's arc was about
self-discovery and reunion. I think the story
hit those themes spot on. I thought he showed
true marks at the end of being a hero in his
bravery, in the face of adversity, his willingness
to sacrifice, his remorse over his perceived
moral failures, his loyalty to his companions.
He's a fantastic new addition to the MCU. And
maybe him and his brother Speed will show up
in Vision Quest. Who knows? I'm really hoping
they do Tommy as much justice as they did Billy
for this series. Let's talk about death, aka
Rio played by Aubrey Plaza. Now, Aubrey Plaza
is a captivating and really talented actress.
But I'm not entirely sure she even did any
acting here. I think legitimately she just stumbled
on the set a few times, interacted with the
other performers, just being her normal, regular
self, shepherding the dead into the afterlife
like she do, you know? That is Aubrey Plaza,
right? That's her in a nutshell. Like how can
you get better casting for the character of
death than Aubrey Plaza? She's so deadpan,
so mysterious, and yeah, she's kind of been
typecast as the sarcastic dry persona, but
I think it really works well here. Like if you've
ever seen her chameleon-esque portrayal as
Lenny Busker in Legion, or her heavily dramatic
side in Emily the Criminal, or her nuanced
role in Ingrid Goes West, you know the girl
can act. She has range. But with Death, it
seems more like she was having fun here, you
know, getting to try some action heavy stuff
in the first episode, and, you know, getting
to play a witch and the character of Death.
Yeah, I didn't know what was going on with her
character, but when the reveal came that she
was Marvel's Death, that was one of those moments
where I had to pause it and just be like, holy
shit! My wife was like, what? What's the big
deal? I was like, this is Death. Like, this
is the Death that Thanos loved. in Marvel Comics
and he worshipped. The fact that they changed
it so that it was a relationship with Agatha
kind of levels up Agatha in my book. That's
true. Yeah, they took the death persona, who
historically has been romantically linked to
Thanos in the comics. Although, you know, that
romance is unrequited and they shifted it to
Agatha, who is a dark magic witch. And conceptually,
I actually kind of like that more. Like death
as a personification seems more at home in the
realm of fantasy magic more than, you know,
the sci-fi bent of Thanos's cosmic stories.
Yeah, 100% I agree. How weird though would
it be if Aubrey Plaza's death character fell
in love with Deadpool? Because that happened
in the comics. That was kind of like a gag in
the Deadpool books where death fell in love
with Deadpool because he's like this unattainable
figure for her because he can't die, right?
And so like Thanos beats the shit out of Deadpool
and they kind of like compete for her love.
Could you see Aubrey Plaza vying for Ryan Reynolds
Deadpool in a future Marvel project? 100 percent.
I don't even know how that's a question. Absolutely.
They should put out like a Valentine's Day
special with those characters. That'd be hilarious.
I also got to say, I love how they leaned into
Aubrey Plaza's Hispanic heritage by portraying.
Death's true form with this Dia de los Muertos
style design, those elements I think really
brought an interesting take to the more basic
skeleton in a robe look that Death has in the
comics. Yeah, it's like La Catrina without
the giant hat. Yeah, exactly. So cool. The whole
show is pretty diverse, right? I actually like
that about it. Yeah, including Jennifer Cale
played by Sashir Zamata. I've been a fan of
Sashir's from her days at Saturday Night Live.
She's a stand-up comedian. So I initially thought
that Jennifer Cale was gonna be like hilarious
in this show. She wasn't, but I'll say that
I was impressed with Sashir's capacity for dramatic
acting, like able to convey horror, anger,
sadness, all with authenticity. Jennifer Cale
in the comics is a sorceress who is part of
the Cale family whose line was cursed with harboring
the spirit of vengeance. So Jennifer's aunt
is Naomi Cale, who married Barton Blaze and
had Johnny Blaze. who would later become Ghost
Rider. So Jennifer Kale is Ghost Rider's first
cousin and in the books is a powerful witch
in her own right, primarily known for her adventures
with Man-Thing and Jennifer Kale has actually
even been a member of the Midnight Suns. That's
really cool to hear. I was wondering how many
of these characters were actually from the comics.
And I'm glad it wasn't just- All of them. Oh,
all of them? All of them. Bad ass. Including
the Wu. aka Alice Wu Gulliver played by Ali
An. Now, I've never seen Ali perform before,
but I liked her in the show. Like Jennifer
Kail, her character is a hero in the comics
called The Wu, who is a supernatural police
detective in China. She's the daughter of the
former supernatural hero called August Wu of
the Coral Shore. And I thought it was pretty
interesting here how they turned the mom's
superhero name into the name of her band. The
band was called Coral Shore. I thought that
was a neat Easter egg. But I am really bummed
that they killed Alice off so quickly because
she is a neat character. In the books, she inherited
some of her mom's magic which gave her this
red streak in her hair. But she uses her magic
more indirectly. She imbued her regular police
gun with supernatural abilities. And I think
there was a lot of potential there for the
character to maybe not headline her own show,
but maybe show up in future Marvel projects
as a police officer. We never know. Maybe she
could come back as a ghost or something like
that. I do have to say I love the fact that
they're bringing in these obscure characters
because they didn't need to. But it just shows
that the showrunners are fans of the source
material. Well, I mean, there's certainly interpretations
of the characters from the comics, right? But
yeah, at least they're pulling inspirations
from the books. You love to see it. Yeah. Including
Lillia Calderu, who's played by Patty fucking
Lepone. How the hell did the casting director
land Patty Lepone for this show? No idea who
she is. She is a massively renowned Broadway
star. Fantine in Les Mis. She was the Evita.
She was Mrs. Lovett in Sweeney Todd, Norma
DeMond in Sunset Boulevard, Joanne in Company.
She's probably one of the most celebrated theater
actresses of all time. And the fact that she
was cast in this was actually a big deal in
those theater circles. Like my wife lost her
shit when she realized it was her. And I imagine
it's kind of the equivalent of like when Marlon
Brando joined Superman or when Ian McKellen
became Magneto. It was just kind of surprising
and cool that these renowned actors are not
like slumming it in the genre, but like they're
down to do this more fantasy adventure geek
level stuff. I think it adds legitimacy to superhero
projects. She was probably one of my favorite
characters. So I'm glad to hear that she has
like a fan base behind her. That's incredible.
Yeah, she portrayed the character magnificently
in the comics. Lilia Calderou is related to
Baron Mordo, the Doctor Strange villain. She's
actually his niece, and they're both descendants
of Cogliostro. Lilia is the witch queen of the
gypsies. She's a very minor character, I'll
say, probably the most minor out of all these
comic book characters. I think that they probably
should have gone with a more prominent witch
from the comics, like Topaz or something like
that. I think Patti LuPone could have done well
as that character as well. I'm not complaining.
I thought she did a fantastic job. Are you jealous
that- Marvel was able to land such awesome
casting for their projects, whereas like DC
scrapes the bottom of the barrel most times.
The fuck are you talking about? You just mentioned
Marlon Brando. How many Marvel projects has
Marlon Brando worked on? That was in the 1970s,
man. Oh, I'm sorry. And? It was a long time
ago. And? I'm talking about now. Who cares?
Where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
DynaMic Podcast Network presents Console Combat,
where video game legends brawl every Monday.
Comic Book Titans smash every Tuesday, Max Destruction,
where TV and action heroes battle every Wednesday,
and Sendro World, where anime champions clash
every Thursday. Join us as we speculate on
the matches and, armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge victorious.
Visit dynamicpodcast.com where we settle the
debate and settle the score.
Let's go ahead and move into our episode highlights.
Episode 1 was called Seekest Thou the Road.
Still stuck in the spell that the Scarlet Witch
cast on her at the end of WandaVision, Agatha
Harkness sees herself as a police detective
in a television crime drama called Agnes of
Westview where she investigates the murder of
a Jane Doe. She's visited by Rio Vidal, whom
Agatha sees as an FBI agent inquiring about
the case and her true identity. After chasing
and apprehending a teenage thief who broke into
her home, Agatha's false reality falls apart.
The spell breaks as Agatha realizes that Jane
Doe is the deceased body of the Scarlet Witch.
Coming to in her home, Agatha finds herself
powerless. Formerly protected from her enemies
through her possession of the Darkhold, Agatha
is attacked by Rio. She successfully bargains
to halt the conflict until she gets her powers
back and discovers the bound and gagged teen
thief in her closet. the crime drama on, I think
it was AMC that was inspired by a Danish television
crime drama. I saw like the final episode of
it. Oh, why would you do that? I don't know.
It was on. I was waiting for The Walking Dead.
Oh man, it was such a good show. And there
was such a great twist at the end of that episode
where the mystery is finally solved. Fantastic
show. If you haven't seen it, you got to watch
it. It's one of television's best crime dramas
ever. And I loved how they really weren't subtle
about their homage to that show in particular.
with the opening scene of episode one here.
Yeah, it was all right. I have to imagine that
upon rewatching it, the whole thing becomes
a lot more humorous because you just have to
imagine what was really going on outside of
Agatha's head as she was talking with everyone.
I love that twist that they did later on when
they showed how Billy was actually interacting
with her during the whole interrogation room
scene and stuff like that. That was great.
Yeah, I like the moment in the second episode
where she was like, let's get in the car. and
her car turns out to be like this makeshift
thing in her living room. Just imagining her
walking around all day doing that kind of stuff
is just hilarious. Yeah, yeah. Episode 2 is
called Circle Sown with Fate, Unlock Thy Hidden
Gate. The teenager reveals he freed Agatha
from the Scarlet Witch's spell and begs her
to take him to the Witch's Road, a legend that
allegedly grants its travelers what they desire
most. Agatha agrees to the idea in order to
get her powers back, and learns that the teen's
identity is hidden from witches through a sigil.
Needing a coven for the journey, she and teen
recruit Lillia Calderou, a divination witch
representing the air element, Jennifer Kael,
a potions witch representing the water element,
Alice Wu Gulliver, a protection witch representing
the fire element, and her neighbor, Sharon
Davis to stand in for a green witch to represent
the earth element. While singing the ballad
of the witches' road to open the portal to their
journey, the Salem Seven come after Agatha.
Though the door to the road doesn't initially
open, prompting Agatha to antagonize the coven
into attacking her, a doorway finally appears
and the coven, along with Teen, flee into it
to escape the approaching Salem 7. One thing
I didn't understand in the show is why Billy
was deceptive about his true intentions. Like,
why would he say that he needed power if what
he was really looking for was his brother? That's
a great question. I think maybe he didn't want
to clue her into the idea that he was the Scarlet
Witch's son, because in doing research on Agatha
Harkness, he probably would have known that
they fought against each other, and maybe he
thought he might put himself in danger by revealing
his true identity. But then again, he did reveal
his identity. It was just hidden by the sigil.
So, great question. And I think that's probably
one of those things that doesn't hold up on
the rewatch, because... The real reason why
he didn't do it is because the writers didn't
want to clue the audience into the idea that
this was Billy. Even though everyone knew even
before the show aired? Right, exactly. But
that's the only rationalization you could give
to your question. The Ballad of the Witches
Road song here was superbly done. Like, when
they started going in round with the song,
I was getting fucking chills, man. That chant
was awesome. What did you think of the Salem
7? Terrifying? Absolutely terrifying. They're
like ringwraiths. Yeah, I really like that
because they're not like that in the comics
at all. They're more like a ragtag group of
sorcerers that happen to be the children of
Nicholas Scratch. But here, yeah, they were
like ringwraiths and they were like represented
by various woodland animals like a fox, a crow,
snake, owl, rat. The one downside, I think,
is that they were more of an abstract threat
than a tangible one because they never caught
up to the group. You know, they never actually
got to fight the Salem Seven, which is kind
of disappointing. I mean, I will say that Lillia
Caldru took them out in the most badass way
possible. Oh, yeah. But you were kind of expecting
this climactic showdown that never really happened.
Well, by the time we got the reveal that she
was death, I was kind of like, OK, she's the
big bad. I understand now. I didn't really
mind the way they were taken out because, like
you mentioned, I thought that was really cool.
So I was fine with it. They served their purpose
in being spooky. They didn't appear too many
times in the show itself. So yeah. Yeah. Episode
3 was called The Many Miles of Tricks and Trials.
The coven enter the first trial on the Witch's
Road, a coastal home with a bottle of wine
that poisons the group. The coven race to find
ingredients for a cure to be brewed by Jennifer
Kael, but face hallucinations from their past
that hinder their efforts. Teen learns the
rumor that Agatha traded her son Nicholas Scratch
for the Darkhold, and Agatha sees a vision
of her former child's bassinet. The house floods
as the final ingredients are put together.
but the coven is unable to deliver the potion
in time to Mrs. Davis and she dies. The group
escapes the coastal home back onto the Witch's
Road. Talk about setting the stakes. I was
actually shocked when Sharon Davis died. Oh
yeah, absolutely. The show did a fantastic
job setting the stakes, so much so that I didn't
even believe she was dead initially. Because
I was like, there's no way they're going to
be killing off characters in the show, but
sure enough, they did it. Yeah, and I thought
Agatha's callousness was played to great comedic
effect when she was like, who's Sharon? I was
like, jeez. And then the episode ended. They
kept that up all the way to the very last episode,
too. That was great. Yeah. She was like, who?
One thing I do think is interesting just in
hindsight is that when Agatha pulled back the
bassinet cover, there was the dark hold, but
that's not really what happened. So that was
a manifestation of what Billy thought happened.
Right. As opposed to. You know, his powers
reading Agatha's mind and then manifesting something
that was more in line with what she would actually
fear. I wonder why he never read her mind. I
don't think he had good control over his ability.
But apparently his subconscious did, right?
Again, just all the weirdness. I'm telling
you, the revelation of the road being a manifestation
of Billy's unconscious is a bigger issue than
you think it is. Hmm. Okay. Episode 4 is called,
If I Can't Reach You, Let My Song Teach You.
In it, Agatha and the Coven decide to summon
a new Green Witch to take Mrs. Davis' place,
and they end up bringing Rio onto the road.
The next trial manifests as a 1970s recording
studio where the Wu family curse manifests as
a demon that attacks and nearly kills Tein.
In order to defeat the demon, the Coven is forced
to play Alice's mother's rendition of the ballad,
which is revealed to be a protection spell.
With the demon and the curse vanquished, the
group go back to the road and heal Tein. Rio
reveals that she used to love Agatha, but hurt
her deeply when doing her job. Privately, she
also reveals to Agatha that Teen is not her
son. It was at this point where, I know you
liked the Ballad of the Witches Road song,
but where it kind of grew old for me. I was
like, oh, okay, we get it. Are you gonna sing
it like every episode or what? They only sing
it twice. This was the second time. Well, I
guess they sing it again in the final episode
as we see it evolve through time. Although
by that point, I was just so caught up in how
the song even developed and why it became so
important to the series as a whole that I was
much more forgiving of it. Yeah. I think the
weirdness regarding Billy's manifestation here
manifested in that Billy almost died. You know,
he created something that nearly killed him
by knocking him through the window. Oh, that's
true. Yeah. If he was like unconscious or dying,
why was the road even still there maybe? That's
a good question. I'm trying to think if there
were any instances where the Scarlet Witch
was unconscious during the events of Westview,
but you have to imagine that she slept at some
point. So I think the Chaos Magic reality still
operates when the Spellcaster is not conscious.
That's fair. Episode five was called Darkest
Hour, Wake Thy Power. The Coven flee the Salem
Seven by enchanting broomsticks for themselves.
Though they managed to escape, the road's magic
forces them down to the next trial, a cabin
in the woods. They're forced to use a Ouija
board to summon the ghost of Agatha's mother,
whom she killed back in 1693 when her magic
absorption power first manifested. The ghost
possesses Agatha, who attacks the group and
claims the way to pass the trial is to continue
on the road without her daughter, claiming
she was born evil. The ghost possesses Agatha
again, prompting Alice to blast her with fire
magic, dispelling the ghost but activating Agatha's
absorption power which drains Alice of her
magic and kills her. Back on the road, Teen
gets upset with Agatha and claims Witchcraft
should not be about killing. Agatha cryptically
remarks that he is so much like his mother,
prompting his magic abilities to manifest as
he forces Agatha and the rest of the coven
to sink into the mud. I think the weirdness
here with the Chaos Magic reality manifestation
was, first of all, you know, the killing of
Alice, which I think played into the end scene
pretty well because Billy's over here telling
Agatha that Witchcraft is not about killing,
and she looks at him and she's like, are you
sure? he was the cause of Alice's death in
that moment. Well, he wasn't though, because
Agatha was responsible for that. Yeah, but
Billy was the reason that her mother's ghost
was there and took over her body, which led
to Alice protecting Agatha. So, he was indirectly
the cause of it. That's true. Same thing with
Mrs. Davis's death. So, Billy manifested Agatha's
mom's ghost, which possessed her. Yes. Okay,
interesting. Well, then was the Ouija board
real? None of it was real, man. Yeah, okay.
I'm kind of confused now because like the Ouija
board was saying like death was among them
and death was among them But he didn't know
that at the time. It's wild. I think the initial
Ouija boards Message was actually fake. It was
Agatha Harkness fucking around. She said death
was among them I think is kind of like a jest
which Rio laughed at but then you know She
pretended to be mrs. Davis come back from the
dead. That was weird. That was stupid It was
unnecessary, it kind of felt like a moment of
filler, I think. I will admit, when the Ouija
board spelled Mrs. Hart, I could have sworn
it spelled Mr. Shart.
I thought the same thing because you know, the
subtitles were reciting the letters as they
were naming them and written out, it looked
like Mr. Chart. So, I was like, what the hell
is that? That was hilarious. Episode 6 was called
Familiar by Thy Side. In a flashback, William
Kaplan from Eastview celebrates his bar mitzvah
where he encounters Lillia the fortune teller.
She has a premonition of his future casting
a sigil on him to protect him from other witches.
During the ride home, William and his family
get into a car accident at the same time the
Scarlet Witch removes her hex over Westview,
erasing her twin boys Billy and Tommy from
existence. As William dies from the accident,
Billy's soul survives by reincarnating into
his body, and he wakes up in the hospital with
no recollection of either of his previous lives,
but retaining the ability to read minds. Three
years later, Billy confesses to his boyfriend
that he believes he died that day and that his
reincarnation is tied into the Westview event.
He contacts Ralf Boner, whom Agatha previously
used as a puppet to investigate the Scarlet
Witch. Ralf reveals to Billy Agatha's existence
and status under Wanda's spell, and also tells
him about Wanda's son, making Billy realize
who he is. Looking into Agatha Harkness, he
learns of the witch's road and breaks into her
home to steal a personal artifact to break
her of the spell. Back in the present, Agatha
claws her way out of the mud as Billy destroys
the sigil hiding his identity. She deduces that
he's seeking his brother Tommy at the end of
the road, and the two continue on together.
Now, I think you and I both mentioned that
one of the biggest mistakes Marvel has done
was the whole misdirection with Evan Peters
as Pietro Maximoff in WandaVision. Correct,
yeah. The fact that they were able to play
up on that with Bonerific69, AKA Ralph Boner,
was, I thought, a stroke of genius. Yeah, I
mean, that didn't really have anything to do
with the previous misdirection. There are massive
issues, and I think it's one of Marvel's biggest
missteps in that subversion of casting the
guy from Days of Future Past in the same time
that they're introducing the multiverse concept.
But I talk all about that in our WandaVision
review. Here, Evan Peters continues playing
Ralph Boner for laughs, which I think are very
well earned. The character is just hilarious.
And I don't know if they've made Ralph Boner
yet a character in the comics, but if they
haven't, they need to. because he's just too
good to not be a regular fixture within Marvel.
No, I'm not going to lie. For a second I was
really hoping that he was actually Nicholas
Scratch and that was going to be like a big
reveal at the very end. That ended up not being
the case. But yeah, that's what I thought for
a while. Well, I thought Nicholas Scratch was
going to be the main bad guy considering that
he is Agatha Harkness's biggest antagonist
in the comic books. Her and her son do not get
along. But I like even more what they did here,
where he was just this sweet innocent kid. Yeah,
no, that was expertly done for sure. Episode
7 was called Death's Hand in Mine. Agatha and
Billy find the next trial, a castle tower where
they're made to read tarot cards in the proper
sequence or face impalement from swords falling
from the ceiling. They're discovered by Lillia
and Jennifer who find their way from under
the mud into the castle. with help from Lillia's
precognition which told her to find the secret
bookshelf into the room. Using her skills of
divination, Lillia uses the tarot deck to read
her own fortune. In her last card, she learns
that Rio is actually the personification of
death, and that she is the end of her road.
Lillia saves the rest of the coven who escape
the room just as the Salem 7 catch up to them.
She stays behind, using the tarot deck to invert
the castle tower and destroy the seven and herself.
This episode reminded me of Crisis on Infinite
Earths part one with the nonlinear narrative.
When you have a nonlinear narrative like this
episode, like the movie Memento, everything
is a twist, right? And I really like the way
that it played out here. I think this episode
is gonna get nominated for an Emmy. It would
be a shame if it doesn't. I'd be truly shocked
if it didn't win. This episode and the last
episode. were my two favorite episodes, but
I think this one edges out the last one just
barely. I really, really liked it. Yeah, Patti
LuPone gave a great performance. I really like
how the episode ended with her first divination
spell with her maestra. It was just poetry.
It was poetry. Really well written and beautifully
executed from everything to the castle tower
with the falling swords. That was so cool. Like
the costumes. There was a little bit of brand
synergy going there with like the Disney outfits
and whatnot, but I didn't mind it so much just
because it really fit the theme. and the room
itself was pretty dangerous and cool. Episode
8 was called, Follow Me My Friend to Glory at
the End. Alice follows Rio as Death into the
afterlife, after which Death reveals to Agatha
that she's there to take Billy, who broke the
rules of Death by reincarnating. Agatha wagers
with Death to get Billy to give himself up
in exchange for leaving her alone. Agatha, Billy,
and Jennifer continue along the road until
they come to their shoes left at the beginning,
realizing that the road is a loop. Confused
and enraged, the group argues until Billy puts
his shoes back on, transporting Kim into an
empty room for the final trial. He's joined
by the others, who have no clue how to proceed,
when it's revealed that Jennifer's powers were
bound a century ago by Agatha Harkness herself,
who was using witchcraft to make money at the
time. Jennifer performs an unbinding ritual,
regaining her magic and freeing herself from
the road. Agatha and Billy perform a spell
to locate Tommy's soul. and Billy places it
in the body of a boy who just drowned, also
freeing himself from the road. Agatha completes
the Earth Trial by growing a dandelion from
a seed, freeing herself from the road as well
but with no prize at the end. Death attacks
Agatha, but she is rescued by Billy, who is
now Wiccan, who gives her some of his power.
Together they fight Death, but realize they
can't win, and Death demands one of them to
return to the afterlife with her. Billy offers
to sacrifice himself, fulfilling Agatha's wager.
However, Agatha reneges on her plan, kissing
death and choosing to sacrifice herself instead.
Shocked, Billy goes home and comes to the realization
that the road was just a manifestation of his
own chaos magic. Great episode. I was really
confused as to how Jennifer realized that Agatha
was the one who put the Binding spell on her.
Uh, Agatha basically admitted it, putting it
out there herself. You think she would have
done that earlier when their lives were in
danger? That's... Actually, another great question,
and I think again, just part of the weirdness
of the whole twist that the road wasn't real.
Even if the road was real, Agatha could have
given her powers earlier. Yeah, that's true.
That's true. I think maybe it was more of a,
I don't want to get in trouble type thing, maybe.
I did think that the slow reveal in Billy's
room that he created the road was kind of cheap
considering we didn't really get good looks
at those things earlier in the show. I kind
of wish there was a scene that kind of explored
a little bit more earlier in the series. Well,
it was straight out of usual suspects, right?
It was the usual suspects moment. For sure.
Yeah. I don't know if that was a direct homage
or just a ripoff, but I kind of liked it. I
mean, I think it's an interesting reveal. I
just thought it was cheap. Yeah, I don't disagree.
The whole spell where Billy used his psychic
ability to find Tommy's soul and put it into
the body of a dying boy, that was fascinating.
I think the line that happened at the end there
was one of the best of the entire series He
asks Agatha if he's killing this boy just to
bring back his brother. And she says, no, sometimes
little boys just die. And that was really touching
as we learned in the next episode, which was
called Maiden Mother Crone. In a flashback to
1750, Agatha is giving birth to her son as
her lover, Death, comes to claim him. Begging
for mercy, Death grants her special treatment,
giving the child more time, but refusing to
say how much. Agatha raises the young boy Nicholas,
traveling the country and killing witches to
increase her own magical power as a means to
protect her son. In their travels, Nicholas
invents a song about their journey down the
road, a tune which catches on among the witch
community. Though Nicholas questions his mother's
actions, they have a close loving relationship
which leaves Agatha devastated when the boy
grows ill and dies one night. She then uses
the ballad as a means to prey on the power
of unsuspecting witches looking to find the
road. growing her magic over the centuries.
When the doorway to the road actually manifests
in her latest attempt with Lily, Jennifer,
Alice, and Billy, she realizes who Billy is
and recognizes the road as a manifestation
of his chaos magic. Back in the present, Agatha
comes back as a ghost to guide Billy in his
powers and help him find his brother Tommy.
Now there's a line here right after Agatha
gives birth where she says that she made her
son Nicholas from scratch and that's why he
gets his name. Is that implied that he's a virgin
birth or is that implied that, you know, she
made him the old-fashioned way? Not with any
magic, but you know knocking boots. I think
it's the latter. Yeah She brought life into
being without using magic But you know using
the good old basic ingredients basically birds
in the bees exactly It was such a tragic scene,
especially as a dad now just seeing agatha's
reaction to no longer having her child Just
broke my heart like oh, yeah Just even when
the kid was getting sick, I was like, please
don't let this happen. You just really felt
for her in the same way that you felt for Wanda
in WandaVision. I felt for him. The whole time
I was kind of like, beat him. Don't let him
sleep outside. What are you doing? Yeah, give
him a nice home. Don't wander around, you know,
traveling the countryside, gaining power to
defend him. Your time might be better spent
just, you know, taking care of the kid, you
know? Right. Giving him stability. That's kind
of the whole tragedy of it all, you know? Yeah,
she loved him. She just didn't know how to
care for him. Yeah. I think it's really awesome
that she's a ghost now because Agatha Harkness
has been a ghost in the comics, you know, advising
people even from the afterlife. And you know,
she's not only been a mentor to Franklin Richards,
she's also helped out, you know, the Scarlet
Witch. She was a professor at Strange Academy
helping people like Nico Minoru. She's cared
for even Billy and Tommy. So basically the story
puts these characters to the point where they
are in the comics. I thought it was really well
done. Not only that, but her reasoning for
staying behind as a ghost in that she couldn't
face her son in the afterlife was very profound.
Yeah, I think she doesn't want him to really
see the person that she became after his death.
Like even worse than she already was? Yeah,
exactly. That's crazy. I was also excited to
see her white hair. That was awesome. Yeah.
more in keeping with her look in the books.
I can't wait to see her show up again because
these characters are just too good to stop
here. No, I agree. Yeah. I'm definitely looking
forward to seeing both Wiccan and Agatha Harkness
in future Marvel projects. There are certain
storylines that Marvel has done post-Endgame
that I think have resonated more than others.
With this show, I think one of the strongest
threads they have still going is WandaVision
by far. Yeah, WandaVision, Agatha all along,
and the upcoming Vision Quest are all part of
like a trilogy of shows, according to the showrunner.
I think we're really getting a lot more of what
we love about the Marvel Cinematic Universe
with these television series. Marvel sucks.
Really? You're talking about how great the
show is and then you're following it up with
Marvel sucks? I think you might be a little
bit confused there. I have to circle back somehow,
you know? That's the whole review. In summary,
you know, the show's blend of shifting settings.
eclectic characters and jaw-dropping twists
come together to conjure a delightfully unpredictable
journey. I am rating the show 4.5 stars out
of 5, one of Marvel's best television series
ever, and I'm giving it a fresh rating on Rotten
Tomatoes. Yeah, 4.5 is a really high score.
If you had told me before I had seen it that
you wanted to rate it that high, I would have
not believed you. But having seen it with my
own eyes, it's hard to fantastic. I agree with
you. One of Marvel's best shows. I enjoyed
it way more than I thought I would. So yeah,
4.5. Really, it's about as good of a Agatha
Harkness show as you can get. Even better than
that, actually. So like it did not even need
to be this good. It's fucking... They did not
need to go this hard. Right. But yeah, that
does it for this review. AJ9K helped close this
out. Thanks for listening to Dynamic duel.
Visit the show's website at dynamicduel.com
and follow us on Instagram at dynamicduelpodcast.
You can support the show on Patreon at patreon.com
slash dynamicduel and joining a tier that works
for you, or by rating and reviewing Dynamic
duel on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser
or on our website. Don't forget to listen to
the other shows in the DynaMic Podcast Network,
including Max Destruction, Senjow World and
Console Combat. In our next episode, we will
be doing another television review, this time
on the DC end, with HBO's The Penguin series,
which takes place in Matt Reeves' The Batman
Universe. I haven't started watching it yet,
but I'm just going to binge the whole thing,
and from what I've heard it's really good,
so I can't wait. Well, let's see if it's as
good as Agatha all along. Obviously, they're
going to be very different shows. You know,
Agatha is very fantasy magic. The Penguin is
very gritty, realistic, grounded crime drama.
I'm expecting good things from it. Yeah, I
think both of these shows has the potential
to showcase the best of both worlds. The best
of what each studio has to offer. Exactly. But
that does it for this episode. We want to give
a big thanks to our executive producers, Ken
Johnson, John Strosky, Zachary Hepburn. Dustin
Balcom, Miggy Mathen-Geehan, Brandon Essergard,
Nathaniel Wagoner, Levi Yeaton, Austin Wazilovski,
AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam
Spies, Andrew Schunk, Dean Maleski, Devin Davis,
Joseph Kirsting, and Josh Schleiner for helping
make this podcast possible. And we'll talk
to you guys next week. Up, up and away, true
believers.