This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
and peruse our merchandise, accessories, posters,
calendars. Again, Jonathan and I are donating
10% of the proceeds between the months of November
and December to the charity Stand Up to Cancer.
So support our show, support A Great Cause,
and do it in a timely fashion because you're
running out of time. Thanks guys, happy holidays
and on with the show.
Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the superiority
between Marvel and DC by comparing their characters
in stat-based battle simulations. I'm Johnny
DC. And I'm his twin brother Marvelous Joe.
And in this episode, we are reviewing the conclusion
of the two-part Watchmen animated adaptation
Watchmen Chapter 2. I can't say I was looking
forward to watching it. because the first one
I thought was very, very redundant. And you'll
find out later on in this episode whether I
thought the same about chapter two. So Jonathan,
I was thinking we watched the Watchmen, right?
And the listeners are listening to us talk
about watching the Watchmen. So are they watching
us watch the Watchmen? They're the watchers
of the Watchmen watching the Watchmen. Answering
the real philosophical questions on this podcast.
Before we dive even more into the philosophy
of the Watchmen, we're going to break down
the comic book movie news from the past week,
of which there was just one news item, and
that was the reveal that Rob Hardy is the cinematographer
for Supergirl Woman of Tomorrow. As always
guys, we list our segment times and our episode
description, so feel free to check out the
show notes if you want to skip ahead to a particular
topic. Our artificially intelligent duel simulator
AJ9K has a quick message for our listeners,
so listen up. Why hello there, do you want
even more from this podcast? Then become a part
of the dynamic duel community on Patreon, where
you can choose from three tiers. The dynamic
two-oh tier gives you access to our Discord
chat server. The fantastic four tier gives you
two bonus episodes each month. And the X-Force
tier makes you an executive producer of this
show. Lastly, The Diner Mike podcast network
tier lets you create your own podcast using
this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe
will help you develop your show, provide graphic
support and consultation, and get you simulation
results. Pitch the twins your ideas via email
at dynamicduelpodcast at gmail.com. Check it
out at patreon.com slash dynamicduel. Pip pip
cheerio. Thanks Adrian and Kane, thanks to
everyone who supports the podcast. Guys, be
sure to tune in to the other shows on the DynaMic
podcast network this week, including Max Destruction,
which pits your favorite action heroes from
film and television against each other. Hosts
Scotty and Gilly are taking a break for the
holidays, so now is the perfect time to get
caught up on their back catalog of episodes
if you missed any. On the Sendrow World podcast,
host Zachary Hepburn speculates on fights between
fan favorite anime and manga characters. This
Thursday, Zach will reveal who would win in
a fight between Tsuna-Dei from Naruto Unohana
from Bleach.
Definitely make sure to check that out by visiting
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our
show notes to listen to all of the shows in
the DynaMic Podcast Network. But with that
out of the way, quick to the No Prize! A No
Prize is an award Marvel used to give out to
fans. Our version, the Dynamic Duel No Prize,
is a digital award that we post on Instagram
for the person that we feel gave the best answer
to our question of the week. Last week we asked
you guys, or not last week, it was like two
weeks ago, we asked... What Marvel character
would you cast former 007 actor George Lazenby
as and why? And this is coming off of the news
that Daniel Craig is currently negotiating a
deal with DC to play Sergeant Rock in an upcoming
Sergeant Rock film. And I, being a huge 007
James Bond fan, was super jealous because it
seems like all the currently living Bond actors
have gotten DC roles but not Marvel roles.
Of course, you had Pierce Brosnan as Dr. Fate.
You had Timothy Dalton as the chief from Doom
Patrol. You even had Sean Connery as Alan Quartermaine
in the League of Extraordinary Gentlemen, which
came from a DC imprint. George Lazenby though,
he's still kicking, and we gotta get him a
Marvel role so that we could have some 007 in
the MCU. And we got a lot of answers actually.
Yeah, way more than I thought we would actually
get. We're gonna break down this week's honorable
mentions before revealing the no prize winner.
Our first honorable mention goes to Cyrus Moore,
who said, Hey guys, Cyrus Moore here. Uh, George
Lazenby would be a perfect old man Hawkeye,
I believe. And DC side, just I know you guys
didn't ask, but I think he'd be a perfect Alan
Scott. Uh, but old man Hawkeye? Oh, that'd be
fantastic. He's kind of already got the look
that matches the old man Hawkeye comic book
series, so it just be flawless. Yeah, that's
a fantastic answer. You know, Old Man Hawkeye
is a character established in the world of
the Old Man Logan series, and Old Man Hawkeye
even got his own comic book. George Lazenby,
I think, would be great in the role. Not just
because, like, he has a great sense of humor,
but also because I feel like George Lazenby
is kind of, like, seen as the Hawkeye of the
James Bond actors, and that he doesn't seem
quite as relevant because he was only in one
film, so, yeah, I think there's a lot of through
lines there, and I think Lazenby could pull
it off. How old is George Lazenby? Uh, dude
is 85 years old right now. Oh snap. Yeah, pretty
up there. Well, I mean, Ellen Scott is an old
guy. I could totally see George Lazenby playing
Kim. Like you'd probably have to do CG work
for the action shots, but just do it from far
away. It'll be it'll work out. It'll work out.
Plus, George Lazenby is pretty dapper, as is
Ellen Scott. I actually think Ellen Scott would
be a better choice for George Lazenby than
Old Man Hawkeye. You might be right, because
like Old Man Hawkeye has long hair. And I don't
know if I could see Lazenby pulling off that
look. Our next honorable mention goes to Mike
Williams. who said,
Yeah, coming off of our recent duel matchup
of Black Mask versus Madame Mask, I think this
was a great answer. We know that Madame Mask,
of course, is the daughter of Count Nefaria,
who was a leader within the Magia crime family
in the world of Marvel. And yeah, I could totally
see Laysen be as like the patriarch of a mafia
crime family for sure. Yeah, that would be
kind of cool. Almost like a Marlon Brando-esque
type role. There you go. Yeah. Take that vibe
and then add superpowers to it. I think you
got yourself a good Count Nefaria with George
Lazenby in the role. Great answer, Mike! Our
next honorable mention goes to Mason Thompson,
who said, Hey guys, so first thing I saw when
I looked at some photos of him, Uncle Ben.
Maybe he's in the multiverse as an Uncle Ben.
And he comes to our universe, gives our universe,
the Spider-Man, a little motivation, something
like that. But if we're talking like Prime,
when he was in his Prime, he's He's Tony Stark.
Look at him and tell me he's not Tony Stark.
Give him a little goatee and he's Iron Man.
Great answer. Yeah, actually, Uncle Ben was
the answer that I immediately thought of. And
I was really hoping like people out there would
come up with better options than just having
him as Uncle Ben. But the problem I had with
casting George Lazenby as Uncle Ben is that
even though he looks exactly like him nowadays,
the MCU Uncle Ben would have to be a lot younger
to have dated Marissa Tomei's. Aunt May, right?
Maybe. But then Mason Thompson reminded me that
the multiverse is a thing, so he could always
be a multiversal Uncle Ben. I think it totally
works. Mason also went on to say that the prime
version of George Lazenby, you know, back in
1969 when he played Bond, would make a great
Tony Stark. And I don't disagree. I think a
lot of the James Bond actors would make a great
Tony Stark. In fact, if I recall correctly,
artist Alex Ross paints his version of Tony
Stark. in the likeness of Timothy Dalton, who
was another James Bond actor. Oh, man, I need
to look this up. Yeah, look up Alex Ross, Tony
Stark. Oh, holy cow, he does. That's awesome.
So there are definitely like parallels between
the Stark and James Bond character. And thanks
to Mason Thompson for reminding us all about
that. I want to give a quick shout out to Colby
Hentges, who. called in with the answer of Silvermane,
but also suggested that Aaron Taylor Johnson
would be a good choice for the next 007 after
Daniel Craig, and he's totally my choice as
well. Also shout out to Judson Batty, who actually
gave a DC answer. He said George Lazenbeek
could play Uncle Marvel from the Captain Marvel
Shazam family. And a dishonorable mention to
Miggy for not having the imagination or trust
in his fellow listeners to produce answers
for this question. It was just crickets. But
he said on behalf of everybody. But the winner
of this week's snow prize is Brandon Estregard,
who said. Hey guys, I would cast George Lazenby
as the original human torch, Jim Hammond, for
three reasons. One, they were both ornate created
in the same year, 1939, which was also the year
that World War II started. Two, you can cast
him at his current age and give him a cameo
like how Hank had his World War II amman cameo
in the original amman movie. And three, every
Bond actor deserves an iconic role. I really
liked this answer. Of course, Brandon said that...
George Liza to be could play the original Human
Torch, who was the superhero on the very first
issue of the very first Marvel comic book ever.
The original Human Torch was not a member of
the Fantastic Four. Of course, Marvel fans
know that he was an android named Jim Hammond,
who was created by Dr. Phineas Horton. I go
a little bit into his backstory in the Vision
vs. Marsha Manhunter duel episode that we have.
But yeah, the android was actually briefly featured.
in the Captain America movie when Steve Rogers
and Bucky went to the World's Fair with their
dates. Jim Hammond's Human Torch was a hugely
influential World War II hero and it would be
really cool to see him show up in the MCU as
George Lazenby. I thought it was a really cool
factoid that Brandon pointed out that the Human
Torch comic book character and George Lazenby
were both born in the same year of 1939. Yeah,
it might be even cool to see that version of
the Human Torch. appear in the upcoming Vision
television series, considering the character's
backstory. Oh yeah, that would be totally great.
No matter how it happens, we just gotta get
this Bond actor in a Marvel role, cuz screw
DC for taking in all the 007 actors. But thanks
to everyone who called in, congrats to Brandon
Eschergard for winning this week's No Prize.
If you the listener want a shot at winning
your own No Prize, stay tuned to later on this
episode when we'll be asking another question
of the week. And now that that's done… No SCREW
MARVEL! And onto the news!
Alright, over a week ago, James Gunn revealed
on threads in a conversation there that Rob
Hardy, a veteran cinematographer in Hollywood,
will be doing the cinematography for the upcoming
Supergirl Woman of Tomorrow film. That film
of course is starring Millie Alcock as Supergirl
and is based on the comic of the same title.
Now, this news is pretty awesome because the
comic Supergirl Woman of Tomorrow takes place
across the cosmos and visits different planets
and it looks really awesome. The art in the
comic is fantastic. So to get someone of Rob
Hardy's caliber to do the cinematography for
it makes it seem like the movie is just going
to be breathtaking to watch. Rob Hardy has done
cinematography on prior films that include
Ex Machina, Annihilation, Mission Impossible
Fallout, Men, and Civil War among other films.
Yeah, a lot of those movies have a very grounded
approach to the cinematography, I would say,
with probably Annihilation being the exception.
I'm assuming he's going to pull largely from
that experience to direct the photography for
Supergirl Woman of Tomorrow. Yeah, yeah, I
think Annihilation is a good precedent for what
he could do with the film in terms of her visiting
these alien worlds. DC has had some amazing
cinematography in their past films. You can
take a look at... The Batman, the Joker films,
Marvel films, their best one was probably what,
The Eternals? For the MCU, yeah, I would say
the best cinematography was The Eternals or
maybe Guardians. Prior to that, I think the
Sam Raimi, Spider-Man films had great cinematography.
Cinematographers aren't as renowned as directors,
but they contribute a lot to the look of the
film. And I gotta say, Rob Hardy joining Supergirl
makes me really excited for how that film is
going to look. I've yet to hear like really
anything bad about that film. It looks like
it's shaping up to be really something special.
But speaking of cinematographers, that brings
us to our question of the week.
What live action Marvel or DC film do you think
had the best cinematography and what was your
favorite shot? Yeah, give us the film, give
us the cinematographer, and give us your favorite
cinematic scene from that movie. Record your
answer at dynamicduel.com by clicking on the
red microphone button in the bottom right hand
corner of the screen, which will prompt you
to leave us a voicemail. Your message can be
up to 30 seconds long, and don't forget to
leave your name in case we include you on the
podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer. and
award that person a dynamic duel no prize that
we'll post to Instagram. Be sure to answer
before December 14th.
Well that does it for all the news for this
episode, but now let's go ahead and move on
to the main event where we review the animated
adaptation Watchmen Chapter 2.
Watchmen Chapter 2 is the second half of a two-part
animated adaptation of the comic medium's seminal
masterpiece created by writer Alan Moore and
artist Dave Gibbons. It concludes the mystery
of a killer targeting retired crime-fighting
vigilantes in New York City amidst escalating
global tensions and the threat of nuclear armageddon
at the height of the Cold War. It's a satirical
examination of superhero comics that revolutionized
the comic medium in the 1980s. And because
it was so narratively complex and perfectly
suited to the comic medium, it was long considered
unadaptable to screen. Of course, you know,
until the 2009 live action film by Zack Snyder,
but even that was met with mixed reactions.
15 years after that, Warner Brothers has attempted
another on-screen adaptation, this time split
into two parts, chapters one and two. with
our podcast being the only tomato meter approved
publication that gave chapter one a rotten
rating, saying in our review that despite the
filmmakers best intentions, the film is faithful
to a fault, and in essence, it's an abridged
and superfluous version of the celebrated graphic
novel. Well, it just means that we have integrity,
okay? We're willing to call out something as
bad if we perceive it to be bad. And I definitely
don't think it was deserving of a 100% Rotten
Tomato rating, because after watching Chapter
1, I concluded that the story of Watchmen is
too good and too important to justify an abridged
version. But if you're going to condense the
story into something easier to consume on screen,
then we already have a better, more cinematic
abridged version in the live-action film. And
this animated adaptation, in its ambition to
be even more faithful to the graphic novel,
makes itself redundant and less special. We
speculated in our review of Chapter 1 that because
of the ramped up tension in the latter half
of the story, Chapter 2 is probably going to
be better, and it is, but just barely. So I'm
not going to recommend watching this movie.
I am going to recommend everyone read the graphic
novel though, and if you're going to, stop listening
to the spoiler review now because it will also
spoil the book. And if you're not going to read
the book, then I would recommend pairing the
2009 Zack Snyder film with the 2019 HBO Watchmen
series. With the understanding that the end
explosion was caused by different sources, though.
I don't care. I just don't recommend this two
part animated adaptation. I will agree, though,
that this chapter two film was better than
chapter one. Right. Yeah. Now, I went on at
length as to why Watchmen is such a celebrated
story in our review of Chapter one. So I won't
repeat any of that here. What I will say is
that I regret that Warner Brothers' animation
didn't release both chapters simultaneously,
because releasing the story in two parts, I
feel, didn't allow the story's tension to build
and conclude in one unified experience. So the
narrative's most powerful moments, especially
the final moral quandaries, lose some of their
impact because of the rushed nature of this
second half. There's a ton more story here from
the books that was cut or rushed through than
there was in Chapter 1, and because of that,
the lead villain of the story doesn't even
debut in this film until the final act. Both
Chapters 1 and 2 were just shy of 90 minutes
each, putting them combined at under 3 hours,
which is shorter than the director's cut of
Zack Snyder's Watchmen, and that's still my
favorite adaptation. I'm afraid this means
that there was no reason to split the story
in two parts other than corporate greed on
behalf of Warner Brothers. Like no reason. If
they wanted to do the graphic novel justice,
which I'm now convinced as I mentioned in our
last review, that the only way to have done
that was a 12 episode animated series. For sure,
or live action series. I still hope to see
that one day. maybe as, you know, another HBO
series where every issue of the Watchmen graphic
novel is an episode of the series. If they could
do a series that was like in the same vein
aesthetically as something like Blade Runner,
I think that would be absolute perfection.
Yeah, Blade Runner is a little sci-fi, but if
you could like throw in some like taxi driver
type vibe, like make the television series really
feel like the time period that it's set in,
like it was made during that time. I think that
would be mind-blowing. Absolutely. 100% agree.
Now, my gripes aside, I do have to say that
I did actually think this film was enjoyable.
There's a lot more action in the second half
than there was in the first in more ways than
one, if you know what I mean. I don't know what
you mean. What do you mean, Jonathan? What
do you mean by that? You know, action. What
does that mean? OK, virgin sex. That's what
I mean. From the prison fights with Rorschach.
to the escapades of Night Owl and Silk Spectre,
to the actually good climax we got this time
at the end of the film, the movie moves at
a pretty brisk pace, even with the tales of
the Black Freighter interludes. That said,
for all the action it had, I felt Chapter 2
absolutely dropped the ball on the underlying
tension of nuclear war that the book expertly
managed to balance along with the character
drama. Like- There was only one brief scene
with Richard Nixon in this film. And to me,
the adaptation struggled to capture the moral
gravity that defined the source material, that
Cold War-era fear of nuclear Armageddon that
loomed over every scene in the comic, creating
this almost suffocating tension and urgency
to the characters' struggles, as well as their
moral compromises. The heart of Watchmen, for
many readers, I think, has always been its
commentary. on humanity's capacity for self-destruction
and the horrifying lengths one might go to
in order to prevent it. That's the moral of
the story, right? We are creatures who stand
on the brink of annihilation and any solution
to that problem can be as monstrous as the
threat itself. Watchmen Chapter 2 does present
Ozymandias' terrible solution in full detail,
Giant Squid and all, which is something previous
adaptations have shied away from. but without
the nuclear dread consistently simmering throughout
the narrative, the final twist feels more like
a shock tactic than this culmination of the
existential anxieties from that era. I wonder
if the animation has anything to do with that.
It's kind of just really hard to connect with
anything that you're seeing on the screen due
to the rather stiff nature of it all. Yeah,
as we mentioned in our review of Chapter 1,
the animation for this film particularly now
that I've seen Suicide Squad Isekai, which we
reviewed after Chapter 1. Suicide Squad Isekai
has kind of ruined, in a way, all DC animation
for me because it is, I would say, DC's best
animated project that it's ever done and way
better in comparison to the animation that
was done for Watchmen, unfortunately. Tragically
even. Like imagine what this squid exploding
scene would have been like in anime style. That
would have been incredible. Like Akira? Yeah,
like I was just gonna say Akira. Yeah, that's
what it kind of reminded me of. The nuclear
Armageddon felt secondary until the very end
of the film, which devotes most of its running
time to the Mask Killer mystery and only fully
acknowledges the specter of nuclear war after
Ozymandias' plan has been fully revealed and
executed. And I think that was a huge mistake.
especially during these times when we still
live under the threat of nuclear war. You know,
the doomsday clock that is used as a motif throughout
the comics series is a real thing. And currently
we're at, I think, 90 seconds to midnight as
of this recording, which is wild. I mean, we
got more than a whole minute left before humanity's
destruction. Oh, okay. I'm feeling pretty good.
Let me know when it's like 15 seconds, then
I'll start shitting my pants. One thing I noticed
from Chapter 2 is that it seemed like they actually
diverted more from the source material than
Chapter 1 did. Like I saw a few new scenes,
a lot more original dialogue, and I remember
thinking to myself like, what the fuck did they
just say? Like, what is this? Like, when did
Hollis Mason go back and visit Dan Dreiberg?
Since when did we spend so much time on Archie,
you know? It wasn't a bad adaptation and we
really came down on Chapter 1 for... being
a little bit too faithful and maybe they hurt
us. Maybe that's why they added all this extra
stuff. I don't know. I doubt it. They've been
working on this film for three years. So I
don't think it was us. Their one negative Rotten
Tomatoes review. I doubt it. But no, I definitely
noticed those extra scenes. They were definitely
drawing to me as well. And I don't mind them
condensing the story. It was just the writing
that I felt was off. Like Shazinsky, the writer
of this film. is a really good comic book writer,
but he's no Alan Moore. And when you hear lines
like, your butt is in safe hands, it better
be or else I'm gonna kick it. I'm just like,
what the fuck is this? I thought the exact same
thing when I heard that line. I was like, this
chapter two adaptation has way too much butt
stuff. Like I remember when Dan and Lori were
about to get it on the couch the first time,
there was a whole shot of her slapping his
ass. just out of the blue. Like they cut to
that specifically. And I was like, that was
never in the comic book. What the fuck was that?
And on Archie. I didn't need to see that. There's
a lot of butt stuff going on in chapter two
of Watchmen. A lot of ass kicking and ass slapping.
But yeah, that line was just groan worthy. It's
one of several changes where I'm like, that
was unnecessary. Like honestly, looking back
on these two films, I kind of wish they would
have cut the tales from the Black Friday. because
it would have given them more room to include
some more of the better stuff from the books.
Yeah, I think the parallels that they tried
to draw between the story of the Black Frater
and the story of Watchmen did not work as well
within this adaptation. No, I disagree. I actually
think some of the parallels they made were
more successful than what they did in the comic.
But that doesn't mean it was necessary. What
is the moral of the Black Frater? What's the
lesson there and how does it pertain to the
story of Watchmen? Well, it has like this meta
context with a lot of things that are going
on within the story intentionally. But overall,
I would say that it tells the story of this
man who has gone through these horrible tragedies
and kind of lost his soul. In the same way,
you could make connections between that and
Rorschach or Ozymandias in coming to the conclusion
that he felt he had to come up with in order
to save mankind. He became a monster in much
the same way that the sailor from Tales of the
Black Frader did. Except the sailor learned
his lesson whereas Ozymandias did not. Maybe,
maybe, we don't know. I'm just gonna say now,
hot take, I don't think Tales from the Black
Frader is necessary at all even in the comic
book. The parallels that it tries to draw are
just too thin to hold much weight in the larger
context. Fight me. Okay, I will fight you with
my fists. Not with any kind of argument against
that. Yeah, yeah, those are frightening words,
my friend. Your opinion is trash. Here's a
punch to the face. Exactly. You get it. I like
Tales of the Black Freighter, but I have not
liked it in any other adaptation. Like, I didn't
even really enjoy it in the ultimate cut of
the Watchmen film. The live action one by Zack
Snyder. They made an animated version of the
Tales from the Black Freighter and cut it into
the movie. But honestly, as I said earlier,
the director's cut without that is still my
favorite adaptation of Watchmen. I rest my
case. If they ever did a TV show though, like
a 12 part series, I could see them leaving
it in. Yeah, at that point, I think you'd almost
need to just to fill the runtime. Yeah. Let's
go ahead and move on to the character breakdown,
though I will say I don't have anything to
add regarding the voice performances that I
have already said in our review of Chapter
1. So I'm going to skip over all of that. But
let's start with Rorschach, aka Walter Kovacs.
After being captured by police and accused of
the murder of Malik, Rorschach is forced into
a prison where he's surrounded by hundreds of
criminals he helped put behind bars. Despite
this, Rorschach shows no fear, even going so
far as to tell the prisoners that he's not
locked up with them, they're locked up with
him, and proving as much in how he's able to
disable their attacks. We see how his hardened
view of the world was shaped by his upbringing,
being the offspring of a prostitute. and teased
for it growing up. And choosing the life of
a crime fighter showed him the absolute worst
in humanity, shaping his viewpoint that life
is random and meaningless with no pattern save
for what we impose on it. And Rorschach imposes
his own strict black and white morality, deontological
and uncompromising, which is why he's killed
by Dr. Manhattan in the end. Because his inability
to compromise to allow a little evil for a
greater good would lead to greater harm. I do
wish that they would have taken a little bit
more time with his personal backstory that is
revealed during his sessions with the psychiatrist.
Super rushed. It does seem like he rushed through
it. Oh yeah. And to me that was always one
of the more interesting parts of the Watchman's
story, how this man kind of just fell into
the void. Yeah, absolutely. I think if Watchmen
had a protagonist, it probably would be Rorschach,
but I definitely feel like he didn't get as
much screen time as like Dan and Laurie in
this adaptation. I feel like they were treated
as the protagonists, which isn't bad. You know,
I don't mind Night Owl. He's probably one of
my favorite characters. Speaking of him, you
know, after returning to vigilantism alongside
Laurie, Dan Dreiberg finds a renewed sense
of purpose he lacked since giving up his Night
Owl persona. rediscovering the thrill and meaning
in what he does, whether it's rescuing people
from a burning building or orchestrating Rorschach's
jailbreak. As he uncovers Adrian Veidt's plan,
Dan is forced to confront his own ideals. He
sees the bigger picture and understands that
sometimes terrible sacrifices need to be accepted
for the greater good. Unlike Rorschach, Dan
can compromise, and it allows him to let go
and embrace a new life with Laurie. As they
reinvent themselves, and find a peace in the
world that Adrian has created. I liked Dan more
in Chapter 2 than I did in Chapter 1. Chapter
1, I found it difficult to avoid comparing Night
Owl's on-screen performance to Patrick Wilson's
from the 2009 live-action film, but with Chapter
2 maybe a little bit less so because Chapter
2 is really where the character comes into his
own. The moment when he was explaining to Laurie
how he just felt impotent because of all the
pressure surrounding the events worldwide and
locally, I really connected with. It felt believable
to me in a way that felt a little bit more
palpable than even the comic book. Maybe, I
don't know. In this movie, I think he came
across as much more confident earlier on in
the story than he was in the comic. You know,
when the second half of the story starts, he's
still very meek. It wasn't until he really
went out crime fighting for the first time that
he kind of began to get his edge again. But
I feel like he was flirting with Laurie even
before he put on the costume in this adaptation.
For sure. Yeah, he got his groove back a little
bit earlier than in the books. Yeah. One of
my favorite things about the character of Night
Owl in the comic was his gadgets. He's a gadgeteer
inspired by the character of Blue Beetle. And
there were a lot of them that were missing
from this adaptation, unfortunately. I think
he had some cool ones. He had those crescent
darts. I call them that because that's what
Moon Knight calls them. But they were like
in the shape of crescent moons. But they were
like taser disks, right? They had like an electrical
current running between the tips. But did he
have a hot cocoa dispenser in Archie? Like
he did in the comics? No, but he had jazz music.
Yeah. Let's move on to Laurie Yuspechik, aka
Silk Spectre II. You know, after walking away
from Dr. Manhattan's, Laurie begins carving
out an identity. on her own terms. Joining Dan,
she finds someone she can truly relate to,
free from the weight of her mother's expectations
or the stifling life at Dr. Manhattan's side.
Fighting crime with Dan renews the sense of
purpose within her, letting her step out of
the shadow of her mother and enter her own spotlight.
During her time on Mars, Laurie comes to the
revelation that the comedian, the man who tried
to rape her mother, is her father. and it affects
everything she thought she knew about not only
her upbringing, but also love and ultimately
forgiveness. When Adrian's plan is revealed,
it helps her adapt and accept the same compromises
that would allow her to reconcile with her mother
and grow further into her being her own hero.
Laurie's Ark is always a good one, especially
in Chapter 2, but I will say that I think that
this film handled the revelation on Mars. more
clumsily than I would have liked. There's just
some weird dialogue surrounding it when like
Dr. Manhattan's like, look at this chaotic
terrain. And she was like, we have chaotic terrain,
look at the chaoticness of my family. I'm like,
that was kind of a stretch. I think that was
from the comic. Well, that's just bad writing.
I don't think it's a terrible line. The whole
exchange was done so much better in the comic
because there was just a lot more to the conversation.
So it didn't feel forced and it didn't feel
rushed. It felt very natural. I actually really
liked that issue from the comic. I thought
the live action version handled it believably
and just better all around. The live action
version was better and the comic is even better
than that. The way the comic plays with time
is done in a way that I feel like you can't
really translate as well to film just because
of the nature of the different panels and the
way you shift from scene to scene in a comic.
In the comic book, it doesn't necessarily feel
like flashbacks. No, it feels literally like
the events are taking place concurrently in
the same way that Dr. Manhattan perceives time.
Right. It's not as forced in a comic book as
it is on screen. Exactly. Because like you
have to treat a flashback as like a memory.
So you kind of see Laurie kind of almost have
to zone out kind of to think about this thing
that happened to her previously in her life.
With the comic book, you don't have to do that.
I almost feel like if they ever want to do
this scene justice, like if they ever did a
12 episode miniseries on television, they would
need two frames on screen at the same time,
kind of playing concurrently with each other.
That would be really hard to do, though. Split
screen stuff. It could be done. Is pretty clumsy.
Just look at the Captain America trailer. They
did it fine there. Yeah. OK. Yeah, sure. I'd
at least like to see it attempted before I judge
it. Yeah. Let's go ahead and move on to Dr.
Manhattan, aka Jonathan Osterman. After retreating
to Mars, Dr. Manhattan finds himself increasingly
removed from the human condition he once knew.
Observing Earth from a distance, he contemplates
time, probability, and the very structure of
existence, growing more indifferent by the
moment. But when Lori appears, bringing with
her the messy complexities of love, trauma,
and hope, he's forced to reconsider humanity's
worth. The simple, unlikely miracle of Laurie's
own life rekindles a faint spark of empathy
he thought was gone. After returning to Earth
and witnessing Adrian's atrocity, Dr. Manhattan
agrees to keep the peace through silence, yet
in doing so he chooses to leave Earth behind,
forging a new path where he can create life
and shape his own meaning in the cosmos.
the existence of life, a highly overrated phenomenon,
and then almost immediately after that calls
all life a miracle. Well, he just came to that
realization. His mind was changed. A being
even as omnipotent as him can still be reasoned
with. To me, he just seems like a man who can't
stand by his convictions. That's what I say.
Well, lucky enough, he didn't. I always thought
that it was a convenient bit of writing. on
behalf of Alan Moore and the original Watchmen
story in that, you know, if Laurie is such a
miracle, he's like, oh yeah, all life is a
miracle. By its very nature, then you'd have
to redefine the term miracle, I think. Well,
she helped him realize that the rarity of life
itself in the cosmos is a miracle and that
by its very nature, each human life is its own
miracle, which it is because, you know, all
of us were at one point, you know, different,
competing. sperm and ova fighting for a chance
to become what we are now. I just feel like
that's a little bit ridiculous because sure,
the odds of the sperm connecting with that specific
egg from your mom statistically is highly unlikely,
but again it happens all the fucking time. So
on earth, again, I think you have to redefine
your definition of miracle because it's not
that special. Cynical asshole says what?
Appreciate your own life. What does that have
to do with anything that we were talking about?
I'm saying you're a miracle, bro. I'm saying
you have to perceive life as a miracle in order
to appreciate it. I'm just saying you have to
redefine miracle if it happens repeatedly over
and over and even sometimes by accident. Whoa,
gotta put a rubber on it, man. Gotta put a
rubber on it. Well, how would you redefine it
then? I would define it as highly probable,
even though the fact that the comedian and Sally
Jupiter didn't get along at first, you know,
later on they did. And they boned each other
and they had a baby. As these things happen.
So I'm not like freaking claiming it's the same
thing as air turning into gold, like Dr. Manhattan
is. And yet the rest of the universe may say
differently. They'd be like, holy shit, there's
a planet with life on it. What? Says the planet
that also has life on it. Yeah. Okay. Yeah.
All right. I may be coming across as overly
cynical and I'm not really a cynic, but I'm
not nearly as wishy washy as Dr. Manhattan either.
I don't think you appreciate being alive enough,
Joseph. Really? Yes. I guess what I'm saying
is you need like an existential breakdown.
Okay. I'm pretty busy at work, so it might happen.
We're going to get to Ozymandias aka Adrian
Veit. Adrian doesn't have too much screen time.
In Chapter 2, he spends most of that revealing
the full extent of his grand, terrifying vision.
He was an admirer of Alexander the Great. And
Adrian's master plan is his way of slicing through
the Gordian knot that was the Cold War tensions,
a problem too tangled and complex for any rational
negotiation. Rather than seeking a delicate
solution, he opted to manufacture a common enemy
to rally humanity. By sacrificing millions
of innocent lives, he took the utilitarian approach
that the ends justify the means. Yet after
the dust settles and the surviving heroes reluctantly
agree to silence, he looks to them for validation,
an assurance that he truly did the right thing.
His triumph feels hollow, and despite all his
brilliance, he remains uncertain whether he
succeeded in preserving life's value. or simply
proved that humanity can be manipulated into
salvation for however long that lasts. Here's
another issue I have with the story of Watchmen.
Okay! And Ozymandias' plan. And another reason
why I like the 2009 live-action adaptation better
because in that film, they showed that Ozymandias
not only attacked New York, but a lot of major
cities across the globe. True. Which I think
was important to humanity coming together. against
a common enemy. Let me draw a metaphor for
you, okay? Say you're about to get in a fist
fight with your sworn enemy, okay? And right
before you two are about to throw punches, your
enemy gets hit by a bike or something like
that, okay? Are you two all of a sudden gonna
join forces together against the bicyclist
or are you gonna be like, thank god it was that
guy and not me, that guy hit by the bike? I'm
not necessarily convinced that New York specifically
getting attacked, and only New York getting
attacked, would draw the entire globe together
in world peace, considering that, you know,
America was about to be part of the end of the
world, you know? I'm not sure that New York
would draw that much sympathy from America's
enemies at that time. Well, if I thought that
the bicyclist was also going to come after me,
right after he attacked you, then yeah, I'd
probably join forces with you to fend off the
bicyclist. I don't know if you caught that
I consider you my mortal enemy. I was like,
wait, what? Why is it me that got hit by the
bike? I guess you're right in that regard. But
yeah, I can totally see why the live action
adaptation had multiple attacks across the globe.
Yeah, I would agree with you, actually. That
is one of the things that the film version did
better than the book version. It was that and
also Rorschach going to Dr. Manhattan to see
if he. could see into the future to find out
who the masked killer was. Those are two kind
of gaps that are in the book that the movie
covered well, I thought. Let's move on to the
story highlights.
In a world where fantasies collide and heroes
clash, one podcast network rises above the
rest. Prepare yourself for the ultimate showdowns
in comic books, video games, movies, and anime.
The Dynomic Podcast Network presents Console
Combat, where video game legends brawl every
Monday.
Smash every Tuesday, Max Destruction, where
TV and action heroes battle every Wednesday,
and Sendro World, where anime champions clash
every Thursday. Join us as we speculate on
the matches and, armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge victorious.
Visit dynamicpodcast.com where we settle the
debate and settle the score.
On a remote island, horror comic writer Max
Shea and surrealist painter Hira Manish reflect
on how they, along with a group of scientists,
contributed to creating a nightmarish creature
for unclear reasons and for an unnamed benefactor,
currently being shipped off the island. Over
the course of the film, interwoven within the
narrative, one of Max Shea's comics,
after his ship was destroyed by the dreaded
Phantom Pirate ship known as the Black Freighter.
Forced to build a raft from corpses of his shipmates,
the traumatized sailor grows mad as he battles
sharks and the sea itself to get home to Davidstown
and protect his family from the oncoming Black
Freighter pirates, only to mistake his wife
for a pirate while attempting to rescue her.
The sailor is then chased by a mob to the sea,
where the Black Freighter waits for him. Now
this of course isn't all in the first scene,
it's interspersed throughout the film, but
I wanted to get the Black Friday narrative out
of the way. Yeah, I think I said my piece on
it. Again, fight me. With my fists! Now captured
and imprisoned, Walter Kovacs, aka the vigilante
Rorschach, overcomes a prison attack by inmates
he helped put there. During a psychological
evaluation, Rorschach reveals his traumatic
childhood, and how he was driven to murderous
vigilantism, after confronting a man who fed
a young girl he kidnapped to his dogs. Meanwhile,
Dan Dreiberg rescues Laurie Yuspechik from a
fire in his basement that Laurie accidentally
caused while inspecting his high-tech hovercraft,
Archie. While talking about their inspirations
for becoming costumed vigilantes, Dan admits
the comedian's death, Rorschach's imprisonment,
Dr. Manhattan's exile to Mars, and the attempted
assassination of Adrian Veidt are too coincidental
to be unrelated. While watching television,
Dan and Laurie eventually kiss, and though
they attempt to make love, Dan finds himself
impotent from the nightmare-inducing stress
of impending nuclear war. One of the things
they did in this movie that was taken straight
from the comic that I thought they did better
than the live-action version was Rorschach
tying the guy who killed the young girl to his
boiler and giving him a saw to cut off his
own hand as he set fire to his house. The movie
was way more violent. But I actually think
it's a little bit more jigsaw-esque, like from
the movie Saw, to make him try to cut off his
own hand to save himself, knowing that he ultimately
would not be able to do that. I think the shock
of the violent moment within the live action
movie was more effective in portraying that
transition from Walter Kovacs into Rorschach,
because like he couldn't even speak. All he
did was jam the meat cleaver in the guy's head
saying, men get arrested, dogs get put down.
You know, I thought that was in... extremely
graphic but also effective look at his transitioning
psyche. Here it was just kind of like, eh, you
know, saw your way out if you can. If you can't
then, you know, guess you're gonna die. Well
the whole transition moment was supposed to
be as he's watching the building burn down.
It was sort of this cathartic moment in which
he like arose from the ashes as Rorschach. Sure,
I'll still say less effective. Maybe. While
a mobster named Big Figure attempts to intimidate
Rorschach in his jail cell as a prison riot
bruise, Dan and Lori decide to put their old
crime fighting costumes on and take Archie
out for a spin, during which time they rescue
tenants of an apartment fire. Feeling empowered,
Dan and Lori make love aboard Archie before
deciding they should break Rorschach out of
prison. While planning the breakout in Dan's
basement, Dan is visited by his mentor, Hollis
Mason, the original Night Owl, who warns Dan
that if he could figure out which crimefighters
rescued the apartment fire tenants, which was
an illegal crimefighting act, the police could
too. After sharing his theory with Hollis regarding
the corporate connections between all of the
recent murders, Dan leaves with Laurie and Archie
just before the police raid his house. While
Dan and Laurie fend off police and rioters,
Rorschach defends himself against a big figure,
killing his men and him before escaping with
his allies. Now the scene with Hollis Mason
visiting Dan is not in the comics. Dan is actually
visited by a detective in that scene. But I
actually liked this more because it gave one
more scene between Hollis and Dan before Hollis
dies. Yeah, that was nice. It kind of gave viewers
that are familiar with the story a little bit
of closure in regards to that relationship,
you know? Right. In the movie, it did seem
like it was just a means for a big exposition
dump. Yes. Yeah. What the story actually was.
One thing I didn't like here was how Dan does
give the exposition dump in regards to all
of this research that he seemingly did off screen
about all the different corporations that are
tied to the different deaths throughout the
film. Yeah, he was much more informed here
than he ever was in the comics. And we never
really got to see all that information come
together. Regarding the rescue scene of the
tenants from the building fire, that was another
bit of bad dialogue, I thought, when one of
the ladies was like, mother of the deus. And
then Silk Spectre was like, different Spectre
and I'm nobody's mother. Yeah, that was a Trisinski
original there, I believe. And regarding the
sex scene that happened right after, if nothing
else, it just proved how unnecessarily pornographic
Zack Snyder made that scene in his film. Okay,
virgin. Damn it! Sorry it makes you so uncomfortable.
It's just gratuitous. I don't know. I don't
disagree. I don't disagree. I thought this was
done very tastefully actually in this animated
version. Yeah. In retaliation for Rorschach's
escape, a violent gang of not-tops mistake
Hollis for Dan and beat him to death. During
their escape from police, Dr. Manhattan appears
aboard Archie and takes Laurie with him back
to Mars, where Laurie reminisces through her
life in an attempt to view it from Dr. Manhattan's
extradimensional perception of time, accidentally
revealing in the process that she's sleeping
with Dan. Upset by the revelation, Dr. Manhattan
refuses to help save Earth from impending nuclear
war until Laurie comes to the revelation that
the Comedian was her father. Astonished by the
near-miraculous unlikelihood of the union between
Laurie's parents and of Laurie's existence in
general, Dr. Manhattan decides to take her
back to Earth and help. Meanwhile, Dan and Rorschach
visit Adrian's office, hoping he can help them
figure out the connection between the corporations
involved with the recent deaths, only to discover
that Adrian is away at his Antarctic base, Carnac,
and that he owns all of the corporations involved.
On their way to Antarctica, Rorschach mails
his journal to the conspiratorial magazine,
The New Frontiersman. I do like the way this
movie handled Dryberg's revelation that Ozymandias
was behind everything more than the book's method
of having Ozymandias have a really obvious
password on his computer. Like he's the world's
smartest man and yet his password was Ramesses
II, right? Wait, that's an obvious password?
Yes. Oh shit, I need to change mine. Here there
was like no hacking of anything, you know, it
was just good old-fashioned detective work
looking through financial records. Maybe, I
guess you could also say that those records
should have probably been in a vault or a safe
of some sort. And not just like in a drawer
that could be easily opened. I guess that's
fair. When Adrian arrives at Carnac, his assistants
reveal that the shipment from the island has
arrived and that everything for his plan is
in order. Adrian thanks them with wine that
poisons and kills them, while listening to
an interview that he had done with a reporter
that details his life's inspiration for unifying
the world. As Dan and Rorschach approach Antarctica,
we see the ship blow up that was carrying Max
Shea, Hera Manish, and everyone else who built
the unseen creature, now at Karnak, who Adrian
teleports away. Dan and Rorschach attempt to
ambush Adrian, but he counters and disables
them, before revealing that he was the mask
killer, having killed the comedian for learning
of his plan, along with others to get rid of
Dr. Manhattan to prevent him from stopping
his plan. which was to force the world governments
into an era of cooperation and peace, while
seemingly under the threat of an alien attack,
which Adrian achieved prior to Dan and Rorschach's
arrival by teleporting a genetically modified
giant squid monster to New York City and causing
it to blow up half its population. Do you ever
feel like... the squid monster was a little
bit far-fetched in the realm of science fiction
for the very grounded world that the Watchmen
story is set in, or relatively grounded world.
I think without Bubastis it was. But with Bubastis
we understand that Ozymandias has been researching
genetic modification for years. Bubastis of
course is Adrian's pet Lynx, genetically modified
Lynx. You know, we know Adrian put a lot of
resources into a lot of different sci-fi-esque
technologies to try to pull off this massive
hoax, including genetic engineering, including
teleportation. Do you think that there is a
more plausible way to fake an alien attack?
When we know that in history, sometimes faking
an alien attack can be as simple as Orson Wells
reading a radio broadcast. Of course, I'm describing,
you know, War of the Worlds. Do you think that
there was probably a better way for Alan Moore
to more convincingly have Adrian depict an alien
attack than through all this sci-fi technology
stuff? Well, how else would you kill two million
people? Well, probably a bomb? I think a more
plausible approach would be like the Independence
Day route where Adrian just develops this UFO
hovercraft that drops a big bomb or something
like that. I think that's... still believable.
Developing an aircraft that's unidentifiable
by the world's military is more simple than
genetically engineering this whole entire new
creature. Yeah, probably. But I also think
that, who knows? I think that if something like
a giant squid monster suddenly appeared on
the planet, I'd have an easier time believing
it came from outer space. Then if you just
had a craft drop some kind of explosive and
then like vanish. then, you know, that's nothing.
I guess there would be some deniability there.
Yeah, if Adrian went the ship route, he'd have
to have like the ship crash and it would have
to be of like such advanced technology that
no one would have ever suspected that he was
the one who created it. Still seems a little
bit more plausible than a fucking squid beak
tentacle beast monster. Hey, man, don't hate
the player, hate the game. Well, I will say
I don't hold Alan Moore nearly as high regard
as you do. How does that mean? It means you
put him on a pedestal is what I'm saying. They
have a better writer than Alan Moore. Jonathan
Hickman. No. Wrong. OK.
Dr. Manhattan and Laurie arrive amidst the carnage
in New York. Too late to do anything due to
the tachyon radiation from the explosion. Dr.
Manhattan traces the teleportation energy signature
to Karnak, where he, Laurie, Dan, and Rorschach
hunt down Adrian for what he did. Though Adrian
seemingly kills Dr. Manhattan in an intrinsic
field subtractor, Dr. Manhattan rebuilds himself.
Confronted by the other four, Adrian reveals
via television that his plan was a success
and that world leaders are calling for peace
amidst the tragedy. Each of them accept the
reality that Adrian's plan worked and agreed
to secrecy except for Rorschach, whom Dr. Manhattan
kills before informing Adrian that he's leaving
for a less complicated galaxy to create new
life. I can't remember, in the comic book, did
he say that he was leaving for a new galaxy
or was he leaving for a new world? Because in
the Watchmen HBO sequel, we saw that he went
to one of the moons of Jupiter, I believe, Europa,
if I'm remembering that correctly. which is
not in another galaxy. And I'm wondering which
adaptation got it incorrect. In the comic,
he said he was leaving the galaxy. Okay, so
the HBO series got it wrong then. Uh, yeah,
yeah it did. What are you trying to say? That
it's not good now? Why are you so defensive,
Jonathan? I just don't think you like the fact
that I keep attacking what you keep referring
to as the seminal work of the comic book medium.
Uh, yeah, because it is. And you can't accept
that. you think you're too good for it. No DC
work is ever going to be called seminal. Not
while I'm still alive. That could be arranged.
Laurie and Dan, now disguised as Sam and Sandra
Hollis, visit Laurie's mother Sally in a California
rest home, where Laurie reveals she knows the
comedian was her father. Upon leaving, Laurie
and Dan share renewed excitement for costumed
adventuring. In the final scene, employees of
the new frontiersmen are forced to find a new
story to run in their magazine now that the
government no longer allows the press to criticize
their former enemies. A junior staffer is asked
to look through a pile of public letters for
a story lead as his hand hovers above Rorschach's
journal. That's the end of the film. I always
liked that ending a lot, and I really like how
the HBO series ran with that too, where it
kind of became like this conspiracy among the
militia group. in that series. Even with like
the squid babies, you know, that kept the world
on its toes. That was interesting. What did
you think of the Sam and Sandra Hollis disguise?
Because the live action movie didn't run with
that. I don't see why not. I thought it was
a good ending for Dan and Laurie and I like
the way they, you know, paid homage to Hollis
and everything like that. In the end, the book
is definitely the best way to experience the
story. And while chapter two was better. than
chapter one. You know, it's still this abridged
animated adaptation that, yeah, may benefit
from increased action in the source material's
latter half, but ultimately it fails to capture
the impact of the book, largely because the
background threat of nuclear war plays second
fiddle to the character drama. Now I'm giving
chapter two three and a half out of five stars
a fresh rating on Rotten Tomatoes. That said
I'm actually not recommending this because
it's the second half of a story starting with
Chapter 1, which I don't recommend. And I don't
recommend this animated adaptation overall.
So you're giving it a fresh rating, but you're
saying you don't recommend it? Yes. Because
of Chapter 1's inferiority? Yes, actually.
Okay, yeah, I think that makes sense. You wouldn't
want people to see Chapter 2 on its own, right?
They coexist with each other, Chapter 1 and
Chapter 2. Right. I agree chapter 2 is better
than chapter 1, but if chapter 1 was a bigger
letdown then I recommend the films as a whole.
I'm really hoping that by me doing this it's
not going to give chapter 2 a 100% tomato meter
score because I don't think it deserves it.
I don't think this film really should have
ever been made. But I don't think it also deserves
to be shit on. The film exists in this weird
limbo of irrelevancy. Neither good nor bad,
just redundant. Here's what I will say. who
made chapters 1 and 2 liked the source material
enough to take a crack at this. I think their
passion shows in how faithful they tried to
make it, but ultimately it was a waste of time.
But you guys have good taste. Most DC things
are a waste of time. Really. So is your face.
But that does it for this review. AG9K, help
close us out.
Visit the show's website at dynamicduel.com
and follow us on Instagram at dynamicduelpodcast.
You can support the show on Patreon at patreon.com
slash dynamicduel and joining a tier that works
for you or by rating and reviewing dynamic duel
on apple podcasts, spotify, podchaser or on
our website. Don't forget to listen to the other
shows in the dynaMic podcast network, including
Max Destruction, Senjo World and Console Combat.
In our next episode, we are going to be reviewing
Craven the Hunter. I have my tickets and I am
expecting to be entirely whelmed. I think is
the best way to put it. Not underwhelmed, not
overwhelmed, just whelmed. Just whelmed, yeah,
yeah. That is it for this episode. We wanna
give a big thanks to our executive producers,
Ken Johnson. John Swarovski. Zachary Hepburn,
Dustin Balcom, Miggy Mathingian, Brandon Estregard,
Nathaniel Wagener, Levi Yaten, Austin Wieselowski,
AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam
Spies, Andrew Shunk, Dean Molesky, Devin Davis,
Joseph Kirsting, Josh Leiner, and Mike Williams
for helping make this podcast possible. We'll
talk to you guys next week. Up, up and away,
true believers. Who watches the watchman watching
the watchman? That's what I'd like to know.