This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
So not only are you supporting our podcast with
your purchase made this holiday season, but
Jonathan and I are also giving 10% of all proceeds
that we earn in the months of November and
December to stand up to cancer. So support a
great cause, support our show, and get 10%
off your order again with the code duel10 at
checkout. Which will only be good for this
week, so make sure you use that before December
7th at the end of this week. Thanks guys, and
on with the show.
Hey and welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast,
a weekly show where we review superhero films
and debate the superiority between Marvel and
DC by comparing their characters in stat-based
battle simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe. And I'm
his twin brother Johnny DC. And in this episode,
we are going to find out who would win in a
fight between the DC villain Copperhead and
the Marvel villain Scorpion. I was gonna say
that this is like a lizard-themed duel, but
uh... Yeah, only one of these guys are reptile
themed. Of course, Scorpion is an insect. So
I had kind of a brain fart right there. Actually,
scorpions aren't insects. They're arachnids.
Fuck you, Jonathan. It was right off the gate.
You're stupid. You're going down. I hope you
lose this match now. Don't correct me. It disgusts
me. Anyway, Jonathan and I are recording this
episode a little bit early. We're actually recording
this the week before Thanksgiving. And this
episode is actually coming out the week after
Thanksgiving. Initially, this episode was going
to be a review of Watchmen Chapter 2, but we
got a lot of stuff going on during the Thanksgiving
week. So we decided to put this episode out
now and next week we're going to be reviewing
Watchmen Chapter 2. Yeah, we had Thanksgiving.
I have a work trip. It's just a lot of stuff
going on. Plus it gives me, you know, more time
to sit with my thoughts after watching Watchmen
Chapter 2, which I have not done yet because
it's not out. Please bear with us because this
is actually a pretty bare-boned show. We're
not gonna have a no price segment. We're not
going to have any news. We're just gonna get
right into the duel. Right, but first we do
have to hear from our artificially intelligent
duel simulator, AJ9K, who has a quick message
for our listeners. Why hello there, do you want
even more from this podcast? Then become a
part of the dynamic duel community on Patreon,
where you can choose from three tiers. The
dynamic two-o tier gives you access to our Discord
chat server. The fantastic four tier gives
you two bonus episodes each month, and the X-Force
tier makes you an executive producer of this
show. Lastly, The Diner Mike podcast network
tier lets you create your own podcast using
this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe will
help you develop your show, provide graphic
support and consultation, and get you simulation
results. Pitch the twins your ideas via email
at dynamicduelpodcast at gmail.com. Check it
out at patreon.com slash dynamicduel. Pip pip
cheerio. Thanks AJ9K, and thanks to everyone
who supports the podcast. Right now we're not
sure what the upcoming episodes in the DynaMic
Podcast Network will be, but be sure to listen
to Max Destruction, which pits your favorite
action heroes from film and television against
each other, Senjou World, which speculates on
fights between fan favorite anime and manga
characters, and Console Combat, which simulates
battles between popular video game characters.
Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link
in our show notes to listen to all of the shows
in the DynaMic Podcast Network. But with that
out of the way, let's go ahead and get on to
the main event where we find out who would win
in a fight between Copperhead and Scorpion.
All right, Copperhead versus Scorpion. This
episode is coming out in lead up to the upcoming
Craven the Hunter movie that's coming out in
a few weeks. Of course, that film will be based
off of the Spider-Man villain known as Craven
the Hunter, but we've already done a duel episode
with Craven. We pit him against DC's Vixen.
So we were thinking of another Spider-Man villain
to do a duel episode with, and actually my favorite
Spider-Man villain of all time is Scorpion.
And it is a damn shame that we have not gotten
to a duel episode with him yet. So we're going
to fix that right now. Pitting Scorpion against
Copperhead, who was not an easy foe to come
up with. Took us a while to settle on Copperhead,
us and the executive producers. But essentially,
these guys are incredibly agile. They're strong
and in part, they're gifted that strength thanks
to the suits that they wear, which include these
long tails that can wrap people up. One guy
uses acid attacks. Another guy uses venom based
attacks. It was actually a hard sell once we
realized Copperhead could work. Yeah, I think
I primarily know Copperhead from the Suicide
Squad Hell to Pay animated movie in which he
was a member of the Suicide Squad team. And
he was pretty cool. He was like a cyborg with
like snake-like powers in that film. I'm assuming
that's what he's like in the comics. Not quite.
Well, we will find out all about him and Scorpion.
You know what's crazy is that I feel like Copperhead
has been better represented in the medium of
film than Scorpion has. Scorpion, again, my
favorite Spider-Man villain, has yet to make
an appearance in the films besides that stupid
cameo that was in Spider-Man Homecoming. I
think prominently he was best featured in Spider-Man
Into the Spider-Verse, although that was the
ultimate version of Scorpion. Copperhead wasn't
in any films either except for Hell to Pay.
Oh, he was also in a video game, although it
was the girl version of him. in Arkham Origins
and that was awesome. That was really cool.
Well, I mean, Scorpion's been in a lot of Spider-Man
video games, so I guess he has that going for
him. Can't wait to see who's gonna win this
fight, but to explain the methodology behind
our duels, let's go to our sentient duel simulator,
Alfred Jarvis 9000. AJ9K, tell our listeners
how you go about determining a winner in our
duel matchups. Yes, of course, sir. The way
I determine a winner between the contestants
is by running 1000 Monte Carlo simulations using
the characters' statistics. The Monte Carlo
simulation is a probabilistic model used to
determine outcomes through random sampling.
In this case, I randomised the statistics along
a normal distribution as a way to simulate
the many variables that can occur during battle.
The stat parameters are based on the official
Marvel power grid from which the DC characters'
statistics are extrapolated. Additional stat
categories are included such as range, damage
potential, versatility and perception in order
to create a more detailed and accurate simulation.
The results of the 1,000 simulations provide
a percentage of wins for each character. The
contestant with the higher percentage is declared
the victor, as they have a higher probability
to win any given battle. In an equitable pairing,
neither character should win 100% of the matches.
The comic book stories have shown that there's
even a way for Batman to defeat Superman, so
the confidence rate of my method falls in line
with the precedents that have been established
in the source material. My mathematical simulations
are without subjectivity or bias. Feats are
not the sole consideration, nor are fan votes
tabulated for determination of the winner. Thanks,
A.J. 9K. Before we run the simulations, though,
we like to break down each character's histories
and abilities before improvising a scenario
on how we imagine one of the 1,000 simulations
would play out beat for beat. And I believe
it's my turn to go first with the Marvel characters
backstory, so let me go ahead and tell you
all about Scorpion. McDonald Mac Gargan's early
life is shrouded in mystery, but he eventually
became a private investigator known for his
willingness to take on difficult and morally
questionable jobs. This reputation drew the
attention of Daily Bugle publisher J. Jonah
Jameson, who was determined to reveal how Peter
Parker consistently captured such astonishing
photographs of Spider-Man, whom you could learn
more about in his duel against Blue Beetle.
Jameson hired Gargan to shadow Parker, hoping
to uncover a secret connection. However, Peter
Parker's spider sense alerted him to Gargan's
presence each time, leaving Jameson frustrated
and ready to pursue a bolder strategy. Jameson
arranged for Gargan to undergo a risky procedure
with Dr. Farley Stillwell, a scientist exploring
genetic manipulation. In exchange for a $10,000
fee, Gargan agreed to become Stillwell's first
human test subject. His DNA was fused with
that of a scorpion, one of a spider's natural
predators, granting endurance and reflexes.
Stillwell also outfitted Gargan with a cybernetically
controlled mechanical tail, completing his
transformation into Scorpion. But while the
experiment made Gargan physically formidable,
it also had unforeseen mental consequences,
driving him toward insanity and sparking a
deep-seated aggression that he would later be
unable to control. Initially, Gargan reveled
in his new powers, believing they made him invincible.
His first encounters with Spider-Man reinforced
this confidence, as he defeated the webslinger
twice. However as Gargan's powers grew, so
did his hatred toward Jameson, whom he now saw
as the true architect of his monstrous transformation.
This contempt soon became an obsession, leading
Scorpion to attack Jameson at the Daily Bugle,
only to be foiled by Spider-Man in their third
battle. Despite being arrested, Gargan's animosity
toward Jameson, whom he saw as both his creator
and his enemy, would remain a driving force
for years to come. Over time, Gargan's animosity
turned him into a hardened mercenary, accepting
dangerous assignments that often brought him
into conflict with other heroes. As Gargan's
criminal career advanced, he became part of
the Masters of Evil supervillain team under
Egghead, joining forces to battle the Avengers,
though they were ultimately defeated. You can
learn more about the Masters of Evil in their
duel episode against the Legion of Doom. Gargan's
reputation for brutality grew, making him a
reliable go-to for villains who needed muscle
for their operations. Yet he remained haunted
by the life he had lost and the monstrous identity
he was now trapped in, leading him to believe
he can never remove his costume. Desperate
and mentally unstable, Scorpion attempted to
subject Jameson to an acid bath, a scheme foiled
by Captain Marvel, who threw Gargan into the
acid herself. Horribly burned and in agony,
Gargan retreated into the sewers, his sanity
slipping further. He would spend weeks in isolation,
spiraling deep into madness and becoming convinced
he was truly a monster. This self-loathing
and paranoia haunted him until another confrontation
with Spider-Man revealed that his monstrous
identity was more of a psychological prison
than a physical one. In a bid to regain his
sense of control, Gargan accepted offers from
corporate backers like Justin Hammer, who saw
value in enhancing Scorpion's deadly abilities.
Hammer outfitted him with a new suit and extended
his tail, equipping it with advanced weaponry.
but Gargan's volatility proved disastrous as
he repeatedly jeopardized Hammer's operations
with his inability to follow orders. Despite
these setbacks, Gargan continued to cling to
his criminal career, unable to give up his
vendetta against Jameson and Spider-Man. In
one of his most significant turning points,
Gargan was approached by Norman Osborn, who
sought to harness Gargan's hatred for Spider-Man.
Osborn, aka the Green Goblin, now aware of Spider-Man's
true identity, offered Gargan an upgraded suit.
and revealed Parker's secret to him. He instructed
Gargan to kidnap Peter's Aunt May if Osborn
was ever incarcerated. Gargan nearly completed
his mission when he encountered the Venom symbiote,
which offered him even greater power, becoming
the new monstrous Venom, whom you can learn
more about in our Clayface versus Venom duel
episode. As Venom, Gargan discovered newfound
powers, joining Osborn's Sinister 12 in a bid
to destroy Spider-Man. Though he was defeated,
Gargan enjoyed the raw powers the symbiote offered.
However, controlling the symbiote came at a
cost as his bloodlust drove Gargan to increasingly
savage acts. Concerned with his violent tendencies,
the government implanted electrical inhibitors
in Gargan's body, hoping to restrain the symbiote's
influence. Following the Skrull invasion, Osborn
elevated Gargan's status by assigning him to
the Dark Avengers, where he took on the public
persona of Spider-Man to present a twisted
reflection of the hero to the public. His hatred
for Jameson? Now New York's mayor led him to
orchestrate a gang war aimed at tarnishing Jameson's
reputation, plunging the city into chaos. When
Osborn's empire finally fell during the Siege
of Asgard, Gargan and the other Dark Avengers
were arrested, and the symbiote was forcibly
removed. Without it, Gargan experienced severe
health repercussions, his body having grown
dependent on the symbiote for stability. His
freedom came when Alastor Smythe, a villain
known as the Spider Slayer, broke him out of
prison and outfitted him with an advanced scorpion
suit. which included a life support system
and a quote-unquote scorpion sense similar to
Spider-Man's spider sense. Smite's intervention
provided Gargan with a semblance of normalcy,
but it also rekindled his obsession with revenge.
Together, the two staged a high-profile attack
on Jameson and his family, though Spider-Man
ultimately thwarted their plans. His ongoing
vendetta against Venom resurfaced after Eddie
Brock reclaimed the symbiote.
Gargan adopted a new identity, Virus, and acquired
a heavily weaponized suit. He pursued Venom
relentlessly, but was ultimately captured by
Codex, a symbiote hive ruler who forced him
to resume his Scorpion identity. Gargan eventually
accepted a position on the government-run symbiote
task force, targeting rogue symbiotes in a twisted
attempt at redemption. Powers-wise, Scorpion
is a mutate with Scorpion-human hybrid physiology.
This grants him superhuman strength, able to
lift around 20 tons. and enhanced running speed
around 50 miles per hour. His scorpion suit
grants him enhanced durability that renders
him bulletproof to small arms fire and he's
equipped with pincers and the gloves that allow
him to grasp onto walls and rip through solid
metal. Best of all though is his 10 foot long
mechanical tail that can whip at 100 miles
per hour and is dexterous enough to carry objects
or use as a springboard to launch himself three
stories into the air. The tip of his tail is
equipped with a poisonous barb. and from it
he can fire both laser blasts and corrosive
acid. While Scorpion is not a trained fighter,
he is an adept brawler and a gifted investigator.
That's Scorpion. Wait so you're telling me
I can get a suit like the Scorpion for just
10 G's? Not only a suit but also Scorpion DNA.
Eh it doesn't matter I don't have that anyway.
A guy could dream though, although I'm not
sure how much it costs to get Copperhead's suit.
But I would say it's even more oppressive than
Scorpion's and probably more expensive. Probably.
Well, I mean, Scorpion debuted in the 1960s,
so $10,000 in the 1960s now, it's got to be
at least $10 billion. Oh, Copperhead also appeared
in the 60s, the late 60s. Interesting. Let me
get into his backstory. The criminal known
as Copperhead first emerged in Gotham City as
a mysterious figure whose agility, stealth,
and cunning allowed him to execute a series
of audacious thefts. His costume, resembling
a snake's scales, included a prehensile tail
that he could use to bind an incapacity to
his victims, earning him the moniker Copperhead.
Though his true identity remained a mystery,
his modus operandi was distinct, striking swiftly
and vanishing without a trace. Copperhead's
contortionist skills and snake-like agility
made him nearly impossible to apprehend, confounding
Gotham's police force. Copperhead's first major
heist involved the theft of a tiara belonging
to a foreign dignitary visiting Gotham City.
Disguised as an elderly man, Copperhead infiltrated
the dignitary's heavily guarded quarters, stealing
the tiara before escaping into the shadows.
His theft drew the attention of Batman, who
enlisted the help of Batgirl and Wonder Woman
to help capture the slippery villain. The trio
set a trap for Copperhead using the golden
cask of Montezuma. a priceless artifact as bait.
Though Copperhead failed in his attempt to
steal it, the trap failed as well, and he successfully
evaded the heroes once again, disappearing
into Gotham's underworld. Shortly after, Copperhead
captured Wonder Woman during an encounter in
Gotham Park and brought her back to his lair.
Batman and Batgirl were able to track him,
however, to his hideout where they managed to
capture and arrest him. After escaping from
prison, Copperhead upgraded his suit. with help
from the Secret Society of Super-Villains,
who invited him to join their ranks. While working
for the Society, he collaborated with villains
like Gorilla Grodd and Star Sapphire on a series
of heists, the former of which you can learn
more about in our Gorilla Grodd vs. Psylocke
duel episode. Internal conflicts within the
group, however, led Copperhead to abandon his
associates after becoming suspicious of the
Society's leadership. As a freelance assassin,
Copperhead expanded his criminal endeavors
internationally. He was hired to assassinate
a French finance minister only to be thwarted
by Elongated Man, the first of several battles
against the hero across Europe. When the archdemon
Niron offered numerous villains upgraded powers,
Copperhead sold his soul to be transformed
into a human-snake hybrid. This new form enhanced
his physical abilities, granting him actual
venomous fangs, superhuman strength, and predatory
instincts. However, it also eroded his humanity.
making him more animalistic and driven by primal
urges. In his transformed state, Copperhead
became a vicious killer. He battled Superboy
in Hawaii, where his venomous bite managed
to pierce the young hero's skin. Though he was
temporarily defeated, Copperhead survived and
joined the Suicide Squad, only to betray the
mission and escape with his newfound freedom.
As his monstrous tendencies grew, Copperhead
devolved into a serial killer monster. consuming
the victims he slaughtered. His killing spree
ended when District Attorney Kate Spencer,
secretly the vigilante Manhunter, tracked him
down. In a brutal confrontation, Manhunter
killed Copperhead with an energy baton, ending
his reign of terror. By the time of his death,
Copperhead had claimed over 48 lives. Later,
Copperhead was resurrected as a member of the
Black Lantern Corps during the Blackest Night.
As a Black Lantern Zombie, He attacked Coast
City along other reanimated villains and attempted
to kill the Flash. However, he was ultimately
destroyed when Green Lantern annihilated his
Black Lantern ring. In post-Flashpoint continuity,
Copperhead underwent several incarnations. The
first was Samir Park, a snake-like metahuman
who joined the Seeker Society of Super-Villains.
This version of Copperhead was nearly successful
in killing the hero Black Canary, as he was
immune to her sonic scream due to his lack
of ears. She was rescued, however, by the Justice
League, and Copperhead continued working with
the Seeker Society up until his death at the
hands of Deathstroke, who betrayed the Seeker
Society to join Lex Luthor's and Justice League.
You can learn more about Black Canary, Deathstroke,
and Lex Luthor in their respective duels against
Black Widow, Deadpool, and Baron Zemo. After
Samir Park's death, the mantle of Copperhead
passed to a South American woman using the
alias Jane Doe. This version of Copperhead was
a deadly hitwoman and crime boss renowned for
her lethal, venomous attacks, rivaling the toxic
villainess Cheshire, who you can learn more
about in her duel against Silver Samurai. Copperhead
established herself as a prominent figure in
Central City's criminal underworld, taking over
her family's crime syndicate after serving
as a mercenary. Her tenure as a crime boss brought
her into conflict with several heroes, including
Batman and The Flash. When Two-Face placed a
bounty on Batman's head, Copperhead was among
the mercenaries who pursued him, tracking him
to a moving train. Though she attempted to
kill him, he evaded her by leaping into a nearby
river. Copperhead's activities eventually drew
the attention of The Flash, who arrested her
mercenary enforcers including Shrapnel, Black
Spider, and the Trigger Twins. This setback
forced Copperhead to negotiate with Captain
Cold. the rival crime lord encroaching on her
territory, who you can learn more about in
his duel against Pyro. Captain Cold betrayed
Copperhead, however, by planting a bomb in
a weapon's delivery. The Flash intervened to
save Copperhead from the explosion and apprehended
Captain Cold, though Copperhead herself avoided
prosecution due to insufficient evidence of
her involvement. This Copperhead was later jailed
in Iron Heights, prisoned by Superman, after
she attacked reporters at the Daily Planet.
An unnamed iteration of Copperhead, possibly
a reimagining of the original, recently appeared
as a copper-skinned criminal. This Copperhead
joined forces with Asp and Lady Viper to form
the Snake Gang, and were nearly successful
in defeating the Birds of Prey before the villainous
group was defeated and disbanded.
who traditionally wears a suit woven from experimental
elastic metal fibers coated in a polymer film.
This not only grants him enhanced durability,
flexibility, and the insurance that most physical
blows will glance right off of him, but it also
allows him to travel with surprising speed
due to his reduced friction and his knack for
slipping into tight spaces. The guy is basically
untouchable. The suit also has suction cups
at the ends of the limbs, allowing him to adhere
and maneuver across most solid surfaces, and
his helmet is equipped with sharp, fang-like
blades, coated with a toxin that causes paralysis
and eventual death after a half hour. He's
also an experienced martial artist, often using
his suit's heavy and stretchable tail to shatter
bones or even rock, or bind and crush his foes.
That's Copperhead. You know how I know that
Marvel is better than DC? Uh, no I don't know.
Because when DC gets a supervillain group of
snake-themed villains together, they call them
the Snake Gang. Yet when Marvel does it, they
call it the Serpent Society. That's a badass
name. That's how Marvel's better. Okay, I'm
pretty sure the Serpent Society name was already
taken by the time the Snake Gang was formed,
so you should go f yourself. Serpent Society?
Oh, that sounds a lot like the Secret Society
to me, of which Copperhead was already a part
of. You mean the Secret Society of Super-Villains?
Well, yeah, that's the longer version of the
name. Okay. How long is Copperhead's tail?
Uh, it could stretch. It could stretch to wrap
a man up at least twice. So, comparatively
to Scorpion's 10-foot long tail, Copperhead
has kind of like a chode going on. I didn't
realize this was a tail measuring contest, my
friend. Doesn't matter the size. It's how you
use it. Well, let's find out how these guys
use their tails as we get into the match.
Where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
Dynomic Podcast Network presents... Console
Combat, where video game legends brawl every
Monday. Dynamic Duel, where comic book titans
smash every Tuesday. Max Destruction, where
the world is at its limit. The Dynomic Podcast
Network presents... TV and action heroes battle
every Wednesday, and Sendro World, where anime
champions clash every Thursday. Join us as
we speculate on the matches and armed with the
power of mathematical simulations, discover
who will emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com,
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
Now that we got their histories and abilities
out of the way, we're going to speculate on
how one of the 1000 simulated matches will go.
The winner is determined by simulations, not
our speculation, but it's fun to imagine how
the fight could play out. AJ9K, what are the
rules of our speculation? Well, I should say
there are no rules, other than the characters
have no prior knowledge of the other going into
the fight. All they are aware of starting out
is that the other character is a threat that
needs to be eliminated. For the speculation...
The contestants will begin approximately 50
meters apart in a nondescript environment that
will have no bearing on the match itself, as
no environmental statistics are considered
in my simulations. The contestants must earn
victory on their own merit. Alright then, let's
get into it. Copperhead and Scorpion meet on
the battlefield. Who goes first? So I'm going
to say that Scorpion goes first. And like they
seem about the same in terms of speed anyway.
So Scorpion... is gonna use his prehensile scorpion
tail to launch himself into the air with this
like giant leap that covers the entire 50 meter
distance between them and as he lands near
copperhead scorpion's gonna lunge with his tail
in a move that just impales copperhead on his
tail bar. Well I mean of course copperhead is
gonna see scorpion leaping towards him it's
very telegraphed so just before scorpion's tail
impales him copperhead's gonna You know, dart
to the side, just enough for Scorpion's barb
to glance off of his suit's slick surface.
At which point, Copperhead's gonna, you know,
drop to the ground, slide underneath Scorpion
between his legs, and then slip up and over
his back and just wrap his tail around Scorpion's
neck, crushing his throat like it was just nothing.
You dumbass! You don't want to attack Scorpion
from behind. That's the worst place to attack
Scorpion, okay? So... As Copperhead's choking
Kim out from behind with his tail, Scorpion's
just gonna fire a green laser beam from his
tail that's gonna tag Copperhead right in the
back of the head and essentially just blow
his brains out. Dude, blow his brains out? What
are you talking about? Like not only is Copperhead
wearing a metallic helmet for protection, but
it's also coated in a gel that's heat resistant.
So yeah, he's fine. Heat resistant gel on his
head? Yeah. Okay, alright, so the laser beam
didn't work because fucking lube boy is all
lubed up over here. Ha ha ha! Scorpion's getting
choked out, he's about to pass out, so instead
he's gonna use his tail to wrap around Copperhead's
body and just yank him off of him and slam him
into the ground. Okay, but I mean, the stronger
Scorpion's tail wraps around Copperhead, you
know, the faster Copperhead's just gonna get
squeezed out of that tail's grasp, because again,
he's super slippery. Ha ha ha! So... Copperhead
slips away from Scorpion and he slides across
the ground in this zigzagging, like confusing
motion. So Scorpion doesn't know if he's coming
at him or if he's moving away from him until
it's too late. Copperhead's gonna lunge at Scorpion
and sink his helmet's fangs into Scorpion's
neck, poisoning him. Scorpion has Scorpion Sense
with his new suit that Smythe gave him. So
his Scorpion Sense activates, it alerts him
to Copperhead's attack, and as his big ass
mouth is about to chomp down on him. Scorpion
grabs Copperhead by the jaw with his pincer
gloves on his suit and he's gonna use their
superior grip to just straight up rip Copperhead's
jaw off with his hands. Big ass helmet you mean.
What? Big ass helmet. It's not his actual mouth.
You said Scorpion is larger, but Copperhead
has a bigger helmet. Yeah, I was talking about
his mouth helmet. I hate that phrase. What are
we saying? I never want to say mouth helmet
again for the rest of my life. But yeah, Scorpion
uses his pincer gloves to rip off Copperhead's
helmet. Or at least he tries to, but his pincer
just slipped right off. Copperhead's helmet
is just too slippery. Well, if Scorpion's pincers
slip off of Copperhead's helmet, then they're
just going to slip right onto Copperhead's exposed
face. And then Scorpion just rips the guy's
face right off. There's nothing he can do with
his face anymore. Oh damn. Maybe he should
lube up his face too next time. Well, I mean,
actually, with Scorpion's hands so close to
Copperhead's fangs, that was just the opportunity
that Copperhead needed to twist his head and
pierce Scorpion's hands, paralyzing them and
causing Scorpion to drop Copperhead, at which
point all Copperhead has to do is evade Scorpion's
attacks as the paralysis spreads and Scorpion
soon dies from the venom. You said it takes
like half an hour for Copperhead's venom to
kill somebody? Yeah, but in the meantime they
slowly lose the ability to move. A half an
hour is a long ass time. Like eventually you
would think that Scorpion would get a shot
in. The more time that passes the less likely
that would be the case. But I think you're
forgetting an important detail in that Scorpion
has armored gloves. So no, Copperhead does
not bite through his hands and I say Scorpion...
does rip off Copperhead's face with his pincers,
and then he shoots acid down the face hole for
his Mortal Kombat fatality. Oh, what scorpion
is this? You know, scorpion. Okay. I say you're
dreaming, because scorpion's hands may be armored,
but Copperhead's fangs are sharp, and they'll
manage to puncture a spot on the wrist where
it's unarmored, like at an exposed joint or
something. Well, let's find out. We'll go ahead
and leave the match there. We'll input these
characters' stats, run the simulations, and
find out which scenario happens when we come
back with a winner. Yeah, either Copperhead
managed to pierce Scorpion with his poisonous
fangs, slowly paralyzing and killing him, or
Scorpion straight up rips off Copperhead's face
and burns his body inside the suit with acid.
AG9K, run the stats. Running calculations, processing
results, simulations complete. Copperhead is
a pretty cool character. I think he was a pretty
solid match up for Scorpion. The characters
had a lot of stats that evened out, including
movement speed, durability, intelligence, and
they came pretty close in other stats like perception
and versatility. Yeah, I think the two biggest
discrepancies between their stats were strength
and evasiveness. Copperhead. is really damn
evasive. I had no idea that he was such a slippery
character until our speculation. But Scorpion
is stronger than Copperhead. We did say that
Copperhead was a better fighter, but Scorpion
is more versatile considering he can do everything
Copperhead can do, but he also has, you know,
the laser beams and the acid. So with all that
in consideration, Jonathan, who do you think
is coming out on top in this match? I think
both characters are pretty impressive. I'm
hoping Copperhead comes out Not 100% sure. Instagram
definitely disagrees with me in our poll so
far. It looks like 67% of people believe that
Scorpion will win this match. So about two
thirds. Well, let's see if the stats agree with
them. AJ9K, the results please. Hey, Yuasa.
All right, the winner between Copperhead and
Scorpion is Scorpion. I figured, here I am!
Rock you like a hurricane! You know, that song
that's sung by the scorpions, Rock you like
a hurricane. Anyway, Scorpion wins. Is there
a band called Copperhead? Probably, but they
probably suck. Anyway, this wasn't that close
of a match. Scorpion beat Copperhead 627 times
out of the 1000 battles, whereas Copperhead
only won 373 matches. So it was Scorpion's
62.7% win rate over Copperhead's 37.3% win rate.
Well, that's dumb. In the end, Scorpion was
just too strong. He had a slight range advantage
considering that Copperhead doesn't really
have much range at all except for his shorter
tail and versatility. I think in the end, we
learn here that size actually does matter. Yeah,
the size of the helmet, right? And being lubed
helps. Clearly not enough in Copperhead's case.
But that does it for this duel guys. Congrats
to Marvel fans for the win this go round. AJ9K
helped close this out. Thanks for listening
to Dynamic duel. Visit the show's website at
dynamicduel.com and follow us on Instagram
at dynamicduelpodcast. You can support the show
on Patreon at patreon.com slash dynamicduel
and joining a tier that works for you, or by
rating and reviewing Dynamic duel on Apple
Podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser or on our website.
Don't forget to listen to the other shows in
the DynaMic Podcast Network, including Max
Destruction, Senjow World and Console Combat.
In our next episode, as we mentioned earlier,
we will be doing a review of the direct to
video animated DC film Watchmen Chapter 2, the
conclusion in a two-part animated Watchmen
adaptation. Yeah, we found the first part to
be redundant, but at least the second half
of the Watchmen story has a lot more exciting
things happen. So we'll see if it's any better.
But that does it for this episode. We want to
give a big thanks to our executive producers.
Ken Johnson, John Swarovski, Zachary Hepburn,
Dustin Balcom, Miggy Mathen-Geehan, Brandon
Estregard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Austin
Wazilowski, AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Gil
Camacho, Adam Spies, Andrew Shunk, Dean Maleski,
Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, Josh Leiner,
and Mike Williams for helping make this podcast
possible. We'll talk to you guys next week.
Up up and away, true believers. I'm a snake.
I'm a thnike. I'm a thlithery little thnakey
thnike.