This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
Welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin brother, Marvelous
Joe. And in this episode, we are doing a throwback
review to the 1993 animated theatrical film,
Batman, Mask of the Phantasm. We were interested
in reviewing it now. because we just got done
reviewing X-Men 97. And of course, both that
cartoon and Batman, the animated series for
which this film is a tie in to were both popular
Saturday morning cartoons that a lot of us 90s
kids grew up with. Yeah, it's a nostalgia episode.
The question is, does Batman mask the phantasm
hold up to the animated series in the same
way that X-Men 97 held up to the 90s series?
We'll find out later on this episode. Before
that we're going to break down the comic book
movie news from this past week, of which there
was only one major news item, and that was the
trailer for Venom 3. There was some casting
announcements made for the new Superman movie,
but other than Beck Bennett as Steve Lombard,
I didn't really have too much to say about the
casting choices. But as always, we list our
segment times in our episode description, so
feel free to check out the show notes if you
want to skip ahead to a particular topic. Our
artificially intelligent duel simulator AJ9K
has a quick message for our listeners, so listen
up. Why hello there, do you want even more
from this podcast? Then become a part of the
dynamic duel community on Patreon, where you
can choose from three tiers. The dynamic two-oh
tier gives you access to our Discord chat server.
The fantastic four tier gives you two bonus
episodes each month, and the X-Force tier makes
you an executive producer of this show. Lastly,
the Diner Mike podcast network tier lets you
create your own podcast using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and consultation,
and get you simulation results. Pitch the twins
your ideas via email at dynamicduelpodcast at
gmail.com. Check it out at patreon.com slash
dynamicduel. Pip pip cheerio. Thanks AJ9K and
thanks to everyone who supports the podcast.
Quick note, watching or sharing our YouTube
videos actually helps us a lot. We've recently
been putting up some shorts. So make sure to
check those out and please subscribe.
On the Sanjo World podcast, host Zachary Heppard
speculates on fights between fan favorite anime
and manga characters. The show is currently
on a season hiatus, so this is the perfect
time for you anime fans to catch up on Sanjo
World's 40 episode library. And on the Console
Combat podcast, hosts John and Dean find out
who would win in fights between popular video
game characters. In yesterday's episode, they
found out who would win in a fight- between
Mr. Incredible from the Incredibles video game
against the Thing from, I'm guessing the 2005
Fantastic Four movie tie-in video game, or maybe
like the Thing from the Marvel Nemesis game.
I'm not sure. Either way, sounds like a great
matchup. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or click
the link in our show notes to listen to all
of the shows in the DynaMic Podcast Network.
But with that out of the way, quick to the no
prize. A no prize is an award Marvel used to
give out to fans. Our version, the Dynamic Duel
No Prize, is a digital award we post on Instagram
for the person that we feel gave the best answer
to our question of the week. Last week's question
was, who's your favorite Green Lantern and why?
And of course this was coming off of the news
that the showrunners for the upcoming Lanterns
television series in the DCU was Damon Lindelof
and Chris Mundy. We got four different answers
for this week's question, so we're going to
break down our honorable mentions before announcing
this week's No Prize winner. Our first honorable
mention goes to Judson Batty who said, Hi guys,
Judson Batty here. I'd say my favorite Green
Latin is Sinestro. I feel like the stories when
he is a Green Latin and not yellow in the Sinestro
core just some of the most interesting, whether
it's the early ones where he's training how
Jordan or prequels with Abin Suh. or even the
new 52 when he gets the Green Lantern ring
back. I feel like they just make for a really
interesting reads because it really pushes
the boundaries of what the ring and the core
allow to happen. Good to hear from you again,
Jutsson from the land down under. For everyone
who is confused by us claiming that Jutsson
was from Austria or from New Zealand, those
people need to watch Dumb and Dumber and Flight
of the Conchords. Yeah, totally. But his answer
of Sinestro is actually an interesting one,
considering Sinestro is, of course, one of the
lead enemies, if not the lead enemy. of the
Green Lantern Corps. He started off as a Green
Lantern but then defected, and recently for
a time came back to being a Green Lantern, and
even a White Lantern. He's a very complex character,
if you don't know too much about him, I definitely
suggest listening to our Sinestro vs Magneto
duel episode. Yeah, he trained Hal Jordan. He
was, I think, really good friends with Abin
Sur, who was Hal Jordan's predecessor. And that's
pretty much what I remember from your backstory
on him, Jonathan. Wow, you also need to go back
and listen to that episode. That was like five
years ago. Come on, give me a break. Good answer,
Judson. Our next honorable mention goes to
Mickey Mathingian, who said, it was because
of Mickey and my favorite Green Lantern is
Jon Stewart. I think you guys have asked this
before, but I'm going to answer it again. He
was my favorite because of the Justice League
cartoon. I grew up on that. So he was like
the first Green Lantern I was introduced to.
I also just really like his story. with him
being one of DC's first African-American superheroes
and the fictional backstory, too, with him
being an architect and a really good sniper.
Yeah, thanks, guys. Yeah, I didn't grow up
really with the Justice League cartoon that
was a little bit after my time when I was in
high school. So I never really considered Jon
Stewart to be like the Green Lantern. But just
from doing this podcast and doing research on
the various Green Lanterns for our duel episodes.
Jon Stewart has become my personal favorite
Green Lantern. It used to be Kyle Raynor and
then it was Hal Jordan, but I just love the
backstory of Jon Stewart, how he's this Green
Lantern of prophecy and yet his military and
architecture background kind of blend the best
of all worlds for each of the human Green Lantern
characters. If we were left with just one human
Green Lantern, I would definitely pick Jon Stewart.
I would agree. I think... between the recent
Green Lantern vs. Quasar episode we did and
the Green Lantern Beware My Power animated
feature film. I think Jon Stewart has quickly
become my favorite Green Lantern as well. Fantastic
answer, Miggy. Our final honorable mention goes
to Cyrus Moore, who said, Hey guys, Cyrus Moore
here. Although my favorite Green Lantern is
Kyle Rayner, I feel like he's gonna be a popular
answer. So therefore I'd like to go with Reloc
Hag, who is just a really cool Lantern to start
with. He's an alpha lantern. He has a really
interesting backstory. He's a centaur. I mean,
you can't get any better than that. Okay, I'm
not gonna lie. I had to Google this guy. I
know nothing about him other than he looks like
a total badass. Seriously, he has one of the
coolest designs out of any Green Lantern ever.
Like I know the Green Lanterns span all the
races in the galaxy and the universe, but this
particular centaur race is just a really cool
design. Reloc Hag, it's spelled R-E-L-O-K. H-A-G.
If you don't know him, look him up. I think
you'll be similarly impressed. And the fact
that he's an alpha lantern, like that just
gives him some extra cred in my book because
those guys are awesome. The hell is an alpha
lantern? They're kind of described as the internal
affairs of the green lanterns, but they're
essentially elite lanterns. Interesting. Now,
Cyrus also mentioned Kyle Rayner, who was your
initial favorite Green Lantern, Jonathan? Yes,
yeah, he was the Green Lantern that I personally
grew up with in the comics when I began reading
DC Comics. He was, in fact, the only Green
Lantern that existed at that time. So he was
my favorite by default. So, great answer, Cyrus.
But the winner of this week's No Prize is...
Peter Trull, who said... What's up, Dynamic
Dudes, it's Peter. Uh, my favorite Green Lantern
has got to be... Hal Jordan easily. He's the
one I grew up on the most and he's literally
one of the greatest lanterns of all time. He's
mentioned in different comics, several of them,
that he is the greatest lantern. Not even greatest
green lantern, but other lanterns of all the
lantern core. Like he is the best. So what
else would you think other than Hal Jordan as
the best green lantern of all time? Thanks
guys. So the only reason we didn't give the
no prize to Miggie for his answer of Jon Stewart
is because one, I think We have in fact asked
this question before, and two, because Hal
Jordan is the iconic Green Lantern. As much
as I like Jon Stewart, I have to admit that
when it comes to other forms of media and just,
you know, the public perception of the character
with the movie and everything, yeah, everyone
knows Hal Jordan as the quintessential Green
Lantern. The dude can wield basically any ring
and is just a master of it. I remember you
had a graphic novel called Green Lantern Fear
itself, in which there was a segment at the
end where Kyle Rayner and Alan Scott were discussing
the greatest Green Lantern of all time, and
they were talking about how Hal Jordan was the
best of them. He was, you know, the specter
at the time, he was dead. But I always think
back to that when I think about the greatest
Green Lanterns and how if you were to ask the
core themselves who the best among them is,
a lot of them would actually pick Hal Jordan.
Yeah, maybe. Or they'd be like... Oh, that
guy who killed all of us? Fuck that guy. He
redeemed himself. He's all good. He's good.
He was possessed. What are you gonna do? That's
true. But great answer, Peter. You win this
week's note prize. If you're the listener, want
a shot at winning your own note prize. Stay
tuned to later on in this episode when we'll
be asking another question of the week. And
now that that's done, on to the news.
This past week we got the first official trailer
for the Venom The Last Dance movie which is
coming out in October. And right off the bat
I just want to talk about my kind of love-hate
relationship with the Venom franchise because
I actually really liked the first Venom movie.
As you will learn if you listen to our review
I think we gave it about three and a half stars
and then I really disliked the Venom sequel
Let There Be Carnage which I think we gave
about two or two and a half stars in our review.
This third movie is really just a big question
mark as to whether or not it'll be closer to
the first film and what made that so enjoyable
or closer to the second film which was kind
of a dumpster fire. And honestly, I couldn't
really tell you judging off of this trailer.
It kind of looks like it's a mix of both. There
are some great moments where we see Venom take
on a group of criminals running a dog fighting
ring it looks like. The intro to this trailer
was really fantastic. But then there were like
these jokes that were sprinkled through that
it made me think of the second movie. And one
of the biggest criticisms we had of Venom let
there be carnage is that Venom became a parody
of himself. You know, it's always kind of cute
and fun to make Venom a quirky character. But
these filmmakers have to understand that they
have to do it within reason. You know, if Venom
starts making too many jokes. then he doesn't
really feel like who he is from the comics.
You know, the jokes have to be used sparingly
and that's how you get the most out of them.
Yeah, I've never really saw Venom as a comedic
character. So I was actually taken aback by
the first movie and pretty much despised the
second. There are jokes sprinkled in this trailer,
but by this time I'm familiar enough with what
they're going with to not entirely hate it.
Honestly, the first time I saw this trailer,
I couldn't tell if it was gonna be like over
the top ambitious or actually more low key.
It looks like the primary antagonists of this
movie are going to be General Orwell Taylor.
It looks like played by Chiwetel Ejiofor who
is in charge of like this elite military symbiote
hunting squad called the jury. In the comic
books, the jury were like a bunch of Iron Man
knockoffs. Like they literally stole blueprints
to the Iron Man suit and then made their own
venom fighting suits of armor. But here they
look a little bit more generic. I'm not sure
if that's them being carried on that helicopter
and then being dropped into the water to fight
Venom, but it really looks like that's who
they are. In addition to the jury and General
Taylor, it looks like we're also getting other
symbiotes and the xenophage who are alien monsters
that actually feed off of symbiotes. We see
one attack Venom on top of an airplane, which
was a pretty crazy looking scene. So it's interesting
that Venom is kind of facing threats from both
sides. The humans coming after him in the form
of General Taylor and the jury and the clintar
coming after him in the form of other symbiotes
in the xenophage. So Eddie Brock looks like
he's being put through the wringer even more
so than he usually is in these films and you
know, he goes through a lot physically throughout
the course of this franchise. And Tom Hardy
I think does a fantastic job of portraying
the wear and tear that the symbiote takes on
his body and the duelity of the character and
everything. And that's definitely one of the
things I'm looking forward to the most and
seeing. in this upcoming movie because these
characters have been through a lot together.
Yeah, Eddie Brock and the symbiote, there's
a bromance there. It's almost like a buddy
comedy in a way that the way they play off each
other. And there were definitely some like
iconic scenes in this trailer that kind of played
up on that with like Eddie Brock trying to
master the we are venom line with venom. That
was weird because they did it correctly in
the first movie. So you think they would, you
know, have it down already. That's true. But
also, I'm thinking of Eddie Brock riding the
venom symbiote horse. That was pretty cool.
I remember there was a moment in the Venom comics
when Flash Thompson was Agent Venom. He had
acquired the symbiote at the time and he had
used the symbiote in a bunch of weird ways,
including some ways that I hate. Like he turned
a car that he was driving into the Venomobile
by having the symbiote take over the car, which
I thought was kind of bullshit because a car
is not an organic being. The way they had the
symbiote take over a horse makes so much more
sense to me and I think just works. really well.
I can't wait to see the venom horse in the
movie. How do you feel about General Taylor
apparently being a variant of Baron Mordo?
Because of the casting? Yeah. That's a little
weird right? You know if we're talking about
the multiverse, there's a very strange shot
in this trailer that I know a lot of people
are talking about where we see General Taylor
acquire the sample from the bar in Mexico that
Eddie Brock left behind in the end credits scene
for Spider-Man No Way Home. Apparently that
piece of symbiote was left behind in the Marvel
Cinematic Universe apart from the Sonyverse
and yet we see General Taylor somehow acquiring
that sample. It's really unclear what's going
on here, whether or not Eddie Brock leaving
the sample behind in the MCU is going to be
retconned to have been actually left behind
in the Sonyverse or what the hell is going
on? Who the hell knows? Yeah, Marvel and Sony's
relationship right now is like really weird.
It's like, are they together? Aren't they? It's
a situationship, as the kids are saying these
days, and that extends into, you know, the upcoming
Spider-Man four and everything like that. But
I'm really interested in seeing how this movie
even pertains to the multiverse or if it even
does. And if so, how Tom Holland is going to
get the symbiote, if he will. If that's going
to happen in Secret War, that would be really
cool. But yeah, we'll see what happens. It
was really cool to see Detective Mulligan back
as Toxin, although we didn't get to see him
in his Toxin form in this trailer. But we know
that he acquired the symbiote, which was an
offshoot of the Carnage symbiote in the last
movie. It'll be interesting to see how he factors
into the story, whether or not, you know, like
he's the one that's reaching out to the Klintar
home planet and bringing all these aliens or
not. but he does say that as long as Venom
lives, everyone, everything will end. So the
trailer really tries to sell us on the idea
that Venom or Eddie Brock may be dying in this
movie. I'm not really buying it. You know,
even the poster says, till death do they part.
I don't think either Eddie Brock or Venom are
actually dying, but it is a great way to try
to, you know, convince people to come see it
in the theaters, considering that most likely,
you know, this will be the last Venom movie.
I'm really hoping though that he still shows
up maybe in a Spider-Man movie, but we'll see.
Yeah, anytime studios say that something is
the and now, I'm like, but is it? I mean, Hugh
Jackman's coming back as Wolverine. Right. Yeah,
that can happen. Anything can happen. But again,
the movie comes out on October 25th of this
year. We'll see if it's more of the first Venom
movie or more like the second Venom movie as
it closes out this trilogy of films. But speaking
of trilogies, that brings us to our question
of the week.
What Marvel or DC character do you think has
had the most successful trilogy of films and
why? And we'll go ahead and count characters
that have had four films, such as Thor or Superman,
you know, just count like the first three films
of their franchise, and we want to know which
one you thought was the best. And that includes
old franchises too. Can't wait to hear you
guys' answers! Record your answer at dynamicduel.com
by clicking on the red microphone button in
the bottom right-hand corner of the screen.
which will prompt you to leave us a voicemail.
Your message could be up to 30 seconds long,
and don't forget to leave your name in case
we include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a dynamic
duel no prize that we'll post to Instagram.
Be sure to answer before June 15th.
That does it for all the news for this episode,
now let's go ahead and move on to the main
event where we review the 1993 animated film,
Batman Mask of the Phantasm.
Alright, Batman Mask of the Phantasm was a 1993
animated film that, unlike a vast majority
of DC's animated projects, had a theatrical
release. It was a feature film tie-in to the
popular 90s animated television series, and
though I didn't see this movie in theaters
when it came out, I became aware of the critical
hype surrounding this film as I got older and
still saw the movie when I was relatively young.
This was after I read Frank Miller's Batman
Year One comic arc, however, which came out
in 1987. When the movie came out in 1993, Mask
of the Phantasm was the closest thing non-comic
readers had to an origin of sorts for how Bruce
Wayne became Batman until Batman Begins. In
my opinion though, and this is the same opinion
I had when I first saw the movie, Phantasm is
kinda over-hyped and comparatively not as good
as Batman Year One, Batman Begins, and other
tales of Batman's origin. It's also not terrible,
however. It's not bad. It's actually pretty
good. I want to be clear. I'd still recommend
it to people, so if you haven't seen it yet,
you should consider checking it out before
we get into spoilers in this review. Yeah, I
mean, if you're a 90s kid, you most certainly
have already seen this film because it was pretty
ubiquitous along with the television show back
when we were children. I think we first saw
this movie at home back in the glory days of
VHS. Yes, yeah, I think that's correct. Just
for some quick backstory regarding the film,
Mask of the Phantasm was made because Warner
Brothers sought to capitalize on the success
Fox was having with the WB Batman character
in Batman the Animated Series, which Warner
Brothers let Fox use for that series and which
debuted on television a year prior to this
film's release. The film was originally intended
to be released directly to video, though halfway
through production, Warner Bros. decided to
release the film in theaters, forcing the animators
to meet a highly aggressive production schedule.
And for as much praise as I've seen critics
give this film in regards to its stylish animation,
I feel like they just hadn't seen much animation
back then in general. Because by this point,
we'd already had groundbreaking animated films
like Akira and Mask of the Phantasm seems super
basic in comparison. Well... Yeah, there was
a lot of 80s anime stuff that was truly groundbreaking
in how they approached more mature subject
matter in the medium of animated film. This
movie was animated exactly like how the Saturday
Morning Cartoon was, maybe with a little bit
more detail and frames and everything like
that. But I think if you had never been exposed
to that sort of 1940s minimalistic style, you
would still be impressed by it. Yeah, I've seen
a few critics. praise its Art Deco style, but
I'm like, well, have you not been watching the
cartoon? Because it's there as well. It's awesome.
I agree. Bruce Tim's style will always be iconic
to me. The Art Deco style is one of my favorite
styles by far. And while I'm glad that we've
kind of moved past it, I understand why it
became so influential to a lot of DC animated
work in the following decades. Yeah, that sort
of retrofuturism is a pretty awesome style that
I think suits DC really well. Now from start
to finish, the entire film was completed in
only eight months, which is insane. It's actually
pretty interesting. Half the movie was animated
in a 4-3 aspect ratio intended for squarish
television screens from that time. So to meet
the animation deadline, the production studios
had to simply crop their work into a wider 16
by 9 ratio for theater screens. So there's
a lot that was animated that was left on the
cutting room floor of sorts. but that full
version is a special feature on the digital
and disc versions of the movie. I like watching
it in the 4-3 ratio largely because I don't
think the scale of the film really suits a
theatrical format. To me, this movie always
played like an extended two or three part television
series episode. Yes, I agree. I definitely agree.
There was just a kind of a lack of spectacle.
As good as the story is, I just don't think
it holds a candle to some of the spectacles
that we get from animated films. But certainly
today, but you know, even in the early 2000s
and stuff. Yeah, it's lacking spectacle. It's
lacking a number of things. I've always felt
like the Batman mask of the fantasy movie was
missing something. And in doing my research
for this review, I realized what that was. Arguably,
you could say fantasy was a work of corporate
passion rather than artistic passion. Bruce
Timm created Batman the animated series to
tell Batman's iconic comic stories in a similar
fashion as the Max Fleischer Superman cartoons
that he grew up with. But Phantasm was something
of a cash grab by Warner Brothers in the same
way the Hobbit films or the Matrix Resurrections
or the Fantastic Beasts films were. Those films
just lacked the same creative spirit and life
that the filmmakers breathed into the films
that inspired those other works. I think that's
especially evident in Mask of the Phantasm
because none of the story elements ended up
being carried over to the animated series itself.
Because there are a lot of unanswered questions
by the end of the film that good writers, if
they cared enough, would have answered, such
as, you know, where did Andrea Beaumont get
her powers? Or why did Bruce specifically choose
the symbol of the bat? Or even what happened
to Joker at the end of the film? Yeah, there
were a lot of, I guess, plot holes, you could
call them, although they didn't like hamper
the story. I guess they're more unanswered
questions that were left unresolved. So a lack
of closure. I also wondered things like why
did Andrea even court Councilman Reeves and
why didn't she kill him? Basically, considering
that he gave up her father. I think it was her
plan to kill him if the Joker hadn't already
gotten to him. That's just speculation, though.
That's a good question. Maybe she knew the
Joker would go after him. Who knows? Right.
Now. If the film doesn't succeed in my opinion
in regards to story or animation, one of several
things it does succeed in is the theme, particularly
vengeance and duty. For both Batman and the
Phantasm, the film presents these parallel
arcs, these internal struggles for both of the
titular characters that highlight the conflict
between personal fulfillment and societal obligation
in their individuel pursuits of justice. most
interesting thing about this film to me are
the questions it posits about Batman's nature.
Now the filmmakers initially denied it, but
much of the story from this film was borrowed
from the comic book storyline Batman Year 2,
in which Batman fought a skull mask wearing,
scythes for hands vigilante that turned out
to be the father of a woman Bruce Wayne proposed
to. Spoilers, if you haven't read that, sorry.
But it was so obvious that that's where they
got a lot of the story from that the writer
of Batman year two Mark Barr Approached to
DC Comics president Paul Levitz about it and
Levitz actually agreed to give Barr a portion
of the film's earnings as well As financial
credit for the creation of the Phantasm character,
which is pretty cool Now the Phantasm never
appeared in the mainstream comics until recently
introduced in a run by Tom King Who has also
largely run with the same themes presented
in Mask of the Phantasm such as whether or not
Batman can ever find love, get married, be
happy, and still be Batman. But let's touch
more on Batman and the themes in the character
breakdown. Now Batman slash Bruce Wayne was
voiced by Kevin Conroy, who, as we've stated
numerous times on this podcast, is perfect as
Batman. And this film showcases one of the
best examples of the heart and emotion he was
capable of bringing to the role. Yeah, I don't
think we've ever seen Batman as emotional as
he was in this story. You know, usually he's
kind of a stoic badass, but in this, you know,
we actually see him cry, you know, and he's
like weeping and like pleading with his dead
parents and everything like that. So, this
movie is just a testament to Kevin Conroy. This
was actually early in his Batman career and
he went on to, you know, really define the character
I think for a lot of people. Rest in peace.
Yes, RIP Kevin Conroy. Now in the film, Bruce
grapples with his identity as Batman and his
desire for a normal life with his former fiancee,
Andrea Beaumont. When Bruce's past with Andrea
resurfaces, he's forced to confront these unresolved
emotions regarding his own personal desires
and how they conflict with his sense of duty
as Gotham's protector. Ultimately, Bruce accepts,
albeit- reluctantly perhaps that the sacrifices
inherent to his role as Batman, this duty to
Gotham City and vengeful crusade, transcends
his own happiness. And the arc of him realizing
that was a pretty profound one I would say in
this movie, and again a very emotional one.
The line of him at his parents grave where he's
saying I never expected to be happy or something
along those lines was unbelievable. And still
watching the film to this day kind of gets
me the fact that this guy would sacrifice his
life essentially to protecting others is like
the definition of heroism. It was really tragic
that moment when he was basically, you know,
begging his parents to break his promise to
them. and step away from the role of Batman
and be happy with a wife and family and everything
like that. It was particularly tragic because
you can assume, especially as a parent, that
Batman is not what the Waynes would want for
their son Bruce. You know, they would actually
want him to be happy and to move on from the
tragedy of their deaths and not be so affected
by it. And so, when he's essentially pleading
with them to like let him do that, you have
to imagine the Waynes. being like, of course,
but he won't let himself break his own promise
that he made. Right, because he's so unbelievably
dedicated to that vow and to his cause. It's
a very, very interesting character study. And
I think that, you know, goes to show why the
character is so popular. That sort of exploration
isn't something that has been explored much
for the character that I think warrants further
exploration, for sure. I think they attempted
it in the Nolan films, especially The Dark
Knight Rises. but not to the same level of success
I would argue as Batman Mask of the Phantasm.
This idea that Batman has an ending is not terribly
attractive. I want Batman to continue his crusade
forever because I think that's heroic and I
think giving that up is not heroic. And maybe
that's selfish of me, but it's just this ideal
that Batman represents that is attractive in
a way. Well, you've always said that you like
your DC characters because they're aspirational
and more symbols than they are characters. And
I think Batman giving up his crusade to actually
be happy would make him more relatable and therefore
more of a Marvel character. So I think maybe
that's your own bias. Maybe. I mean, do you
want to see Batman give up his crusade? I don't
give a fuck about Batman. Geez! Whatever. Moving
on to Andrea Beaumont, aka the Phantasm. She
was voiced by Dana Delaney. Now this was several
years prior to her voicing Lois Lane in Superman
the Animated Series. So I'm sure there was not
a problem with her voice when this hit theaters,
but holy crap, all I could hear was Lois Lane
watching this now. And she did a great job
in the role, don't get me wrong, but her voice
is extremely recognizable and it did present
a challenge for me in watching this film once
again. Character wise, they were both, you
know, these spunky romantic interests. And yeah,
I just, I just kind of shake it. It's like,
oh, it's, it's Lois Lane. My brain was just
thinking that the whole time. That too time
in... Now we know where she went off to in the
boat. She went to go get a die job and moved
to Metropolis. Change her name. Boom. Now, though
we don't know it for most of the film, Andrea's
arc revolves around themes of loss and vengeance,
much like Batman's. She's driven by this desire
for retribution against the mobsters responsible
for her father's death and adopts the persona
of the Phantasm to exact justice. But in contrast
to Batman, Andrea lacks his morality and is
willing to kill and lie to loved ones including
Bruce himself, manipulating him to prevent
him from stopping her mission. The thing is,
despite this, Andrea is still a sympathetic
character. because it clearly shows in the movie
how the mob took literally everything from
her, including the life of her father. Alfred
describes vengeance in the movie as a soul-destroying
abyss that Bruce skirts the edge of every day
and that Andrea fell into long ago. I think
she recognized this as well, which is why she
chose not to be with Bruce at the end of the
film. She's a study on what would happen, I
think, if Batman started killing people like
the Joker. Right. he would kind of lose himself
and become a serial killer, really. How could
he not? Like, he's so effective at what he does,
it would be so easy for him to do that. And
once he did it once, you'd figure he'd be like,
oh, it's very easy to do this. It's just, yeah,
a bad path to go down. That being said, I still
think he should do it. But we've had this discussion
a million times before. If you want to hear
more about this discussion, listen to our review
of Batman Under the Red Hood because they really
get into it deep in that story. Yes, absolutely.
Also, you're fucking evil, bro. I think it's
evil to not kill him. Well, you're wrong. Anyway,
now one of my biggest problems with this film
is something I noticed even as a child watching
this for the first time. And that's how the
hell did Andrea get her powers. Like intangibility
and teleportation are pretty impressive feats.
You'd think Batman's first question upon learning
she was the Phantasm would have been, dude.
Teach me. I mean, we all know that Batman seemingly
teleports when like people have their backs
turned. We know he just kind of like scampers
off and hides. So people think that he just
vanishes out of thin air, but we literally
see the phantasm character disappear completely
in a puff of smoke. There's no other way around
it except teleportation. So she's doing something
we're here. Maybe she got into like the occult
or something. That's the idea that I have in
the back of my head. Oh, interesting. I always
assumed it was technology. Why did I never assume
it was magic? That's a good answer. And it's
my new headcanon, so thanks for that. There
you go. But another thing that really bothers
me about this film is the twist is so obvious.
And this has bothered me about other Batman
stories such as like Hush, where the newly introduced
friend of Bruce Wayne is also the newly introduced
villain. Even as a kid, I was like, I bet you
that's Andrea. And I was fucking right. I was
a smart kid. Moving on to the Joker, voiced
by Mark Hamill. Again, we've said so many great
things about Mark Hamill's performance as the
Joker. Like Kevin Conroy for Batman, he is
the quintessential Joker voice. Yeah, I think
we spoke a lot about him in the Killing Joke
animated movie review that we did. This performance
is also... pretty early in Mark Hamill's career
as the Joker. And it's just amazing to see how
consistent these guys were throughout the decades.
Oh yeah, for sure. So the first time we see
the Joker, we don't know it. He's an anonymous
mob lackey of Salvatore Valestra. There's been
a number of ways that writers have tried to
tie the Joker into Batman's origin throughout
the years, you know, for making him the one
who murdered the Waynes in the 1989 Batman film.
or causing a citywide riot that resulted in
the Wayne's death in the Joker movie. In this
film, he wasn't involved in the deaths of the
Waynes that we know of, but he represented a
threat to the object of Bruce's desire and
happiness, namely, Andrea, which if Bruce had
been allowed to keep, he would not have become
Batman. And honestly, that's as direct an influence
to Batman's origin as I'd personally care for
the Joker to have. Yeah, I remember that the
Joker was in this movie from watching it as
a kid, but I couldn't remember in the course
of the film how and why and when he shows up.
Now he doesn't actually show up until like a
little bit past halfway through the runtime,
if I'm not mistaken. And I thought his presence
was actually sorely missed because once he
shows up, I think the film starts firing on
all cylinders, but before that the pacing was
a little bit slow. I was really glad to have
Joker in this movie. Yeah, originally he wasn't
going to be in the movie, but they found a way
to organically bring him in. And I gotta say,
I love it. Now, as we've mentioned before, people
have always wondered why Batman doesn't kill
the Joker, and interestingly enough, in this
film, Joker actually seems somewhat threatened
by the Phantasm when he confronts Councilman
Reeves because he knows he was one of the mobsters
that the Phantasm might be after. I feel like
this is the first time I've seen the Joker
threatened by a ghost from his past. And I just
thought that was fascinating. Yeah, the Joker
never really fears any of the consequences to
his actions because he knows that Batman will
never kill him. So he kind of feels like he
has the freedom to do what he wants. And in
a way, he's kind of right. So when he is faced
with death, he of course, you know, goes above
and beyond to eliminate that threat. Whereas
with Batman, he never truly wants to kill Batman,
he would rather corrupt him. It is kind of cool
that he tries to do that using his secret lair.
made out of the ruins of the Gotham World Fair.
I thought that was a nice little setting that
they incorporated into this film. Yeah, absolutely.
It was a great place for a final climactic
battle, the way Joker was able to utilize all
the different toys and stuff around him. I
loved that like, knife chopping robot. I loved
like, the miniature Gotham City. It was all
pretty great stuff.
World where fantasies collide and heroes clash.
One podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
Dynomic Podcast Network presents Console Combat,
where video game legends brawl every Monday.
Comic Book Titans smash every Tuesday, Max Destruction,
where TV and action heroes battle every Wednesday,
and Sendro World, where anime champions clash
every Thursday. Join us as we speculate on
the matches and, armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge victorious.
Visit dynamicpodcast.com where we settle the
debate and settle the score.
Moving on to the story highlights, the film
opens with the opening credits, just want to
touch on those briefly. It's a CG rendition
of the animated Gotham Cityscape, and it's
actually pretty awesome. Of course, it's made
even better by Shirley Walker's iconic animated
series score, which sets the perfect tone for
a Batman movie. It almost makes you wish that
they had taken bigger swings with the animation,
right? Because we have this really cool animated
setup into the film, and then all of a sudden
it goes back to standard Saturday morning cartoon
fare. But at least if they had kept the environment
CG or something like that, I think it would
have felt like a more true theatrical experience.
Yeah, I mean, CG was pretty new to that time.
So I think that probably would have been more
of a challenge for them. I could be wrong.
But yeah, I think that also would have been
cool. I wonder why they didn't take that 3D
model that they had created of Gotham City and
then incorporate it into the television series
kind of the same way they did with the Spider-Man
animated television show in the 90s where they
had a 3D model of New York that they would keep
revisiting as he was like swinging through
the streets or to use as a transition between
scenes and stuff like that. I think it makes
sense for the character of Spider-Man. You really
didn't have those transitional scenes with
Batman in his series. I'm not sure it would
have been necessary. Although, you know, honestly...
If they thought of that, they probably could
have found a way to make it work. I'm sure
for audience members in the theater at the time,
it was like breathtaking because you have to
remember this was pre mainstream CG animated
films, like pre Toy Story. Right. So, yeah,
I bet it was really cool. Now, moving on to
the plot. Well, Batman confronts a gang of
mobsters led by Chucky Saul for counterfeiting.
Chucky flees only to be encountered and killed
by a new enigmatic vigilante known as the Phantasm.
whose silhouette resembles Batman's, resulting
in witnesses blaming Batman for Chucky's murder.
Amidst a public censure from city councilman
Arthur Reeves, Batman analyzes a shard of glass
with a chemical residue from the Phantasm's
signature smokey aura, while Andrea Boumont,
Bruce's former fianc, returns to Gotham after
years of being away. And this is sort of like
the first plot hole. The fact that Andrea was
already in Gotham as the Phantasm, and yet we
see a scene of her arriving via plane. It's
supposed to be this misdirect that actually
just results in confusion later on. Well, Batman
addresses it. He's like, you came into Gotham
early. Seemingly, she came in by boat and then
she probably left by boat and then came in by
plane. But like, why would that matter to someone
who wasn't specifically following her movements?
You know? a little bit strange. Do you think
that Andrea specifically designed her phantasm
outfit to resemble Batman and therefore be
confused for him by eyewitnesses? Well that's
a good question. I don't know it's possible
although I don't really think she had a vendetta
against Batman per se so I think she was honestly
just trying to scare people in the same way
that Batman was trying to scare people. She
wouldn't have been familiar with Batman because
she had been away from Gotham for so long.
It just kind of turned into this kind of shitty
coincidence for Batman. Now regarding the suit,
I didn't really touch on her appearance. I thought
the design of the Phantasm was actually pretty
bomb. Again, it's inspired somewhat by the Grim
Reaper character from Batman Year 2, but I
think that further went on to inspire Asriel's
look from the comics. I thought Asriel predates
the Phantasm. He does, but I don't think that
costume does, because for the longest time,
Asriel wore like a cybernetic Batman suit. Asriel
being the guy who took over for Batman after
his back was broken by Bane. Yes, if you want
to learn more about him, check out our Asriel
vs. Blade episode. During a party at Wayne Manor,
Bruce is accosted by an old romantic fling
and reminded of Andrea by Councilman Reeve,
who unbeknownst to Bruce... has been talking
with Andrea. Bruce reminisces in a flashback
to the time he first met Andrea in a cemetery
while visiting his parents' grave. That same
evening, Bruce begins his masked vigilante
career, stopping a group of bandits, though
facing significant resistance and getting injured
in the process. Recognizing he needs to strike
fear in criminals to have an advantage over
them, Bruce nonetheless becomes distracted by
Andrea when she visits him during his training.
and the two share their first kiss. Now an interesting
note for the flashbacks in this film, they
were inspired by Citizen Kane. I could see that
for sure. Yeah, yeah, me too. Right when I
read that I was like, oh yeah. If you're not
familiar with Citizen Kane, it's an old film
by Orson Welles, black and white, but it's highly
regarded by a majority of film critics as the
greatest film that's ever been made. Yeah, I
mean, I don't know how much I buy into the
idea of it being inspired by Citizen Kane, because
then you could say like all flashbacks are
inspired by Citizen Kane, but the kind of 1940s
Art Deco feel of Mask of the Phantasm kind
of easily lends itself to those comparisons
to Citizen Kane. Yeah, and sort of like the
main character being this sort of tortured billionaire.
Yeah. I think if any comics character is going
to have a film based on Citizen Kane, it's definitely
Batman. I think that was a really smart decision.
to take inspiration for the filmmakers. Or Tony
Stark. Yeah, Tony Stark could go fuck himself.
WHAT? I SAID IT! Anyway, back to the present,
mob boss Buzz Bronski visits the grave of Chuckie
Saul at the cemetery, where he's confronted
and killed by the Phantasm. Batman is blamed
by the press once again to the dismay of both
Mob Boss Salvatore Velestra and Councilman
Reeves, the latter of whom presses Police Commissioner
James Gordon to go after Batman, though Gordon
refuses. While Batman investigates the cemetery
for clues, he finds more chemical residue before
finding his parents' grave, where he's caught
by Andrea, who realizes Batman must be Bruce.
Maybe a little bit of a stretch, but yeah, he
shouldn't have been at his frickin' parents'
grave. Rookie move. I gotta say earlier on in
the story when we see that Batman year one
moment where Bruce Wayne is kinda trying his
hand at being a vigilante the first time. It
was quite comical to see him attempt that outside
of the Batman costume, where he's just some
like guy who shows up and he's like, Hey guys,
stop it. And like their reaction to him was
actually kind of funny. They're like, who's
this guy? Right. Absolutely. To all the haters
who are like, Oh, Batman's so dumb. He's a guy
wearing a bat costume. Have you considered
the alternative? I think this is a perfect example
of that. Just how ridiculous it is. You better
listen to me or else. He's much better as this
haunting mythical creature of the night for
sure. Batman spies on Andrea as she dines with
Councilman Reeves. In a flashback, we see his
and Andrea's romance bloom as they visit a futurism
exhibit at the Gotham World Fair. Andrea later
introduces Bruce to her father, Carl Beaumont,
whom Bruce learns handles the finances for
Salvatore Valestra and for whom a younger Arthur
Reeves worked for as a lawyer. As Bruce and
Andrea leave her father's office, they encounter
a biker gang robbing a civilian on the street.
When Bruce intervenes, he becomes distracted
by Andrea and gets injured, allowing the biker
gang to get away with the money. Realizing he
can't pursue the life of vigilantism that he
vowed on his parents' grave and simultaneously
lead a fulfilling, happy life with Andrea,
the tormented Bruce visits his parents' grave,
where Andrea finds and comforts him. Best scene
of the whole movie. Yeah. Do you think that
maybe Batman would just be more effective if
he wasn't distracted by his girlfriend while
trying to fight crime? Like maybe he could
have it both ways and he's just kind of being
dumb? Well, that's a good question. I think
he would always kind of have her at the back
of his mind. He'd be afraid to take certain
risks because he could get injured and, you
know, that would not be good for his loved
ones. You could argue that, you know, he probably
runs into the same issue with his Robins. You
know, what happens to young Dick Grayson if
his caretaker, Bruce Wayne, gets killed while
being Batman? But for some reason, Bruce's romantic
life seems to affect him more, I guess. Well,
with Robin, he's setting up a legacy, so he
knows that if he ever kicks the bucket, he
has someone to take up his mantle. That's true.
Why doesn't he just train his wife or girlfriend
to, you know, kick ass too? That's a fair point
considering, you know, Andrea actually can
fight and be a masked vigilante as the phantasm.
I don't know, maybe if he knew that they could
have fought crime together. Maybe they should
have ended up together in the end. When Batman
was spying on Andrea and the councilman, do
you think he was crying or do you think it
was just raining on his face? Rain, dude. Rain.
Batman doesn't cry like that. It's always in
the rain. You can't prove anything. Back in
the present, Salvatore confronts Arthur Reeves
and confirms Reeves' suspicions that Batman
is killing mob bosses. Meanwhile, Batman deduces
that Salvatore, Buzz Bronski, and Chuckie Sol
were business partners in the past. While investigating
Sal's office, he notices a photo of Sal, Buzz,
Chuckie, and Andrea's father, Carl, all together.
In a flashback, Bruce remembers his sunset marriage
proposal to Andrea. just as a swarm of bats
emerged from a nearby cave on his property.
As Bruce drops Andrea off at her father's home,
they notice he has company. The following day,
after Bruce investigates the cave from where
the bats came, Bruce receives a letter from
Andrea saying that she can't marry him, that
she's leaving to Europe with her father, and
that he should forget about her. In his grief,
Bruce rededicates his vow to his parents and
becomes the Batman. Another really iconic scene
in this film is when Batman puts on the cowl
for the very first time and you just see the
look of shock and horror on Alfred's face. That
was, I thought, really effectively done. I
don't love the way he came to adopt the mantle
of the bat because it's not entirely clear
why he chose the bat in this movie, but that
reveal of him as Batman without even seeing
him on screen was fantastic. You have to imagine
that Alfred seeing Batman become this monstrous
figure, a guy who, like he says in this movie,
diapered his bottom since he was a baby, is
actually significantly terrifying. Yeah, he's
like, that's way scarier than, you know, fighting
crime in your civilian clothes like you were
before. Right. Now back in the present, Salvatore
visits the abandoned World Fair, the secret
hideout of the Joker, attempting to hire him
to kill Batman, though Sal angers Joker in the
process. After Councilman Reeves returns Andrea
home from a date, Andrea and Batman confront
each other in her room, with Batman inquiring
about her father Carl and Andrea accusing Batman
of being controlled by his parents. When the
Phantom attempts to kill Salvatore in his home,
it finds that the Joker beat him to it, poisoning
Salvatore with Joker venom and rigging his body
with a camera to find out who's really killing
the mob bosses. The Phantasm manages to escape
before the Joker blows up Sel's home, only
to then be chased down by Batman. The Phantasm
disappears, however, and Batman is forced to
flee from the police, who believe he's responsible
for the Joker's explosion and Sel's death.
Badly injured in the police pursuit, Batman
is rescued by Andrea, who takes him back to
Wayne Manor. I wonder if Joker rigged the camera
on the body because he knew that the killer
wasn't Batman. because he knew that Batman doesn't
kill. I think it's that exactly. Yeah, he was
trying to find out who was really going after
the mob bosses and therefore later on, possibly
even him. Now you brought up a point earlier
about a plot hole as to why Andrea was dating
the councilman. And I am kind of angry now because
I didn't think about that. And I do have to
wonder, like, if she's coming into Gotham, why
not contact Bruce, her former fiance right
away? I wonder if she was waiting for her whole
crusade to be over with, and then maybe she,
like Batman, considered the possibility that
they could continue their lives together? Or
what was going on there? Why did she have to
make her presence known as Andrea to begin
with? She should have just snuck in and been
the phantasm all the time. She didn't need
her alter ego there out in public. That's very
true. Plot hole, dammit. Now Andrea reveals
that on the day of Bruce's marriage proposal,
the visitors at her father's house were Sal,
Buzz, and Chucky, demanding money from her father
Carl, who had it tied up in investments. After
lying to the mobsters, saying they'll have their
money the next day, Carl explains to Andrea
that they had to flee or face death from the
mob. Though Carl made a fortune in Europe and
later paid back the mob their money, it wasn't
enough for them, and Bruce deduces that the
phantasm must be Carl. Bruce and Andrea rekindle
their love for one another, and the following
morning, as Bruce contemplates retiring the
cowl after settling this whole matter, he recognizes
in the photograph of Carl, Cell, Buzz, and Chucky
that another familiar face, one of Cell's mobsters,
is in fact the Joker. Now that was an interesting
twist, because I had forgotten that the Joker
was the mobster that worked for Salvatore. The
camera always kept going back to the long nose
henchmen in the flashbacks and everything like
that. But even then, I didn't put two and two
together until this scene where he's looking
at the photo. I was like, oh, okay. Yeah, that
is the Joker. Right. Yeah. And of course, the
Joker has a alternate history as a mobster,
not only from the comics, but also, of course,
Tim Burton's 1989 Batman film. So I thought
it worked really well as a quasi history of
sorts for the Joker in the Batman animated
series universe. After Joker confronts Councilman
Reeves, suspecting he may be the Phantasm,
Reeves ends up in the hospital, unable to stop
laughing. Batman visits him and learns that
Reeves and Carl kept in touch while he was away
in Europe. When Carl refused to help Reeves
find his election campaign, Reeves turned to
the mob and gave them Carl's location in exchange
for money. When Batman arrives at Andrea's to
tell her the news, he answers her phone only
to hear the Joker threaten to kill her. As Batman
manages to prevent a bomb strapped to a plane
from the World's Fair from blowing up Andrea's
home, we see Andrea at the World's Fair where
she remembers in a flashback when she witnessed
the pre-Joker mobster leave her father's house
just before she found him dead. Now, the scene
of Batman interrogating Councilman Reeves in
the hospital as he's, you know, dosed up on
Joker venom and can't stop laughing was one
of my favorite scenes in the movie. And I think
one of my favorite scenes in the movie. favorite
Batman interrogation scenes I've ever seen.
A lot of props has to go to the animation department
for, I think, realistically depicting this condition
that the councilman is in. It was very believable.
The voice acting was fantastic. Just really
interesting. Felt bad for the guy. Yeah. I'm
still surprised that he made it out alive through
the course of this movie. I guess you could
rationalize Andrea dating Kim because maybe
she was trying to figure out on her own whether
or not the councilman was involved in her father's
death. That's my head, Kenan now. Oh, yeah.
Yeah. She was investigating him. And that's
also maybe why she actually came back as Andrea
and didn't just sneak in to Gotham as the phantasm.
Plot hole filled? I'm going to say yes. We
figured it out. There you go. Now when the Phantasm
confronts Joker at the abandoned World's Fair,
Joker reveals that he knows it's Andrea, who
reveals it is in fact her beneath the mask
before the two fight. Using the fair's technology
to his advantage, Joker nearly succeeds in
killing Andrea before Batman arrives and rescues
her. Though Batman and Andrea argue over her
actions, Andrea agrees to leave and Batman pursues
the Joker, who reveals that he's triggered
explosives throughout the fairgrounds, that
will soon detonate. When the Joker is defeated,
Andrea reappears and grabs him and the two disappear
just before the entire fair blows up. One thing
that kind of bothered me here is once Batman
rescues Andrea, she starts using his name Bruce
willy nilly and they're talking like they know
each other. It would be so easy for Joker to
figure out this is Bruce Wayne. What? Like kind
of reckless. After Batman escapes the explosions,
Alfred consoles Bruce, saying there was no way
to save Andrea, as she had already fallen too
far into the abyss of vengeance. Bruce finds
Andrea's locket in the Batcave, and it's revealed
that Andrea survived the explosions and is hiding
away on a boat. Batman, meanwhile, remains
committed to his vow of vengeance against the
criminal element of Gotham City. And that's
the end of the movie. Makes me wonder, did Batman
assume that Andrea- died in the explosion and
if so why did he assume that when he saw her
teleport? I don't think he assumed that she
died especially considering the fact that he
found the locket in the cave. I think that
was a clear indicator that she was still alive
and that she had kind of given up on their
relationship because she didn't need the locket
anymore. I think really this whole thing kind
of just embittered him in a way which in turn
kind of renewed his commitment to his cause.
Like if she died, he would be sad. But I think
he was more angry or at least it came across
that way to me in the final shot of the film.
I wonder what she did with the Joker considering,
you know, she got away. It seems like she had
a change of heart and decided to just not kill
him and then, you know, go into hiding as Lois
Lane. Headcanon. No, who knows? Like they should
have addressed that fact. because it's just
a weird anticlimactic element of this film
that just kind of sucks. I don't know what else
to say about it. She was on this mission of
vengeance. There's no real sign that she was
willing to change or would change. So why wouldn't
she have killed the Joker? Maybe he got away.
Maybe the Joker was too good and he escaped.
Well, then you would think that Andrea would
never stop in her pursuit to kill the Joker
and would end up in Gotham City once again.
I don't know, man. Exactly. That's the problem.
One of several in this movie, which I feel almost
bad not liking more. I feel like I should like
it more because critics really liked it. But
again, I think critics just weren't watching
a reading a lot of stuff that you and I are
watching and reading now or have in the past
to justify such a high rating for this film,
like On Rotten Tomatoes. I think at the time
a lot of critics were comparing Batman Mask
of the Phantasm to the live action movies that
we were getting at the time. I think when this
came out it was following Batman Returns and
I would agree that this movie is better than
Batman Returns. I don't know if it's better
than the 1989 Batman movie but better than Burton's
follow-up and certainly better than the Schumacher
films that came out later. Maybe that's the
case? Maybe they liked it because it was really
the first foray that the general... non-comic
book reading public got into Batman's psyche.
That's gotta be it. Yeah, that's the best thing
going for this film hands down and one that
really has yet to be done as well arguably in
any subsequent film, except for maybe The Batman.
So you're probably right. Now overall, despite
its strong themes of vengeance and duty, the
obvious mystery reveal and plot holes prevent
the film from comparing to Batman's best stories.
like Batman Begins, like The Dark Knight, like
even Batman Year One. Those were all much better
origins for the character and it's really difficult
not to make those comparisons. I know critics
weren't able to do that when this film came
out in theaters, but I'm reviewing it now and
that's really the only way I can review it.
I'm giving it three and a half stars, a fresh
rating on Rotten Tomatoes. I would agree with
that rating. It's still a good movie, but when
you compare it to some of the more recent Batman
animated films that we've gotten, such as,
you know, Batman Year 1, or especially Batman
The Long Halloween, that was fantastic. Yes.
Again, I just don't think that this movie, while
good for its time, holds up in comparison to
the newer stuff. Absolutely, and it kind of
makes you wonder, like, what if Warner Brothers
released animated films like Batman Year One
or Batman the Long Halloween in theaters? Like,
how would critics respond and how would the
box office respond? I think they should do
it. I mean, look at how well the Spider-Verse
movies do. I think Batman the Long Halloween
has a chance of holding up just as well with
general audiences considering how well that
was made. I agree. I agree. Although, I mean,
you know, the Spider-Verse movies are on a
whole other level animation-wise. You would
have to get up to that level of animation,
I think, for the general audiences to really
make a push to go see it. Because Mask of the
Phantasm was not a box office success in theaters.
It later became a success on home video. And
now that, you know, Spider-Verse has set the
bar for animated films in theaters, things
like Mask of the Phantasm are kind of embarrassing
by comparison. That's right. Marvel likes to
embarrass DC. That's one of my favorite things
about Marvel. Did I say embarrassing? I meant...
I don't know, embarrassing. Damn it. But that
does it for this review. AG9K, help close this
out. Thanks for listening to Dynamic duel. Visit
the show's website at dynamicduel.com and follow
us on Instagram at dynamicduelpodcast. You can
support the show on Patreon at patreon.com
slash dynamicduel and joining a tier that works
for you, or by rating and reviewing Dynamic
duel on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser or
on our website. Don't forget to listen to the
other shows in the Dynamite Podcast Network,
including Max Destruction, Senjow World and
Console Combat. In our next episode, we will
be doing a duel between the Earth elemental
characters of GeoForce and Quake. I wouldn't
describe Quake as an Earth elemental character.
She more just has vibration powers. But that
does it for this episode, we want to give a
big thanks to our executive producers Ken Johnson,
John Swarovski, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Abalkom,
Miggy Mathengian, Brandon Esfregard, Nathaniel
Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Austin Wazilowski, AJ
Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam
Spies, Andrew Shunk, Dean Molesky, Devin Davis,
and Joseph Kirsting for helping make this podcast
possible. We'll talk to you guys next week.
Up, up and away, true believers. Your angel
of death awaits, and it brought snacks.