This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
Welcome to the dynamic duel podcast a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters And stat based battle simulations.
I'm Marvelous Joe and I'm his twin brother Johnny
DC And in this episode we are going to put
the debate to rest on who would win in a fight
between Geoforce and Quake a match that literally
a few people asked for Because Geoforce is not
very well known I think As opposed to Quake?
Like what if she did some like ragtag shield
agent who doesn't even have like a superhero
costume? No, I mean she was the lead character
and agents of shield besides, you know, Phil
Coulson. So I don't know what you're talking
about Quake is taking this one. You have no
idea how hard she's gonna lose. You'll find
out. You're gonna learn today We'll see before
we get into that matchup before we put in the
character stats and run a thousand simulations
and find out who would definitively win We're
gonna break down the latest comic book movie
news which came out this past week of which
we have a few news items including the news
that the Blade movie has lost its director,
Yann Dimage, and we got a teaser trailer for
the upcoming animated Watchmen films. As always,
we list our segment times in our episode description,
so feel free to check out the show notes if
you want to skip ahead to a particular topic.
Guys, our artificially intelligent duel simulator
AJ9K has a quick message for our listeners,
so listen up. Why hello there, do you want even
more from this podcast? Then become a part
of the dynamic duel community on Patreon, where
you can choose from three tiers. The dynamic
two-oh tier gives you access to our Discord
chat server. The fantastic four tier gives
you two bonus episodes each month, and the X-Force
tier makes you an executive producer of this
show. Lastly, The DynaMic Podcast Network tier
lets you create your own podcast using this
Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe will help
you develop your show, provide graphic support
and consultation, and get you simulation results.
Pitch the twins your ideas via email at dynamicduelpodcast
at gmail.com. Check it out at patreon.com slash
dynamicduel. Pip pip cheerio. Thanks AJ9K,
and thanks to everyone who supports the podcast.
Be sure to tune into the shows in the DynaMic
Podcast Network this week. including Max Destruction,
which pits your favorite action heroes from
film and television against each other. This
week, hosts Ken and Scottie are going to review
the movie Saving Private Ryan. Great film. Great
movie. Perfect movie. On the Sendrow World
podcast, host Zachary Hepburn speculates on
fights between fan favorite anime and manga
characters. The show is currently on a season
hiatus, so this is the perfect time for you
anime fans to catch up on Sendrow World's 40
episode library. And on the Console Combat
Podcast, hosts John and Dean find out who would
win in fights between popular video game characters.
In yesterday's episode, which you can listen
to right after this one, they found out who
would win in a fight between Captain Falcon
from the F-Zero video games against Sweet Tooth
from Twisted Metal. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com
or click the link in our show notes to listen
to all of the shows in the DynaMic Podcast
Network. But with that out of the way, quick
to the no prize! No Prize is an award Marvel
used to give out to fans. Our version, the
Dynamic Duel No Prize, is a digital award we
post on Instagram for the person that we feel
gave the best answer to our question of the
week. Last week we asked, what Marvel or DC
character do you think has had the most successful
trilogy of films and why? And of course this
tied into the trailer for the third Venom film,
Venom The Last Dance. Yeah, little round out
that character's trilogy and we were curious
who you guys thought had the best trilogy.
So let's run down our honorable mentions as
well as the no prize winner. Our first honorable
mention goes to Waldo, who said, Hey guys, it's
Waldo again. So as far as the most successful
film trilogy, I'm pretty sure it'd be Nolan's
Batman with Christian Bale. So while I may
not like it, he was Batman in name only, he
did very little detective work. And all his
stuff was made by Fox, and she showed very little
actual intellect of His fans are still raving
about it to this day. I hear you man, I am not
a fan of the Dark Knight trilogy being a Marvel
fan myself. Like that Batman was not the Batman
that I know. My gosh. He wasn't that smart.
He didn't make anything. He didn't deduce anything.
He was basically a piece of shit. But for some
reason- I'm gonna slap the shit out of you.
People really like the Dark Knight trilogy.
I don't know why. Jonathan, can you explain
it? The films are amazing first of all. I don't
get why you wouldn't like the Dark Knight trilogy.
It's such a great saga. of Batman from beginning
to end. You know, it starts off perfectly with
Batman Begins, ramps up with the Dark Knight,
and doesn't quite stick the landing with Rises,
but it comes damn close. Making arguments that,
oh, it's not good because Batman didn't make
his own gadgets. I actually liked what they
did with this movie because Bruce Wayne is not
an engineer. Like, it's OK if the head engineer
from Wayne Tech makes his gadgets for him. That's
not a problem. It's kind of cool, actually.
that he would have a cue of sorts in the same
way James Bond does. And as for detective work,
you guys are smoking so much crack. What are
you talking about? Like he did fantastic detective
work like in The Dark Knight with like his sonar
gear and stuff like that and finding answers.
And you guys are so wrong, but yet so right
in that it's a fantastic trilogy. I never said
it was a fantastic trilogy. Waldo did. OK, well,
you're wrong then. And Waldo's right. Great
answer, Waldo. Our next honorable mention goes
to... Miggi Mattingian, who said... Hey what's
up guys, this is Miggi, and my favorite superhero
trilogy is the Dark Knight trilogy. Of course,
you know I had to do it as a DC fan, but not
just that, because of that. It's just legitimately
a really great trilogy. Batman Begins just kind
of revolutionized the genre, bringing like
a grounded, like, serious take on superheroes.
Dark Knight is just a masterpiece inducted
into the National Library of Congress. And then
Dark Knight Rises is just like... wraps it
up really nicely. So yeah. Thanks guys. Yeah,
the Dark Knight influenced an entire generation
of films and filmmakers. You wouldn't even have
the Iron Man movie if the Dark Knight wasn't
made as influential as it was in terms of taking
a really serious approach to the subject matter.
You're aware that Iron Man came out before the
Dark Knight, right? No, I'm fucking not aware
of that, obviously. Well, it did. So I met after
Batman begins, which it was inspired by with
all the flashbacks and nonlinear storytelling.
All right. You're dumb. No, no, you are. Great
answer. Make your next honorable mention goes
to Cyrus Moore, who said, Hey guys, Cyrus Moore
here. And we all know, obviously the best movie
trilogy is the X. I mean it's the Christian
Bale Batman movies. You physically can't get
any better. We all know Christian Bale was
the best Batman. Most successful movie is Christian
Bale Batman. It's the movie trilogy we deserve
and the one that we need also, cause it's so
damn good. It seems like everybody's answering
the Dark Knight trilogy. Yeah, cause it's clearly
the obvious winner. Even though it's not the
winner of the Snow Prize for some effed up reason.
I'll tell you why it's not the No Prize winner.
It's because, you know, if everybody's answering
The Dark Knight Rises, how do we choose among
them? Obviously, we have to go with the choice
that is not the Dark Knight trilogy, and therefore,
the winner of this week's No Prize goes to Scotty
Macho, who said, Scotty Macho from Max Destruction,
my DC cohorts are not going to like me for this
answer, but they will understand. I'm going
to say Deadpool. Now Deadpool Overring hasn't
come out officially yet. But I mean, when it
does, is there any argument? I mean, the Deadpool
series has been phenomenal and only Ryan Reynolds
can deliver it. Deadpool is my pick. Is there
any argument? Hell yeah, there's a lot of argument.
The first two Deadpool movies were good, but
none of them even come close to approaching
the quality of The Dark Knight. I would argue
that the first Deadpool movie is funnier than
The Dark Knight and therefore better. So there
you go. I mean, Deadpool 2 is a little bit
eh, but I think Scotty has a point, even though
the fact that he is empirically incorrect in
his answer because the third Deadpool movie
has not yet come out. But we're gonna give
it to him anyway because he had the originality
to not be a sheeple and say the Dark Knight
trilogy. There's only one answer to this question.
Like it was a bad question to begin with because
obviously it's the Dark Knight trilogy. I will
say that we retain the right to retroactively
strip Scotty of this no prize if in fact it
turns out that the Deadpool and Wolverine movie
sucks, but I don't think it's going to so I
think this no prize is gonna stick. I mean
even if it doesn't it's still not gonna match
the influence and magnum opus That is the Nolan
trilogy of Batman films. What if Deadpool and
Wolverine is so good that it wins like Best
Picture Oscar You don't know how good it's gonna
be shut the hell up Check your expectations
Jonathan, what would you answer to this question?
What do you think is the best superhero trilogy?
The Dark Knight trilogy, obviously, hands down.
Okay, you're also a sheeple then, okay. What
would you say? I mean, there's a lot of Marvel
answers that you could give. I thought Spider-Man,
the Tom Holland Spider-Man trilogy, like the
Home trilogy was incredible. I think it was
even better than the Sam Raimi trilogy, but
also Guardians of the Galaxy. I think all three
of those films, Guardians, Volume One, Two,
and Three, were incredible. and they probably
won't ever be beaten in terms of that franchise.
So I guess my pick would be for Guardians.
I'm actually really surprised you didn't say
Captain America because Winter Soldier and
Civil War are really good. Yeah, they're fantastic.
They're incredible. But I'm not sure the first
movie compares to the latter two. The thing
is, though, you know why people didn't call
in with those answers? Because they were lazy.
Because those still aren't as good as the Dark
Knight trilogy and everyone knows it. I don't
know that. Cause you're stupid. Great answer
Scotty, you win this week's no prize. If you
the listener want to win your own no prize,
stay tuned to later on this episode when we'll
be asking another question of the week. And
now that that's done, on to the news!
Alright, this past week we got horrible news
in regards to the Blade movie that is currently
being produced by Marvel Studios. This project
has been languishing in development hell for
quite a while now, ever since it was first announced
by Kevin Feige at the 2019 Comic Con, where
we first saw the upcoming star of Blade, Mahershala
Ali, put on the Blade hat. Ever since that
announcement, I've been waiting with bated breath
for the Blade movie to come out, and it's been
delayed after... director loss after delay,
after new writer, after director loss, and
there's just no end to this bad news. But we
learned that the director that was most recently
attached, Jan Damange, is no longer directing
Marvel Studios' Blade. And it's almost like
the movie is cursed by this point, because it's
already 2024. It seems like the movie is not
going to come out for quite a while now that
they have to. you know, essentially look for
a new director. And at that point you might
get new script rewrites to suit the new director
and stuff like that. Hopefully Mahershala Ali
stays with the project because I do think that
he'd be a fantastic Blade. But at this point,
everything just seems up in the air in regards
to this particular franchise. Would you hate
it if they just scrapped the whole project?
Yeah, obviously. I mean, we already have quite
a few good Blade movies. I'm not quite sure
what they could do with it that has already
been done successfully. in the prior franchise
with Wesley Snipes. We have two good Blade movies
and I mean we've seen what Marvel Studios is
capable of doing with characters that are under
their purview as compared to other studios.
Like say the Hulk. I thought Incredible Hulk
was better than 2003's Hulk. I think Blade
has the potential to not only be an amazing
franchise but also steer the MCU in a direction
that it's really never gone down before. Except
for you know. the werewolf by night special
presentation that they released on Disney plus
a few years ago Honestly, they should have
just introduced blade in that short film It
would have been a much better introduction
than what he got in eternals If I was Kevin
Feige, I would scrap eternals just scrub that
erase it from everyone's memory And scrap this
blade film as well because we don't need it.
Uh, we do need it and I don't know what you're
talking about. We don't need vampires in the
mcu. It's just gonna like make things so complicated
How are vampires complicated? How are they
not complicated? What? They're very complicated.
No, they're not, they're fine. It's all fine.
People already know the lore of vampires, so
introducing a vampire hunter into the mix,
I think, would not only be cool, it would be
unique, at least for the MCU. Now, Yann Dimage
replaced Bassam Tariq as the director, and now
I'm wondering who's gonna replace Yann Dimage.
I think there are quite a few candidates that
I think would make a great Blade movie, and
that brings us to our question of the week.
Who do you want to direct Marvel Studios Blade
movie and why? Record your answer at dynamicduel.com
by clicking on the red microphone button in
the bottom right hand corner of the screen,
which will prompt you to leave us a voicemail.
Your message can be up to 30 seconds long and
don't forget to leave your name in case we include
you on the podcast. We'll pick our favorite
answer and award that person a dynamic duel
no prize that we'll post to Instagram. Be sure
to answer before June 22nd. In DC news, last
week we got the teaser trailer for parts 1
and 2 of an animated watchman film that is going
to be released direct to video and it looks
incredible. Honestly, it looks a lot like the
Zack Snyder film, which also looked incredible.
And I think that was the most surprising thing
to me in this trailer. It was just a reminder
of how faithful Zack Snyder's framing was in
matching the panels from the comic. Now this
project was first announced in 2017 and we didn't
hear anything about it until 2023 at Comic
Con and yeah I totally forgot it existed until
this was released and now I'm pretty pumped
for it. It's coming out fairly soon the first
part is supposed to be released in August of
this year but part two won't be coming out until
next year I guess. My big question is why is
this a thing? Like why is this necessary if
it's so close? to the Zack Snyder live action
Watchmen adaptation, do we need this animated
project? We do not, I believe. I think the
reason they're doing it is because it's been
over 10 years since Zack Snyder's film, and
Warner Brothers just likes to keep Watchmen
out in people's consciousness, as it were.
I mean, we recently had the Watchmen HBO television
series, though, that did a great job of doing
just that. This Watchmen movie that's coming
out looks almost exactly like the What If.
style of animation that we've seen from Disney
Plus. This whole trailer just made me think
like, what if DC were to make a redundant Watchmen
movie? That's what this trailer is asking.
Oh yeah? The style of this actually matches
the style that was done with the Super Sons
movie, if you remember that. So no, they're
not biting off of the what if style of animation
that Disney Plus is doing with that show. So
calm down, okay? I don't know about that. The
teaser trailer was not that long, it's only
41 seconds. But yeah, every frame is basically
like a panel from the comic. So you can make
the argument that this is unnecessary, since
not only do we have a movie and a comic, but
Watchmen is just such a good story. I'm pretty
much down with any adaptation. We did receive
an animated Watchmen motion comic over a decade
ago. and I still loved watching that even with
the live action movie having been made and
I'll probably still enjoy this adaptation as
well. I'm gonna tell you now and I'm speaking
on behalf of everybody else besides you. No
one gives a shit about this. No one cares if
they want to experience the Watchmen story.
They're gonna read the graphic novel or they're
gonna go watch Zack Snyder's version and if
they want more than that they're gonna go watch
the HBO television series. No one gives a shit
about this. Except for people who haven't read
the graphic novel. who maybe haven't seen the
Zack Snyder film and maybe want more information
behind the story that was the HBO Watchmen sequel
series. So like two people. Burn. What? I'm
sure it's more than two. You know what? And
you also forget people like me who just legitimately
like Watchmen and are totally down to watch
this. I think people just need to get over
Watchmen already. Like it was a thing. It was
fine when it came out. It was fantastic even,
but you know what? It's been adapted so many
times now. Who cares? Who cares? Oh wow, someone
sounds butthurt from a teaser trailer. What?
Wow. It's just not necessary. It's just not
necessary and I'm sick of Watchmen and people
just need to move on. Well, you know, we are
going to review it. So I'm sorry. I'll get you
a hemorrhoid pillow for when you do it. Cause
from all the butthurt that I'm sure will come
out of the review, I will be looking forward
to it. I'll get you some cream too. All right,
cool it. If you haven't seen the trailer, I
definitely recommend checking it out again.
It's not long, looks really cool. And I'm curious
to hear what you guys have to say about it.
Tell Joseph how wrong he is. You're not going
to get any feedback about what people think
about this because they're not going to care
enough to answer. It's fine. I can't wait till
I get feedback. I'm going to screenshot it.
I'm going to text it to you. You're not going
to get feedback from anyone outside of discord.
I'll say that. McGee is going to be the only
one that messages you. Well, me and him will
enjoy the movie then. All right.
But I think that does it for all the news for
this episode, so let's go ahead and move into
our main event where we find out who had went
in a fight between the Outsiders member Geoforce
and the Agent to Shield, Quake.
Alright, GeoForce vs Quake. This episode is
in lead up to our upcoming team duel which
pits the outsiders against X-Force. Now, a lot
of the outsiders are kind of, I feel like,
isolated within the DC universe, but they have
played a prominent role within that team itself,
GeoForce being one of them. Yeah, GeoForce is
a major member of the outsiders. I would say
he's probably the third most important after
Batman and Black Lightning. He's actually led
the team on occasion. Has Quake led SHIELD?
Yeah, she has in fact. She's been the director
of shield so you thought you had something going
there Well, has she been the queen of a country?
Geoforce has been the queen of a country. He
has been the king Wow I'm really interested
in learning about this obviously both of these
characters have the ability to generate seismic
waves Geoforce can control rocks and quake can
just kick all kinds of ass. If you guys have
watched the Agents of SHIELD television show
that was out a few years ago, you obviously
know Quake. She was the main character of that
series next to Agent Phil Coulson, and she
was played by Chloe Bennett, and she was a fantastic
character. She has really cool powers as well.
And if you guys watched the Young Justice series,
you'll know about GeoForce. All two dozen of
you. Yeah, that's two dozen more than watched
Agents of SHIELD. That's probably not true.
Excuse you, Agents of SHIELD was a popular show.
And it was a fantastic show too, for the most
part, before season 5. It was good. I feel like
you're trying to convince me. I don't need
you to be convinced, I just need you to be sorry
when you lose this match. And I expect you
to die. No. I don't know. But to explain the
methodology behind our duels, let's go with
our sentient duel simulator, Alfred Jarvis 9000.
AJ9K, tell our listeners how you go about determining
a winner in our duel matchups. Yes, of course,
sir. The way I determine a winner between the
contestants is by running 1,000 Monte Carlo
simulations using the characters' statistics.
A Monte Carlo simulation is a probabilistic
model used to determine outcomes through random
sampling. In this case, I randomize the statistics
along a normal distribution as a way to simulate
the many variables that can occur during battle.
The stat parameters are based on the official
Marvel power grid from which the DC characters'
statistics are extrapolated. Additional stat
categories are included such as range, damage
potential, versatility and perception in order
to create a more detailed and accurate simulation.
The results of the 1000 simulations provide
a percentage of wins for each character. The
contestant with the higher percentage is declared
the victor as they have a higher probability
to win any given battle. In an equitable pairing,
neither character should win 100% of the matches.
The comic book stories have shown that there's
even a way for Batman to defeat Superman. So
the confidence rate of my method falls in line
with the precedents that have been established
in the source material. My mathematical simulations
are without subjectivity or bias. Feats are
not the sole consideration, nor are fan votes
tabulated for determination of the winner. Thanks
AJ9K! Before we run the simulations though,
we like to break down each character's histories
and abilities before improvising a scenario
on how we imagine one of the 1000 simulations
would play out beat for beat. And I believe
it's my turn to go first with the DC characters'
backstory, so let me tell you about Geoforce.
Now within the DC Comics universe nestled between
Luxembourg, Belgium, and France, exists the
small fictional country of Markovia, ruled by
a monarchy until it was overthrown by the Nazis
during World War II. When the Nazis were defeated,
their occupation of Markovia ended, and the
monarchy was restored, with its rightful king,
Victor Markov, returned to the throne. King
Markov ruled over Markovia and eventually sired
two sons, Gregor and Brian, and an illegitimate
daughter named Terra, who was raised in America
to spare the throne any embarrassment. You
can learn more about Terra in our Terra vs Avalanche
duel episode. In a land consisting primarily
of farmers and miners, Markovia had no superpowered
champion to call their own, and in an effort
to protect the country against any superpowered
threats, as well as bolster the power of the
royal family, Markovia's chief royal scientist,
Dr. Helga Jace, began genetic research to find
and trigger a potential metagene within the
Markovs. After a successful experiment on Terra,
which imbued her with geokinetic metahuman ability,
the illegitimate princess was sent back to
America, where she eventually teamed up with
the villain Deathstroke to infiltrate the Teen
Titans, which you can learn more about in our
Titans vs. X-Men Team Duel episode. Meanwhile,
the former Nazi Baron Frederick de Lamm, who
was instituted as Markovia's ruler by the Germans
during its World War II occupation, also lived
in exile from Markovia, conspiring to overthrow
its monarchy and return to power, while also
granting him access to a hidden vault within
Castle Markov that contained a secret Nazi weapon.
Under the nom de guerre of Baron Bedlam, he
hired mercenaries to secretly and successfully
stage a violent revolution within Markovia,
resulting in King Markov being fatally wounded.
Prince Gregor assumed his father's throne,
though he refused to undergo Dr. Helga Jace's
metagenic experiment as he wasn't keen on becoming
a quote-unquote freak like his sister
His brother, Prince Brian, however, believed
in Dr. Jace's research and agreed to undergo
her medelline procedure to help protect his
country. A procedure that harnessed the energy
of the planet itself, which Dr. Jace referred
to as the Geo Force. The procedure was nearly
interrupted by revolutionaries, however, and
Brian was shot immediately upon its completion.
Quickly buried alive in an unmarked grave to
prevent him from becoming a martyr, Bryan's
new powers drew healing strength from the ground,
and he emerged from his grave only to find
that Baron Bedlam had forced Dr. Jace to perform
the Geo Force procedure on him as well, though
she failed to inform him that his powers would
be unstable and temporary as he wasn't of the
royal bloodline of the Markovs. Alongside Batman,
Black Lightning, Metamorpho, Halo, and Kitana,
Prince Bryan was able to repel Baron Bedlam's
invasion of Markovia, with the final duel between
Bryan and Bedlam ending when Bedlam's powers
disappeared just as he was levitating a giant
boulder over his head that he intended to crush
Bryan with. With Baron Bedlam dead and peace
restored to Markovia, Prince Bryan agreed to
join the other heroes in Gotham City to form
a new team known as the Outsiders. Not only
as a way to show his gratitude for their help
in saving his country, but also to train in
the use of his new powers. Although initially
unused to following orders, resulting in frequent
conflicts with the team's leader, Batman, Brian,
who took the codename Geoforce to hide his royal
identity, reluctantly learned the value of
teamwork. After learning that his half-sister,
Tara, died while betraying the Teen Titans,
the heartbroken Brian found comfort in his teammate
Halo's roommate, a woman named Denise Howard,
while he attended Gotham University. While Geoforce
adventured as a member of the Outsiders in
Markovia, Baron Bedlam's corpse was discovered
by an evil geneticist named Dr. Ovarny, aka,
uh, Madame Ovary. After cloning Bedlam and restoring
his memory, Bedlam had her also clone Hitler,
as Bedlam needed his fingerprints to open the
secret vault within Castle Markov. Bedlam orchestrated
another coup on the Markovian monarchy. This
time hiring a supervillain team known as the
Masters of Disasters to aid him, and allying
himself with the Soviet Union, which prevented
the United States from getting involved, as
they didn't want to escalate the situation
into a world war. Though Batman tried to prevent
the Outsiders from interfering, the team abandoned
their leader once they learned that King Gregor's
fiance, Princess Elona, had been kidnapped.
Though Brian and the Outsiders were initially
defeated by the Masters of Disaster, and imprisoned
as Baron Bedlam gained access to the Nazi superweapon
of a proton cloud generator, they eventually
escaped and rescued the princess, culminating
in Brian granting Bedlam the opportunity to
kill himself, only to be shot in the back instead
and Brian decapitating Bedlam. After separating
themselves from Batman, the Outsiders team became
funded by Markovia, and Brian was made the
team leader. Not long after, however, King Gregor
was assassinated. and Brian became the new
king for a time, until it was discovered that
Queen Ilona was pregnant. It was later revealed
that his brother's murderer was none other than
Dr. Helga Jace, who was in fact a sleeper agent
of the Manhunter cult, and she accidentally
killed herself while trying to destroy the
outsiders. The team disbanded shortly after,
and Brian lived with his girlfriend Denise
in Markovia for some time, until Brian was framed
for killing Queen Ilona. While on the run with
the reformed Outsiders team, Brian managed to
clear his name and bring down Ilona's true
killer, an evil vampire. Eventually, Brian married
Denise and the two served as regents until
his nephew came of age to take the throne as
King of Markovia. After joining the Justice
League for a time, Brian left the team to rejoin
the Outsiders, during which time he faced Deathstroke
for what he had done to his sister, Tara, and
the two nearly killed each other. learn more
about Deathstroke in his duel against Deadpool.
In post-Flashpoint continuity, Prince Bryan
was the ruler of Markovia, and the origin of
his powers remained largely the same. When
the country of Markovia was destroyed by the
League of Assassins and the Seeker Society
of Super-Villains, Bryan vowed revenge against
both organizations by assassinating Grassal
Ghul and injuring his daughter Talia while disguised
as Deathstroke. His actions resulted in an
underworld shadow war that drew in Batman and
culminated with a showdown between Talia and
Deathstroke, at which point Bryan revealed he
was responsible for everything. Batman's son
Damien, who you can learn more about in our
Robin vs. Patriot episode, subsequently defeated
Bryan single-handedly, and Bryan was arrested
for killing Ra's al Ghul.
allowing him to generate gravitational fields
that can make objects heavier or lighter, in
effect giving him increased durability and strength.
He also possesses geokinesis, allowing him
to levitate, move, and shape the Earth around
him as well as lava, which he could also shoot
from his hands as beams of molten rock, flames,
or waves of heat. Combining gravity manipulation
with heat propulsion allows Geoforce to fly
at fast speeds. though for short periods of
time, as his powers diminish the longer he's
out of contact with the ground. When underground,
he can heal his wounds and survive without food
or air. Lastly, he is also a skilled hand-to-hand
combatant. That is Geoforce. Madame Ovary, really?
You know, I'm not proud of it. Somebody in
the comic book writing bullpen was just out
of ideas that day. It kind of seems like they
wanted to see if they could get away with it,
and they did. And that's a shame. It is a shame.
But to help us move past that atrocious writing,
let's go ahead and get into the backstory of
Quake. Now Daisy Johnson was born in New Orleans,
Louisiana to Calvin Zobbo and Kim Johnson.
Her father, Calvin, was an Avengers villain,
also known as Mr. Hyde, who, prior to Daisy's
birth, had developed a serum known as the Hyde
formula that could drastically enhance his
body mass and strength within seconds. though
it came with the side effect of making him
prone to savage anger. In the process of developing
the Hyde formula, Calvin had performed numerous
experiments on himself, inadvertently altering
his own DNA. Daisy's mother, Kim, was an inhuman
prostitute who Calvin frequented, and who gave
Daisy up for adoption immediately after her
birth. Daisy was taken in by foster parents
who named her Cory Stutter, and though Daisy
showed her troubled nature resulted in her dropping
out of high school to fend for herself. While
committing an act of theft, Daisy's power suddenly
manifested and she discovered she could generate
seismic vibrations when anxious. She was unable
to control these new abilities and was soon
discovered by the International Peacekeeping
and Espionage Organization, known as SHIELD.
Though they initially believed Daisy was a mutant,
SHIELD later discovered that due to her father's
genetic experimentation, Daisy's inhuman powers
were able to manifest without the need for
Terragen, a substance used by the inhuman race
to trigger their latent abilities. You can
learn more about Inhumans and Terragenesis in
our Shazam vs. Black Bolt duel episode. Nick
Fury, the director of SHIELD, took notice of
Daisy's potential and had her train with SHIELD
to become an agent. She excelled at the organization
and quickly rose through the ranks, honing
her abilities and completing numerous successful
field missions. often partnered with SHIELD
agent Phil Coulson. Eventually, Daisy went on
to become one of Nick Fury's most trusted operatives,
taking on the codename Quake, and getting level
10 security clearance, the only other field
agent beside Black Widow to ever do so. Daisy
was tasked with her biggest, most secretive
mission yet when Nick Fury asked her to accompany
heroes such as Captain America, Black Widow,
Daredevil, Spider-Man, Luke Cage, and Wolverine
in a top secret coup of the nation of Latveria.
At the time, Latveria's monarch, Dr. Doom, was
trapped in hell due to dark bargains he had
made earlier. Latveria's new prime minister,
named Lucia von Bardis, was covertly funding
America's supervillains as a way to wreak terror
on American soil. Nick Fury found evidence
of this, though the government administration
at the time refused to act on the intel. Nick
Fury found his hand forced and took his secret
recruitment of heroes to Latveria, including
Daisy, to quietly take Lucia von Bardis out.
However, one year later, von Bardis returned
as a cyborg with a cybernetic army to enact
revenge against the heroes involved in Fury's
operation. Daisy and the others fought to disable
a bomb that von Bardis used to try and destroy
New York City, and Daisy herself destroyed the
cyborg threat. You can learn more about Liberia
and Doctor Doom in his duel against Superman,
and more about Nick Fury in his duel against
Rick Flag. When Nick Fury's Liberian coup came
to light, he was ousted from S.H.I.E.L.D. and
replaced by new director Maria Hill, who removed
Daisy from duty. Although inactive, Daisy helped
the X-Men fight Magneto on the island of Genosha,
where she proved instrumental in knocking the
villain unconscious by inducing vibrations in
his brain. Not long after, Nick Fury returned
to draft Daisy into his covert team of secret
warriors to fight clandestine threats. This
included the secret invasion of alien Skrulls
on Earth and stopping secret cells of the evil
organization Hydra around the world. After the
Skrulls defeat and the dissolution of SHIELD,
Daisy was drafted into the Avengers and was
tasked with spying on Norman Osborn, who had
taken advantage of the SHIELD power
and the Dark Avengers. Captain America ended
up reactivating SHIELD and appointed Daisy
as its new director, where she was now in charge
of the entire operation. However, her decision
to assassinate the leader of the scientific
criminal organization AIM led to her being
demoted and replaced as SHIELD director by Maria
Hill. You can learn more about the Avengers
in their duel episode against the Justice League.
Back as a SHIELD agent, Daisy went on a mission
to locate and retrieve her father, Mr. Hyde.
She sought his help in fixing her powers, which
had begun to take their toll on her body, causing
her bones to splinter and sometimes shatter.
Feeling affection for his daughter, Mr. Hyde
was able to cure her, but then tried to inject
her with his Hyde formula, claiming that it
would protect her. Agent Phil Coulson took
the injection instead in an effort to spare
Daisy, and he and Mr. Hyde fought, giving Daisy
enough time to use her restored powers to create
a fissure in the ground that swallowed her
father whole. And that's her backstory. Powers-wise,
Quake is an inhuman with the innate ability
to generate seismic vibrations, the magnitude
of which she can control via a pair of gauntlets
she wears on her wrists. Her vibrations can
be so powerful and widespread as to create
a massive earthquake that topples buildings
or so small and targeted as to explode the
heart in someone's chest. The vibrations can
be forceful enough to shatter objects or delicate
enough to render someone unconscious. As an
inhuman, Quake has innately enhanced physicality,
including greater reflexes, durability, and
strength than any human athlete. She is a highly
trained fighter taught by Nick Fury and Shield,
an elite spy, and an intelligent strategist.
And that's Quake. So what you're basically saying
is that anything Quake can do, Geoforce can
do, and then some. Can he shatter the heart
in someone's chest? I mean, yeah, by putting
his fist through it. Okay, all right, okay.
Where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
DynaMic Podcast Network presents Console Combat,
where video game legends brawl every Monday.
DynaMic Podcast Network Comic Book Titans smash
every Tuesday, Max Destruction, where TV and
action heroes battle every Wednesday, and Sendro
World, where anime champions clash every Thursday.
Join us as we speculate on the matches and,
armed with the power of mathematical simulations,
discover who will emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
Well now that we got their histories and abilities
out of the way, let's speculate on how one
of the 1000 simulated matches will go. The winner
is determined by simulations, not the speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how the fight could
play out. AJ9K, what are the rules of our speculation?
Well I should say there are no rules, other
than the characters have no prior knowledge
of the other going into the fight. All they
are aware of starting out is that the other
character is a threat that needs to be eliminated.
For the speculation... The contestants will
begin approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the
match itself, as no environmental statistics
are considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. Alright
then, let's get into it. Geoforce and Quake
meet on the battlefield. Who goes first? Well,
Quake is an inhuman, so she has greater reflexes,
slightly. I'm going to say that she goes first.
and she's just gonna let rip a wide blast of
seismic vibrations from her hands that just
tear across the ground and slam into Geoforce,
sending him flying backward onto the floor.
Okay, Geoforce, you know, he was caught off
guard by the attack, but he's gonna land gently
on the ground thanks to his manipulation of
gravity, and once he does, he quickly opens
up a fissure beneath Quake that just sprays
her with hot lava. No, cause Quake will see
the fissure opening up beneath her. and she's
gonna shoot her vibrations down into the fissure
and the lava below her, keeping the lava from
boiling up and spilling out, and the downward
blast is just gonna propel her away from the
fissure, and when the lava does come out of
it, she's gonna use her vibrations to guide
the lava across the battlefield like this lava
wave that's just gonna fall on top of GeoForce
and just scald the shit out of them. through
lava and like shoots it out of his hands. What?
He's not gonna be hurt by it. All right. So
instead of getting scalded, he's just gonna
blast that wave coming at him with a torrent
of his own lava that then crashes right into
Quake. So now she's burned up. No, cause Quake's
gonna shake the ground beneath her and cause
a convergence so that this giant piece of land
just juts up right in front of her. And she
uses that as a shield. So the lava never reaches
her. Quake is gonna blast herself into the
air again, sending herself over to GeoForce,
and she crash lands right on top of him, legs
first, where she does the, you know, like the
Black Widow, Lucha Libra style flip, and she
just flips him onto the ground, onto his back.
Okay, so as she was about to land on him, suddenly
though, she's just floating in the air, right
above him, because he nullified the gravity
around her so that she can't land. So now she's
just trapped in the air. and he's gonna summon
a giant fist made of rock to shoot up from the
ground beneath her and just uppercut her right
into the sky. No, because as she's stuck in
midair with this stone fist beneath her, she's
gonna like force blast karate chop this giant
fist in half as it rises up and the shock waves
that she generates to break the stone fist in
half also shakes the ground beneath Geoforce
and that causes him to lose his concentration
so he drops her. And her gravity is restored
and she lands on the ground next to Geoforce
and just leg sweeps him. Okay, but as Geoforce
is falling, he's gonna increase his gravity
so that he actually slams into the ground hard
enough to generate this massive crater that
Quake is also gonna fall into. And at the bottom
of this deep crater, Geoforce is gonna levitate
all of the rock shrapnel that's all around
them and he's just gonna- send it flying at
Quake, just pummeling her with it, not stop,
essentially stoning her to death. Now, Quake
is just gonna disintegrate all these stones
flying at her one by one. You know, they just
turn into dust. And she's just like really
annoyed by this point, you know, just dealing
with GeoForce. So she continues by disintegrating
GeoForce's nuts, turning those into powder.
No! And he's like, oh my God, my nuts! Oh no.
Okay. Uh, so Joe Force, you know, he's gonna
drop instantly to the ground. Yeah. And, uh,
actually he's going to like drop into the ground.
It's just going to envelop him and bury him
and underground. He's able to rapidly heal and
regenerate his balls. What? Quick. She's going
to be busy trying to climb out of this giant
crater that he created, but it's too fucking
late. It's super volcano time, right? So this
is basically a huge lava bomb that just decimates
everything around it for miles. No way she could
escape in time. So she dead. I don't think
so. I mean, if GeoForce is busy hiding like
a punk ass deep underground, that's also Quake's
domain. Quake is gonna shake the ground beneath
her so hard that it pummeled GeoForce to death.
Just like he's gonna get rattled around down
there and his body's gonna get crushed into
pieces. That's match over. Dude, she doesn't
know where underground he was. All she has
to do is aim down. She just shakes all the ground
beneath her. He's somewhere down there. That's
where he dies. Okay, I mean, that's probably
a good place to leave off the match. Either
Quake gets decimated in a super volcanic eruption
or GeoForce gets essentially flattened by an
earthquake while he's busy healing underground.
We'll go ahead and leave the match there. We'll
input the character stats, run a thousand simulations
and come back with a winner. AG9K, hit it.
Inputting data, running calculations, processing
results, simulations complete. Okay, so stat
wise, this was a horrible matchup. Well, I thought
it would kind of turn out the same way as Terra
versus Avalanche, but there were a lot of notable
differences between Avalanche and. Quake. As
well as some notable differences between Terra
and GeoForce, surprisingly. Yeah, GeoForce
not only has all the abilities of Terra, but
he also has the added benefit of being able
to control lava and heat and gravity as well.
Yeah, which is pretty dumb. I mean, Quake is
a powerhouse. Both of these guys are, you know,
off the charts in terms of damage level and
the amount of destruction that they're able
to cause. They're both pretty comparable when
it comes to things, you know, like... fighting
skill, evasiveness, range. We said GeoForce
had the edge though when it came to things like
perception. Because he could sense things underground.
Yeah, and durability, because I guess he can
increase his own personal mass by increasing
his gravity. Right, we also said he had the
edge when it came to versatility and when it
came to speed because he could rocket himself
pretty fast through the air. Well, Quake is
an inhuman and she can run really fast. So,
considering all of the stats, Joseph. Who do
you think came out on top? Quake. You are lying
to yourself. No, do not lie to yourself. I
have my reasons. Oh yeah, what are they? Their
personal reasons. Okay, well what did the Instagram
poll say? I don't fucking know. What are you
doing? 58% of the people on Instagram who took
the poll said that Geoforce would take this,
which is surprising to me because I feel like
Quake is fairly well known, especially among
people who watched Agents of Shield. Everybody
knows, you know, Chloe Bennett, right? And Quake.
They know she's hot, but they don't know that
Quake can be GeoForce because she can't. At
least I'm pretty confident she can't. Let's
find out. AJ9K, the results please. Hey Yuasa.
The winner of the matchup between GeoForce
and Quake is... GeoForce! Obviously! What do
you mean obviously? I mean obviously! He won
82.4% of the 1000 matches. or 824 of those compared
to Quake, who only won 176 or 17.6%. This is
one of the most lopsided matches we've ever
done, and you my friend I think have just received
a rude awakening about not only the popularity
of Quake, but also the power of Quake. Yeah,
she's super powerful. At sucking and losing.
You know... Those kind of results just signify
that maybe this wasn't the best matchup. Which
is strange because, you know, Avalanche vs.
Terra wasn't that bad of a matchup. I know that
when the executive producers were helping us
develop this match, we had also considered other
characters besides Quake, including Magma,
because she could control lava and rock as well,
as well as Richter, who is kind of a similar
character to Avalanche. But we ended up going
with Quake. because she's popular, because
she's a badass, and because she can use her
seismic abilities in a variety of ways. Probably
should have gone with Magma. Magma would have
been a great match, for sure. But I feel like
these results would be different because I think
every time Geoforce would just get his heart
exploded and or nuts every time. There's no
instance of any battle between these two where
one of those things doesn't happen. Yeah, how's
that gonna happen when she's too busy being
burned alive in lava? She'll get over it, it's
fine. Sure. Sure she will. Clearly she won't.
Clearly Geoforce wins. Cause Geoforce is awesome.
Have fun taking Kimon again in our team duel
between the Outsiders and X-Force. Oh I can't
wait to. I can't wait to. Can't wait to lose?
I bet. But that does it for this duel. AG9K
help close this out. Thanks for listening to
Dynamic duel. Visit the show's website at dynamicduel.com
and follow us on Instagram at dynamicduelpodcast.
You can support the show on Patreon at patreon.com
slash dynamicduel and joining a tier that works
for you, or by rating and reviewing Dynamic
duel on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser
or on our website. Don't forget to listen to
the other shows in the Dynamite Podcast Network,
including Max Destruction, Senjow World and
Console Combat. In our next episode, it's going
to be another duel episode that will be a tie-in
to our upcoming team duel. Next week, we're
going to find out who would win in a fight between
Halo, who is an outsider's character, against
Power Pack, who is a group of superhero kids
who were pretty popular with Marvel back in
the day. I think their popularity has waned
a little bit, but they're pretty interesting,
cool characters. Yeah, I don't know really anything
about them. I- Just know that this will be
the first time where you have a group of characters
that goes up against one of my characters in
a similar way where the metal man went up against
Colossus in that duel episode. Right, right.
We'll figure out how to do the stats when the
time comes. That's future us's problem. But
that does it for this episode, we want to give
a big thanks to our executive producers Ken
Johnson, John Sturowski, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin
Belcombe, Mickey Mantengian, and Brandon Estergard,
Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Austin Wasylowski,
AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam
Spies, Andrew Schunk, Dean Molesky, Devin Davis,
and Joseph Kirsting for helping make this podcast
possible. And we'll talk to you guys next week.
Up up and away, true believers. I think I win
because paper beats rock and I got that paper
baby.