you
Hi and welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast,
a weekly show where we review superhero films
and debate the superiority between Marvel and
DC by comparing their characters and stat-based
battle simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe. And I'm
his twin brother, Johnny DC. And in this episode,
it's a duel episode. Really excited to get to
this one. We haven't done a duel in a while,
but we're going to find out who'd win in a fight
between Sandman, aka Dream of the Endless,
versus Mephisto. aka the devil himself of the
Marvel Universe. Right, Neil Gaiman's Sandman
is one of my favorite literary works, not just
comic books of all time. So I've been dying
to do a dual episode with him forever. But now
that the Netflix show is out, we finally have
that opportunity. Yeah, so this duel will tie
into the review of Netflix's The Sandman television
series that we're going to review next week.
Now, I know last episode, we said that the
duel was going to be between Sandman and Nightmare.
of the nightmare realm who is a doctor strange
villain but we both kind of balked at that idea
because it felt like it was too much of an
apple versus an apple as it were and who wins
in a fight between an apple versus an apple
an apple exactly on this show we more like to
find out who would win between similar power
level but different power set characters but
with similar themes or stories occasionally
yeah more along the lines of an apple versus
an orange that's much more interesting to me
because who wins that I have no fucking The
apple has cyanide in its core. What's gonna
happen? I feel like the apple is more durable.
Uh-huh. So I think the apple, I don't know.
We'll have to run the stats on this one day,
not today or any time soon. But yeah, that's
this episode. Before we get into the character
histories and abilities and run their stats
in 1000 Monte Carlo Simulations, we're gonna
go over the comic book movie news to come out
in the past week, including the news regarding
the main candidates for the head of DC Studios.
We also learned what Warner Brothers may do
with the upcoming Flash film. and we got a
trailer for the upcoming Pennyworth television
series season 3. As always we list our segment
times in our episode description so feel free
to check out the show notes if you want to
skip ahead to a particular topic. Don't forget
guys to join us on Patreon where we offer ad
free episodes of this show, bonus content including
top 10 episodes and bloopers, you don't want
to miss those. We also do monthly live movie
watch alongs and we give you access to our
Discord chat server where you can chat with
Jonathan and I and fellow fans of the show.
Yeah, check us out right after this episode
at patreon.com slash dynamic duel, which is
linked in our show notes. Our lowest tier is
only $2 a month and for 10 bucks a month, you
can become an executive producer of this show
and help us determine our episode content and
to get credited as such. But with that out of
the way, quick to the no prize. A no prize
is an award that Marvel used to give out up
until the nineties to fans. Our version, the
Dynamic Dual No Prize, is a digital award that
we post on Instagram for the person that we
feel gave the best answer to our question of
the week. Last week's question was a really
tough one. We asked, if you were rebooting the
DCEU as the new head of DC Studios, what would
be your 10-year plan in 30 seconds? It wasn't
an easy ask. Some of you guys sent in multiple
answers just to make sure everything was correct
within the 30-second span. And it wasn't easy
to choose a winner. But we have three honorable
mentions and a winner, so let's go through
those now. Our first honorable mention goes
to Miggy Mathengian, who said. Hey guys, this
is Miggy in phase one, Superman American Alien,
Batman Dark Victory, Wonder Woman Gods and
Mortals, Flash movie like Groundhog Day, Green
Lantern movie with Jessica Cruz, and a Justice
League origin film. Phase two would be a Superman
sequel with Supergirl, Wonder Woman sequel
with Donna, Flash sequel with Wally and Grodd,
Green Lantern Far Sector, a Zatanna movie,
and Justice League Doom. Phase three would be
Superman Brainiac, Wonder Woman Hikateya, Flash
movie where he fights Abracadabra, Green Lantern,
third movie, Titans movie, Mr. American movie,
and Apocalypse War. Wow, he really made a great
use of those 30 seconds. He had it all fleshed
out. That's a great plan. Like in the first
phase, you really set up the Justice League.
The second phase, you set up like the legacy
characters, like the sidekicks and stuff. The
third phase, like you even introduced the Titans
team and everything. I love that answer. Yeah,
and he managed to squeeze three phases into
10 years, which is really cool. The only gripe
I have with it is that there really wasn't a
lot of Batman. And considering he's one of
the main pillars of D.C., I feel like he should
have had a few more film projects in that plan.
Well, we've already had The Batman. I'm assuming
that Miggie's incorporating The Batman movie
into his phases. I'm sure he is. Yeah. Good
job, Miggy. Thank you for putting so much thought
into that. Yeah, great work. If DC Studios put
your plan into action and announced that that's
what they were gonna do, Jonathan would probably
shit his pants. Oh, I would. I mean, I almost
did when I heard his response. Ha ha ha. Our
next honorable mention goes to Adam Trumbull,
who said. This is Adam Trumbull here. I'll continue
with the Robert Pattinson Batman Gotham. I'll
release a film about Dick Grayson's perspective
on Gotham, the Batman, and the Riddler, and
instead of him coming. Robin would become Nightwing
right away and the different angles he would
take by catching the Riddler. So that sounds
like just a couple of films. Yeah, I mean this
is the opposite problem that Miggie had in that
it's overly Batman focused, right? I think
if you took Adam Trimble's and Miggie's plan,
you mix them together, you have a really, really
solid 10 year lineup. I'm surprised Miggie didn't
say he was going to do a Nightwing movie, considering
that's one of his favorite characters. Yeah,
well he mentioned... Titans, but again, there's
only one Batman film in those 10 years. Gotta
do Nightwing, gotta do Gotham Knights I think
that would be awesome. That would be awesome.
Our final honorable mention goes to Eric Maisel
who said My 10 year reboot looks like this solo
movies for a Constantine Deadman swamp thing
which is gonna lead into a Justice League dark
movie Then Nightwing's got to get his own solo
film which will lead into a Titans movie You
got to do far sector in there somewhere and
then All of it can wrap up with death metal
so that all the previous versions don't need
to be rebooted. And then for animation, deceased
and DC versus vampires. I really liked his
answer because not only did he expand upon the
Justice League Dark characters, but he also
mentioned DC death metal, which I think is another
big event that DC could eventually get to,
sort of like, you know, Marvel's Endgame or
something like that. If you do Miggy's Justice
League Dark Apocalypse War and then maybe like
death metal after that, You're going someplace,
right? It's a plan and a good one too. Yeah,
I didn't know much about death metal until
our recent Cosmic Ghost Rider versus the Batman
Who Laughs dual episode. And yeah, it sounds
really interesting. It's definitely something
that you would want to save for one of the
later phases though, for sure. Oh yeah, I agree.
Yeah, totally. Because it really goes into
the nature of the DC universe itself, that story.
Right, right, right. We want to give a quick
shout out to Landon Parker, Laksh Tangi, Scotty
Macho, Lu. Noah Terry for taking the time to
visit our website and record good answers to
our question of the week Yeah, I loved hearing
all of your ideas, but the winner of this week's
no prize is Jacob Bell who said hey guys, this
is Jacob. Here we go Superman solo movie then
do a Wonder Woman movie that introduces the
Atlanteans then do a Superman Batman team up
movie Then do a Green Lantern core movie that
introduces all the Green Lanterns then do a
Gotham Knights movie where we have the bat
family then do a Flash solo movie, then you
do Superman 2 as the sequel where Lex Luthor
is the villain and at the end he introduces
Brainiac and Brainiac is the villain for the
next movie which is the Justice League. Great!
I like that. That's nice and simple. I like
how he managed to incorporate all the members
of the main Justice League but he also had
interesting ideas like a Gotham Knights movie
and introducing the Atlanteans in Wonder Woman.
Right, right. It really takes advantage of world
building, I think. Yeah, he does a really good
job of building upon his shared universe as
it develops. I don't know if it's quite enough
films for 10 years, but I think those are pretty
much all of the movies I would love to see.
Yeah, it's a great start to the plan. Jacob
did send a clarifying message saying that this
would actually exist separate from Robert Pattinson's
Batman universe. Which I don't know if I love
that. I definitely think that Robert Pattinson's
universe should be the start of DC's new plan.
Now is that just because you don't want to have
multiple Batman again? Because I don't know
if their approach that Matt Reeves took with
the Batman, which is overly grounded, would
work in a team environment. I think it depends
on the writer. I think a solid writer could
make it work. Maybe we'll see. But thanks to
Jacob Bell for the answer. Congrats again for
winning this week's No Prize. Guys, be sure
to check out Jacob's own podcast called The
Rankers, where he and his buddy rank the top
10 of a bunch of different topics. And if you,
the listener, want a shot at winning your own
No Prize... Stay tuned to later on this episode
when we'll be asking another Question of the
Week. And now that that's done, on to the news!
Okay, as we talked about last week, Warner Brothers
Discovery has canceled the Batgirl film and
this has led to just chaos, pure chaos, in the
movie industry. Yeah, apparently everybody
at DC hates David Zaslav. What, where did you
hear that? Places, sources. You don't know
anyone from DC. I read things on the internet.
I guess that wouldn't surprise me. I don't
think it's fair because you know, you have a
guy really looking out for the DC brand for
the first time. and maybe forever when it comes
to films at least. And of course, this is a
guy who wants a solid plan for DC going forward,
a 10-year plan to sort of capture the same
magic that Marvel has created. Now to spearhead
this 10-year plan, there are currently rumored
to be three candidates to head up the new DC
studios. The first one being Greg Berlanti,
who was basically in control of the CW's DC
Comics television series, including Arrow,
Flash, Supergirl, Legends of Tomorrow, Black
Lightning, all of them. Yeah, he oversaw the
Arrowverse, as it were. Exactly, yes. So a lot
of people at Warner Brothers in DC apparently
are rooting for him to take that role, even
though he hasn't officially even talked with
David Zaslav about it. Well, he definitely seems
the most qualified candidate. To an extent,
he definitely is capable of producing a plan,
as we've seen with multiple crossover events
on the CW, like Crisis on Infinite Earths. like
Elseworlds, things like that. But was that
the level of quality that we see from like the
MCU? I'm not convinced. Well, I mean, it was
made for TV on the CW with the TV budget. And
that's fair, and that's fair. But he was also
responsible for the Green Lantern movie. He
was one of the writers on that. Oh, that's
right. Now he has a shot at redemption for that
because he's producing the Green Lantern television
series for HBO Max, which apparently is still
on track. So we'll see. Maybe if that's successful.
he could step up into the reins of the head
of DC Studios. The other contender for the
top spot would be Walter Hamada, the current
head of DC Films, who apparently is being championed
by existing Warner Brothers Discovery executives.
I don't know if I like Hamada in the role though.
I mean, like out of all the films that he's
produced for DC, 75% of them have been rated
R. Quite a few of them have been outside of
any sort of existing continuity like the Joker
and the Batman. He doesn't really seem to have
a good idea. for a sense of continuity. He
just likes to tell good stories, assuming this
like, multiversal approach where filmmakers
can do whatever they want. Right, right. Hamada
is a good producer, and he's had a lot of success
during his time at DC Films, but you're right.
His current method is not gonna be something
that David Zaslov is happy with, because again,
he's chasing after Marvel money. I do have
to give him credit for DC's television series
on HBO Max though. You know, you had... Watchmen
come out during his time as head of DC films
Peacemaker was phenomenal and he's really spearheading
a lot of the upcoming the Batman television
tie-ins, which is pretty cool I'm really torn
as to whether or not I think I want him to come
up with a 10-year plan for DC It seems like
he doesn't have a good plan for Superman. No,
absolutely not. Yeah, that's a huge downgrade
in my book Now the third contender for this
role is a producer by the name of Dan Lin who
produced the Lego movie and the Sherlock Holmes
films. He was also the producer of the ill-fated
Justice League Mortal film that was going to
be directed by George Miller back in 2008.
Now, a lot of concept art and story details
have come out for that film, and it seems like
it could have been a pretty cool movie. Dan
Lin is a DC Comics fan, and that's something
you absolutely want. for the head of DC Studios.
I would consider that the primary criteria,
given that Kevin Feige was a huge Marvel Comics
fan as he came aboard Marvel Studios. Dan Lin
is definitely the dark horse in this race, considering
he also has his own production company and
may not wanna give that up for this role. But
if he's chosen, I think you could find success
with him. Out of these three candidates, I would
say that my preference would be Dan Lin. Yeah,
I think he's done some great films. Like, you
know, the Lego movie had Batman in it. Not
that he would go with that same Batman, but
again, he's a fan of the DC Comics characters.
And he has some history with them. Little bit.
Now, of course, we have no idea when the new
head of DC Studios is going to be hired and
come on board and start shaping things. Hopefully
it's soon, and hopefully they come up with some
plan for the Flash movie. Because right now,
we've learned Warner Brothers has three different
options that they're considering. Now, the
first scenario sounds a little optimistic. Basically,
Warner Brothers wants Ezra Miller to seek professional
help. Now, recently, when he's been coming on
sets, doing reshoots and stuff like that for
The Flash, his mother has been accompanying
him. And that's been a big help in sort of
reigning in his behavior, apparently. But they
want him to get therapy and they want him to
do an interview at some point that explains
Ezra's erratic behavior over the past few years.
Apparently, Ezra has communicated that he is
willing to do that. But if he keeps getting
charged with burglary for stealing liquor from
someone's home, that's going to make that a
lot harder. Yeah, honestly, who steals liquor?
Just go buy your own, especially if you can
afford it, right? Really weird. Really weird.
Bizarre. Dangerous behavior. Absolutely. Now
the second scenario is that if Miller doesn't
seek professional help, Warner Brothers can
still release the film, but they just wouldn't
have Miller play a prominent role in the marketing
and publicity of the movie. It's not an ideal
scenario. this one because Ezra Miller is so
prominent throughout the movie. It's going to
be weird if he doesn't promote it. And if things
continue to get worse with Ezra Miller and his
behavior, Warner Brothers has a third option,
which is to scrap the movie outright, just like
what they did with Batgirl. At a certain point,
the public would really no longer want to see
any movie with them. It would just be kind
of tainted and not enjoyable. And while previously,
while that probably would have been detrimental
to the future of DC films, Since we already
know Zezlav wants to reboot the whole thing,
canceling the film is not the worst thing that
could happen. I don't think so, honestly. And
I'm still kinda hoping they reboot sooner rather
than later. I know a lot of people don't feel
that way. But so again, basically Warner Bros.
Discovery's options are release and promote
the film with Ezra Miller provided they get
professional help. Or still release the film
without having Ezra Miller promote it. Or scrap
the film. Yeah, and it kinda seems like their
hands are tied. by Ezra Miller's choices, which
is not a good spot for a studio to be in, I
feel like. But even if the best-case scenario
happens, would people still be interested in
seeing the Flash movie? That brings us to our
question of the week.
If Ezra Miller gets professional help and explains
their erratic behavior, would you still be
open to watching The Flash movie? If you weren't
already. And let us know why. Record your answer
at dynamicduel.com by clicking on the red microphone
button in the bottom right hand corner, which
will prompt you to leave us a voicemail. Your
message could be up to 30 seconds long. And
don't forget to leave your name in case we include
you on the podcast. We'll pick our favorite
answer and award that person at Dynamic Duel
no prize that we'll post to Instagram. Be sure
to answer before August 20th. In our last bit
of news, HBO Max has released the trailer for
season three of Pennyworth, which now has a
new subtitle, Pennyworth, the origin of Batman's
butler, which has to be the worst fucking subtitle
of any show ever. It's so bad. It's embarrassing.
It's so literal. I know, it's so on the nose.
I don't know who came up with that. They just
need to undo that, release a new trailer. It
could be salvaged. Have you watched any seasons
of Pennyworth? No, I don't have the Epics network.
Prior to this being an HBO Max original, this
show was an exclusive on Epics, of course. They
released two seasons, haven't seen either of
them, was never really interested, honestly,
in seeing them, even though it's a DC show.
It's not terrible from what I've heard. Well,
I mean, it's on season three, so it obviously
has some sort of fan base. Yeah, absolutely,
absolutely. This trailer, I have to say, doesn't
quite sell me on anything, though. It's a little
bit more style over substance. It seems a little,
I don't know, Austin Powers, I guess, if I could
describe it as anything. A non-comedic version
of Austin Powers, which some might say is James
Bond. Austin Powers is a James Bond parody.
Yeah, and I definitely get spy intrigue vibes
from this show. Just very dated vibes, I would
say. Like 70s dated. Hey, some of the best James
Bond movies came out in the 1970s, man. The
worst fucking James Bond movies came out in
the 1970s. Yeah, also the worst ones. Yeah.
Roger Moore was a little inconsistent in the
trailer. Alfred Pennyworth explains that he
charges for his services, but that his honor
isn't for sale in a very decent Michael Caine
impression. Yeah, it really seems like this
is the Alfred Pennyworth of the Nolan Batman
films. I get that impression. Absolutely. But
the rest of the trailer doesn't tell me anything
about the story for the season. It's just a
bunch of quick action shots before the new
title of the series is revealed. Do you think
the show delves into any of Batman's rogues
galleries past? Like, do we see any of the Falcone
crime family or something in the show? I would
be surprised considering the show takes place
in Britain. But I have no idea because I haven't
seen any of the seasons. Well, which one of
Batman's villains is from Britain? Mad Hatter?
Yep. Possibly him. Who else? I don't know. Not
many. I feel like it's really him just going
up against like KGB agents or something like
that. That's the impression that I get. We
are considering reviewing this season. It doesn't
start until October. We don't have an official
release date yet. We just know the month and
we do know that it's going to have 10 episodes.
If we do review it, I can't say I'm going to
commit to watching seasons one and two in lead
up to it. So you have to you have to you're
the DC fan. I don't want to. You have to because
I'm not gonna. Somebody has to. It might be
good, you never know. If someone out there
who's listening has watched the Pennyworth television
series and is a fan of it, reach out to us
and let us know why you like it. Yeah, maybe
I can be convinced to watch the earlier seasons,
which are on HBO Max now, as the trailer also
teases, it's like, catch up now before the
third season. We'll see, we'll see HBO Max.
But I think that does it for the news for this
episode, so let's go ahead and get into our
main event where we find out who'd win in a
fight between Sandman of the Endless, and Mephisto,
the devil himself.
Alright, Sandman versus Mephisto. Now again,
this duel is in lead up to the review of season
one of The Sandman, which is on Netflix right
now. Check it out, it's awesome. Yeah, Jonathan
won't let me watch past episode three because
he has an idea for this duel speculation that
we're about to do that he doesn't want me to
spoil for myself. Right, right. Because I guess
in the series, at some point, Sandman gets into
a battle with Lucifer. Yeah, it's Lucifer in
the TV series and a demon in the comic book.
but it still works out because it's a demon
game. And perfect for this matchup. Yeah, and
if you guys don't know who Mephisto is, he
has been long rumored to appear in the MCU for
ages now. It's become kind of a meme, but he's
basically the devil in the Marvel universe.
He's a villain for almost all of Marvel's heroes,
but especially like Silver Surfer, Ghost Rider,
Doctor Strange, Thor, and Spider-Man sometimes.
I think we primarily chose these two characters
because they're both insanely powerful and
they both have their own realms that they're
like in charge of. Right, exactly. They could
basically do almost anything within their own
realm, but they're no slouch either outside
of their home. And they both have like rock
star haircuts. So yeah, totally. Yeah. If you've
never listened to one of our dual episodes before,
the way we determine a winner between these
two characters is by running 1000 Monte Carlo
simulations using their statistics. is a probabilistic
model used to determine outcomes through random
sampling. And in our case it randomizes statistics
along a normal distribution, which is a bell
curve, as a way to simulate the many variables
that can occur during battle. The stat parameters
we use are based on the official Marvel power
grid, and we use that criteria to extrapolate
the DC character's stats. We've included some
additional stat categories of our own, such
as range, damage potential,
Running these 1000 simulations gives us a percentage
of wins for each character, and we declare
the one with the higher percentage to be the
ultimate victor, considering that they're more
likely to win any given battle. No character
ever wins 100% of the time. Comics have shown
that there's usually a way for Batman to defeat
Superman, and we feel our method falls in line
with the precedents that have been established
in the comic book stories. And we used this
method because it was the least subjective,
most unbiased way to determine who would win.
Of course, we are both heavily biased toward
our respective allegiances, so instead of debating
these matches forever, we just let the math
decide for us. There's no fan votes here, and
no relying on just feats. Before we run the
simulations though, we like to break down each
character's histories and abilities before improvising
a scenario on how we imagine one of the 1000
simulations we run would play out beat for beat.
Yeah, and I think it's my turn to go first
with my character's backstory, though I do,
before I begin, want to preface this backstory
with a spoiler warning. I know some of our patrons,
specifically, are working their way through
the Sandman comic series, and anyone who wants
to get through the Sandman television series
completely fresh should know that unlike the
stories of many comic characters we break down
on this podcast, the story of Sandman has a
definitive ending. which I will be revealing,
so skip this part if you don't want to get spoiled.
Definitely recommend the series and or watching
the show. Alright, so Sandman is one of many
titles bestowed upon a being known as Dream,
who is the ruler and personification of dreams,
stories, imagination, and essentially thought.
He's one of seven personified beings of unimaginable
power known as the Endless, who manifested
naturally as the universe formed and are older
than the gods. When life first emerged, so
did destiny, then death. When beings became
sentient, dream came into existence, followed
by destruction, desire, despair, and finally,
delight, who later became delirium. Each of
the Endless have their own realms which they
are responsible for, dreams being the dreaming,
where beings go when their consciousness escapes
reality. When the first murder victim in the
universe died, Dream took pity on him, and death
allowed Dream to bring him into the Dreaming
instead of the afterlife. Dream named him Abel,
and he became a storyteller who lived in the
House of Secrets. Eventually, Abel became lonely,
however, so Dream also brought his brother
Cain into the Dreaming when he died, gifting
him the House of Mystery. Over the course of
billions of years within the Dreaming, Dream
crafted more and more Dreamlands and Nightmares,
while also collecting more and more titles such
as Morpheus, Oniros, and The Sandman. To help
him maintain the Dream Inc, Dreamcrafted several
tools, including a pouch of magic sand, a ruby
red dreamstone to harness Dreams and Focus's
power, and a helm made from the bones of an
ancient god as a symbol of his station and power.
Ten thousand years ago, while traveling on
Earth, Dream and an African queen named Nada
saw each other and fell in love, though Dream
disappeared afterward and Nada was unaware that
he was one of the Endless. After finding him
again in the Dreaming, Nada fled when she realized
who he was, knowing they could never be together.
Dream sought after her, however, and eventually
the two copulated their love, only to awaken
the next morning with Nada's city destroyed.
Blaming herself, she committed suicide. though
Dream was able to save her soul and promised
to make her Queen of the Dreaming. When she
refused, he banished her to hell for eternity.
That's cold blooded. Oh yeah, Dream was petty
as hell back in the old days. Just over 2,000
years ago, Dream and the Greek muse of epic
poetry, Calliope, had a son, the mythic loot
player Orpheus. Orpheus led a tragic life,
however, losing his fiance, Eurydice, to the
underworld and later dying by having his body
ripped apart. As a progeny of the Endless, however,
his head survived and continued to live on
as an oracle. Meanwhile, Dream and Calliope
became estranged from one another. In 14th
century London, Dream accompanied his sister
Death amongst the people at her request. While
in a tavern, they overheard a man named Hob
Gadling tell his friends that he refused to
die, and as a favor to Dream, Death agreed never
to take him.
every 100 years, and in their second meeting
in the 16th century, Dream also met a man named
Will Shaxbird, an aspiring playwright who made
a deal with Dream to write stories that would
spur new dreams in the minds of men in exchange
for unlimited inspiration. Dream commissioned
two plays from Shaxbird, who would find success
under the name Shakespeare, one of which, A
Midsummer's Night Dream, was made specifically
so that the people of that used to inhabit
the world. During Dream's 18th century meeting
with Hob in the Tavern, the two were ambushed
by Lady Johanna Constantine, who had heard of
their meetings and intended to kidnap them
in order to learn their secrets. Dream put her
to sleep and later requested her help in retrieving
his son Orpheus's head, which had been stolen
by the French government. In the early 20th
century, a British occultist named Roderick
Burgess accidentally trapped and imprisoned
Dream. during an occult ritual in an attempt
to capture and control death. While Dream was
imprisoned, several people around the world
suffered from severe sleeping disorders, including
a young British woman named Unity Kincaid, who
would not wake up. Remaining silent and offering
nothing in exchange for his release, Dream remained
trapped for over 70 years, during which time
his sand pouch, helmet, and dreamstone were
stolen by When Dream finally managed to break
free, Roderick had already died, so he got his
revenge on his son Alex Burgess by cursing
him with a never-ending nightmare. Dream returned
to the dreaming weekend, and found his realm
in near collapse, abandoned by his creations
due to his absence. Needing the tools that
were stolen from him to regain his power, Dream
summoned the Three Fates, who directed him
to John Constantine for his sand pouch, Hel
for his helm, and and the Justice League for
his Dreamstone. You can of course learn more
about John Constantine and the Justice League
in their respective dual episodes of this podcast.
After regaining his sand pouch from Constantine's
ex-girlfriend and his helm from a demon after
defeating him in a game, Dream learned that
his Dreamstone had been used by the reality-warping
super-villain Dr. Destiny, aka John D., the
son of Ethel Cripps, who had corrupted the Dreamstone.
When Dream tried to recover the Dreamstone
from Justice League's storage, its corrupted
form sat his remaining energy, just before
John D broke out of Arkham Asylum and retook
the Dreamstone. Causing the world to go insane,
Dream challenged John D to a battle in the Dreaming,
where John D attempted to kill Dream by destroying
the Dreamstone. Instead, Dream's full power
was returned to him, and Dream returned John
D back to Arkham Asylum. After restoring the
Dreaming to its former glory, its former citizens
all returned, save for a domain known as Fiddler's
Green and three nightmares named Brut, Glob,
and the Corinthian. Thanks to a young woman
named Rose Walker, the granddaughter of Unity
Kincaid, Dream was able to return Fiddler's
Green to the Dreaming, unmake the Corinthian,
and banish Brut and Glob to the darkness for
creating their own pocket Dreaming inside the
mind of Rose's younger brother Jed. where they
also kept the ghost of Hector Hall, the son
of Hawkman and Hawkgirl, and his pregnant wife,
Lyta. Dream pushed Hector's ghost into the
afterlife and told Lyta that since her baby
gestated in the dreaming, it belonged to him.
Rose turned out to be a being known as a Vortex,
capable of breaking down the barriers between
people's dreams, and Dream was nearly forced
to kill her to protect the world until Unity
Kincaid intervened and revealed that she would
have been the Vortex had Dream not been trapped
by Roderick Burgess. Unity took Rose's vortex
aspect and died in the process. Dream later
learned that Desire impregnated Unity in her
sleep, making Rose his niece. Had Dream killed
Rose, per ancient rules that bind the Endless,
Dream would have been forced to sacrifice his
life to the Fates for spilling family blood,
which was Desire's goal all along as he slash
she had hated Dream. for billions of years,
constantly interfering in his affairs in secret,
and was even responsible for the death of Eurydice.
Dream later learned Calliope had been imprisoned
by a rider with Rider's Block and he freed her,
as well as Nata from Hell, finally forgiving
her for rejecting him and helping her reincarnate.
While in Hell, Lucifer, out of revenge for
Dream's previous visit, abandoned Hell and gave
it to Dream. resulting in many pantheons visiting
the Dreaming to ask for the realm. This included
the fairy, who gifted Dream a fairy servant
named Noella to gain his favor. In the end,
two angels from heaven visited Dream to claim
hell in the name of God. Dream was later asked
by Delirium to help her find their long-lost
brother Destruction, who had abandoned his responsibilities
and gone missing thousands of years earlier.
With the help of his oracle son Orpheus, Still
a living decapitated head, Dream and Delirium
found their brother Destruction, who rejected
their suggestion that he return to his role
as one of the Endless. Fulfilling a promise
to his son, Dream returned to Orpheus and peacefully
ended his pitiful life. Having returned to the
Dreaming, Dream set Noella the Fairy free,
giving her a magic pendant that allowed her
to summon him as a reward for her faithful
service. Dream also recreated the Corinthian.
who he sent along with his raven Matthew to
rescue Daniel, Lyda's son, who had been kidnapped
by the Norse god Loki and Robin Goodfellow.
Believing that Dream had killed Daniel, Lyda,
merged with the Fates, stormed the Dreaming
to destroy Dream for supposedly killing his
adopted son, per the ancient rules. Though
it was revealed that this wasn't the case, the
Fates, in their vengeful state known as the
Kindly Ones, maintained their claim on Dream's
life, since he had killed his son Orpheus.
Soon, the Kindly Ones began harming Dream's
loyal servants and freeing his prisoners, and
to protect him, Nuala used her pendant to summon
Dream to the Fairy Realm, unaware that the
Kindly Ones could not harm Dream outside of
the Dreaming. Before facing the Kindly Ones,
Dream gifted Daniel, who had been saved by the
Corinthian, an emerald dreamstone. As he was
chosen to take on the role of the ruler and
caretaker of the Dreaming, after Dream's death.
To save the Dreaming from the Kindly Ones, Dream
summoned his sister, Death, to escort him to
her realm known as the Sunless Lands. A massive
wake was held in the Dreaming in Dream's honor
with all of his siblings in attendance, and
his body was sent to drift on a barge within
the Dreaming. And that's Dream's complete story
from Neil Gaiman's initial Sandman run. I haven't
gotten into any of the apocryphal works at all.
Powers-wise, Dream of the Endless wields the
power of stories and imagination, capable of
creating or uncreating anything, anyone, or
any place that could be dreamed up. He can will
other beings to sleep, cast or dispel illusions,
affect the thoughts and perceptions of others,
and he could teleport himself or others to
any location in the dreaming, and he could travel
through or track anyone who dreams. He can
alter his appearance at will, heal injuries,
and he can transfer his powers to objects or
people. Within his own realm of the Dreaming,
he is nigh omnipotent, having complete control
over its reality, and he cannot be harmed. That's
the Sandman. That was a lot of names to keep
track of. There's a ton of characters in the
series, absolutely. I think there was like,
Kaliope and Lida, and they were people within
the story. I don't remember what they did.
I'm sorry, did you have a hard time following
that? Yeah, because it was so many names. So
many names. Just re-listen, just re-listen,
the names will catch on. All right, okay. Well,
usually within your backstories, the name dropping
that you do are of characters that I know of
and I have that context going. But with this
one, it was a lot of name dropping of characters
that I didn't know and therefore had a hard
time keeping up. That's probably fair. The
Sandman series took place in DC's Vertigo imprint.
for mature readers. So a majority of it exists
sort of outside of DC continuity, even though
it still is a part of that. So yeah, it's no
surprise that you weren't familiar with a lot
of the characters. And because of that, I feel
like you didn't really ruin the Netflix show
for me. I literally just ruined all of it.
Well, I mean, then it doesn't seem like it's
gonna be that interesting then. Oh my gosh.
I left out a ton of stuff. There's way more
to the Sandman series than what I said. I just
gave you specifically. Sandman story, which
is why I stopped with his death. OK, I mean,
the entire like final volume of the series takes
place after dreams death. So there's a lot
more to the story. OK. Well, I think the big
takeaway I took from it, though, is that dream
has died and can die and he's going to die again.
All right. Is what's going to happen if you
chose to. OK, OK. You know who hasn't chosen
to die? Mephisto, because he's a winner. And
he's going to win this match. Let's hear about
him. All right. Mephisto. sometimes called
Mephistopheles, Satan, Beelzebub, the Prince
of Lies, the Lord of Evil, and the Master of
Hell. He is the devil himself in the Marvel
Universe whose sole aim is to corrupt those
who are good and claim as many souls for his
netherworld. The true nature of Mephisto's
inception is a mystery, though it's said he
is nearly as old as the universe itself, created
by a force that had no concept of morality.
As a manifestation of pure evil, Mephisto drifted
along the burgeoning cosmos and settled in the
molten mass that would one day form the planet
Earth to form his hellish domain. Mephisto evolved
there into something like that of a fly, who
billions of years ago witnessed a celestial
fall to the newly formed planet, infected by
a cosmic disease that helped spread perversion
and grotesqueries across the Earth's barely
evolved life. This helped the demon Mephisto
grow in power, influencing Earth's inhabitants
toward damnation. the millennia, where he would
manifest to mankind's most hateful, most naive,
and most needy to grant them their desires and
manipulate them into selling their souls, for
they were what Mephisto fed off of and gave
him power. As humanity developed their mythologies
and religions, many of their dark deities were
based on Mephisto and he fed off that, in turn
perpetuating their belief in a supreme evil,
shaping his appearance to fit their greatest
fear of the devil. Other great demons would
rise to challenge him, and Mephisto was constantly
at war with potential usurpers of his Hell Throne,
such as Thog, Satanish, and the demon Zerathos,
whom Mephisto defeated and would one day bond
to Johnny Blaze the Ghost Rider, whom you can
learn more about in our Etrigan vs Ghost Rider
episode. Mephisto tempted and prodded the villains
of Earth's past, including the powerful mutant
Apocalypse and the treacherous sorceress Morgan
Le Fay. Mephisto grew fascinated with Earth's
developing superpowered heroes and their capacity
to protect and inspire despite his unceasing
campaign to corrupt and destroy. During World
War II, he convinced Nazi scientists to open
a portal to his realm, assuring them it led
to a race of perfect beings when it in fact
was his demonic horde. Mephisto confined the
soul of Dr. Doom's mother in Hell and would
battle and defeat Doom every Halloween when
the barrier between Earth and Hell's realms
were weakened. Eventually, Doctor Doom freed
his mother by betraying his temporary ally,
Doctor Strange, offering Mephisto the Sorcerer's
Supreme Soul in exchange for his mother's. Mephisto
had become a long-standing enemy of Doctor
Strange and coveted his righteous soul, but
the hero was able to escape Mephisto's hellish
grasp. You can learn more about Doctor Doom
and Doctor Strange in their respective dual
episodes. Mephisto made many enemies over the
years, but desired most of all the pure spirit
of the hero Silver Surfer. whom he tempted time
and again with riches and with his former love,
Shalabal, but the surfer would never give in.
Mephisto fought the Fantastic Four and dragged
Franklin, the son of Mr. Fantastic and Invisible
Woman, into Hell. The child's vast psychic
and reality warping powers temporarily destroyed
Mephisto, however, and his essence was scattered
into fragments. The mystical energies of two
of these fragments were unknowingly used to
create Billy and Tommy, the sons of Vision and
the Scarlet Witch. When Mephisto eventually
reformed, he drew back all of his remaining
fragments, erasing Billy and Tommy from existence
to the Scarlet Witch's despair. Mephisto would
eventually create a son of his own, named Blackheart,
who delighted in creating misery for heroes
such as Ghost Rider and Daredevil. Mephisto
tried to teach his son how to rule hell, but
Blackheart rebelled and tried to overthrow
his father and claim his throne, forcing Mephisto
to put him in his place. Mephisto developed
a strong rivalry for souls with other underworld
rulers, including Pluto, the Greek ruler of
Hades, and Hela, the Asgardian ruler of Hel,
spelled H-E-L, one L. Right, not the double
hockey stick. Right. When Hela attempted to
expand her realm to engulf the living, Mephisto
temporarily stole Thor's soul and tormented
it, forcing him to witness the horrors of the
underworld. After the God of Thunder was freed,
Thor vowed to forever stand against Hela and
stopped her advances into Earth's realm. much
to Mephisto's delight. He was actually successful
in getting Black Panther to sell his soul to
him for some assistance. However, Mephisto
had no idea that the hero was forever tied to
Bast, the Panther God, and therefore was outsmarted
by the Wakandan King. One of Mephisto's greatest
successes though, was the eradication of the
love between Spider-Man and Mary Jane Watson.
The couple sacrificed their marriage to him
in order to save the life of Peter Parker's
Aunt May. Which is weird, she was gonna die
anyway, she's old. To achieve this, Mephisto
erased the knowledge of Peter Parker's identity
to the entire world. When the villainous organization
Hydra destroyed the city of Las Vegas, Dr.
Strange restored it, and Mephisto used the opportunity
to manifest a piece of hell on Earth, called
Hotel Inferno, where gamblers could bet their
very souls. This forced Dr. Strange to summon
the Midnight Suns, a group of supernatural heroes
whom you can learn more about in our Justice
League Dark versus Midnight Suns dual episode.
While Mephisto battled the team on Earth, Ghost
Rider took over the Realm of Hell, cutting Mephisto
off from his power and he was imprisoned. But
ruling hell corrupted Johnny Blaze, and his
brother Danny Ketch and Doctor Strange were
compelled to exercise and rescue him from the
underworld. As the heroes escaped hell, so
did a horde of demons into Earth. They were
taken over, however, at the time by alien clintar
symbiotes like Venom that were created by the
deity Null who was taken over Earth. Mephisto
was then released from his prison to help fight
the symbiote-possessed demon horde, and then
he returned to hell as its rightful ruler. And
that's his backstory. Powers-wise, Mephisto
possesses nearly limitless supernatural power,
nearly unrivaled in the Marvel universe, energized
by the evil of mankind and the souls he imprisons
in hell. With this power, he can manipulate
his own form to take on any appearance or level
of strength. He can sense the morality of others
from any distance and transport himself instantaneously
and across the galaxy. Mephisto can also cast
illusions and manipulate reality around him
to fulfill almost any desire of one he's bargaining
with. This can range from psychic feats to power
enhancement, time manipulation, and so on.
He wields Hellfire, which burns not only anything
physical, but anything metaphysical as well.
Mephisto is immortal and virtually indestructible,
though if he is somehow destroyed, he reforms
in his domain after a while where he is most
powerful. He can peer through time to see the
past and potential futures of his victims, and
he can trap people or their astral selves,
their souls, in hell. Finally, Mephisto does
have a couple of limitations despite his immense
power. He cannot force his will upon someone
without their permission, and the longer he
spends away from his realm, the weaker he becomes.
And those are his powers. Yeah, I'm not impressed.
I'm not impressed. What? For a Sandman, like,
all that stuff is beneath him. He's way above,
like, morality of, like, good and evil. It's
just trifling matters. You're talking about
a guy who was trapped by an amateur magician
in a snow globe. It was ancient magic. And
apparently he doesn't have any of his powers
without his items, so I mean, good luck with
that. Well, he undid that. Okay. Yeah, he learned
from that mistake. Alright, not too smart,
but whatever. Now that we got these characters'
histories and abilities out of the way, let's
speculate on how one of the 1000 simulated matches
will go. The winner is determined by simulations,
not the speculation, but it's fun to imagine
how this fight could play out. We don't set
any rules for this match other than the characters
don't know anything about each other going
in, except that the other character is a threat
that needs to be put down. And we say that
they start off about 50 meters apart in an environment
that has no bearing on the match itself, because
we don't take stats for the environment. Plus
certain characters have advantages in some
environments over others, and we want these
characters to win on their own merit. So let's
get into it. Sandman and Mephisto meet on the
battlefield. Who goes first? Alright, as I
mentioned earlier, I want to do something special
for this one, so I'm going to say Dream goes
first, okay? Okay. Dream sees Mephisto and recognizes
him as a powerful lord of hell. Uninterested
in coming to blows, Dream's going to make a
proposition. Since both beings are immensely
powerful and a battle between them could truly
upset the fabric of the universe, Dream will
suggest that they instead play an ancient demons
game. It's the same one that Dream played in
hell to regain his helmet. Basically, they take
turns saying and describing that they are different
things, each time saying that they are something
that can destroy or overcome what the opponent
said, and so on and so forth until one of them
draws a blank. Whoever loses must see defeat
and withdraw back to their realm defeated. Okay,
so kind of like our Riddler vs Arcade dual
episode where we tried something a little bit
different. Instead of Mephisto and Sandman
throwing down with blows, they're going to play
a game of wits, as it were. Exactly. OK, I'm
fine with that. Let's try it out. OK, so since
Dream came up with the idea for the game, for
this match, how they're going to do it, he's
going to go first. All right. So he says, I
am a dire wolf, prey stalking, lethal prowler.
OK, so then Mephisto, he transforms into a
fiery dragon and says, I am a fire breathing
dragon who can consume the dire wolf with fire.
Alright so then Dream transforms into a knight
and he says, I am a shining knight, armor wearing,
dragon slaying. And then Mephisto turns into
an army tank. Uh huh. And says, I am a tank!
Armor crushing, sword blocking, knight flattening.
Alright, a tank, alright. Dream turns into
rust, alright. The tank just starts decaying
and he says, I am rust, metal decaying. And
then Mephisto turns into a bottle of CLR. And
he was like, I am a bottle of CLR, which fights
the development of rust and protects your household
fixtures. This game's a little weird. I'm just
gonna say it. Okay, so Sandman, he's gonna say,
I am a body of water, chemical diluting. Okay.
And then Mephisto takes on the appearance of
the sun itself and says, I am the sun, water
evaporating. That's fine, because Dream could
just be like, I am a supernova, sun destroying,
matter exploding. And then Mephisto turns into
this dark mass, becoming what's like a black
hole. And he's like, I'm a black hole, sucking
in that supernova and extinguishing all light.
Okay, okay, so then Dream, he's gonna say, I
am the universe, all things encompassing, all
life embracing. And then Mephisto turns into
the ultimate nullifier, which can destroy the
universe with but a point and click. It's a
weapon within the Marvel Comics universe. Okay,
so then Sandman says, I am hope, unfailing,
never ending. And then Mephisto says, I am
despair. No, it's unfailing hope. Okay, so then
Mephisto says, I am, but wait, how does hope
defeat the ultimate nullifier? Anyway, it doesn't.
I mean, it does. That's how Sandman beat the
demon in the comic when he made the universe
and from Anti-Life. That doesn't make any sense
either because if the universe is over, there's
nothing left to hope. Okay. Dream's probably
like, fuck. So he's just gonna like throw a
fistful of sand right in Mephisto's face. Just
putting him to sleep. Okay, so Mephisto's asleep.
I don't think Mephisto sleeps, but even if
he did, let's say he couldn't overcome Dream's
sleep sand. I'm just gonna say Mephisto sleeps
with his eyes open because he's creepy like
that. That's- that's fine. Like, Dream has
seen everything, alright? So, while Mephisto
is asleep, Dream's gonna transform the ground
around Mephisto into like this magic quicksand,
this portal that causes Mephisto to sink into
it and fall into the realm of the dreaming,
where Dream has complete control. So he's just
gonna conjure some shackles on Mephisto. Well,
as the movie Inception taught me, you know,
any falling experience is guaranteed to wake
you up. So if Mephisto's falling through the
quicksand into the dreaming, he's gonna wake
up mid fall. So even before these shackles
can be placed, Mephisto from the air is gonna
like shoot this blast of hellfire at Dream,
and hellfire burns not only the physical, but
also the metaphysical. So Dream's just like
burning alive. Not in the dreaming, dude, okay?
Dream can't be harmed in his own realm. He
literally writes the rules. It's Hellfire. Literally
he writes the rules. If he doesn't want Hellfire
to hurt him, it's not gonna do it, all right?
So, you know, Dream, all this Hellfire is around
him. He's just gonna like calmly gather like
all of the flames into like a lit candle. And
then he'll blow out the candle and that's just
gonna extinguish like all of the lights all
around them. So when Fisto can't see shit. And
then from the darkness, this horde of- nightmare
creatures like with like teeth and tentacles
they emerge and they just start tearing the
Mephisto apart. That's creepy. Heck yeah it
is. Heck yeah. But before that happens in the
darkness this like fiery crack in the ground
appears beneath these nightmare creatures because
Mephisto is opening a portal to hell. So the
rift widens and the creatures fall through
it and also Mephisto and Dream also fall through
this fiery fissure into the realm of hell.
So now they're in Mephisto's domain. Okay. And
Dream falls into this area of hell called the
Arena of Tainted Souls, where souls do battle
for Mephisto's pleasure. So Mephisto's watching
from his throne above this pit area and Dream
looks up and all of a sudden, guess what? There's
this like giant Gladiator Kaiju demon troll
monster that he has to now fight. He's fighting
a demon in hell now? Yeah. So Dream, he's just
gonna be like, all right, let's play a demon
game. Demon's gonna be like, no! And then just
like smash him. Like these demons don't know
this fucking demon game that he keeps talking
about. These are hardcore demons. Okay, but
before Dream gets smashed, he's just gonna like
let out a breath from his palm, all right?
And that's gonna blow the demon away. And this
wind gust is gonna turn into like a massive
storm, a tempest with heavy rain that's still
pouring in from that portal above them from
the Dreaming. And it's just gonna flood the
entirety of hell, like almost instantly, all
right? And with another breath, Dream, he's
gonna freeze hell, which is flooded, cutting
off Mephisto from access to his souls since
they're frozen and trapped. Sandman literally
made hell freeze over. Oh, wow, that's pretty
clever, I like that. But even if Mephisto is
cut off from his power source, he's not powerless,
his power is just diminishing. So with hell
frozen over, Mephisto is just gonna like burn
his way to the surface of the ice where Dream
is, and he's gonna like burn this Pentagram
sigil thing into the ice beneath dream just
like the Magus guy did Roger Caburgis. Yeah.
Yeah and Mephisto telekinetically yanks away
dreams bag of sand dream is trapped in hell.
How did I know you were gonna do that? Yep,
I didn't you're gonna pull that move match over.
All right Okay, so all this happens and Mephisto
is feeling pretty good about himself and then
he fucking wakes up. No Yeah, I know you're
gonna do that is all a dream. He's actually
still in the dreaming shackled and powerless
forever imprisoned in Dream's dungeon. So he's
the one who's trapped. We'll agree to disagree.
We'll go ahead and end the match there and run
the stats on these characters. Either Dream
is forever trapped by a sigil in hell or Mephisto
is forever trapped in the dreaming powerless
and cut off from his souls. Exactly. So let's
go ahead and run these simulations and we'll
come back with a winner to find out what really
happened.
Okay, we're back and these are some pretty powerful
guys. Oh yeah. Both Mephisto and Sandman are
omnipotent essentially within their own realms,
but they're no slouches when it comes to fighting
outside of the realm such as on Earth. Except
when it comes to the stat category of fighting
in which both of them kind of suck because they
don't really throw hands. Right, exactly. So
they're pretty much maxed out in all categories
except for fighting skill. We did say there
was some disparity between Mephisto and Sandman's
durability. While outside their realm, it seems
like Sandman is a little bit more vulnerable
than Mephisto. Yeah. But we did say that since
Sandman knows the subconscious of every being
in existence due to ruling the Dreaming, he
has slightly higher perception of his opponents
than Mephisto does, who often has to ask people.
what they desire most or what they need or what
they fear, whereas Sandman already knows this.
Yeah, he knows everyone's story. It's literally
a book in his library. So their stats came
out not too dissimilar in terms of their overall
ability. It's gonna be a really close match
here. Well, let's find out. I have the results
right here. Who do you think came out on top?
I think, I don't know. I have no idea, honestly.
I wanna say Mephisto, but I'm not entirely
sure. I think it's too close to call, honestly.
But our Instagram followers. said in our poll
on the matter that Mephisto would win by 57%
over Dream. Which actually really surprised
me because like Sandman has his TV show out
right now. I'm not sure why people are rooting
for Mephisto at all. I guess he was a character
in the Ghost Rider movie. Yeah, Mephisto was
in Ghost Rider and Ghost Rider Spirit of Vengeance.
Well, let's hear the results. The winner of
the matchup between Sandman and Mephisto is...
Yeah, you see what I did there? See what I did
there? But barely, though, barely. Laphisto
won 51.9% of the 1000 matches. Oh. So 519 wins
compared to Sandman's 481 wins or 48.1% win
rate. And what was the defining factor in this
match? Honestly, there really wasn't one. Again,
they were pretty evenly matched when it came
to the stats. It's a coin toss and fucking
as usual. Marvel comes out on top. Most of the
time, yeah. I kind of like my luck for sure.
But guess what Jonathan? Jonathan, guess what?
What? Mephisto confirmed to be better than
Sandman. How do you feel about that? Hashtag
Mephisto confirmed. Everybody hashtag Mephisto
confirmed with no context. Just, you know, spread
the conjecture. This hurts. I am not going
to lie. You know, Dream definitely has like
a rivalry with Lucifer in the comics where
he's basically said that Lucifer is like the
second most powerful being in the universe
next to the creator, the presence. Uh-huh. So
I guess it kind of makes sense that Mephisto
would win considering he's kind of Marvel's
equivalent of Lucifer. But, uh, yeah, it's
still stupid. At least Sandman is a way better
story than any Mephisto story. I don't know
about the- oh, honestly, I've never read any
of Sandman's stories. But, uh, I'm trying to
think like the- probably the best Mephisto story.
I think would probably be Faust, nothing from
Marvel. No, I'm talking about Marvel story.
Nah, none of them are good. I think Triumph
and Torment was pretty good with Doctor Strange
and Doctor Doom. If you wanna read a good Mephisto
story, that was pretty good. Yawn, I fell asleep.
Just hearing about that. All right. But that
does it for this duel guys. Let us know what
you thought about the results by writing to
us at dyna or by visiting us on Instagram or
Twitter. You can find links to all of our accounts
by checking out our show notes or visiting our
website, dynamicduel.com. And on our sites,
you could also find a link to our Patreon page,
where we offer ad-free episodes of the show,
bonus content including top 10 episodes and
bloopers, monthly live movie watch-alongs,
and access to our Discord chat server. Again,
check it out right now at patreon.com slash
dynamicduel, which is linked in our show notes.
Our lowest tier is only $2 a month. In our
next episode, we are going to be reviewing season
one of The Sandman, which is on Netflix. And
it's good, it's good. I've watched the first
three episodes, the first one I didn't love,
but it definitely picks up by episode three.
I'm looking forward to the rest of it. It gets
better and better. I can't wait to talk about
it. But that does it for this episode. We wanna
give a big thanks to our executive producers,
John Spees, Ken Johnson, John Storosky, Zachary
Hepburn, Dustin Balcom, Mickey Mathagian, Brandon
Estregard, Nathaniel Wagner, Lee Vyeen, Austin
Wisselowski, Nick Abonto, and AJ Dunkerley for
helping make this podcast possible. And we'll
talk to you guys next week. Up, up, and away,
true believers.