This is a Dynamike Network podcast. Hey everyone,
Johnny DC here at the top of the episode. With
the approaching holiday season, we're officially
underway with this year's Holiday Charity Drive
in lead up to our charity dual episode this
month, which is going to be Alfred Pennyworth
vs Edwin Jarvis. This year, all donations will
be going once again to Pop Culture Classroom,
a non-profit organization that delivers educational
resources. to school districts, teachers, and
community organizations using comics, graphic
novels, and related pop culture media. Their
mission is to inspire a love of learning, increase
literacy, and build community through the tools
of popular culture and the power of self-expression.
To donate, visit our official store through
dynamicduel.com, where you'll find two donation
options, one if you're Team DC and one if you're
Team Marvel. Or go directly... to dynamicduel.com
slash donate DC one word or dynamicduel.com
slash donate Marvel, which are linked in our
show notes. We're making the charity drive
a competitive duel this year, except the only
stat is which side can donate the most. Everyone
who donates will receive a digital poster featuring
original art of Alfred and Jarvis drawn New
Yorker style by me. One lucky random winner
will also win a framed print of the Alfred
vs. Jervis art that we'll announce during that
December duel episode. Which fanbase will be
the most charitable? Team DC has actually pulled
ahead since last week. Who's the slackers now?
Marvel guys, it's you. Keep up the good work,
Team DC. On with the show.
Hi, welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters and stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin brother, Marvelous
Joe. And in this episode, we are doing a review
of the Amazon Prime animated feature film, Merry
Little Batman. I actually got the opportunity
to see this film in the movie theater with my
family, and I loved the heck out of it. Yeah,
I mean, it's probably one of the better like
holiday releases that Marvel and DC have ever
produced, right? I mean, there's not many, so
it's not hard to do. But yeah, this is the
best of anything holiday related that Marvel
or DC has put out. We're going to talk all
about the movie later on in this episode. But
before that, we're going to break down the
comic book movie news items from the past week.
There's not many news items. We did learn,
however, that Sean Gunn has been cast as Maxwell
Lord in the DC universe. and we got a couple
of video game trailers, one for Suicide Squad
Killed the Justice League, and the other is
a teaser trailer for a new Blade video game.
As always, we list our segment times in our
episode description, so feel free to check out
the show notes if you want to skip ahead to
a particular topic. As our listeners may know,
our duel simulator is so advanced that it's
gained sentience and has named itself the Artificial
Lifeform for Running Extensive Duels, just
a rather very intelligent simulator 9000, or
Alfred Jarvis 9000. He has a quick message
for our listeners, so listen up. Why hello there.
Do you love listening and chatting about Marvel
and DC? Then become a part of the dynamic dual
community on Patreon, where you can choose
from three tiers. The dynamic 2.0 tier lets
you listen to this podcast without ads and
gives you access to its Discord chat group,
where you can chat with Johnny DC and Marvelous
Joe. The Fantastic Four tier gives you that
and more with two bonus episodes each month,
including bloopers and top ten shows where Johnny
and Joe count down your favorite Marvel and
DC subjects. The X-Force tier makes you an executive
producer of Dynamic Duel, where every month
you help the host choose what to review and
who to fight against each other. And finally,
the Dynamite Podcast Network tier allows aspiring
podcasters to create their own battle-focused
show using this Monte Carlo simulator.
Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast. Be sure to tune in to the Max
Destruction Podcast tomorrow which is part of
the Dynamite where host Ken Dustin will let
us know their thoughts on the holiday classic
film Die Hard. Yes, it's a Christmas film.
Everyone knows it's a Christmas film. If you
disagree, then shut the hell up. Also just
released yesterday was the latest episode of
the Dynamite Network's newest show, Console
Combat, in which hosts John and Dean find out
who would win in fights between your favorite
video game characters. Yesterday's episode,
they speculated on who would win between Luigi...
and tails.
to listen to all of the shows in the Dynamike
Podcast Network. But with that out of the way,
quick to the NO Prize! A NO Prize is an award
Marvel used to give out to fans. Our version,
the Dynamic Dual NO Prize, is a digital award
we post on Instagram and in our email newsletter
for the person that we feel gave the best answer
to our question of the week. Last week we asked,
what is your favorite alternate universe slash
dimension for Marvel or DC? We only got three
answers. So we're gonna break down the two honorable
mentions before revealing this week's no prize
winner. Our first honorable mention goes to
Travis Herndon who said, Hey guys, Travis here.
So my favorite alternate universe or dimension
would have to be the mangaverse. As a person
who loves anime and manga, I really like what
they did with some of the characters in that
universe. Like Spider-Man being a ninja, Wolverine
a samurai, Hulk being a kaiju, Godzilla monster
do. It seemed like a pretty cool universe and
honestly, Marvel should make that into an animated
series like they're doing with Suicide Squad.
So yeah, Mangaverse for me. Fantastic answer.
Yeah, I remember when the Mangaverse for Marvel
came out in the early 2000s. It looked super
fascinating. There was the Spider-Man series,
X-Men. There was an Avengers title, if I remember
correctly, and it was like an Iron Man Mecha
style subgenre of Manga. And yeah, there was
the Hulk who was a 70 foot. Kaiju monster. It
was a really cool universe. I remember like
Punisher was like a lady samurai assassin type
character. It was pretty sweet. Good stuff.
Good stuff. If you haven't checked it out and
you're into manga and you're into Marvel, definitely
do that. I actually don't know anything about
this. I mean, I know about Spider-Man manga,
but I don't know about any of the other characters
and that all sounds pretty fricking awesome.
I'm not going to lie. Yeah, that's a fantastic
answer. A fantastic other universe. If you
guys are into manga, then you should also probably
be listening to the Send Your World podcast
as well. Great answer Travis! Our next honorable
mention goes to... Miggy Mathengian who said...
Hey what's up guys this is Miggy and I'm gonna
go with the first one, which is my favorite
ultimate mention. It's the one where DC is like
medieval and there's like knights and dragons
and stuff like that. It's a pretty good story,
better than I thought it'd be. I wasn't really
expecting much from medieval. alternate universe,
but Tom Taylor knows what he's doing. So, thanks
guys. Yeah, Dark Knights of Steel is a comic
book series written by Tom Taylor, who's also
known for writing the Injustice comic as well
as Deceased. It's a high fantasy adventure,
kind of like Game of Thrones, but with DC characters.
I actually haven't read anything from it. I
just know of it, and I gotta say it looks incredible
art-wise. And Miggy, who's an executive producer
of the podcast, is an avid comic book reader.
And I totally trust him when he says that something
is really good. If he recommends Dark Knights
of Steel, that probably means I should be reading
it along with everyone else. Not me, even you.
What? Yes. Great answers, guys. But that brings
us to the winner of this week's no prize, Andrew
Shunk, who said, Hey, guys, Andrew Shunk here.
My favorite alternate universe. Is. Marvel because
Marvel rips everything off of DC. Thanks. Have
a nice day. And yeah, this gets the win because
Andrew Shunk admitted that Marvel is his favorite
and it's a great answer. Yeah. It should be
your favorite because it's amazing. Um, I liked
this answer not only because it admits that
Marvel is a rip off of DC, but I've also always
held the theory that Marvel is just earth six
one six. Like they say it themselves. DC says
we're earth one. Marvel says they're 616. Of
course DC is the true universe, the prime universe.
It doesn't matter what's the true universe,
it matters what is his favorite and he clearly
is a member of Team Marvel. So I will be changing
his name to Red on the Discord. Go Team Marvel.
Great answer Andrew Shunk, you win this week's
no prize. If you the listener want a shot at
winning your own no prize, stay tuned to later
on this episode when we'll be asking another
question of the week. And now that that's done,
on to the news.
Alright, so a couple of days ago we learned
that Sean Gunn, James Gunn's brother, has been
cast as Maxwell Lord in the DC universe. James
Gunn, of course, being the new CEO of DC Studios.
Now this is pretty interesting because we recently
saw Maxwell Lord as a villain. He was played
by Pedro Pascal. And I thought Pedro did a pretty
good job, even though the character was fairly
different from who Maxwell Lord is in the comics.
Now this isn't the only role that Sean Gunn
is going to be playing in the DC universe. He
also plays Weasel in Creature Commandos. He's
supposed to be playing that character in both
live action and do voiceover work for animation.
Well he also played the character in the Suicide
Squad movie too. Right, he did mocap work for
it and I believe he was also the voice for the
character. Sean Gunn of course is no stranger
to playing multiple roles within the same universe.
He did mocap work for Rocket Raccoon in Guardians
of the Galaxy, and he also played the live-action
version of Kraglin in the same franchise. Do
you typically view Maxwell Lord as a villain
or as a hero character? I typically see him
as a villain. In the comics, you know, he's
a benefactor for the Justice League, or he
was at one point. But overall, I would say throughout
the character's history, he's primarily been
a villain. I think this is casting very much
against type. Sean Gunn tends to play roles
of characters that aren't quite bright, usually.
So for him to play a character like Maxwell
Lord, who is supposed to be hyper intelligent,
you know, he's a telepath, a mind reader, a
mind controller, is something that I never thought
I would see Sean Gunn play, honestly. So this
casting to me is actually pretty surprising.
Well, I mean, he's a good character actor,
but a role like Maxwell Lord would give him
an opportunity to showcase his range, you know?
So I can see why they did this. It's gonna be
hard not to chalk this up to nepotism, which
a lot of people have been accusing James Gunn
of ever since, you know, casting his wife as
a character in the Suicide Squad film and, you
know, Peacemaker series. That said, Sean Gunn
is not a terrible actor. You know, he's actually
pretty good. And I'll be looking forward to
seeing what he does with the role of Maxwell
Lord. It's rumored that while he's not going
to appear in Superman Legacy, he will be name
dropped at the very least. I wouldn't be surprised
if we saw Maxwell Lord in something like the
Amanda Waller television series or maybe Peacemaker
2. We're not sure yet, but if he's been cast,
I'm sure they'll be announcing what project
he's a part of relatively soon. I like to think
that if I ever directed a movie, Jonathan,
I'd give you a part. Hey, man, if I'm the lead
making the big bucks, I'll do it. No, you wouldn't
be the lead. God, no. What? I mean, all right.
Maybe I don't want to be a part of your movie,
then. I'll let you star in my movie, it's gonna
be called Joseph Sucks. It's gonna be about
how much you suck. Well, at least I'll be the
star of that one. Yeah, you will be. But speaking
of how James Gunn has taken one of his Guardians
of the Galaxy actors and cast them in a DC
role, that brings us to our question of the
week.
What other actor from the Guardians of the Galaxy
would you like to see cast in the DC universe
and in what role? Record your answer at dynamic
duel.com by clicking on the red microphone
button in the bottom right hand corner of the
screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long. And don't forget to leave your name in
case we include you on the podcast. We'll pick
our favorite answer and award that person a
dynamic duel no prize that will post to Instagram
and our email newsletter. Be sure to answer
before December 13th. We're recording the next
episode a little bit earlier, so you guys don't
have as much time this week. Yeah, get your
answers in right away. In other DC news, Suicide
Squad Kill the Justice League recently released
a new trailer titled the official Justice League
trailer. Of course, it seems like we've been
waiting for this game forever. I've personally
really been looking forward to this because
just the concept of it is really interesting.
The fact that the Justice League characters
are going to be possessed by Brainiac and be
the bad guys is kind of awesome. And we got
some really good looks at them, some for the
first time in this trailer. Yeah, the Suicide
Squad is going to be going up against Green
Lantern, the Flash, Batman and Superman and
also Wonder Woman. Although it looks like she's
not possessed by Brainiac in the same way that
the others are, at least initially. What intrigues
me about this is that this game is supposed
to be set in the same universe as the Arkham
video games. And yet, spoiler alert, Batman
died at the end of Arkham Knight. So it kind
of seems like this game takes place before that.
I don't know, there's like a big demon version
of Batman sporadically throughout this trailer.
Maybe that has something to do with it. Like
the Suicide Squad goes to hell or something
like that. Oh shit, Batman's in hell? That's
crazy. Yeah, dude, he beats up poor people.
Of course, that's a one way ticket to hell.
Wow. I hate Saturday Night Live. They suck.
There's quite a bit of gameplay footage in this
trailer and it still looks as awesome as ever
did. Apparently, the game is in beta testing
right now. One of our executive producers,
the host of Sanjo World, Zachary Hepburn, is
actually playing the beta right now. And he
says it's just incredible. And I'm inclined
to believe him. It does look like a fun game.
I like how each player has their own kind of
gameplay style. where Harley Quinn almost feels
like a Spider-Man type game. You know, King
Shark is your bruiser. Deadshot is like your
third person shooter. And then you have Captain
Boomerang, who's like, I don't know, like the
speedster. Everyone's gonna have their favorite
character to play with. It looks like it's
gonna be a blast. And actually it's not gonna
be limited to just these four characters. Data
miners have been going through the code of the
game and found out that you can play as Killer
Croc as an alternate skin for King Shark, I
believe. That's pretty cool. Yeah, it really
makes me wonder what other alternate skins you'll
get to play as. Which member of the Justice
League do you think is going to be the hardest
boss to beat? It should be Superman. He should
be like the final boss. Absolutely. And I think
they kind of imply that much just with like
the Suicide Squad's reaction to him in this
trailer. That said, the giant demon version
of Batman does look like it's going to be hella
tough to get through. The new official release
date for this game is February 2nd of next year.
I'm. somehow going to have to get my hands
on a Xbox or PlayStation five before that time
or a PC. Yeah, no, that's not happening. I'm
an Apple guy. So here's hoping that I've been
good this year and Santa brings me one. Well,
I hope you get it. I hope you have a lot of
fun with it. Rocksteady is a solid studio for
video games, as is Bethesda, who just announced
that they are working on a Blade game. Now,
Bethesda is the video game studio behind such
titles as The Elder Scrolls, Fallout, Doom,
Dishonored, a bunch of great, well-received
games. And so this is some pretty exciting
news that they're working on a Blade game. The
announcement trailer is not really much of
anything. It's basically just Blade getting
a shave and then some kind of alarm goes off
and he's like, the knife's just getting started
and he, you know, looks like he's going to
take out his sword. The style of it is pretty
cool though. There's some pretty interesting
music in it and the graphics look pretty damn
good. Yeah, the world that they establish just
in this teaser reminds me very much of the very
first Blade movie, with like the time lapse
of the skyscraper, skyline shadows moving across
the city. Yeah. Yeah, I don't know what city
this is. It does appear to be some kind of European
city, which makes sense because the character
of Blade, Eric Brooks, is from London. I'm always
a little bit disappointed when they don't give
the character a British accent. He does not
have a British accent in this trailer. It's
definitely American. But yeah, it looks like
he's going international with his vampire hunting.
Yeah, whatever city it is, it's definitely a
melting pot. You have like Spanish, you have,
I believe Arabic. You have a number of languages
scrawled across the city walls. But it also
seems like vampires have taken over the city
and the government has issued like a curfew
for people to be indoors once the sun sets.
So that's an interesting setup for the story.
Yeah, people in this world definitely know that
vampires exist. It's not really a secret. They're
not like underground or anything when Blade's
barber nicks himself with the shaving razor,
he gets nervous that Blade is going to attack
him. But of course, as Blade says, he doesn't
fight. So there you go. Yeah, it's not much
of a trailer and we have no idea what the gameplay
is going to be like. I assume it might be like
some kind of hack and slash thing like God
of War or Devil May Cry. And that would be awesome.
I'm already sold. Already sold. Well, I played
a Blade video game way back in the day on the
PS2. It was the Blade 2 movie tie-in video
And man, that game was a piece of shit. It was
so weird that the fighting system was bizarre
because you would use the second joystick controller
to attack. You just point it in a direction
and he would like kick in that direction because
in the game you would often be surrounded by
vampires. So you wouldn't hit buttons to attack.
The joystick literally would attack in the
direction that you pointed at. So it was a little
bit awkward. Maybe it sounds cool in theory,
but it just didn't pan out in practice. Well,
I feel like video games have come a long way,
like, you know, with the Arkham games and that
battle system. And, you know, I'm sure Spider-Man
is very similar to it. Yeah. So I feel like
for sure you could really nail a Blade video
game nowadays. We'll see if we get the video
game before the movie. It's cool to know that
Blade really seems to be coming back into the
spotlight now, though. Can't wait.
Well, I think that does it for all of the news
for this episode. So now let's move on to the
main event where we review Amazon Prime's holiday
animated film, Merry Little Batman.
Alright, Merry Little Batman is an animated
feature released on the Amazon Prime streaming
platform just in time for the holiday season.
Directed by Mike Roth of regular show fame,
in his film directorial debut, the film follows
Damian Wayne, Batman's son, as he aspires to
become a superhero like his father during Christmas.
It's super cute, super made for kids, but the
best most nostalgic holiday films usually are.
And that's what I like about it. If you're
looking for something new this holiday season
to watch with the kids, I definitely recommend
Mary Little Batman. And if you want to go in
fresh with the family, I also recommend skipping
this review altogether as it contains spoilers.
Yeah, definitely check out Mary Little Batman.
If you have Amazon Prime, it's an easy watch.
It's a quick watch. If you like Batman or your
family loves superheroes, I highly recommend
it for this holiday season. gets a crisp 92
minute film. So almost exactly an hour and a
half. You won't regret it. Now the holiday
season truly is the most wonderful time of the
year for my two daughters. Their birthdays
fall on December 22nd and 23rd. I tell people
that in my family, it's like having four full
days of Christmas each year. But honestly, the
excitement and festivities for Christmas ramp
up exponentially after Thanksgiving. beginning
with holiday music on the radio and Christmas
movies after dinner. Films like How the Grinch
Stole Christmas Home Alone. These and more
have become annual viewing traditions, as they
are for many families, I'm sure. And after
getting the chance to see Merry Little Batman
on the theater big screen, my family all easily
agreed that this movie should be a part of our
annual rotation, which it's already become,
because we've actually watched it again since
it came out on Amazon Prime. Now the movie
was inspired visually by the artwork of English
cartoonist Ronald Cyril, who inspired the character
design for quite a few animated films such as
101 Dalmatians and Despicable Me. This film
though I think captures the charm and humor
of his aesthetic more than any other film.
From Alfred to Joker to Selena the Cat, the
Cyril-esque character design is one of the
highlights of the film. And watching the way
these awkward bodies move... particularly in
the case of the Joker, contributed to the humor
of the film. Oh yeah, the art style is so silly,
but perfectly in keeping with the whimsical
attitude of the film. I was actually really
impressed because I think that this is the best
version of that art style ever done in a full
length feature. Oh yeah, I agree. Everything
from like the line work to even the coloring
and the way it was like constantly shifting,
almost like a little kid drew it. It was really
charming. It was like an animated comic strip.
And, you know, being a big fan of like Calvin
and Hobbes and a bunch of other comic book strips
growing up, I really appreciated that. Yeah,
I thought it was fantastic. I'm actually kind
of sad that this film debuted on a streaming
platform and people didn't get the opportunity
to watch it on the big screen, because I think
this could have easily been a theatrical release.
I think families would have got to see it.
I mean, this past weekend, Miyazaki animated
film The Boy and His Heron won the weekend.
Like, if this would have been released at the
same time. I think it could have been a contender
to get the number one box office spot for this
week. Yeah, I mean, like I liked this movie
more than the Lego Batman movie, both in terms
of story and animation style. So yeah, I could
totally see this working in theaters. The movie
is just silly and funny. And I think a lot
of that has to do with the writers for the movie,
Morgan Evans and Jace Ricci, who have written
for Teen Titans Go and the Teenage Mutant Ninja
Turtles cartoon, respectively. But there's
a third writer as well. who wrote Tropic Thunder,
and who I think leveled up the humor to a point
where adults could find it funny as well. That's
actually surprising to me because the humor
isn't terribly adult, it's actually quite childish,
but charming. I wouldn't say it's dumbed down
for kids, but it's definitely not raunched up
for adults or anything. It's at that perfect
level where I think both kids and adults can
enjoy it. I agree, it's like that sweet spot
right in the middle, especially for a holiday
film. The writers also injected tons of holiday
homages into the film as well, from the obvious
like Home Alone and how the Grinch stole Christmas,
but also deep cuts like Die Hard when we see
Damien shuffling through air ducts. For DC
fans, there were also homages to Batman films
of the past, primarily when it came to the
villains, but also things like Batnipples and
the Batpod. Yeah, I saw references to Batman
and Robin, Batman Returns, The Dark Knight,
yeah a bunch of them. And those are things
that you could kind of appreciate as an adult,
especially as an adult fan of DC Comics, because,
you know, a lot of kids watching the movie aren't
going to get the Batnipples reference. Now,
while some can knock the film's unoriginality,
I actually think that's the worst thing you
could say about the movie. And ultimately, it
was all put together in a funny, heartwarming
package. Apparently, a spinoff series called
Bat Family is in the works for Amazon Prime.
with Mike Roth to serve as the showrunner. And
I'm looking forward to it. Yeah, I could totally
see a series based off of this. This type of
content is perfect for an animated show. And
the world that they built is so rich that it
would be a shame not to continue it. Right,
yeah, and I also think there were enough references
to the larger world, like Damien's mom, for
example, that there's enough to explore there
for an animated series. I just want to make
one more point that the songs used in this film
were awesome. Like the opening with Father
Christmas by the Kinks, All I Really Want for
Christmas by Little John Later On, along with
Don De Esta Santa Claus, and at the very end,
just another Christmas song, This Time I'll
Sing Along. These aren't typical songs you hear
in family Christmas movies, but they had me
dancing in my seat and singing on the car ride
home. They were all great songs, yeah. And
Patrick Stump from Followboy is the one who
did the music. I knew I recognized that name
from somewhere. That's awesome. I was listening
to the score for this film earlier and yeah,
it was really good. He's a great composer. Yeah,
I didn't even know he did film work until this
movie, but he's done some work for Marvel too,
including the Spidey and His Amazing Friends
television series. Did not know that. That's
pretty cool. I definitely recommend checking
out the soundtrack to this if anyone hasn't
already. But moving on to the character breakdown,
let's start with Damien Wayne, AKA Little Batman
for this movie. Surprisingly not Robin. Yeah,
surprisingly. I thought that was an interesting
choice. The character was voiced by Jonas Kibrib.
I'm not sure if I'm pronouncing that correctly
at all. I'm not familiar with Jonas's work,
but I thought he pulled off the role as perfect
as you can get. You know, he nailed the emotion
and the humor needed for the character. Just
a great like little kid voice, essentially.
Yeah, I was actually surprised at his level
of range and comedic timing. Great delivery.
Yeah, now this of course is not the first time
we've seen Damien in animated form. We've seen
him as Robin, of course in the past. But this
is the first time that I can recall that we've
seen him this young. You know, I have an eight
year old and it's a pretty fun imaginative
age. In this film, Damien imagines being like
his father Batman, though he doesn't realize
the hardship that comes with being a superhero
because his father rid Gotham of crime when
Damien was just a baby. Damien was told what
to do in any emergency except for crime. So
when the burglars break into his house, he's
forced to jump into the role of a superhero
on his own. When his utility belt, the gift
his father gave him for Christmas, is stolen,
he makes a vow to get it back. That's the focus
part of the lesson his father told him, that
crime fighting requires focus, responsibility,
and sacrifice. By the end of Damien's adventure,
he accepts responsibility for the chaos he caused
across Gotham and sacrifices his prized possession,
his utility belt, to make things right. The
entire film, Damien was trying to prove to
his father that he wasn't a baby and that he
was ready to be a superhero and he thought
that by losing his utility belt, his dad would
think that he wasn't ready for that. But that
wasn't going to prove anything, as the Bat Dad
AI explained. It wasn't until Damien proved
himself capable in battle that Batman rewarded
Damien with a real utility belt and accepted
him as his partner. I'm consistently surprised
how many different ways writers can take the
character of Damien Wayne, who is relatively
new to the world of comics. But we recently
saw an adaptation of Damien Wayne in an animated
feature film as recently as last year in the
Battle of the Supersuns, where he was also used
to great effect. And then you see how he was
done here, and you just... realize how versatile
the character is, you can go super dark with
him, you can go super light with him, it all
works. Definitely one of the best characters
to be introduced within the past couple decades.
Yeah, he's sort of like his father in that
regard. I know a lot of people don't like bright
and cheerful Batman sort of like he was in
this movie, but the character still works somehow
in that regard. I definitely prefer my Batman
very, very dark, but I also don't mind when
they adapt him into like new worlds like this.
Yeah, I mean, it just all depends on the world
that he exists in, right? In a world as light
and cheery as this one, a lighter, cheerier
Batman makes sense. Right. Speaking of Batman,
let's move on to him, aka Bruce Wayne, who is
voiced by Luke Wilson. Now, Luke Wilson would
never have been my first choice for Batman,
but in this lighter I thought he brought the
right amount of brightness to the role, along
with familiarity. He's really the only voice
you hear in this film where it's like, hey,
I know that voice. Yeah, it's cool to hear
him, especially considering we just got off
of Loki Season 2, which stars his brother Owen
Wilson. So to see the Wilson bros getting in
on the Marvel and DC content is pretty neat.
That is cool. That's really cool. Now, like
I mentioned earlier, this is very much an Elseworlds
Batman. which may in fact piss off fans of Batman,
but I'm guessing those people don't have children
or a life. In this film, Batman learns about
Damien much earlier than in the comics and
works overtime to rid Gotham of crime and villains
so that the city is a good one to raise a child
in. Bruce is overprotective you could say, but
as Alfred tells Damien, Bruce wants to give
his son the one thing he never had, a childhood.
which means Damien gets foam batarangs before
metal ones. Bruce knows, however, that Damien's
destined to take up his mantle one day, so
it was nice to see that the master of prep time
would be prepared with Damien's batsuit way
early. A high-tech version that not only sizes
itself to Damien's body, but also comes with
a built-in artificial intelligence called Bat
Dad. that was based on Bruce's mind so that
his son would never be alone like he was growing
up. Yeah that was really touching. The AI was
cool too, I thought that was a pretty neat concept.
Yeah, it's something I think that all fathers
wish that they could leave their children in
some way. When Batman returns to Gotham to
help his son, initially he holds Damian back,
protecting him from his villains. But the years
without crime apparently made him soft because
he gets knocked out only to witness his son's
awesome ninja skills in action when he awakens
and decides that Damien is a capable and worthwhile
partner after all. That's pretty much his whole
arc and it's nice that he found a way to connect
to his son in a way that he was never able to
with his own father, his parents. Basically,
he comes to terms with the idea that his preconceived
notions of his son aren't necessarily what
he thought and he is surprised Which I assume
happens a lot in parenthood Do you ever find
yourself being like overly cautious only to
realize that the kids are a little bit more
Capable than you thought they were? Not really,
honestly I'm surprised by them in ways that
like when they draw a picture above the skill
typical of their age range I'm surprised when
you know, they know how to do something on their
iPad that like, I didn't even know it's things
like that. Right, right. I did get a roundhouse
kick to the chest one time for my oldest daughter
that actually hurt. I guess that was surprising.
We were just horsing around and I think she
didn't know her own strength or her dad's own
weakness.
I mean, who among you can take a roundhouse
kick to the chest? Like a jumping one. It's
not an easy thing to take. I do have to ask,
what did you think of the bat beard? I like
the bat beard. I think it was a way to distinguish
the superhero Batman from the father Batman.
So it was clear that like this was not like
Batman as he normally is. This is like Batman
very much in dad mode. I understand why they
did it. They just kind of wanted to show that
Batman had become relaxed and more comfortable
having not to deal with crime in some time.
I didn't like it, though. I don't think I would
hate it for Superman, but I don't think Batman
should ever have any facial hair. Moving on
to the Joker, he was voiced by David Hornsby.
This was definitely more of a shrill Tony Hale-like
performance than a menacing Mark Hamill, but
again, it was appropriate for the project and
actually pretty funny, I thought. Which like
no matter the medium, if your Joker's not funny...
Even in a dark, like, I can't believe I'm laughing
at this kind of funny. I questioned whether
it was a successful Joker. Yeah. And I like
how this one loved the Jingle Bells Batman Smell
song. I love how this one would just like do
the most random things. Like he's talking to
someone on the phone, then all of a sudden
he's like typing on a keyboard, ha ha. That
was a great gag. It was just bizarre. It was
a bizarre Joker. I think that's, you know, I
also made for a fairly good Joker as well though.
In that he was like unpredictable. Now in this
universe, the Joker seemingly retired from
super villainy and has taken up residence in
a candy making factory. In his own words, Joker
grew lonely, missing the laughter he had with
his villainous allies and crimes, so he concocted
a plan to steal Christmas from Gotham and bring
back crime to the city. Damien's actions, however,
as a little Batman changed his plans, and upon
realizing the destructive potential of Damien,
Joker used him as a distraction for Gotham,
while Poison Ivy, Penguin, and Bane stole everyone's
presents. Joker thought he had another ally
in Little Batman, but he was proven wrong in
the end. Still, the pitiful nature of the Joker
story here touched Damian's heart, and at the
end, Joker ended up spending Christmas dinner
with the Bat Family, which holy crap, that's
nothing we've ever seen in the comics, but was
a heartwarming touch to end the story with,
sort of a love your enemies type of message.
Well Batman clearly didn't want to be there.
I think it was only done because of Damien's
insistence. I liked how this is not only a
funny joker, but also a smart joker. Like he
was able to outwit this little eight year old
kid and was always a few steps ahead of the
game. It makes sense that he wouldn't be outwitted
by a kid. Right. I like how he was able to manipulate
Damien into villainy of sorts, because like
in the comics, Damien is such like an asshole
little kid that you're never quite sure if
he's going to grow up to be like the world's
greatest superhero. or worst supervillain.
You've seen it go both ways, sort of like in
the Injustice comics compared to like Deceased.
In the former, he becomes fairly villainous
and in the latter becomes like the greatest
superhero. There's always kind of that flirtation
with villainy, especially because of his mother
Talia El-Ghul and Ras El-Ghul, his grandfather,
the whole League of Assassins thing. I thought
this was an interesting way to sort of play
up on that ambiguity with the character. But
yeah. Damien, Batman, Joker, those are really
the three main characters of the movie. Of
course, Alfred also plays a fairly major role,
although there's not too much to discuss there.
He was voiced by James Cromwell, who I didn't
even recognize his voice in this movie. I thought
he did a fantastic job in the role. He was an
adorable Alfred, I gotta say. So cute! And
very much inspired visually, I think, by the
Alfred from the 60s television series. I think.
At least that was the impression I got. But
let's move on to the story highlights.
Hey guys, Marvelous Joe here to tell you that
time is running out to save 20% on Marvel MDC
men's accessories at cufflinks.com, where if
you use the code dual20, that's D-U-E-L-20
at checkout, you can save on your holiday shopping
this year. Just like I saved on the Guardians
of the Galaxy Fair Isle red men's tie. For those
who may not know, the Fair Isle style is how
you would describe most ugly Christmas sweaters,
and cufflinks.com has that tie in a style themed
after the Guardians of the Galaxy. At my company
holiday party this month while everyone else
was wearing Christmas sweaters, I was wearing
my Guardians of Herald Isle tie, being not
only festive, but wrapping some of my favorite
superheroes. And you could do the same, or
shop for the other superhero fans in your life,
by visiting cufflinks.com, shopping their geek
merch using code dual20 at checkout, and just
making everyone happy this year whether it's
you, your gift recipients, or Johnny DC and
I because you're helping support this podcast.
Thank you guys so much. Playing superhero, Damien
chases his cat Selena through Wayne Manor and
ends up in the basement where his father Bruce
reminds Damien that upon learning that he was
going to be a father, Batman worked overtime
to bring down crime in Gotham City, locking
up all of the supervillains or forcing them
to retire. Gotham City has since become a crime-free
haven for the past eight years. The whole eight
years without crime thing, that reminded me
a lot of The Dark Knight Rises. It was the same
amount of time. where Gotham was apparently
like crime free. Now at breakfast on Christmas
Eve, Bruce lets Damien open a Christmas present
early, which turns out to be a utility belt
full of safety gear, which Damien has mixed
feelings about. When the emergency bat phone
begins ringing, Bruce learns from the Justice
League that he's needed on a case in Nova Scotia,
though he promises Damien to be back before
Christmas. After Damien gets caught trying to
stow away aboard the bat plane, Bruce punishes
Damian by taking back the utility belt, which
he gives to Alfred. I like the items that Batman
included in his utility belt, like band-aids,
a whistle, things like that. Just things to
protect him. Yeah, the way they animated the
foam battering just like floating down, I just
found that hilarious. I don't know why. There
are also some other pretty funny things that
happened during these scenes, like when Batman
and Damian were fighting over the utility belts.
And Damien accidentally knocks Alfred over and
Alfred's like, Oh, my good hip. I was like,
Oh no. To lift Damien's spirits, Alfred prepares
a meticulous cup of hot cocoa, though Damien
eats all of the marshmallows before it's completed,
forcing Alfred to leave to the store and allowing
Damien to steal back his utility belt. En route
to the store, Alfred nearly has a car accident
with a couple of burglars stealing Christmas
presents from the neighborhood. while Damien
trains recklessly throughout the mansion. Meanwhile,
Batman becomes stranded on a Canadian mountain
during a snowstorm after the Batplane malfunctions.
I'm glad now that I have Alfred's recipe for
hot cocoa. I thought it was hilarious how Damien
was just eating all of the marshmallows. Like,
marshmallows are not an easy thing to eat. I
feel like after a couple, I just felt sick.
So the fact that he was eating like entire bags
full, I was like... Oh, that's, I felt that.
He also like carb loaded during his training
montage. All right. It's so gross. Yeah. Way
too much. That was kind of like Home Alone 2.
I was actually surprised when we saw the two
bandits going around stealing from all the different
mansions in the Wayne Manor area, because I
didn't know they were going to have this Home
Alone sequence where he actually went up against
burglars, but that's coming up later in the
story. Right. After Damien accidentally causes
a short that disables the manor's main gate,
he's forced to defend his home from the burglars.
After succumbing to Damien's torture and traps,
the burglars flee the mansion, albeit with
Damien's utility belt to his dismay. Vowing
to get it back, Damien races to the Batcave,
where he finds an AI-powered bat suit that Bruce
designed for Damien and programmed himself
into in case he ever died and crime returned
to Gotham. After stealing the suit and the
bat pod cycle, Damien races into the city to
find the burglars who took his utility belts.
The burglar characters were hilarious, and Damien
was such a badass during the whole scene where
he was terrorizing him. Those are my favorite
parts of the movie. Yeah, I went a little over
the top with like the grease fire thing. I was
like, holy shit. But I mean, I guess it was
as bad as a Home Alone movie. Right. Yeah, he
totally would have murdered these guys. I like
when Damien, when the pre-recorded video of
Bruce talking to Damien actually accounted
for the possibility that Damien might be stealing
the suit. That was pretty funny. He's like,
either I'm dead or you're stealing the suit,
in which case you're in big trouble, mister.
Yeah, that was great. I also love how long it
took to get into the Batcave. Like there was
this whole really elaborate sequence that included
everything from multiple elevators to like
rappelling down the side of a waterfall. It
was great. It went on longer than it should
have, but that was the gag. I like the gag where
he didn't know how to work the clutch on the
Batmobile, but somehow he hit a button that
ejected the Batpod. It was just hilarious,
especially when he hit the turbo button. And
basically, he was driving the motorcycle by
barely hanging on to the handlebars. Yeah. All
while listening to little John sing All I Really
Want for Christmas was freaking great. Now,
the burglars returned to their boss, the Joker.
having lost all of the gifts that they had stolen
except for Damian's utility belt. The Joker
reveals that he was responsible for tricking
Batman into leaving the city so that his henchmen
could ruin Christmas. And after witnessing video
evidence of the chaos Damian was able to cause
to his henchmen while dressed as a little Batman,
Joker recruits other villains to help Damian
cause destruction across the city. Meanwhile
Batman discovers Mr. Freeze was responsible
for sabotaging his Batplane while trying to
fix it. Now it's never really made clear how
Mr. Freeze was able to sabotage the Batplane.
There's a lot of instances in the film where
I'm like, do the bad guys know that Batman is
Bruce Wayne? It's never really made clear.
Well you would think they would at least be
able to deduce it at this point when they realize
that the kid from Wayne Manor is little Batman.
Well, I think Joker just thought it was a little
kid in a bat costume. It's not until the very
end that Joker learns that Batman has a son
and even makes a point of scolding Batman for
not telling him saying that, Hey, I thought
we were friends at that point. I think they
could have been able to deduce that Bruce Wayne
was Batman, especially at the very end in the
diner when Joker's having Christmas dinner
with freaking Alfred. That's the big clue. That's
true. Determining Santa Claus would know where
his utility belt is, Damien visits Santa at
the mall only to discover Santa is the villain
Bane in disguise. Ambushed by Bane and Poison
Ivy, Damien manages to accidentally bring down
the city's giant Christmas tree, turning the
press and public sentiment against him, while
the Penguin manages to escape with the utility
belt. The Joker, thrilled with Damien's success,
expresses a desire to meet and speak with Meanwhile,
Batman and Mr. Freeze face off in a blizzard
in the Canadian wilderness, where Batman learns
that Damien is taking on Gotham's villains
as a little Batman. Isn't it strange that they
aged up the villains so drastically in this
movie? They were all almost geriatric. Poison
Ivy had the white hair and the penguin was
on a scooter and everything like that. I always
assumed that Batman's villains were roughly
around the same age as Batman himself, but here
it appeared that they were like 20 to 30 years
older. So this wasn't something I realized the
first time I watched the movie. I thought the
white hair on Ivy was just a design choice and
the whole glasses thing on Bane's I thought
that was just you know something that was left
over from him wearing the Santa Claus costume.
Penguin has always been old in my opinion but
yeah I guess the characters were aged up to
a point where I think it kind of almost justified
them retiring from supervillainy and that's
why they were like outside of Arkham to begin
with. Yeah maybe. Damien and his Bat-Dad AI
contemplate Bruce's relationship with his own
parents at the Gotham Zoo before falling into
a trap set by the Penguin, who taunts Damien
with his utility belt. During a battle between
the two, Penguin manages to damage the Bat-Dad
AI before attempting to flee on a giant balloon
during a Christmas parade. While in freefall,
Bat-Dad sacrifices itself to save Damien's
life by directing power to its inflation capability.
With Gotham City on fire from the ruined parade,
Commissioner Gordon turns on the bat signal.
As Damien flees from the angry Gotham citizens,
he has a panic attack, but is eventually discovered
by Alfred, who offers him some cocoa. Now the
panic attack scene was kind of weird. It went
black and white and very grainy. It was kind
of spooky. I initially thought this was the
result of Damien being exposed to Scarecrow,
but that turned out to not be the case. I like
it for its artistic choice. Apparently an entirely
different artist worked on this woodcutout style.
I think it was just meant to visually portray
Damien in his darkest moment. Yeah it was kind
of dark. I'm glad it ended up being Alfred
and not the Scarecrow because then things would
have gotten a lot scarier. Now Damien encounters
a balloon with a card from the Joker asking
to meet. The card gases Damien and he wakes
up at a candy factory where he finds Joker and
his allies celebrating Christmas. The villains
congratulate Damian on helping them bring crime
back to Gotham. As the city was focused on
little Batman's destruction, they were able
to steal everyone's presence. As Damian languishes
that he's become a villain, the villains present
him with his utility belt, now armed with dangerous,
sharp, and explosive gear. Taking responsibility
for his actions, Damian throws his belt into
the fireplace, blowing up the Joker's party
globe before taking on all of the villains,
single-handedly. This was probably the most
important scene in that it's where Damien really
came to take full responsibility for his actions
and sacrifice the one thing that he really
loved which was his utility belt even now that
was equipped with all the things he originally
wanted it to be equipped with. Yeah it was a
great moment of character growth. During the
fight Batman comes to Damien's aid and together
they bring down the Joker and his allies. Though
Batman is reluctant Damien improves himself
during the battle and is rewarded with Batman's
own utility belt. One of my favorite scenes
in the movie for some reason was when the Batarangs
miss the Joker and he forgets about it and then
he gets hit with them and that sets off his
rocket launcher that creates this massive explosion
like way bigger than it should have been and
he just like flies backwards in slow motion.
Again it's a scene that goes on for longer
than it should but because of that There's just
a lot of humor in it. I found it quite funny.
I thought it was really touching when Batman
saw Damien protecting him. And like Damien
was like, I'll protect you dad. And that moment
of realization where you could tell he was
really proud of his son for the little hero
that he had become. It was just very touching.
Yeah, honestly, all I've ever wanted my dad
to tell me was, wow, sweet ninja skills, son.
I have yet to hear that. And so I think that's
why it was so touching when I heard it in this
movie. There's still hope. Maybe. Now Batman,
Damien, and Alfred use the Bat Jet to return
everything that the Joker and his allies stole,
flying across the city and dropping presents,
returning Christmas to Gotham City. When Damien
expresses pity over how the Joker simply expressed
loneliness, they end up sharing Christmas dinner
with him at a local diner, to Batman's chagrin.
And that's the end of the movie. I gotta say,
Gotham City is not Whoville. The citizens of
Gotham are not Whovians. Because in the Grinch
movie, the Hoos of Whoville realized that it
was more than just the physical gifts that made
Christmas, and it was the time spent together
as friends and family. And, you know, they were
singing around that Christmas tree at the end
of How the Grinch Stole Christmas. But the citizens
of Gotham were like depressed and down and
really sad until the moment they got their presents
back. So somebody needs to teach Gotham City
the true meaning of Christmas or something.
That's that's fair. I didn't even realize that
until you said that. That's probably not the
best lesson. But yeah, I mean, I walked out
of the movie theater just really happy with
this movie. And I don't know if it's just the
holiday season or whatever, but I just enjoyed
the heck out of it. Did you like the ending
line, like the way it ended on the joke where
Batman just says, I'm not your friend, it was
a little bit abrupt for my taste. I thought
it was fine. I mean, the music that came right
after that line, I thought helped sell the joke
a little bit and how abrupt it was. Yeah, it
didn't bother me. I had fun with the film. It
was time worth spending, especially around
this Christmas season. You mentioned earlier
how a criticism of the film could be that it's
unoriginal because it borrows from so many other
holiday movies. But I actually like that about
it, how it kind of plays like a greatest hits
of all these awesome Christmas moments from
other media packaged in a cute little Batman
film. I agree with that, that's why I think
it'll definitely come on at least on an annual
rotation in my household. But borrowing from
nostalgic holiday classics, the film appeals
to adults and children alike thanks to its
charming visuals, fun action, and laugh out
loud humor. I thought the movie was immensely
fun and funny, and I'm giving it 4 out of 5
stars a fresh rating on Rotten Tomatoes. Yeah,
I think four stars is a great rating. I actually
like this movie more than the Guardians of
the Galaxy holiday special that we got last
year, which I believe I gave three and a half
stars. I think if I remember correctly, my issue
with the Guardian special was that it didn't
evoke those feelings that the best holiday specials
did, whereas Merry Little Batman, I think definitely
does. Right. Yeah, I remember you saying that
and I would agree with that. Like we said at
the top of the episode, there aren't many holiday
focused films from Marvel or DC. Merry Little
Batman is obviously the most overt holiday project
for the two companies. So there wasn't much
competition in it being the best holiday project.
But yeah, it definitely is. But that does it
for this review. Let us know what you thought
about Merry Little Batman by writing to us
at dynamicduelpodcast.gmail.com or by visiting
us on Instagram or X. You can find links to
all of our accounts by checking out our show
notes or visiting our website at dynamicduel.com
And on our site, you could also find a link
to our Patreon page where you could join our
dynamic two tier and chat with us and fellow
listeners are fantastic for tier, which gets
you bonus content each month. Our X force tier
that makes you an executive producer of this
podcast or our newest tier that lets you join
our dynamic podcast network. If you can't join
Patreon, you can still support the show by signing
up for our e-newsletter also at dynamicdoll.com
so you'll never miss an episode. Please don't
forget to also visit our website and leave
a donation for pop culture classroom. which
will get you a digital poster of our upcoming
charity duel episode, Alfred Pennyworth vs.
Edwin Jarvis, which is our next episode. I
gotta say, I can't believe Team Marvel let DC
get ahead on those donations. Guys, we gotta
prove that we're more charitable than these
DC dorks, alright? So go to dynamicduel.com,
check out the store, click the donation button
for Marvel, and let's win this little charity
competition. No, no, no. DC, guys, we know what
DC really stands for. does charity.
Absolutely. But that does it for this episode,
we want to give a big thanks to our executive
producers Ken Johnson, John Storowski, Zachary
Hepburn, Dustin Balcom, Miggy Matanguian, Brandon
Essergard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Nick
Abonto, Austin Wazilowski, AJ Dunkerley, Scott
Camacho, Adam Spies, and Andrew Schunk for helping
make this podcast possible. We'll talk to you
guys next week. Up, up, and away, true believers.