This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
Welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin brother Marvelous
Joe. And in this episode, we are reviewing
the Netflix series Dead Boy Detectives, which
is adapted from a DC comic book of the same
name, whose lead characters debuted in the pages
of Sandman. Right, and there were even some
characters from the Sandman series in this season
one of the show. I'm not gonna lie, I was a
big hater of the show before it came out, based
on the God-awful trailer that came out prior
to its release, but I'm gonna change my tune
180 degrees, so look forward to that in our
review. Before that, we're gonna break down
the comic book movie news from the past week,
of which there were some doozies. We got our
first look at David Cornswett as Superman,
and... John Malkovich, Ralph Innocent, and Paul
Walter Hauser have been cast in the MCU's Fantastic
Four film. As always, we list our segment times
in our episode description, so feel free to
check out the show notes if you want to skip
ahead to a particular topic. And guys, our
artificially intelligent duel simulator AJ9K
has a quick message for you, so listen up.
Why hello there. Do you love listening and chatting
about Marvel and DC? Then become a part of
the dynamic duel community on Patreon, where
you can choose from three tiers. The dynamic
2-0 tier lets you listen to this podcast without
ads and gives you access to its Discord chat
group, where you can chat with Johnny DC and
Marvelous Joe. The Fantastic Four tier gives
you that and more with two bonus episodes each
month, including bloopers and top ten shows
where Johnny and Joe count down your favourite
Marvel and DC subjects. The X-Force tier makes
you an executive producer of Dynamic Duel, where
every month you help the host choose what to
review and who to fight against each other.
And finally, the Dynamite Podcast Network tier
allows aspiring podcasters to create their own
battle-focused show using this Monte Carlo
simulator.
Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast, including Ken Johnson. He was
one of our very first executive producers. He's
also the host of the Max Destruction on Mother's
Day, so we just want to give a shout out and
say happy birthday. If I could get you a gift
from DC, it would be a case of Lobo's nuclear
shotgun shells. Because if I trusted anyone
with the nuclear codes, Ken, it would be you.
And I would give you Ulysses Claus' arm cannon,
because now that you're podcasting a lot, you
know, you could use the arm cannon to create
objects out of the sound of your voice. What
am I saying? I don't know. But yeah, you could
do something with it. He'll find a way to use
it. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Be sure to tune in to
Ken's show tomorrow, guys, because even though
Max Destruction is going on a season break,
you'll be getting bonus episodes where co-host
Scotty Camacho reviews the Teenage Mutant Ninja
Turtles movie with his brother Gil Camacho.
And on the Sendrow World podcast, host Zachary
Hepburn speculates on fights between fan favorite
anime and manga characters. This Thursday,
we'll find out who would win between Giyu Tomioka
from Demon Slayer and Takeshi Yamamoto from
Hitman Reborn. And on the Console Combat Podcast,
hosts John and Dean find out who would win
in fights between popular video game characters.
In yesterday's episode, they reviewed the Paramount
Plus television series Knuckles. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com
or click the link in our show notes to listen
to all of the shows in the DynaMic Podcast
Network. But with that out of the way, quick
to the no prize! A no prize is an award Marvel
used to give out to fans. Our version, the
Dynamic Duel No Prize, is a digital award we
post on Instagram for the person that we feel
gave the best answer to our question of the
week. Last week we asked, who is your favorite
Superman villain and why? Got a lot of great
answers, let's go ahead and run down our three
honorable mentions as well as the no prize winner.
Our first honorable mention goes to John Spees,
who said, Hey boys, John Spees here.
My favorite Superman villain is Batman. I like
to see those two go head to head. And I like
to see Batman's brain work on how to defeat
this alien that he definitely just does not
trust. It is interesting to see Batman fight
Superman, because it's two heroes who are battling
against each other. In a way, Bruce Wayne is
kind of like Lex Luthor. and that he's this
very intelligent individuel with no superpowers,
but somehow still finds ways to bring Superman
down, as evidenced in comic books like The Dark
Knight Returns. And BVS, which John called
shitty, and it is, but I will contend that the
ultimate edition of the movie, which I know
you shouldn't have to watch, but it is better.
I actually enjoy that version of the film.
You should have to watch it because it's fantastic.
Way better than the theatrical version, which
I agree is shitty. Ultimate version is not.
Great answer John, our next honorable mention
goes to Scott Camacho who said Favorite Superman
villain is obviously Zod. I grew up watching
the dynamics of Dragon Ball like Goku and Vegeta
and Power Rangers with the Red Ranger and then
the evil Green Ranger. There was always the
the Nemesis who is the same as the protagonist
and Zod is that for me for Superman. Yep, most
superheroes have at least one supervillain
that is like a dark mirror reflection of the
hero and that's always pretty interesting because
it's an exploration on what would happen if
the hero that you love turned evil and how
the hero himself would deal against a similar
power set if they went bad. So yeah, Zod is
a great foil in that regard for the character
of Superman. Yeah, Superman actually has a
number of dark analogs. There's Zod, there's
Bizarro, there's Ultraman, but out of all of
them I would agree that Zod is definitely the
most interesting. Great answer Scotty! Our
final honorable mention goes to Judson Batty,
who said, Hi guys, Judson Batty here. If he
counts I would say that my favorite Superman
villain is Lobo. Though he's not really a villain,
but he's an anti-hero, he's a bounty hunter,
that's close enough. I think he's a great foil
for Superman, because he's really all Superman
could be if he went down that path with similar
powers, but not exactly the same, so he doesn't
feel like a copycat. I think that the bikey
bounty hunter side of things is really cool,
and just really interesting to see him in stories,
and obviously space dolphins. Yeah, Lobo, in
a sense, is almost like a dark analog for Superman
as well, and that he's just unbelievably rude.
Compared to Superman who's normally, you know,
farm boy polite. He's gritty, he's dirty, he
kills like no one else He's a fantastic Superman
foil. Jutsson's right though. He's not technically
a villain as wild as it may seem Considering
how amoral the character is but yeah, he's regarded
as an anti-hero in the same vein of like Punisher
or Ghost Rider Those conflicting ideologies
often pit Superman and Lobo up against each
other. But last episode Jutsson wanted to make
sure that we knew that he was Australian, not
British. And then in the notes of his voicemail,
he wanted to clarify that he was Australian,
not Austrian, as Jonathan and I got him confused
for in the last episode. So yeah, just to clarify,
Jutson is a Kiwi from Australia, known for Lord
of the Rings and It's Sheep and my favorite
band of all time, The Flight of the Concords.
Yeah, go Australia and go Jutson. Great answer,
we want to give a special thanks to Miggy Methengyan
and Travis Herndon, who also took the time
to call in with their answers. But the winner
of this week's No Prize is Christopher Minotti,
who said, Hi guys, Christopher Minotti. My favorite
Superman villain has to be Brainiac. I love
this character. Not only is he an alien super
genius, but he also collects worlds, and he
even let Krypton die. I love that, I think that's
great. I think he looks really cool, honestly,
as well. His ship is really cool. And I especially
love his look in the Injustice games. Yeah,
there was something really cool they did in
those games with Brainiac having the tentacles
like Doctor Octopus. I wish that was his look
in the comics like that needs to be canon because
it's just really cool. But even without the
tentacles, Brainiac is just a top tier villain.
He's also my favorite villain for Superman and
that he's just a strong. but he's also world
smarter and has the technology to back that
up. Yeah, it's an absolute crime that Brainiac
has not been in a live-action Superman movie
yet and so I thought I would try to remedy
that by writing a pitch for Jonathan on what
a sequel to Man of Steel should be. And I called
it Man of Tomorrow and you can listen to my
pitch that I gave to Jonathan on our Patreon.
Yeah, that was heartbreaking. I'm still thinking
about that pitch. That was a fantastic pitch.
They should have made that movie. Idiots! Not
you, Christopher! You're a genius, great answer!
You win this week's note prize. If you the listener
want a shot at winning your own note prize,
stay tuned till later on in this episode when
we'll be asking another Question of the Week.
But now that that's done, on to the news!
Okay, so this past week we got our very first
look at actor David Cornsweat in the Superman
costume, which I've been waiting forever for.
I was super pumped for this. And when it finally
came, I felt the way that I usually feel upon
seeing first looks of characters in their costumes,
a little underwhelmed. I would agree. The costume
itself is pretty solid. I'm just a little bit
confused as to the execution. of the image that
they chose to present in that instead of this
heroic Superman pose, we're getting what appears
to be Superman getting dressed after the condom
broke. It's really what it looks like. Yeah,
it looks like he was about to knock boots with
the low slam, then saw the big laser in the
sky. He's like, damn it, put my boots back
on. But yeah, it's a strange image to release
for your first look at Superman. You would
imagine. that it would be something much more
majestic considering the nature of Superman
and him being almost like this god-like figure.
But they really decided to focus on the man
rather than the super in this. And I don't quite
know why I wouldn't have done that. I definitely
wouldn't have shown him looking as tired as
he looks considering the fact that this giant
eyeball is lasering like half of Metropolis
behind him. You know he could hear that. Yeah,
I think the image is supposed to evoke Alex
Ross's art of Superman sitting in his recliner
chair, which was a really humanizing image for
the character of Superman, if you guys are
aware of the painting. This definitely calls
back to that, but by including the danger in
the background, it makes Superman seem apathetic,
which is not a good look. I mean, just overall,
the whole image is not a good look. Even if
the outfit turns out to be incredible, it's
not really showcased in this image, considering
he's sitting down and it's folded. and bunches
up in weird places. Yeah, the costume is definitely
a departure from what we've seen in the past
in terms of like skin tight costumes that Superman
can wear under his shirt. You know, when he
rips it open, he has a suit already on. This
outfit is not going under any clothes. If anything,
it's almost like a jacket that goes over a shirt.
Yeah, unless Clark can't wears nothing but
chunky sweaters. There's no way we're going
to get that, you know, rip open the shirt to
get the Superman costume reveal. You're absolutely
right. I also wish they would have gone with
a suit that was a little bit more clean. This
one definitely looks battle worn, to put it
nicely. Well, it probably is. I assume that
whatever scene this shot was taken from happens
later in the movie. Well, if it's battle worn,
he needs to throw that thing in the wash after
the battle because you don't want to go into
a battle looking like you smell. All right.
It's just not impressive. It does look stinky,
doesn't it? It looks like a stinky Superman
suit. I honestly don't hate the suit. It's very
different from what I was expecting. I'm actually
really looking forward to seeing this thing
in movement and maybe, you know, with him standing
up without it being so wrinkled and dirty. Because
otherwise, I think it's a pretty good shot.
I love David Cornswett's hair. Not loving his
jawline, but I'm also assuming that's just
from him, you know, like, looking down and not
like off into the horizon with this hopeful
demeanor. He definitely has bulked up. I was
recently looking at photos of him and how much
bigger he's gotten since being cast as Superman
and the guy's almost as big as Henry Cavill.
It's insane. Definitely doing steroids. Hopefully
that doesn't affect him long term, but it's
a thing. I think he looks tired here, but again,
it's not the shot I wanted. I'm sure I would
have a better impression if they chose a better
pose for the character. He actually reminds
me a lot of Henry Cavill, which brings us to
our question of the week.
Which actor wore your favorite Superman suit,
and why was it your favorite? Record your answer
at dynamicduel.com by clicking on the red microphone
button in the bottom right hand corner of the
screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long, and don't forget to leave your name in
case we include you on the podcast. We'll pick
our favorite answer, and award that person a
Dynamic Duel No Prize that we'll post to Instagram.
Be sure to answer before May 18th. In other
news, we received word this past week that
Three major actors have joined the cast of the
MCU's Fantastic Four. We have John Malkovich,
Ralph Innocent, and Paul Walter Hauser in roles
for that upcoming film. That also stars Pedro
Pascal, Vanessa Kirby, Joseph Quinn, and Yvonne
Moss-Bachrock. Still not sure if I'm pronouncing
that correctly. The only actor here that was
announced that is attached to a specific role
is Ralph Innocent, who's going to play Galactus,
and holy shit, that is a fantastic casting
choice for Galactus. Yeah, I'm not familiar
with the actor at all, but once I saw his face,
I was like, yeah, that's Galactus. Yeah, I guess
his face kind of looks like it. I don't think
it'll be, you know, Ralph Innocent in a purple
rubber suit or anything like that. I'm sure
they'll go some kind of CG route or motion capture
type thing. But, you know, it's better than
a cloud. We know that Galactus will actually
have a voice. And what a voice to have in Ralph
Innocent. The only movie that I've ever seen,
Ralph In, was The Vavitch. And he was. really
good in that movie. It was that was a scary
movie. Jonathan, you should watch it. Yeah,
that's not going to happen. His voice is deeper
than the Marianas Trench. Damn. Out of all
the human beings on Earth, his is probably the
only voice suitable to portraying this world
devouring godlike character. Yeah, I think it's
solid casting along with John Malkovich and
Paul Walter Hauser. No idea who these guys are
playing. Of course, John Malkovich could play.
friggin any role he wants and he would just
nail it. But also Paul Wachterhauser, I only
know him from the Cobra Kai series, but I'm
really hoping he gets to play Mole Man. Yeah,
that would be good for Mole Man. Also on the
Discord, I heard someone suggest John Malkovich
for Puppet Master and that would be absolute
perfection. I think it would be surprising
if we got Galactus and Puppet Master and Mole
Man in the same film, but you never know, you
never know. Marvel may be putting all their
chips on the table in order to make sure this
is the ultimate. Fantastic Four movie. Well,
if it's an alternate universe, maybe they can
do all of these characters and then just kill
them off and reintroduce them at a later point.
Perhaps, perhaps. But yeah, super excited for
this movie. I can't wait to get our first look
at the costume reveals of the Fantastic Four.
I guess we kind of got them as a drawing of
these characters, but I'm not sure if those
were the final outfits for the FF. We'll see.
The movie is slated to hit theaters on July
25th, 2025. So a little over a year from now.
Wait, that's the release date? Yeah. That's
like only a week after Superman is released.
Good. Superman's being released on July 11th,
2025. Well, I can't wait for the Fantastic
Four to take all of Superman's money. That'll
make me smile. If you think the Fantastic Four
are more popular than Superman, you have another
thing coming, my friend. It's not about who's
more popular. Look at how much money BVS made.
You seem to think it's about popularity when
in fact it's about what's a better movie. OK,
Superman. Yeah. OK.
That does it for all the news for this episode.
Now let's move on to the main event, where
we review season one of the Netflix series,
Dead Boy Detectives.
Dead Boy Detectives is an 8 episode Netflix
exclusive television series with Steve Yawkey
as the showrunner, who is also the lead writer
on The Flight Attendant for Max. Dead Boy Detectives
is the second Netflix series in their Sandman
universe, the first being the acclaimed series
The Sandman, which we gave 4 and a half stars
in our season 1 review. I'm a big fan of Sandman,
the Dead Boy Detectives are only a tiny part
of that universe, but But I enjoyed their appearance
on the Doom Patrol series in season 3 for that
show. The Netflix series was originally going
to be produced as a spin-off of Doom Patrol
for the Max platform, but Warner Bros. decided
to allow Netflix to make the show instead as
part of their Sandman universe, which makes
sense considering the titular characters made
their debut in the pages of the Sandman comic.
The characters are admittedly pretty obscure.
So if you don't know anything about them or
don't want to know anything about the show prior
to watching it, I suggest you hit pause now
and watch the show because it's pretty damn
good. And then come back and listen to this
review. Yeah, I highly recommend watching it.
I concur that it is very good. I didn't actually
want to watch this show at all. I didn't want
to review it. And that is all based off of
my feelings about the first trailer that came
out for Dead Boy Detective season one, which
was an atrocity. I actually went back. after
I watched this show and then rewatched that
trailer and I totally feel like the trailer
editor should have been fired because in no
way shape or form captured the coolness that
was this show. I totally take back everything
I said, including my initial gripe that the
two main actors looked too similar to each
other. Oh yeah. Now, when you actually watch
the show, it's highly apparent that they're
not even, you know, the same race. I think the
cast was just phenomenal for this show across
the board. hands down. The cast is definitely
one of the highlights of the series by far
and I'll get into that later on. But I agree
with you, Netflix is notoriously not great
with marketing. I kind of feel like they don't
feel like they need to be because they're churning
out so much content all the time. They tend
to not want to focus on one particular thing,
especially when it comes to series like these
where people aren't really familiar with the
characters or there isn't a really big name
attached to it. Again, These characters are
obscure, even for comic fans. Now in the comics,
the Dead Boy Detectives, namely Edwin Payne
and Charles Roland, are only 13 years old, but
because they've lived for decades, their stories
in the comics tended to be a bit more mature
in terms of horror and violence, and they were
often published by DC's mature imprints such
as Vertigo or Black Label. This series, for
the most part, matched that same kind of mature
tone. It's TVMA. And in my opinion, The tone
was a terrific blend of quirky, dark comedy
and weird supernatural horror, very much in
the same vein as Doom Patrol, a show I loved
and will miss, so it's nice to have this as
somewhat of a replacement. Absolutely, yeah.
When Doom Patrol finished up its last season,
it kind of left a void out there in the superhero
television genre. I think Dead Boy Detective
Season 1 filled that niche perfectly. Which
is high praise because I really liked Doom
Patrol. Yeah, same. I think fairly high ratings
in the course of its run. But one thing I think
this series definitely has over Doom Patrol
is its production value. I'm not sure if the
show is actually more expensive, but it would
not surprise me. Dead Boy Detectives doesn't
look as expensive as Sandman, but in terms of
the special effects, the cinematography, it's
all an upgrade from Doom Patrol. And in that
regard. I'm actually glad the show made the
jump to Netflix because it seems like they really
aren't afraid of investing in the Sandman universe.
Now, the cast of the Dead Boy Detectives on
Do Patrol, I thought, was terrific. They were
originally supposed to be in the Max show, but
that changed in the transition to Netflix,
at least for all of the cast members, except
for the actress who played Night Nurse, strangely
enough. Yeah, I thought that was strange. She
is a good actress, so I don't know. My impression
was that the actors who played Charles and Edwin
in the Doom Patrol series were much more comic
book accurate because I know the characters
like one's a blonde, one's a brunette. And
on this Netflix show, they're both brunettes
who look like they're 18 years old. In the
Doom Patrol series, they looked a lot younger.
But that's not to discount the Netflix cast.
They were less accurate to the source material,
but they were still phenomenal. They're their
own thing. The Doom Patrol cast is absolutely
more comics accurate in terms of look, but
I think the new cast definitely captured the
spirit of the characters pretty well. And also
considering, you know, it is a mature show,
it's not surprising they went with a slightly
older cast, even though they keep calling them
kids in the show and boys. And I'm like, dude,
you look like you're 21. Yeah, I've never seen
such a independent group of 16 year olds in
my entire life. For real. Like going out and
like. Yeah, like renting rooms and stuff like
that. I wasn't doing that at 16. When I first
saw the trailer for this, I was pretty sad
that they didn't go with a Doom Patrol cast.
That didn't survive very long once I started
watching the show, because, as I mentioned earlier,
one of the major draws of the Netflix show
is its charismatic cast and their chemistry.
Charismatic is the perfect word for sure. Yeah,
and the charisma goes even beyond the leads.
Like even with. basic filler, you could say
superfluous characters such as Nico and Jenny,
it's kind of hard to imagine the show without
them because the actors gave such endearing
performances. While the show's major drawback
is that it's loaded with story threads and subplots
that lead nowhere, such as Nico's parents or
Jenny's stalker, there's still enough to enjoy
there that you wouldn't mind if the characters
returned for a second season with how well they
work with the main characters of Edwin, Charles,
and Crystal. Yeah, I think this is the only
show where I didn't mind getting sidetracked
a little bit. I don't know why. I don't know
if it was due to the serial nature of the show,
kind of where they were working on a different
case every episode. But I just enjoyed the
world building, I guess. And the more they expanded
on that, the more I felt like I was immersed
into the small Washington town. Yeah, I don't
know if I would describe the show as serial.
I would probably describe it as procedural.
It had this procedural nature, almost like.
You know, a NYPD blue episode where there's
like a new case to solve each week, a new mystery
for the detectives to solve each episode. I
loved that. Yeah, it was fun to watch. That's
what I was hoping She-Hulk would be, where it
would be a new law case every week. But that
didn't quite pan out. Yeah, that would have
made She-Hulk so much better. And that show
had like a lot of side characters as well. You
know, I feel like Dead Boy Detectives is a
perfect template for how She-Hulk should have
gone. Exactly. I would have loved that. Now
in terms of smaller characters such as Cat King,
Tragic Mick the Walrus, and the foul-mouthed
Dandelion sprites, who I'm sure some people
found annoying, but I found hilarious, they
also seem to blend themselves into the overarching
story and the episodic nature seamlessly almost.
There were a few cameos that didn't quite work
I think, but may later on in subsequent seasons,
including Despair and I don't know if you remember
him. He was the ringed man inside of Angie
the sea monster. No idea who that guy is. I
don't recognize him from the comics, but to
be fair, I haven't read all of the Dead Boy
Detective graphic novels yet. If I had to guess
though, maybe he's a character we'll see appear
again in Sandman, though that's just a shot
in the dark. I actually liked the despair cameo.
I thought that was just a very surreal scene
when Edwin meets her among the floating mirrors.
Yeah, that was interesting. And I guess it
also kind of fit with the whole nature of how
Edwin and Charles are able to traverse the
world by going through mirrors. Now, that's
something that they took from the Doom Patrol
show when they traversed the mirror into the
underworld. They don't do that in the comics.
They can teleport naturally wherever they want,
although it's like uncomfortable for them to
do so. The whole mirror play was interesting.
And I wonder if they did that with the intention
of playing upon despair, because her whole realm.
is mirrors in the comics. Interesting. Well,
she did tell Edwin that, you know, they were
friends now and that she would be seeing him
again later. I'm assuming maybe in Sandman season
two. I hope so. I would love to see these guys
make an appearance, because actually they're
due for one in the next season if they're following
the comic books. It was like issue 25, I believe,
of Sandman, which would fall in season two
of where the characters were introduced. Nice.
But let's talk more about the characters in
the character breakdown. starting with Edwin
Payne. Now he was played by George Rexdrew,
and this is basically his first performance
ever on screen. As you mentioned, he definitely
didn't look like the character from the comics,
but he gave a fantastic performance, I thought,
for sure. As this brainy amateur magician of
the group, you know, one who died as a ritual
sacrifice to a demon at his school, and whose
soul was traded amongst the demons in Hell,
which he eventually escaped. When he returns
to the mortal plane, in the same place where
he died, the attic of his school, he found Charles
there dying and he stayed with him. I'm not
sure if he did that out of sympathy for someone
else at the school who was bullied and killed,
like in the comics, or from romantic attraction
to Charles, which has only recently come out
in the comics, or because he wanted to start
doing good to avoid hell should he ever be
caught by death. It may have been all of the
above, but motivation wise, Being good and
doing good to avoid hell is definitely what
drives Edwin in the series. A truth that was
revealed to him by the Cat King. You know, Edwin
helps ghosts because he loved detective stories
when he was alive and because it's the right
thing to do. I am still shocked that you said
that this was his first performance because
I thought the actor as Edwin did a phenomenal
job. I totally bought him as this like young...
gay Sherlock Holmes with some like Constantine-esque
magic tricks at his disposal. And I think he
did a really good job of not only selling him
as this like closed off character who's actually
been through lifetimes of misery, but also
I think he sold the romantic aspects too. You
know, this pining for someone that is unattainable
just felt very tragic and there's a lot that's
tragic about Edwin and it all just came across
expertly. Yeah, the romantic angle was a slow
build, but it felt very natural. I think they
did a terrific job with that. Yeah, there was
a huge payoff when he finally admitted his
feelings to Charles. And I think I remember
that from the Doom Patrol series too. I think
they said that Edwin was attracted to Charles.
But yeah, that felt like such an epic moment,
not only because they were escaping hell, but
because the emotional stakes were so huge as
well. So you just had a lot going on there.
It felt very climactic. Oh yeah, absolutely.
That was one of my favorite episodes, actually.
But for as much as he has romantic feelings
for Charles, you could also see Edwin continuing
his magic studies and detective work without
him if it ever came to that. Whereas Charles
definitely seems to be more attached to Edwin,
interestingly. He's protective over him because
he is a good friend in that way. Yeah, exactly.
Now, one difference from the comics that I wanna
point out that I thought they did really well
in the show was the reason that he went to hell.
Now, that's never explained in the comics.
He was sacrificed by bullies in the school,
but like, why would that send someone to hell?
The reasoning for him to go to hell in the show
is, you know, because he was a sacrifice to
a demon, so the demon took him, I thought was
much better. You never see that in the comic.
That was a horrifying but quirky scene in that,
you know, the demon showed up during the sacrifice
and killed everybody. But kind of, it seems
like he knew that Edwin was being sacrificed
unethically or something, because he's like,
Yeah. Sorry, mate. Gotta take you cause you're
a sacrifice. Let's go, you know? It's a technicality.
What are you gonna do? Yeah, yeah, it's interesting.
Moving on to Charles Rowland, he was played
by Jaden Reverie, who is a veteran actor, but
I thought his chemistry with George Ruxrew was
perfect. They're both fantastic actors. Yeah,
I remember during the trailer that like I did
not wanna like this show, as I think I've mentioned
before. I think my fear of the show was that
it would be too- Gen Z for me because just
the look of the actor who plays Edwin seems
very of the current time, you know, of the
current young generation of people. And the
show itself, I thought would be unapproachable
because I wouldn't get a lot of it. But if anything,
it helped me feel a little bit more connected
to Gen Z. It's pretty interesting. It is interesting
because his look actually isn't, I guess it
is Gen Z, but that's just circling back to the
time, the 80s, when Charles died, which was
the late 80s. Yeah, it's fascinating how style
kind of revolves like that. Now, Charles is
the muscle and feisty gadgeteer of sorts for
the group. He's equipped with a bag that can
hold an infinite number of items, including
a badass cricket bat that's kind of like Mjolnir.
Charles is also motivated like Edwin to do good,
not because of where he'll go in the afterlife,
but because he always tried to please his abusive
father in life. And now he likes to please
his friend Edwin, who was there for him when
no one else ever was. and of course, Crystal,
his love interest. We were talking about how
tragic Edwin's character was. I think that
Charles is just as tragic. That was so heartbreaking
later on in the series when we actually see
how Charles died. It made me angry because he
didn't deserve that. You know, neither of these
boys deserve to die and it made you want to
root for them in the afterlife, especially
when you get those speeches from Edwin, I think
in like episode two, where he was like, no
one cared about our murders. Like they weren't.
bothered to be solved or anything like that.
So we have to solve these cases for the people
like us. And the whole abuse thing with Charles
specifically just broke my heart. Oh, absolutely.
Yeah. His origin is interesting in that it's
another example of how this show borrowed elements
from the Doom Patrol, specifically him being
stoned in a river where he also caught hypothermia.
In the comics, Charles was burned and stabbed
by the same bullies that sacrificed Edwin 70
years earlier. When they died, they went to
hell, but in the comics, Lucifer gave up on
ruling hell, so all of the denizens of hell
came back to the mortal plane. That's how Edwin
came back, that's how his bullies came back,
and the same ones who killed Edwin were the
same ones who killed Charles. Interesting.
Yeah, I don't know if I like that as much. No,
this show was a perfect adaptation in that
it improved the source of material, in my opinion.
Moving on to Crystal Palace, she was played
by Cassius Nelson. I don't know too much about
her other than she's a Brit who can pull off
a hell of an American accent. Oh, my God. I
didn't even know she was a Brit. I liked the
Crystal Palace that was in Doom Patrol. I remember
thinking after watching the trailer that I
don't understand why they cast this new Crystal
Palace, and I could not be more wrong. So wrong
was so good in this series. She was so good,
she blew me away with almost every line delivery.
She's phenomenal. I could totally see why she
was cast. And I think I judged her way too
harshly based off of just simple lines like,
that's a fucking stupid name, just because
I didn't want to agree with what she was saying.
But you know, her whole arc is that she was
kind of an asshole back in the day. This is
her redemption arc, as it were. It's also your
redemption arc, apparently. It is my- yeah.
Absolutely. She was phenomenal. Yeah, no, the
actress who played her, Cassius Nelson, Cassius,
I'm not sure if I'm pronouncing her name correctly.
But yeah, she's definitely going places. I will
be learning how to pronounce her name as I'm
sure everyone will be because yeah, she's fantastic.
She's definitely the breakout star of the show.
Dude, everyone, everyone is the breakout star
of the show. Her, Nico, Jenny, the boys, everyone.
That's true, fair enough. No, Crystal is the
psychic human of the group who proves her value
to the boys. through her psychic visions and
ability to interact with other humans to get
easy answers. Her motivation in the show is
twofold. One to find out more about her past
and eventually return home, but also to prove
that David, the demon who possessed her and
continues to torment her throughout the series,
is wrong about her nature and that she is in
fact a good person capable of doing good things.
So it's interesting how the three main characters
sort of have the same motivation in the series
of simply to do good. She has less strong feelings
for Charles as he does for her, but the love
triangle between the three results in some
decent tension for the story that I thought
worked really well. In the comics, Crystal's
parents were jerk performance artists who simply
let her do whatever she wanted, but she was
always a nice person and to my knowledge she
was never possessed by a demon named David.
That's an original character, but I thought
a strong one and it's like a great ghost for
the character, like this haunted past for her.
that worked really well with the story. And
again, another example of how the show plusses
the comic. Plus that exorcism scene was just
really cool. Oh yeah, when David runs out underneath
the sheet out of the subway. Yeah. That was
cool. Now there's a ton of characters. I do
want to touch on the two villains before we
get into the plot breakdown, starting with Night
Nurse. She was played by Ruth Cornell. Again,
she was the same actress who played a very different
version of Night Nurse in the Doom Patrol show.
Now she's not to be confused with Asa, the Nightmare
Nurse from Justice League Dark, though I think
she may have been an inspiration for the character.
Night Nurse is original to Doom Patrol and
the series. Now Night Nurse is a strict, by
the book, caretaker of the children's nursery
in the afterlife. A limbo of sorts that tracks
the souls of dead children and ushers them
where they need to go. I didn't really like
her character initially, like her scenes were
the most dull to me. even though I understood
she represented the stakes of Edwin and Charles
being hunted by death. I did get her motivation,
however, that she felt Edwin and Charles were
cheating death and I also liked how she ended
up helping the boys in the end, even being
assigned to be their handler. That was fantastic.
I loved that reversal because, you know, she
is charismatic as well. You didn't really root
against her because you kind of understood
where she was coming from like you said. So
to all of a sudden have these characters working
together by the end was a nice turn of events.
Moving on to the other villain, Esther Finch,
she was played by Jen Lyon, who was fantastic
and effortlessly charismatic in her performance.
It's kind of hammy, but in the best way, and
it looked like she had a ton of fun with the
role. This was another actress that I was hating
on in the trailer because just like the weird
line delivery that she gave when she was like,
Monty, I'm trying to... threaten some boys
or something. I was like, this is so fucking
stupid. But then when you actually see it in
context of who the character is, yeah, it looks
like she had a blast with the role. It was
perfect casting. It's like she was born to play
that role. Exactly. Actually, I felt that way
about most of the characters in this cast. Like
I'm sure I'll see a few of them in other roles
down the line, but I'm always gonna remember
them for these specific roles because a lot
of them are unknown to me. and they did such
a fantastic, iconic job with their performances.
Cannot say enough good things about the cast.
Now Esther was a woman who turned to witchcraft
to punish her cheating husband during the pioneering
days of America's Pacific coast. After being
granted immortality by Lilith, the patron of
wronged women, Esther was forced to feed on
the souls of young girls to her pet snake in
order to maintain her youth and beauty across
the centuries. She's motivated by revenge against
the boys for rescuing a young girl that she
was going to feed on. It takes a while for the
show to reveal her teeth-face mushroom monster
plan, but I could see why due to the procedural
nature of the show. And despite the lack of
reveal of her plan early on, she was still like
a credible threat whenever she appeared in
the background. Yeah, fantastic villain. I thought
they were, you know, over and done with her
by episode one. And I thought even in the final
episode, she made for a fantastic climax. Yeah,
she did. Like the way she beat the shit out
of the cat king, you know. Oh, there was any
cast member I didn't like. It was probably the
cat king. He was just really sleazy. Yeah,
I could get that. I didn't want to like him.
But honestly, the actor also just nailed the
performance in a way that didn't make it feel
as cheesy as it should have been. So I was
just impressed by that fact alone.
Where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
DynaMic Podcast Network presents Console Combat,
where video game legends brawl every Monday.
Smash every Tuesday, Max Destruction, where
TV and action heroes battle every Wednesday,
and Sendro World, where anime champions clash
every Thursday. Join us as we speculate on
the matches and, armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge victorious.
Visit dynamicpodcast.com where we settle the
debate and settle the score.
Moving on to the story highlights, the first
episode was called The Case of Crystal Palace.
After British ghost detectives Edwin Payne and
Charles Rowland help a ghost soldier from World
War I cross into the afterlife, avoiding death
in the process, the duo takes on a new case
to help a young demon-possessed amnesiac psychic
named Crystal Palace. After exorcising her
demon, Crystal convinces the friends to travel
with her to port towns in Washington in America.
to find a missing girl named Becky that Crystal
psychically deduced was still alive after touching
the boy's mail. After getting lodging above
a butcher shop, the trio learns that Becky
is trapped in a witch's house. After a flashback
to Edwin's death in the 1910s, Edwin uses a
magic string to trap a cat and learn more about
the witch, after which the trio makes a plan
to break into her house. Before they escape
with Becky, The witch, named Esther Finch,
confronts and injures them, forcing Charles
to possess her and rescue the team. After Becky
is returned home, the Lost and Found department
in the Netherworld is notified of Charles'
act of possession, bringing Kim and Edwin to
the attention of the Night Nurse. I will admit
that the first episode I think was actually
my least favorite, even though it was really
good and I was compelled to watch more. I think
it just had too much load to bear, basically.
We had to get through all these introductions
and whatnot. And while eventually the show
ended up getting its bearings starting in episode
two, when we started getting a more procedural
formula for the show, it did kind of stumble
out of the gate, I think. But still good. I
agree with you. But honestly, it was one of
my favorite episodes just because of how well
it set up the premise of the series, I guess.
Yeah, and it was successful in the setup. I'll
say that, especially with the tone and the characters.
I guess it was less successful in terms of
plotting. as an individuel standalone piece.
I really liked the action of this first episode,
like right off the bat. You see Edwin and Charles
running from this World War One ghost, and
they're like hopping through mirrors and like
casting spells and getting like blood dripped
on them and stuff. I really enjoyed it. I also
really enjoyed seeing death. I was like, oh,
shit, it's death from Sandman. It's Kirby. How
about East? She's too nice. I want to see her
like get angry once, you know, dude, you like
never see that in the comics. Really? Yeah,
that's too bad. Moving on to episode two, the
case of the Dandelion Shrine. As the trio attempts
to leave Port Townsend, they're confronted by
a cluster of cats that take them to the Cat
King, whose angry Edwin used magic on one of
his cats and traps him in Port Townsend with
a magic bracelet. While the boys go to a shop
of magic artifacts owned by a man named Tragic
Mick, Crystal encounters her new neighbor, a
young girl named Niko Saki, who's emitting
colorful lights and faints. After Charles uses
a mirror to return to their detective office
back in London to collect magical reference
books, the boys learn that parasitic dandelion
sprites have infected Nico and she's in danger
of exploding. While following a map through
the forest to where Nico was infected, the boys
learn that the sprites can be trapped in an
enchanted vessel. Just before Nico explodes,
Crystal uses herself as bait for the sprites
new host while Charles traps them in an enchanted
jar they procured from the magic shop. After
the ordeal, Nico's hair turns white and her
near-death experience allows her to see ghosts,
and the boy's ghost mailman informs them that
all the ghosts in town have heard about them.
Meanwhile, Esther turns her pet crow into a
human boy named Monty to seduce Edwin. I just
want to say that I love Nico. She was so fantastic
in this. We should all strive to be more like
Nico and Charles because as far as I'm concerned,
they're the best people in fiction. She was
fantastic, and while this case was probably
one of the least interesting cases out of the
entire season, I think the actress is the one
who made it endearing. Yeah, absolutely. I
agree with everything you said. What's interesting
is that Nico is an original character. She's
not in the comics. So I think including her
is just a stroke of genius for the writers.
I'm not surprised that she's an original character.
She just seems too unique and special to not
be conceived of on the spot in the making of
the show. I think one interesting thing they
did in this episode is trap the boys in this
town with the bracelet that Edwin is forced
to wear. It was a smart way to keep the show
cheap, I think. Yeah. Well, it did a lot of
things. I mean, the whole trapping them there
addressed, you know, Edwin's burgeoning sexuality.
It addressed a lot of their individuel character
arcs. It did things like made Nico a main character
in this season. And Esther a villain. Yeah,
I was initially annoyed that they actually
got trapped there because I think I wanted the
show to take place in London, but, you know,
by the end I was perfectly happy with the setting.
Yeah, and who knows, maybe season two will
take place in London. Yeah. Episode three was
titled, The Case of the Devlin House. After
meeting with dozens of ghosts, the boys decide
to accept a case involving a grisly murder
slash suicide that happened in a neighborhood
house a couple of decades prior. After learning
more about the notorious Devlin murders from
Jenny the Butcher and the library, Edwin and
Nico meet Monty, while the night nurse is prevented
from going to find the boys on the mortal plane
due to afterlife bureaucracy and red tape. While
visiting the Devlin house hours before it's
scheduled to be demolished, Crystal and the
boys witness a repeated loop of the ghosts
of the Devlin family reliving their grisly deaths
at the hands of their father. Emotionally traumatized,
Charles attempts to stop the father. but gets
stuck in the loop as well. After discovering
a VHS recording of the murders in a hidden room
in the house, Edwin manages to erase the tape
while Crystal is meanwhile tormented by David,
her former love interest and a demon. With
the tape erased, the Devlin ghosts are able
to move into the afterlife, and Charles becomes
unstuck from the loop. While Monty meets up
with Edwin once again, the Night Nurse learns
the location of the boys from the Devlin children.
Now, like Charles, And I guess all three of
them, this was kind of a hard episode to watch.
It was it was horrifying. Yeah, I mean, you
see repeatedly the father murder his wife and
daughters with an axe. It's definitely TVMA,
right? But there's this almost not a true crime
appeal, but it's the same kind of appeal where
you see these horrific things being brought
to justice. Yeah, true. Yeah. Am I the only
one that was super annoyed by Monty? Yeah, he's
probably my least favorite character in the
whole show. I think he's kind of supposed to
be. supposed to get on people's nerves and
then kind of redeem himself in the end. And
I think he did kind of become this tragic figure.
But until he got there, I was just super annoyed
by the kid. Like, I didn't want to see him.
He was dumb. I think it was partly because of
how uncomfortable he made Edwin as well. That
just bothered me a little too. He was like so
forward with him when Edwin was uncomfortable
with who he was necessarily at that point. Exactly,
yet you saw how uncomfortable Edwin was with
the cat king, and to see some other character
just kind of being real pushy in that regard
just made you want him to go away. Moving on
to episode 4, which was called The Case of
the Lighthouse Leapers. After Crystal and Nico
question Jenny about anonymous love letters
she's receiving, a ghost lightkeeper arrives
and requests their services to help stop people
from jumping off of his lighthouse. Crystal,
Nico, and the boys arrive at the lighthouse
just in time to see a woman jump from the top
and become a ghost. insisting she heard from
a loved one that told her to jump. While several
other ghosts tell Charles and Crystal the same
thing, and Crystal nearly succumbs to jumping
herself after hearing her mother's voice call
to her, Edwin is visited by the King of Cats
who accuses Edwin of having romantic feelings
for Charles, and Nico learns in a nearby gift
shop of the local legend of the Washer Woman,
who lends guidance to those in need. Nico finds
a red shard of sea glass on the shore, allowing
them to meet with the washerwoman who tells
them the Jumpers are being lured to their deaths
by a sea monster. While Night Nurse confronts
Jenny about the location of Crystal, she, Nico,
and the boys visit Tragic Mix's shop, who informs
them that their monster sounds like a giant
anglerfish named Angie and sells them a musical
device that will put her to sleep. After getting
meat from the butcher to use as bait, the group
returns to the lighthouse where they are confronted
by the Night Nurse. who torments Charles with
visions of how he was bullied, abused, and
killed. Enraged, Charles beats Night Nurse with
the musical device, knocking her into the sea
where she's swallowed up by Angie, who leaves
the lighthouse. Back home, Charles and Crystal
share a kiss. This was actually probably my
favorite episode because we finally got a chance
to see Charles' origin. And though it was tragic,
it kind of cemented Charles as my favorite
character of the show. Yeah, he was probably
my favorite character of the show too. This
was a fantastic episode. The latter half was
definitely better than the first half. The
first half posed a lot of questions that never
really quite get answered throughout the rest
of the season, such as who is the gift shop
owner? What's the deal with the riddle talking,
washing woman? How the hell does Anglerfish
get that big and nobody notices things like
that? I think it was a supernatural anglerfish.
Sea monster. Obviously. I don't think it was
a real anglerfish, Joseph. But yeah, the latter
half of the episode was actually extremely
powerful. And then you got that kiss at the
end, which felt like an oh shit moment because
you knew all the emotional stakes that were
going around. Right, exactly. Episode 5 was
titled The Case of the Two Dead Dragons. While
the boys are approached by the ghosts of two
murdered high school jocks to find out who murdered
them, Nico identifies Jenny's anonymous love
letter scribe as the local librarian, Lindsay.
After investigating the area in the woods where
the jocks' bodies were found and finding nothing,
Crystal and the boys visit the local high school
in disguise to question the students. There,
they are directed by a boy named Richie, who
is bullied by the Jocks, and informs them that
one of the Jocks' ex-girlfriends, Shelby, killed
herself months after the Jocks were found dead.
After using a spell to summon Shelby's ghost,
Shelby tells them that the Jocks were jerks
who ruined her life. When Crystal gets a phone
call from Marin, one of the Jocks' girlfriends
at the time of their death, Crystal goes to
visit her house. where the boys deduce that
Marin was the one who poisoned and killed the
jocks and was about to kill Crystal as well.
When confronted, Marin confesses to poisoning
the jocks after they threaten to send nude photos
of her to everyone on their football team.
While Marin turns herself into the police, Jenny
has dinner with Lindsay at the butcher shop,
only to learn that Lindsay has been stalking
her at night. When Lindsay is asked to leave,
she becomes violent, but slips and dies via
brain impalement while attacking Jenny. After
the jocks learn who killed them, they cross
over into Hell, and Crystal is once again tormented
by David. When Monty kisses Edwin, Edwin confesses
that he has feelings for someone else. This
was actually probably my least favorite episode,
and I think a lot of it has to do with just
the jocks being jerks. Yeah, the jocks were
assholes. They deserved to burn in Hell. That
was actually a pretty cool special effect when
they got dragged there. I actually really liked
this episode. To me, one of the things that
sticks out in my mind most when thinking about
the show overall is how uncomfortable the scene
was between the stalker librarian chick and
the butcher lady when the librarian mentioned
that she thought she was so cute in her pajama
oversized t-shirt. And just that moment, that
like, oh, shit moment. And then like just fucking
went crazy. Like I know this whole scene had
no bearing on the season as a whole, but it
was my favorite like side plot by far. just
because how fucking bonkers it was. Like she
started chasing her with a butcher knife and
then she fucking tripped and fell onto a spike.
Holy shit, man. My jaw was on the floor. Yeah,
I agree. Like this was definitely my favorite
part of an episode that I didn't really care
for. The actresses just totally pulled off
everything. Again, the cast, so good. Even minor
characters like the librarian. Right, believable
as a total psycho all of a sudden. Totally,
totally. Episode six was titled, The Case of
the Creeping Forest. When Crystal and Niko visit
Tragic Mick to find something that will get
David out of Crystal's mind, they learn about
Mick's past as a walrus before they're given
an artifact known as the Light of Heart, which,
when used, causes Crystal to accidentally remove
her powers of psychic insight as well. After
Esther grows a magic mushroom, she orders Monty
to lure Crystal and the boys into the forest,
where her trap awaits. Making up a story about
a missing ghost friend named Gladys, Monty successfully
gets them into the forest, where they find
traces of ghost fungus, which is deadly to ghosts.
Despite Edwin developing a formula to kill
the fungus, it continues to grow and the boys
realize it's coming from an interdimensional
creature. When the team splits up to locate
the creature, Edwin and Crystal are attacked
by David, but manage to defeat him. Monty, despite
still being hurt over Edwin's unrequited feelings,
has a change of heart and attempts to get Edwin
out of the forest and Esther's trap. but not
before the Cat King appears, who outs Moti as
Esther's crow and reveals the boys are falling
into a trap set up by Esther. Moti leaves in
shame only to run into Esther who kills and
converts him back into a crow. Just as Edwin
finds Charles and Crystal to warn them of Esther's
trap, Esther attacks with her mushroom creature,
Teeth Face, who attempts to eat the boys. Meanwhile,
Crystal discovers within her the magic spirits
of her ancestors, reawakening her psychic powers
and then some. which allows her to defeat Teethface
and Esther, burying them both in the forest
and saving the boys. Back home, Night Nurse
finds the boys and threatens to take them into
the afterlife when suddenly a demon erupts from
hell and steals Edwin, who loses the Cat King's
bracelet in the process. This was a great episode
except for one thing, and it was actually my
least favorite moment of the entire season.
And it was when Crystal defeated the fungus
monster. She basically stuck her hands into
the ground and was like... Hey, leave them
alone. And the monster was like, oops, sorry.
And then like left. It was like, it couldn't
have been that simple. I understand that it
was, I guess, supposed to be this great psychic
feat or whatnot. But to have the mushroom monster
just kind of like apologize and leave undersold
the stakes that I think it was supposed to pose.
Yeah, it was pretty anticlimactic. I'll agree
with that. But I also liked the original aspect
of Crystal and how she was a descendant of
this ancient line of sorceresses. I almost got
the impression that she was a descendant of
Lilith herself, though I may just be making
that up. It felt very Black Panther, you know,
on the ancestral plane. Okay, Black Panther
does not have a monopoly on African culture,
my friend. Well, that seemed like it was Jamaican
culture, but the purple tree and everything,
come on. I liked this episode overall. It definitely
had the most shocking moment to me when all
of a sudden at the very end of this episode,
a demon snatches Edwin to go back to hell.
I was like, holy shit, next episode, next episode.
Yeah, that was horrifying. The next episode,
episode seven, was titled The Case of the Very
Long Stairway. Now Esther emerges from the
ground pissed and confronts the cat king about
revealing her trap, beating him to death and
taking one of his nine lives. In the process,
she learns that Edwin is in hell, but has escaped
before, which inspires a new plan for Esther.
Meanwhile, Charles pleads with Night Nurse
to open a portal to Hell for him to save Edwin,
and after seeing how the two boys first met,
Night Nurse is moved into helping Charles. Using
Edwin's notes, Charles navigates Hell, while
Edwin finds one of the boys who killed him and
despair of the Endless. Crystal meanwhile seeks
out her demon ex-boyfriend for her own way into
Hell to help Edwin after Charles refused to
let her come with him. Jenny follows Crystal,
however, and she ends up being possessed by
David, who then attacks Crystal, though Crystal
easily overcomes him. As Esther visits Tragic
Mic for parts to a device that will torture
Edwin and convert his pain into power, Charles
finds Edwin in Hell and the two manage to escape,
with Edwin confessing his love for Charles
and Charles responding that though Edwin is
his very best friend, he's not in love with
him back. The two continue into the living world
amicably, and before Night Nurse can take the
two into the afterlife, Nico points out that
Night Nurse needs to fill out a specific form
before she can transfer the boys into the afterlife.
Angry, Night Nurse promises to come back for
them before Crystal, having obtained her memories
back from David in the form of marbles, swallows
one to regain her memory. This is my favorite
episode. It was by far the best- It was so
good, it could have been the season finale.
Everything about it was executed really well,
especially the unique depiction of hell that
we got here. It was just horrifying, but in
its own quirky dead boy detective's way, I think.
Yeah, like the different levels where people
were being punished for their various vices
felt very like Dante's Inferno, but you're
right, in a very different, kind of more modern,
quirky way. The fact that Charles really didn't
experience it until he was getting Charles out,
felt very much like a haunted house of sorts.
And it was just creepy. One of the best things
I think about this episode was that it kind
of subverted expectations as far as formula
goes, because my expectation was that Crystal
was going to find another route into hell and
she was gonna rescue the boys out of hell.
And Charles was gonna be proven wrong that he
didn't need her to help Edwin. But Crystal's
demon. didn't have a way into Hell. And so she
had this own little arc on her own where she
actually tapped into her full potential and
got her memories back and everything on her
own and had nothing to do with the Hell adventure.
And I'm kind of glad it turned out that way
because it was nice that the boys had time to
themselves. And it was also good that Crystal
had that as well for her to kind of face David
without the help from the boys. Right, yeah,
I made them a stronger characters individuelly.
Absolutely. In the final episode, episode eight
titled The Case of the Hungry Snake, After remembering
her past crimes and abuses of power, Crystal
calls her parents to check in, only to learn
they didn't even realize she was gone. After
Esther finishes and tests her pain-to-power
generator, Crystal and Nico reveal to Jenny
that she had been possessed and introduced her
to the world of the paranormal. When Crystal
starts off to leave the team, Esther bombs Jenny's
butcher shop with magic and binds Edwin and
Charles' souls into lanterns. Crystal returns
and together with Nico, visits the Cat King
to learn of Esther's past, including a pact
she made with Lilith for immortality, and her
weaknesses, which includes black salt, which
they get from Tragic Mick. As Esther activates
her machine, consuming large quantities of power,
Crystal and Nico sneak into her house and help
Charles escape from his iron shackles in order
to kill Esther's pet snake, which keeps her
young. Crystal and Nico, meanwhile, attack Esther
head on, though Esther manages to kill Nico.
When Crystal reaches into Esther's mind, She
convinces Lilith to rescind her bestowal of
immortality on Esther. After Charles successfully
kills the snake, Esther rapidly ages and is
carried off by Lilith for the harm she had done
to young girls. After agreeing to have Crystal
stay on as a teammate and saying goodbye to
Jenny and the Cat King, the boys return to
their London office only to be confronted by
the Night Nurse and her supervisor, who recognizes
the dead boy detective's beneficial work helping
ghosts receive closure and cross over. and
she transfers Night Nurse to Earth to oversee
the boys' work. Before the final end credits,
we see a hidden figure and an igloo with the
dandelion sprites holding a lucky charm that
had been owned by Nico. Just when I thought
that the story had nowhere really to go after
the previous episode, which was so good that
I said it could have been the season finale,
the show goes and wows me with everything that
happened in the final episode. Moments like
the butcher shop getting blown up, fun moments
like Nico and Crystal speaking with the cat
king and moments like Nico dying. There was
just so much that this last episode delivered
on and I was really pleased with it. Yeah, it
was nice to see them combat Esther in a way
that was much less anticlimactic than the whole
mushroom bit. Yeah. It was very much like a
bare-knuckle brawl with magic. It was gritty
like that, which was pretty cool. And yeah,
I'm really happy with how the show ended. I'm...
excited for a second season. I hope we get
one. I really hope we do too. I have no idea
how the show is performing on Netflix, but
I'm sure it has a wide audience. I just hope
it reaches them. Yeah, I'm kind of nervous
about it because it was in the top 10 Netflix
television series for a couple of days, but
then it like completely fell out of the top
10. I'm really hoping that word of mouth spreads
and more people watch it because I think it's
worth watching and I think it's worth the season
too. It's getting good reviews, not only by
us, but by a lot of the critics on Rotten Tomatoes.
Well, you don't know how I'm going to review
this. You don't know a score I'm going to give
it. OK, all right. I'm pretty sure it's going
to be a good score. Yeah, I mean, I can't lie.
It's a terrific show. You know, it's charismatic
cast and offbeat charm made for a whimsical
mystery horror series and a frighteningly good
addition to the Sandman television universe.
I'm giving it four out of five stars. a fresh
rating on Rotten Tomatoes. It's not perfect.
There were, as I mentioned, some superfluous
characters and subplots that were never resolved,
but overall I had a blast with the show. It's
like my cup of tea. Two a tea. In the same
way that Doom Patrol was. Yeah, I would agree
that this season was not quite as good as Sandman
season one, but you know, just below that and
a really enjoyable time. I'm really hoping
we see these characters again, whether it be
in season two of the Sandman series or, you
know, a second season of this show. The best
thing that I can say about it is that, kind
of like my adventures with Superman, how I was
not excited to review that show and then ended
up being completely blown away by it, I feel
the same way about Dead Boy Detective Season
1. Yeah, I'm glad you saw the light. I'm glad
that DC stuff is impressing you. Yeah, DC's
been killing it with their television series
lately, for sure. I don't know what to say
to that. Why are you being so nice? It costs
nothing to pay a compliment. I still in my
heart know that Marvel's better in every way.
It's just that Charles and Nico have robed
off on you. I get it. I see. I strive to be
more like Charles in my daily life, so here's
me starting to do that. Awesome. Well, that
does it for this review. Let us know what you
thought about this show by writing to us at
dyna or by visiting us on Instagram, which
you can find a link to in our show notes or
by going to our website at dynamicduel.com.
And on our site, you can also find a link to
our Patreon page where you can join our dynamic
2.0 tier and chat with us and fellow listeners.
Our fantastic 4 tier, which gets you bonus
content each month. Our X-Horse tier. that makes
you an executive producer of this podcast or
our newest tier that lets you join our DynaMic
Podcast Network. Please don't forget to rate
the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser,
or on our website. In our next episode, we
will be doing a duel and lead up to our review
of the X-Men 97 animated series. We're going
to be pitting Amazo versus Bastion. Yeah, two
highly adaptable Android characters going up
against each other. It's going to be a lot of
fun. Get into that matchup as well as the review
of X-Men 97 the following week. But that does
it for this episode, we want to give a big
thanks to our executive producers Ken Johnson,
John Strosky, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Balcombe,
Miggy Mathengian, Brendan Estregard, Nathaniel
Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Austin Wazilowski, Adrian
Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Adam Spies, Andrew
Schunk, Dean Molesky, and Devin Davis for helping
make this podcast possible. We'll talk to you
guys next week. Up up and away, true believers.
I see dead people. on TV.