This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
Welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin brother, Marvelous
Joe. And in this episode, we are reviewing
the Amazon exclusive animated series, Batman
Caped Crusader. It was developed by Bruce Timm,
the very same Bruce Timm that created the Batman
cartoon series from the 90s that we all know
and love. Yeah, Jonathan and I are still in
what we call review hell because DC decided
to release a whole lot of summer projects within
the same like four week time span. Just bear
with us. We're almost through to the end, I
think with the Joker Follyado movie. Yeah,
see this kind of like, you know, Dante's Inferno
coming out through Paradiso and the Joker Follyado
film is Paradiso because it's gonna be so damn
good. Have you seen the reviews of it so far?
I don't trust those Rotten Tomatoes critics.
Those guys are assholes. Anyway, before we
get into our review of Batman Caves Crusader,
we're going to break down the comic book movie
news from the past week, including the Venom,
The Last Dance final trailer and the news that
Destin Daniel Crichton is in talks to direct
Spider-Man 4. As always, we list our segment
times in our episode description, so feel free
to check out the show notes if you want to
skip ahead to a particular topic. Our artificially
intelligent Duel simulator, AJ-9K, has a quick
message for our listeners, so listen up. Why
hello there, do you want even more from this
podcast? Then become a part of the dynamic Duel
community on Patreon, where you can choose
from three tiers. The dynamic two-oh tier gives
you access to our Discord chat server. The
fantastic four tier gives you two bonus episodes
each month, and the X-Force tier makes you
an executive producer of this show. Lastly,
The Diner Mike Podcast Network tier lets you
create your own podcast using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Jonny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and consultation,
and get you simulation results. Pitch the twins
your ideas via email at dynamicduelpodcast at
gmail.com. Check it out at patreon.com slash
dynamicduel. Pip pip cheerio. Thanks AJ9K and
thanks to everyone who supports the podcast.
Guys, be sure to tune into the other shows on
the DynaMic Podcast Network this week, including
Max Destruction, which pits your favorite action
heroes from film and television against each
other. This week, hosts Scotty and Gilly are
reviewing Terminator 2, Judgement Day. Great
film. One of the best films of all time. On
the Senjoworld podcast, host Zachary Hepburn
speculates on fights between fan favorite anime
and manga characters. This Thursday, Zach will
be fighting out who would win between Jotaro
from Jojo's Bizarre against Joker from Persona
5. That's a big one. On the Console Combat Podcast
hosts John and Dean simulate battles between
popular video game characters, and yesterday's
episode, they reviewed the Borderlands film.
Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link
in our show notes to listen to all of the shows
in the DynaMic Podcast Network. But with that
out of the way, quick to the No Prize! A No
Prize is an award Marvel used to give out to
fans. Our version, the Dynamic Duel No Prize,
is a digital award we post on Instagram for
the person that we feel gave the best answer
to our question of the week. Last week we asked,
who would you cast as Richard Ryder in the
Nova series and Hal Jordan and Jon Stewart in
the Lantern series? And we got a whole lot
of answers. Let's go ahead and run down our
honorable mentions as well as the No Prize
winner. Our first honorable mention goes to
Jose Marcial, who said, For Hal Jordan, I would
cast Josh Brolin since how Jordan is supposed
to be older and more gruff in this version.
And for Jon Stewart, I would cast David Johnson.
He played Andy in Alien Romulus. He's like
best part of that movie and he's a really good
actor just from that role alone. And what was
that other part of the question? So this may
have been recorded before we received news
that Josh Brolin has actually withdrawn his
name. from the running for the character of
Hal Jordan. So, you know, that's not gonna happen,
although it wouldn't have been a terrible choice.
As far as David Johnson goes, I have not seen
Alien Romulus, but I've heard amazing things
about the movie and his performance in particular.
So this answer gets me pretty excited. Yeah,
I was waiting to see Alien Romulus until I saw
Alien Covenant, because I haven't seen that
yet either. But I am super excited to see Alien
Romulus. It looks really damn good. Of course,
Jose did not get to an answer for Nova because
no one cares. Nobody got time for a Nova answer.
Actually, a lot of the callers this week didn't
answer the full question with all three characters,
Jon Stewart, Hal Jordan, and Richard Ryder.
Only a few of them did, but not our next honorable
mention, Miggy Mathingian, who said, Hey, what's
up guys, this is Miggy. And even though it
might be confusing for general audiences, from
the short list, I would pick Chris Pine to
play Hal Jordan. And then the Hollywood Reporter
said that they would want a newer actor, younger
actor to play John Stewart. So I would go with
Malachi Kirby. Even though I haven't seen him
play in anything, I've seen that he is like
an award winning actor. So, and I think he's
like a lesser known name. So yeah, Chris Pine
and Malachi Kirby. Yeah. Miggi's concern is
that audiences might find it confusing to see
Chris Pine as Hal Jordan, considering he was
very prominently Steve Trevor. in the Wonder
Woman films. That said, I think he would make
a great, damn near perfect Hal Jordan. The guy
is a great actor, and you know, we've already
seen that he could pull off the role of brave
pilot. Yeah, I'm not sure how his role as Hal
Jordan would differ too much from Steve Trevor
from the Wonder Woman films, but I really like
the answer of Malachi Kirby as Jon Stewart.
In fact, I'm going to say don't get him for
Jon Stewart and let's get him for the next Black
Panther. Because... Dude could totally nail
that role. Well too bad, cause Team DC already
called dibs. Great answer, Miggy. Our next
honorable mention goes to Daniel Alonso, who
said, All right, I'm going to start making
an effort to send a message in every week because
y'all's new stuff is also great. So I'm gonna
start off with a co-co-combo and answer last
week's. My favorite episode is Hit Monkey versus
Gleek, funniest shit so far. Casting for Hal
Jordan, I would go with Bradley Cooper. for
Richard Rider, I would do Liam Hemsworth. And
bonus, I would have cast Michael Fassbender
as Dr. Doom. I believe he could have brought
the gravitas that the role needed. All right,
yeah, Daniel gave a few more answers than we
asked. He also answered last week's question
of, what's your favorite episode of Dynamic
Duel? Thank you for doing that. I really like
his answer of Bradley Cooper for Hal Jordan,
though. Yeah, absolutely. I've always wanted
to see Bradley Cooper take on a superhero role,
and... To me, Hal Jordan makes the most sense
for him. I know he's an actor who really likes
to stretch his craft, so I'm not sure how attracted
to that role he would be, but he would be amazing
in it, absolutely. He would actually be my
number one pick, I think. My number one dream
casting, for sure. And Liam Hemsworth for Richard
Ryder, I can see it working, you know, he looks
awful lot like his brother Chris Hemsworth,
who plays Thor, but I don't think that's too
big of an issue, they can make their Richard
Ryder look a little bit different by dying his
hair or something. I don't know. but he definitely
looks like Richard Ryder. So yeah, it could
totally work. Yeah, I mean, as long as you
keep Thor with a beard and Richard Ryder without
a beard, it's fine. It works out. Yeah, I don't
think you could pull off the Nova helmet with
a beard. I don't think, which makes me sad
because now I feel like I can never be Nova.
You never could. We're gonna give a special
thanks to Mason Thompson and Scott Camacho for
calling in and leaving their answers. Scotty.
your idea of casting Robert Downey Jr. as Richard
Ryder was hilarious. I laughed my ass off.
But the winner of this week's No Prize is Cyrus
Moore, who said, Hey guys, Cyrus Moore here.
So the perfect DC lanterns casting for Hal Jordan
is Bradley Cooper, Shamar Moore for Jon Stewart,
and I don't really know the Nova Corps very
well, but I feel like Logan Lerman from The
Maze Runner would make a pretty good Nova Corps
member for Richard Ryder. But yeah, Bradley
Cooper and Shamar Moore would be perfect choices
to be lanterns. Thank you guys. Yeah, again,
Bradley Cooper as Hal Jordan is the best possible
outcome. Shamar Moore would actually make a
perfect Jon Stewart if he was younger, I think.
Shamar Moore, I think, has aged out of that
role. But considering he had a long running
role on the show, Criminal Minds. where he's
kind of done this whole true detective style
thing, which is what the lantern show is being
compared to. Yeah, he would be great. And then
Logan Lerman as Richard Ryder. I actually like
this casting the best. Logan Lerman was actually
not in the Maze Runner movie. That was Daniel
O'Brien. Logan Lerman was Percy Jackson. He
was in those films. But I remember his name
was tossed around for Spider-Man back when they
were casting for Spider-Man Homecoming and
Tom Holland ended up getting the role. But I
think that Logan Lerman definitely looks like
Richard Rider from the comics and could totally
pull it off. And the guy could act as well,
like I remember seeing him in the Noah movie.
And he did a fantastic job. But great answer,
Cyrus Moore, you win this week's No Prize. If
you the listener want a shot at winning your
own No Prize, stay tuned to later on in this
episode when we'll be asking another question
of the week. And now that that's done, onto
the news!
This past week we got the final trailer for
the Venom, the last dance movie that's coming
out in October. It is the second major trailer
that we've gotten for this film. And I have
to say that actually this trailer impressed
me a whole lot more than the first one. I think
the first one I was being really whiny about
it because I hate the title of the film and
we weren't quite sure what was going on with
the story. But you throw null in there and
you got me hooked my friend. As soon as I saw
that the main bad guy of this movie was not
going to be Chiwetel Isheophore's Orwell Taylor,
and that it was going to be null, I was blown
away. That was the best case scenario. Yeah,
all of a sudden the movie seems almost worth
it. I'm not going to lie. I actually enjoyed
this trailer. Like I did not expect to, but
I don't know what it was. Just I don't know
the music and just the relationship between
the two characters. I just found it charming.
I'm trying really hard not to get excited.
at all for this movie because I don't want to
be let down considering it's Sony who's making
the film. But this was a good trailer. Well,
we can all agree that Venom Let There Be Carnage
sucked balls, right? It really sucked. The first
Venom movie was not great, but it was novel
for the way it portrayed the Eddie Brock Venom
relationship. The relationship between those
two characters is the best thing about this
entire franchise. And the way the third trailer
really sold the perhaps culmination of that
relationship I thought was really enticing.
I want to see how this story might end, if it
does. I mean, like, both of the trailers that
came out for this film have heavily alluded
to the idea of Eddie Brock or Venom sacrificing
themselves for the other. I'm totally not sold
that that's gonna happen, but it's possible.
You know, Tom Hardy may in fact want to pull
a Logan and go out in style, you know, but
I'm still really hoping that somehow... Venom
ends up in a Spider-Man movie or vice versa.
And, you know, not counting the stupid post
credit stuff from No Way Home. But yeah, Null
is going to be in this film. And for those of
you who may not know who he is, he is the primordial
deity who created the symbiotes. And he is a
total badass. He was the main villain in the
King and Black storyline from the comics, which
was a great run. It was a great story. I highly
suggest reading it. But he's a badass like.
on the same level as Thanos. Like it took every
single Marvel hero on Earth to defeat this guy.
So it'll be interesting to see him going up
against Venom in this film. Apparently he is
the one that the symbiotes that came to Earth
in the first movie were escaping from and he
is the one who sends the xenophages down to
Earth. Those are the creatures that attack Venom
on the plane at the beginning of this trailer.
But does Null ever come to Earth in the comics?
He does, yeah, but they're probably going to
have to nerf him a little bit. because he's
insanely powerful. Like he could kill Celestials,
if you guys remember Celestials from the Eternals
movie. And here he's only going up against
Venom. So they're probably gonna have to nerf
him, which is a shame, but just to see him
on screen will be worth it, I think. We don't
know who's playing Null as of yet. There are
some rumors going around that maybe Reese Ifans
is gonna play him. And we do see Reese later
on in this trailer, which is super confusing
because the actor played Kurt Connors, the
Lizard. in the amazing Spider-Man franchise.
So it's weird to see him in this movie. Yeah,
considering that Reese Ifans was recently seen
in a MCU Spider-Man movie, I doubt that's the
actor that's playing Null. Yeah. A lot of this
movie takes place in Las Vegas. I bet you that's
where the climax of the film is going to be.
And there's this weird scene where Eddie and
Venom steal a disguise from some guy wearing
a suit. I don't know what's going on here in
the scene. It almost looks like Eddie pees on
him before Venom slaps the shit out of him.
The guy pees on Eddie. Is that what happens?
Yeah. Who the hell does that? That's so fucking
weird. I hate that. Right. But also I hate it
because Venom can change his appearance to
match other clothing anyway. So why do they
need to steal this guy's clothes? Doesn't make
sense. Maybe they just stole a key or something
like that. There was a whole section here where
Venom is gambling and discovers the joys of.
gambling and the addictive quality to it that
I didn't need in a trailer. We'll say that could
have been a funny and I put funny in quotes,
gag for the movie. Didn't need to be in the
trailer. Just wasted time. No, it was dumb.
I never related to that feeling to begin with.
Anytime I put money in a slot machine, it just
goes right away. And I'm like, Oh, this is like,
fuck. But no, I mean, the film, I think shows
promise the inclusion of Null, the relationship
between Eddie and Venom. I think that all looks
fantastic. Those things alone are propping up
my expectations for this film. I'm hoping at
least it'll be better than Venom Let There Be
Carnage, and I'm hoping it's as good as the
first Venom film. But we'll find out in just
over a month when this movie comes out on October
25th. But with this trailer teasing that this
may be the last appearance of Venom, that brings
us to our question of the week.
Do you think this should or shouldn't be Eddie
Brock's and Venom's last appearance in Sony's
Spider-Man universe, and why? Record your answer
at dynamicduel.com by clicking on the red microphone
button in the bottom right hand corner of the
screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long, and don't forget to leave your name in
case we include you on the podcast. We'll pick
our favorite answer, and award that person
a dynamic duel no prize that we'll post to Instagram.
Be sure to answer before September 21st. But
speaking of the Sony Spider-Man universe, we
also learned this past week that Destin Daniel
Cretton is in talks to direct Spider-Man 4.
Now Destin Daniel Cretton is the director behind
the Shang-Chi and the Legend of the Ten Rings
film and the upcoming Wonder Man series. And
Marvel loves this guy. He's a fantastic director.
I really loved the Shang-Chi film. And I'm
actually really excited about this news because
I think he can knock Spider-Man 4 out of the
park. The one downside to this is that it means
that a Shang-Chi sequel is likely going to
be put on a back burner, which breaks my heart
because that franchise deserves better. Yeah,
I'm actually really surprised we haven't received
a Shang-Chi sequel yet. I am happy for Destin
Daniel Cretton though, considering the fact
that he was kicked off the upcoming Avengers
movie. This is not a terrible consolation. No,
you're absolutely right. Now- Shang-Chi the
character was rumored to play a heavy part in
the King Dynasty film back when that was a
thing. Ever since the conviction of Jonathan
Majors and his subsequent firing from Marvel
Studios, you know, they had to rework Avengers
the King Dynasty into Avengers Doomsday. And
it's not quite sure if Shang-Chi is still going
to play a prominent role within that film because
Destin Daniel Cretton was originally attached
to direct the King Dynasty and it was stated
that the film was going to be a quasi-sequel
for Shang-Chi, which is why they hadn't made
a whole lot of movement on a Shang-Chi sequel.
So now, because reports are saying that the
Spider-Man movie is being fast-tracked, like
they're hoping to write the film and start
shooting it as early as next year, Destin Daniel
Cran is not going to be able to get to Shang-Chi
for a while. My hope is that maybe they'll be
able to squeeze Shang-Chi into the Spider-Man
4 film. since those characters have teamed up
in the comics before, and since the MCU Spider-Man
franchise has often included cameos from other
MCU heroes, such as Iron Man in Homecoming,
Nick Fury in Far From Home, and Doctor Strange
in No Way Home. Yeah, that'd be cool to get
like a different cameo for each Spider-Man movie,
I like that. Yeah, the Spider-Man movies could
almost be treated like the Marvel team-up comic
book series, which Spider-Man was often the
star teaming up with other. lesser known characters.
One of our executive producers, Devin Davis,
had the idea that Spider-Man 4 would largely
focus on the Black Cat storyline since reports
are also saying that Zendaya is not going to
have a huge role in Spider-Man 4, which makes
sense considering where they left the franchise
off in No Way Home. And I think introducing
Black Cat is the next logical step for the franchise.
Devin Davis suggested that could mean that
she's working for Kingpin and then you could
have Daredevil be the superhero team up and
I think I like that idea even more. So everything's
just looking bad for Shang-Chi. I feel bad
for the actor Simu Liu because he was a great
Shang-Chi and I feel like he deserves better
than this deal that he's getting. Maybe by the
time they do make a Shang-Chi sequel, China
will have calmed the F down and let that film
be released in their country. We'll see. One
can only hope.
That is it for all the news for this week, now
let's move on to the main event of this episode
when we review the Amazon exclusive DC animated
series, Batman Caped Crusader Season 1.
Okay, Batman Kid Crusader is a new animated
series developed by Bruce Timm and produced
by J.J. Abrams and Matt Reeves. It is a reimagining
of sorts of Bruce Timm's beloved animated series
that us 90s kids used to watch every day after
school and on Saturday mornings. This series,
however, is unhindered by concerns over network
marketability, allowing for a more mature psychological
and progressive take. on the familiar characters
within the Batman mythos. And while I'd hesitate
to say it's an improvement upon the 90s series
in the same way that the recent X-Men 97 series
was over that childhood favorite, Caped Crusader's
retro aesthetics and intriguing interpretations
do make it a worthwhile and standout addition
to Batman's vast library of animated content.
Since the primary appeal of the series really
is how it interprets its characters, If you
haven't seen the show and want to avoid spoilers,
stop listening now. Watch the show, then come
back and listen to our thoughts because we will
be delving into spoilers. Yeah, anyone who
was a fan of the 90s Batman, the animated series
cartoon, I think owes it to themselves to check
this show out. But I think it goes even harder
into the hardboiled elements of the Batman
comics when they first came out. Oh absolutely,
for sure. It's much more in that classic noir
style. It's very hard boiled, very stripped
down, very classic Batman, which is nice. Now
I wouldn't say this is a must-see Batman series
though. The main appeal of it isn't necessarily
Batman, but the creators behind the show. From
Bruce Timm's classic design and strong storytelling
sense, to J.J. Abrams' talent for bringing new
life to established properties, to Matt Reeves'
gritty and realistic understanding of the character
evidenced in his 2022 film, The Batman, to
the involvement of some of the comic industry's
best writers in Ed Brubaker and Greg Rucka.
Fans knew this was going to be something special,
going all the way back to 2014's Strange Days
animated short that Bruce Timm made for Batman's
75th anniversary, which served as a launchpad
for this series' visual aesthetic. Can I just
say that when I saw the names behind the show,
because I had no idea, right? I knew that Bruce
Timm was behind the show, but I didn't know
that Matt Reeves was producing. I think I knew
that JJ Abrams was producing, but that's still
a huge name to see for this cartoon. And then
all of a sudden I saw Ed Brubaker and Greg
Rucka, and I'm like, what the fuck is this?
Is this gonna be the best show of all time?
Right? Man, I was truly impressed by the names
behind this series. 110%. I'd go so far as
to say that between the creators involved and
the success of X-Men 97 and my excitement over
the show's mid-20th century design approach,
I thought this show was going to be the ultimate
Batman series, and this is probably a solid
example of why you should temper your expectations
going into any project involving a character
that's near and dear to your heart. It was
just so d- different, not in a bad way, just
a mildly unsatisfactory way. A way I should
have seen coming when they started revealing
things like their new take on Harley Quinn.
I didn't realize this show was going to be as
Elseworlds, for lack of a better word, as it
was. Yeah, they changed a lot of things, right?
For better or for worse, I didn't mind a lot
of the changes they had here, but I think we
could both agree that they fucked up the Penguin.
You know, honestly? I did not hate their take
on the penguin. I thought I was going to. Some
of the new takes that they did on the characters
that could be considered controversial because
they race bent or gender bent the characters
like Barbara Gordon or the penguin, I didn't
mind. I was surprised I didn't hate Oswalda
the female penguin because it was well done,
I thought. That question of why was pretty much
cast aside once I understood the Elseworlds
vibe of the show. I tend to be a little bit
more forgiving of how characters are handled.
and else world stories like the doom that came
to Gotham or Red Sun, because I understand
it's what if type nature. As a general rule,
I don't mind race bending or gender bending
as long as, you know, they're true to the character.
But Oswalda Cobblepot was nothing like the
Penguin as any of us know. It was almost an
entirely different character. She was like
a big mama type mobster. Yeah, I've never seen
the Penguin do a song and dance number at the
Iceberg Lounge. That was pretty wild. Cabaret
number. Oh, God. I bleach. But you know, expectations
aside, I thought the show did a terrific job
at for the most part reintroducing us to familiar
characters episode by episode. I was 100% tuned
in to each episode and eager for the next one
in the same way I used to be watching the 90s
cartoon as a kid. I love film noir detective
stories. I love mid 20th century design. I love
dark psychological examinations of characters.
So yeah, this show hooked me. I watched the
entire thing in less than 24 hours. And like
I said, I like what they did with a lot of the
characters. Not all of it worked like I would
say on Amada Pia or the Robin characters, but
a lot of them like Clayface or Nocturna or
the Gentleman Ghost felt like they came straight
out of a Tales from the Crypt horror-esque
Elseworlds version of the DC universe. And keeping
your eye out for obscure cameos from characters
like Jim Corrigan or Floyd
for sure. I really liked the anthological take
on this. While the series wasn't entirely anthological
because you had the Harvey Dent through line,
a lot of these episodes were one-offs. Yeah,
that's one thing I really liked about the old
90s cartoon was its anthological nature. For
the most part, every episode Batman would tackle
a new villain or a new conflict that would
get wrapped up by the end of the episode. And
while this series did have some overarching
conflicts, It was more anthological than many
current shows. I'll always argue that long-form
storytelling is superior, and one of the reasons
I love the serialized nature of comic books.
But there's something to be said for short,
quick stories as well. And this show definitely
satisfied a nostalgic itch that I hadn't realized
I had. I mentioned that it was kind of fun
looking out for obscure characters in this season.
That said, I would have much rather seen new
takes on less obscure characters because...
I feel like those are kind of easy. I was much
more impressed by this new take on Harley Quinn
than I was on, say, Gentleman Ghost. I think
it would have been much more of a challenge
to come up with psychological rich takes on
characters like Poison Ivy or Mr. Freeze. So
I'm looking forward to seeing them in subsequent
seasons, if they make them, you know, along
with the Joker, who at the end of this season
was teased in a man- manner, which...
Yes, please. Back when Batman Begins came out,
which was a much more grounded, gritty take
on the character in a way that audiences weren't
used to seeing because we were used to like
the Schumacher films and stuff like that. Grounding
things in reality kind of became popular for
a while. The ideas were if you take the character
and you remove the fantastical elements and
imagine what it would be like if this thing
actually existed in reality, that's what they
did on this Caped Crusader show for the most
part. minus the supernatural episodes with
the gentlemen ghost and the carnival and things
like that. It was really cool to see those
ideas take shape in a more grounded, gritty
way. Because it totally fits the world of Batman.
And yeah, I would love to see how they would
approach more fantastical characters like Poison
Ivy, like Mr. Freeze. I think that would be
really neat. Yeah, I really hope they do more
seasons of this show because that would be amazing
to see. Now listeners of this podcast may have
heard me complain about Bruce Tim's figure design.
I praised the Tomorrowverse for moving away
from that Bruce Tim style and showing us something
less templated than decades past. This show
moves back toward that style, though it does
mix it up a little bit more than in the past.
I actually didn't need chunkier versions of
characters like Renee Montoya or Harley Quinn.
It literally looked like they just took the
female character model and increased the width.
Yeah, in a nostalgic way. But, you know, everything
just felt a little bit cleaner and more varied
and a little bit more modern, too. I would definitely
agree that it looked cleaner. I thought it
actually looked a little bit older in terms
of the design than the 90s series. Like the
90s series had much more streamlined buildings,
I felt. And this one was a little bit more
vintage, I would say. Honestly, you know, I'm
spoiled after Suicide Squad, Isekai. Again,
as we mentioned in that review, that was probably
the best animated work out of any animated
DC project ever. So to go from that to this
was like, oh, more Bruce Tim. Yay. But I've
mentioned characters a lot. Let's go ahead and
move into our character breakdown, starting
with Batman Bruce Wayne. He was voiced by Hamish
Linklater, known for his work on the new adventures
of Old Christine, Legion, Midnight Mass and
Manhunt. Don't think the dichotomy between
his Bruce Wayne and Batman voice was as successful
as Kevin Conroy. I didn't think it was terrible
either. His Batman voice sounded to me like
a mixture between Kevin Conroy's authoritative
approach and Christian Bale's growl. He did
a fantastic job. Now, most Batman animated
voice actors are largely doing a Kevin Conroy
impression and this is no exception. I do think
to that end, I... prefer other animated voices
like what Jensen Ackles did in the Tomorrowverse.
Yeah, I would agree. But this was entirely passable.
I was impressed by the job that Hamish Linklater
was able to do. I'd say like after Conroy, he's
my third or fourth favorite Batman voice. Yeah,
that sounds about right. I do think that Hamish
Linklater would make a fantastic live-action
Batman, considering the guy's a pretty good
actor. I would have much rather seen him as
Bruce Wayne than fucking Ian Glenn in the Titan
series. Hahaha, yeah. It's occasionally a challenge
for writers to make Batman stand out against,
arguably, literature's most intriguing and
colorful rogues gallery. This series definitely
suffers on that front. I felt like Batman actually
got less screen time in each episode than I
thought he would, though honestly, maybe about
the same amount as the 90s cartoon. I'm not
100% on that. When he did appear though, they
made the most of his appearances, as stripped
down as the character was for the show. He
wasn't big on martial arts, but he had a fair
number of gadgets and it was a decent showcase
for his detective work. Well, I feel like they
could have maybe take it away from some of
the screen time that the villains got each episode
in order to show more of his detective work
processes. Absolutely, yeah, they could have
100%. The show hints that Bruce Wayne may be
as insane as his villains, you know, focused
less on justice and more on punishing criminals.
As evidenced, when he lied to the police as
a kid saying he didn't see the face of the
man who killed his parents. Followed by him
appearing in Alfred's room that night telling
him that Gotham's criminals are all going to
suffer. I was like, dang! Get this kid a therapist.
Exactly. But I also liked that approach for
the character. Like, Batman should be psychologically
dark and traumatized. It was actually kind of
fascinating to me that Bruce Wayne didn't blink
once this entire show. Wait, what? Really? Yeah.
Oh, creepy. Super, actually. Um, but I did
like how this series showed that Bruce Wayne
is doing something to help Gotham besides punish
criminals though, like the new housing development
just outside the city, you know, it kind of
addresses the criticism that SNL made that he
just beats up poor people. Now he comes into
conflict with Alfred consistently throughout
the show, calling him Pennyworth and talking
back to him like a teenager would, Bruce is
definitely an angry person in the show. But
by the end of the season, he comes to realize
how much Alfred means to him and refers to
him as Alfred for the first time. Speaking of
Alfred Pennyworth, he was voiced by Jason Watkins,
who's a British television actor. I thought
he did a great job acting as a demure Alfred,
who seems to be guilt-driven in the series into
being less of a father figure, as he's typically
depicted, and more of an enabler, like he just
can't say no to Bruce. It's a fresh take on
Alfred. and not one that I hated by any means,
because I can see it making sense for the character.
And he was still a good man and a good example,
ultimately, for Bruce. He was still trying
to be as conscious. Alfred's always the one
trying to pull back Batman from the brink of
the abyss. But here, with how early Bruce Wayne
started showing signs of psychosis, you would
think that Alfred should have done a better
job of getting this kid some help. Because
he seemed afraid, honestly, of Bruce Wayne.
Yeah. Right. I thought the same thing. Alright,
tackling Commissioner James Gordon and Barbara
Gordon simultaneously, they were voiced by
Eric Morgan Stewart and Crystal Joy Brown respectively.
Barbara Gordon was reimagined as a lawyer for
this series, which I thought was a brilliant
way to keep her story tied into her father's
and Harvey Dent's. You know, Barbara is an idealist,
which often brings her into conflict with Commissioner
Gordon, who's more of a cynic, but one still
trying to help the city. Together, They make
a pretty great pair, I thought, and I can't
wait to see how Barbara evolves into a costumed
crime fighter like Batman. If they decide to
go that route. Right. Yeah, they may not. Since
this is still early days for Batman, he and
Commissioner Gordon aren't allies at the start
of the show. But as the season progresses, Commissioner
Gordon realizes that Batman is trying to help,
particularly when they worked together to save
kids from a burning apartment building, which
was one of my favorite episodes in the series.
Yeah, I thought this is one of the most organic
ways that I've seen them build up the Commissioner
Gordon Batman relationship outside of like
Batman Year One, which was a great story. Yeah.
But like even in the Batman movie, Commissioner
Gordon and Batman are already copacetic from
the get go, right? Right. It's nice to have
this long running narrative where you see that
relationship of trust slowly develop. I thought
it was really well done here. Yeah, I would
say it was better done here than it was in,
you know, even Batman Begins. much more organic,
like you said. Moving on to the last character
I'm going to go over, Renee Montoya. She was
voiced by Michelle C. Bonilla. She does a lot
of the heavy lifting when it comes to detective
work for the GCPD. I actually really liked
how good of a detective she was shown to be,
you know, just by asking the right questions.
She proves herself more and more as the season
progresses, confirming the trust that Commissioner
Gordon put on her to be a leader within the
corrupt police department. I actually thought
that by introducing her in the Clayface episode,
that they were going to lead her into using
some of the makeup putty to begin her like faceless
career as the question, but that ended up not
being the case. That would have been cool though.
That would have been really cool.
fantasies collide and heroes clash, one podcast
network rises above the rest. Prepare yourself
for the ultimate showdowns in comic books, video
games, movies, and anime. The Dynomic Podcast
Network presents Console Combat, where video
game legends brawl every Monday. Comic Book
Titans smash every Tuesday. Max Destruction,
where TV and action heroes battle every Wednesday.
And Sendro World, where anime champions clash
every Thursday. Join us as we speculate on
the matches and armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge victorious.
Visit dynamicpodcast.com where we settle the
debate and settle the score.
Moving on to the story highlights, episode 1
was titled In Treacherous Waters. Oswalda Cobblepot,
owner and singer of the Iceberg Lounge, has
been making a name for herself in Gotham City's
criminal underworld as the Penguin while trying
to eliminate her mob boss rival Rupert Thorne
by destroying his organization's warehouses.
However, Thorne survives with help from a leak
in her circle. Believing it is her youngest
son, Eren, Oswalda kills him. However, her
eldest son, and the real source, Ronald, seeks
out Gotham City's police department, Commissioner
James Gordon, for protection. With help from
Jim's daughter Barbara Gordon and a mysterious
vigilante called the Batman, Ronald safely reaches
the GCPD, but Aswalda launches a missile to
destroy the police station. Unbeknownst to her,
the station is evacuated before it is destroyed.
Batman successfully captures Aswalda, but realizes
later that in doing so, he left a power vacuum
in Gotham's underworld for Thorne to fill. This
was a great setup to the series, you know,
with the whole power vacuum angle and the destruction
of the GCPD headquarters. I mean, it wasn't
too much of a issue in such like episodes, but
I thought that it was a really good setup.
For sure. Yeah, I thought this was a great episode,
a great introduction to Batman when we first
see him interrogating that guy over the train
tracks. Oh, yeah. I thought it was a perfect
Batman moment, honestly. And I thought to myself,
is 1940s Batman peak Batman? when he's able
to operate freely in this very pulpy style?
Uh, you know, honestly, in my opinion, and
this may be a controversial opinion, 1940s Batman,
Superman, Wonder Woman, that's all peak those
characters. Really? Explain. I feel like those
are like the truest essence of those characters.
They kind of get muddled down by continuity
and stuff in later decades. But if you go back
to like the spirit of the characters as they
were first conceived, I think that is the best
version of them. I think you could say that
for a lot of characters actually, even over
at Marvel. As the years go on and the characters
evolve over time, I think the expectation from
a lot of fans is that they always still revert
to their roots. And it's always nice when characters
are brought back to what made them who they
are. Yeah, I mean, DC characters are so pure
in, you know, there's symbolism and their archetype
that Things don't really make sense in a postmodern
world. These characters come from a different
era. And so you see comics like Watchmen kind
of making fun of the very notion of the superhero.
But back then, it made sense. The next episode
was titled, And Be a Villain. GCPD detective
Renee Montoya is assigned to locate missing
actress Yvonne Francis. Following a failed interrogation
of Bruce Wayne, she investigates the film studio.
where she learns Francis's fellow actor Basil
Carlo may have been lying about his alibi.
However, he is seemingly murdered before she
can confirm. Upon further investigation, she
learns Carlo was ashamed of his face, which
led him to be typecasted and Francis rejecting
his advances. Ultimately, he used an experimental
serum to make his face more malleable. Montoya
and Batman eventually stumble across Carlo,
who faked his death and kidnapped Francis out
of a desire to play a villain for real. Montoya
rescues Francis while Batman defeats Carlo
and disappears before Montoya can apprehend
him. Such a fantastic take on the character
of Clayface. I feel like, you know, Clayface
in recent years has really had an opportunity
to shine in shows like Harley Quinn or Suicide
Squad Isekai. But this is probably hands down
my favorite version of the character. Taking
like a Boris Karloff approach to Basil Carlo
Clayface was pure genius. Well, that's really
in keeping with his original story in the comic
books, right? Very true. In the comics, Clayface
wasn't like this huge turd monster. He was
actually just a serial killer who disguised
his face. This version of the character, I
think, was the best of both worlds, though.
For sure. It is weird, though, seeing this
version of Clayface coming off of the back of
Suicide Squad Isakai. Yeah. Who was a very,
very different version of Clayface. Well, from
any media, to be fair. It's just interesting,
I guess, how adaptable the character can be,
which I guess is not so surprising because
he is clayface. He is adaptable, if anything.
Episode 3 was titled, Kiss of the Catwoman.
At a museum displaying Gotham's elite jewels,
Bruce encounters an heiress named Selena Kyle,
who has an interest in his late mother Martha
Wayne's pearls. He is later ordered to attend
a month of therapy with Dr. Harleen Quinzel
after assaulting a patron who insulted his
parents. Kyle resorts to jewel theft after being
left in debt, adopting the Catwoman persona.
After being caught and outed by Batman, she
takes inspiration from him by upgrading her
car and using gadgets before Gotham's District
Attorney Harvey Dent bails her out, allowing
her to resume her crime spree. Deducing Kyle
will try and steal Martha's pearls, Bruce orders
the museum to close early to luring Catwoman,
who is eventually caught once more and left
destitute upon learning her maid Greta. sold
her belongings and refuses to bail her out.
I loved Greta. I loved the idea of Catwoman
having a butler like Alfred who's, you know,
kind of petty. That was great. This was a fantastic
episode. I really liked Christina Ricci's performance
as Catwoman as well. The character design was
very much in keeping with her first appearance
in the comics and While there wasn't like enough
romantic tension, I think, between the two,
I still really liked the moments that they shared
together. Now, it was actually the first appearance
because the first appearance of Catwoman wore
an actual like cat's furry face, but it was
definitely inspired by early versions of the
character. It's not a design that I love, but
it works within this world. Right. Like it doesn't
make sense for her to wear high heels and a
dress. Right. Or a cape. That's bizarre. I did
like that she was very heavily inspired by
Batman though. It was a great version of the
character. Episode 4 was titled The Night of
the Hunters. After Mayor Jessup orders the creation
of a task force to apprehend Batman, Gordon
chooses Montoya to run it. Using Dr. Quinzel's
insights, corrupt GCPD detectives Harvey Bullock
and Arnold Flass use a masked criminal called
Firebug as bait to lure out Batman. As part
of their plan, they let Firebug go to start
a fire. Batman arrives to rescue civilians,
evading corrupt SWAT officers led by Bullock
and Flass in the process. As Bullock and Flass
kill Firebug to cover their tracks, Batman reluctantly
works with Jim, who disapproves of the task
force's methods to save the remaining civilians.
Afterward, Batman disappears once more. Bullock
and Flass are hailed as heroes by Jessup and
put in charge of the Batman task force with
Jim narrowly keeping his job. I loved this episode.
I thought it was a fantastic episode showing
the corruption of the GCPD, which isn't explored
enough in a lot of media, I feel like, but
this show handled it perfectly. Oh yeah. Flash
and Bullock were probably bigger bastards in
this show than they've been in anything else
I've ever seen them in. Yeah, they were big
time jerks here. It was surprising to me how
much this show could get away with. People
were actually shot, killed and stuff like that.
You couldn't get away with stuff like that
in the 90s on television. But here it totally
worked. It's much more mature. And I thought
that made it a lot more interesting. Well, I
realized that from the first episode when Oswaldo
killed one of her sons and then like you saw
his body as a skeleton coming out of the trunk
later. That's right. Like this is pulpy as hell.
And I'm here for it. Oh, totally. We've been
going to episode five. It was titled The Stress
of Her Regard. After several wealthy businessmen
abruptly donate their fortunes to charity and
go missing. Barbara suspects their physician
and her friend, Dr. Quinzel, is involved. In
reality, Quinzel has adopted the jester-like
persona of Harley Quinn and is subjugating the
businessman to immense torture in an attempt
to correct their minds and behavior. Barbara
and Batman track her to the basement of one
of her patients, where the latter is overpowered
and knocked unconscious before the house is
rigged to detonate. Nonetheless, Batman recovers
and saves Barbara, though he fails to save
Quinzel from falling to her apparent death.
Having survived, however, Quinzel calls Montoya
to call off a date they had planned and tell
her that she is temporarily leaving Gotham.
Now, initially I was rejecting this take on
Harley Quinn. Like, I somewhat liked the idea
that she was the resident psychiatrist for the
city as opposed to a doctor at Arkham Asylum.
But I didn't like the idea of Harley Quinn not
having the Joker. But by this episode, I was
sold on the idea. The idea that the psychiatrist
was going beyond helping people who were coming
to her and torturing them was amazing. It was
brilliant, I thought. And the fact that she
kind of justified it and that they felt like
they were kings and that she was bringing them
down as the Jester, making them see the error
of their ways was pretty damn good. It was
solid as hell. As a concept, if you were ever
going to do Harley Quinn without the Joker,
this is exactly how you do it. This is how you
get her motivations, her modus operandi. Everything
about it was so interesting. We've seen lots
of different versions of Harley Quinn by this
point. But this version is something that I
think even Kelly Kuoku's Harley Quinn could
take notes from. Yeah. Because there's a lot
to unpack here. And they only just scratch
the surface of what this Harley Quinn could
be in this show. I did hate the fact that Batman
was essentially taken out by a dude in a diaper
in this series. I was like, no way. That's
not going to happen. That's dumb. But for the
most part, I really liked this episode. The
Lesbian Kiss kind of took me back, given the
1940s setting, 1950s setting, because it was
done out in public. Right. That was just something
I was like, OK, so apparently this Elseworld
story was just a much more progressive reality
for the time. It was one of the things that
I think stood out in terms of all the progressive
changes that they made for the show. Yeah,
clearly. And again, something you definitely
couldn't get away with on Saturday mornings,
kids television when we were growing up. Right.
Episode 6 was titled Night Ride. When a mysterious
ghost on horseback emerges to rob Gotham's working
class, Dent's mayoral election campaign is
threatened due to the robberies happening on
his watch. He is offered a donation from Thorne,
but is hesitant to accept it. Meanwhile, Batman
struggles to fight the ghost directly. Deducing
that it is the spirit of Jim Craddock, the gambling
addicted former owner of an old property that
Bruce's friend Lucius Fox recently bought, he
gains help from Linton Midnight, Papa Midnight,
who advises him to sacrifice the old property's
deed and the blood of a nobleman to draw out
Craddock. Though Craddock possesses Batman's
butler, Alfred Pennyworth, Batman completes
the ritual using Alfred's blood and traps Craddock
in a vial. He subsequently gives it to Midnight
while Dent accepts Thorne's donation. It was
really cool to see Papa Midnight in this episode.
There are any number of magicians that could
have been included in the show, and Papa Midnight
would not have been near the top of my list
of who would have shown up. But I thought it
was really cool that he did. Yeah, in the 90s
cartoon, we saw Jason Blood appear in the Batman
series. And I think it was Dr. Fate who appeared
in the Superman series. I thought it was going
to be one of those. I was definitely surprised
by Papa Midnight. but it was also really cool
to see such an obscure character make an appearance
in the show. Moving on to episode 7, titled
Moving Target. Jim fears that someone put a
bounty on his head after assassins such as
Floyd Lawton and Anomatopeia come to Gotham,
and the former almost succeeds at killing him.
He reluctantly agrees to be escorted to a safe
house at Wayne Gardens, but Anomatopeia's group
finds them. Meanwhile, Batman learns the hit
was placed by a Blackgate penitentiary inmate
named Muller, and follows Jim's detail. Narrowly
fending off the assassins, Berman reveals to
Jim while getting the contract canceled, he
discovered Barbara is the true target. Officer
Jim Corrigan attempts to claim the bounty for
himself, but is disarmed by Jim and arrested.
Mueller later reveals he ordered the hit because
he feels he deserves better prison accommodations.
This was a fantastic episode, another one of
my favorite episodes, very focused on- Jim
Gordon and Barbara Gordon and their relationship,
which I thought was great. I didn't love on
a monopoeia here. He doesn't make sense to me
as like a gang leader. He wouldn't be able
to order anybody around. They would just see
him as a joke. Exactly. His voice didn't work
for me, too. Like it was too raspy and stuff
like that. Like whenever I read on a monopoeia
his voice in the books, I always thought of
it as more like a Hannibal Lecter type voice.
Yeah. something like James Spader's Ultron or
something like that. But here he sounded like
Bender from Futurama or something like that.
It just did not work. I did think it was cool
that they had Jim Corrigan on the GCPD. I was
not expecting him. I actually thought he was
going to die at the very end of this episode
and somehow be reborn as the specter or something
like that. That didn't happen. But you know,
they're setting him up for something like that.
Yeah. But what a guy who double crossed his
own partner B1 that is. qualified to be God's
divine wrath? Well, this isn't keeping with
the character from the comics. Like, Jim Corrigan
was an asshole in the comics. Really? Oh, okay.
Yeah. Okay. Moving on to episode 8, titled
Nocturne. Amidst a fundraiser carnival for Dent's
campaign, multiple orphans are reported missing.
Batman soon finds the culprit, Natalia Knight,
the younger sister of inventor Anton Knight,
who suffers from a mysterious ailment that can
only be staved off by draining energy from
people. which grants her enhanced strength.
After falling out with and attacking Anton
for his perceived controlling behavior, Natalia
continues her attacks until she is intercepted
by Batman. After making her realize she accidentally
killed Anton, who begged Batman to stop her
before he died, Batman takes Natalia to safety
while her victims are taken to a hospital to
recover. Meanwhile, Dent meets with Thorne to
accept his donation, but refuses to accept
his condition of dropping charges against Thorne's
friend. retaliation, Thorin II throws a flask
of acid at Dent's face. This is actually probably
my least favorite episode. Really? Yeah, I
felt like the whole thing kind of drug on. I
didn't really care for the characters of Natalia
and Anton Knight. They're known as the Knight
Slayer and Nocturna in the comics. But I think
I was most offended in this episode by how they
treated the Robins. I was kind of hoping for
a setup of Robin in this series. And I think
this is a poor setup. Well, it seems like it's
never going to happen, right? Right. We're never
going to get a Robin in this series. When one
of the boys referred to the other one as Dickie,
I was like, oh, maybe this is Dick Grayson.
I actually thought that maybe that was just
a coincidence when I saw that Dick was captured
and nearly drained of his life. But then it
wasn't until they mentioned Steffi Brown that
I realized what they were doing with the orphans.
Oh, you didn't get it when you heard Jace for
Jason? No, not even then. And then of course
they had Kelly at the end with the slingshot.
Right. That was obvious. Yeah, for sure. It
was like a nice elseworlds homage. But yeah,
it is disappointing that because of this seemingly
clever nod to the comics that will actually
never get a Robin for this series. Yeah, it's
like either he's going to have five Robins
at once or I imagine none at all. Did not like
it. I was surprised we didn't get like Tim
or Damien. I guess Damien would it make sense.
But at least Tim. Actually, Damien. could make
sense if they introduce Russell Gould and Talia
in a subsequent season. And they just have
Damian be his first Robin. Yeah, I guess they
could go with that. Moving on to episode 9,
The Killer Inside Me. In the aftermath of his
assault, Dent loses his mayoral bid and is
left with half of his face permanently scarred,
which he grows insecure about. Bruce attempts
to cheer him up with a night on the town, but
a paranoid Dent has an outburst in a restaurant.
Alfred scolds Bruce for his poor attempt at
getting through to him. Craving justice against
those who wronged him, Dent goes on a violent
spree throughout Gotham, taking out several
of Thorne's men, though Batman intervenes before
he can hurt Thorne himself. Guilt-ridden, Dent
snaps out of his rage and willingly goes to
Arkham Asylum, where he discovers Barbara signed
on to become his lawyer. I liked what they did
with Harvey Dent for the most part throughout
this season. I did think that his descent into
madness was a little out of nowhere though.
Like the voices in his head, they just seem
to come along with the scarring of his face.
Well, isn't that true to the story of the character?
Like he doesn't begin his descent into madness
until he's actually scarred. No, he essentially
repressed a alternate personality as he was
growing up, becoming a lawyer. Like in this
show, he didn't really even depend on his old
coin in the same way that he has in prior depictions.
I don't know, it was just weird. I loved Diedrich
Bader as the voice of Harvey Dent. I thought
he sounded completely different from when he
voices Batman in shows like Harley Quinn. But
to me, this version of Harvey Dent is not as
good as other depictions that we've seen in
animated films like The Long Halloween or his
live action appearance in The Dark Knight. He
was just too smarmy as Harvey Dent. He wasn't
the shining white knight. that he's typically
depicted as prior to becoming Two-Face. I guess
that makes sense. I thought it was really interesting
how Bruce was essentially responsible for his
descent into madness by forgetting to focus
on the victim and having empathy for him. He
had no empathy. He was just trying to get at
the people who did it and in effect caused
Harvey Dent to go on this crazy rampage. I didn't
really get that. I didn't understand how taking
him out to dinner caused him to have his episode.
Bruce didn't know that was going to happen.
I'm sure he had ulterior motives in doing that,
but I also felt like it's also something a
good friend might try doing. And I think Harvey
even later on said that he understood what
Bruce was trying to do while both of them were
talking in Arkham Asylum. Which brings me to
the final episode titled Savage Night. Barbara
explains to Dent that she is willing to help
him, insisting that he was led astray. Meanwhile,
Thorn's men, Bullock and Flass, seek revenge
on Dent. prompting Barbara and Batman to establish
a form of contact between each other and join
forces with each other, Jim and Montoya to protect
him so he can testify in court. Amidst a fight
at the docks, however, Dent sacrifices himself
to save Barbara from Flass. Batman loses his
temper and threatens to shoot Flass, but ultimately
spares him. Following this, Alfred assures
Batman that while he failed to reach Dent's
humanity, Batman still has his. A mysterious
man kills a series of victims with a toxin that
makes them laugh uncontrollably. Great final
episode. I really liked the pacing of it. It's
mostly a chase scene between the good guys
and the bad guys. Yeah, yeah. The finale at
the docks was really well done and even surprising
at the very end when Batman holds a gun up to
flash and shoots around his head. Although
100% doing permanent ear damage as well, I'm
pretty sure. That's fine. He doesn't have a
problem with that. No, he doesn't. In fact,
if anything, it was showed that Batman was
such a badass with a gun and he has still refused
to do it out of hatred for the weapon. I thought
that was an interesting insight to his character
actually that he took the time to understand
this weapon that he despises. Yeah, that was
interesting. I always kind of assumed that
Batman really didn't even know how to use a
gun. You know, he just hated them so much.
So yeah, again, this was pretty shocking. Even
more shocking than that was actually Harvey
Dent's death. in this season, in this series,
sacrificing himself to save Barbara. The whole
is he good, is he bad approach to Harvey Dent
in this season was really well done. I thought
because, you know, the last episode, we saw
him essentially go on a murder spree. But in
this episode, to see him sacrifice himself for
Barbara Gordon, I thought was extremely heroic
and definitely redeeming for the character.
Like you were sad to see him go. Do you think
they have shot themselves in the foot in terms
of the potential? two-faced stories they could
have told in the future? Potentially, but outside
of the fall of Harvey Dent, there's not too
many great two-faced stories that you could
tell, so maybe it's for the best. Maybe use
this as a way to fuel and motivate Batman going
forward, the fact that he remembers his friend
Harvey Dent. But that does it for season one
of Batman the Caped Crusader. Overall, I thought
it was a mature and intriguing reimagining of
the 90s animated series. featuring new and
modern interpretations of classic characters
within a retro noir framework. Not every interpretation
is successful and it would have been nice to
see Batman a little bit more than we did. But
overall, I definitely recommend the series,
especially for the people who are behind it.
I'm giving it 4 out of 5 stars, a fresh rating
on Rotten Tomatoes. I would agree. I think
the setup and the premise of the series is better
than the execution for the most part. Don't
get me wrong, it was a really good show. It
was enjoyable and I would recommend it to any
fan of Batman and any fan of Batman the animated
series. But it does feel like for some episodes,
they squandered their potential. Even though
I had a really good time with the series and
I'm really looking forward to where they take
it in the future. Oh, yeah, absolutely. I'm
not sure if they're doing a season two, but
I really hope they are. I would love to see
it. But that does it for this review. AJ 9K,
help close this out. Thanks for listening to
Dynamic Jewel. Visit the show's website at dynamicduel.com
and follow us on Instagram at dynamicduelpodcast.
You can support the show on Patreon at patreon.com
slash dynamicduel and joining a tier that works
for you, or by rating and reviewing Dynamic
Duel on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser
or on our website. Don't forget to listen to
the other shows in the DynaMic Podcast Network,
including Max Destruction, Senjo World and Console
Combat. In our next episode, we will be doing
a duel between Kite Man and Stilt Man. Both
of whom are kind of ridiculous villains in
concept. It's going to be a lot of fun, though.
Yeah, I'm really looking forward to the episode.
But that does it for this episode. We want to
give a big thanks to our executive producers,
Ken Johnson, John Strosky, Zachary Hepburn,
Dustin Belcombe, Miggie Mathing-Geehan, Brandon
Nestregard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Austin
Wazilowski, AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Gil
Camacho, Adam Spies, Andrew Shunk. Dean Maleski,
Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, and Josh Leiner
for helping make this podcast possible. And
we'll talk to you guys next week. Up up and
away, true believers.