This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the superiority
between Marvel and DC by comparing their characters
in stat-based battle simulations. I'm Johnny
DC. And I'm his twin brother Marvelous Joe.
And in this episode, as a tie-in to our last
episode, which was a duel between Eclipso and
Malekith, we are now doing a throwback review
to Thor the Dark World. Right, because Malekith
is the main villain of Thor the Dark World.
You know what? I'm just gonna say it now. It's
a good movie, guys. I'm sick of pretending
like it's not. Alright? I never pretended like
it wasn't. I always thought it was pretty good.
Especially compared to where the franchise has
gone now with Thor, Love and Thunder, you know?
I really wish the franchise would go back to
the tone of Thor the Dark World. And we'll
talk more about the movie later on this episode.
But, you know, for the haters out there that
may dislike this movie, try sticking around.
You might change your mind about the film.
Before we review Thor the Dark World, we're
going to break down the comic book movie news
from the past week, of which there is one news
item, an amazing news item, it was the official
teaser trailer for Joker, Fall Ya Do, which
was released during CinemaCon this past week.
I don't know if I would call it an amazing news
item so much as a news item, but as always
we list our segment times in our episode description,
so feel free to check out our show notes if
you want to skip ahead to a particular topic.
We're gonna fight, we're gonna throw hands.
Our artificially intelligent duel simulator
AJ9K has a quick message for our listeners,
so listen up. Why hello there. Do you love listening
and chatting about Marvel and DC? Then become
a part of the dynamic duel community on Patreon,
where you can choose from three tiers. The
dynamic two-o tier lets you listen to this podcast
without ads and gives you access to its discord
chat group, where you can chat with Johnny DC
and marvelous Joe. The Fantastic Four tier
gives you that and more with two bonus episodes
each month, including bloopers and top ten
shows where Johnny and Joe count down your favourite
Marvel and DC subjects. The X-Force tier makes
you an executive producer of Dynamic Duel, where
every month you help the host choose what to
review and who to fight against each other.
And finally, the Dynamite Podcast Network tier
allows aspiring podcasters to create their own
battle-focused show using this Monte Carlo
simulator.
Thanks AJ and IK and thanks to everyone who
supports the podcast. Guys, be sure to tune
into the shows in the Dynamite Podcast Network
this week, including Max Destruction, which
pits your favorite action heroes from film and
television against each other. This week, Ken
and Scotty are going to break down the latest
WrestleMania that happened a few weeks ago,
and I believe they're also tying in a Ready
to Rumble review to that episode. Although
that might come out the next week, we'll see.
On the Send Your World podcast, host Zachary
Hepburn speculates on fights between fan favorite
anime characters. He was not able to put out
an episode last Thursday, so this Thursday,
again, we're going to find out who would win
between Sanji from One Piece and Mic Guy from
Naruto. And on the console combat podcast,
hosts John and Dean find out who would win in
fights between popular video game characters.
And in yesterday's episode, they found out who
would win between earthworm Jim and Booger
Man. An incredible episode. Definitely check
it out. Visit dynamic podcasts.com or click
the link in our show notes to listen to all
of the shows in the DynaMic podcast network.
Also guys, check out the TV and movie trivia
podcast. where I did a guest spot with the
host Brian over there on that show and I competed
in trivia regarding the movie X-Men First Class.
So, if you're a fan of X-Men First Class and
of movie trivia and you think you know more
about that movie than I do, go see if you're
right by listening to the TV and movie trivia
pod. But with that out of the way, quick to
the no prize! A no prize is an award Marvel
used to give out to fans. Our version, the Dynamic
Duel No Prize, is a digital award we post on
Instagram for the person that we feel gave the
best answer to our question of the week. Last
week we asked, what would be your favorite out
of left field casting choice for an alternate
universe Marvel or DC character? And this was
coming off the news that Julia Garner was cast
as the Silver Surfer in the upcoming Fantastic
Four movie. We got a lot of great answers,
so let's go ahead and break down our three honorable
mentions, as well as the No Prize winner. Our
first honorable mention goes to Brandon Estergard,
who said, Hey guys, my out of left field casting
would be for Anya Taylor Joy to play Luke Cage,
not Lucille Cage, not Lucy Cage, Luke Cage.
And right out of the gate with the left field
casting choice, Brandon gave us Anya Taylor
Joy as Luke Cage. I don't know if she could
pull off the character that well, now that
I think about it. She could probably pull off
the yellow blouse. that he wore back in the
day. And the tiara. The tiara she called. And
the matching bracelets. Yeah, yeah, the bracelets,
maybe the chain link belt that he's got going
on, but I'd like to see her try it at the very
least. Yeah. I feel like there would be riots
if she did. She would get canceled so hard,
so fast. She would, but I would still be interested
to see it. Brandon actually gave two answers.
He also said that he would like to see Dwayne
the Rock Johnson play Starfire. He could pull
off the outfit. for sure. Yeah, if any guy could,
he could. But Brandon also said that he was
especially looking forward to seeing the Rock
wear a Starfire wig, which I would also love
to see. Our next honorable mention goes to Jacob
Bell, who said, Hey, what's up, guys? Jacob
Bell here. You guys know that I love casting
stuff. I'm super passionate about it. This
one is definitely out of left field a little
bit, but just kind of hang in there with me.
But why can't Natalie Portman play the Joker?
The like Bruce Wayne's mom version of the Joker
from the Flashpoint Paradox movie. She has an
Oscar. We know she can act. I like her in the
Thor movies. I think she's good and she's old
enough to play a mom. I just, I think it would
be awesome. Awesome casting. So when we first
heard that the Flash movie was going to take
inspiration from the Flashpoint storyline in
the comics, all of us loved the idea of Jeffrey
Dean Morgan and Lauren Cohen. playing the Flashpoint
versions of Batman and the Joker because of
course in that universe Bruce Wayne's parents
become Batman and the Joker respectively. I
thought Lauren Cohen would have made a fantastic
Joker but I also know that Natalie Portman
could knock it out of the park. The Joker seems
to be this role that good actors seem to thrive
in, Jared Leto notwithstanding. So as could
have been actress as Natalie Portman is, I'm
sure she would also do well in the role. Yeah,
in reference to this answer, I go back to the
Natalie raps from Saturday Night Live and what
a crazy character she is there. I think that
could easily be transposed into the character
of the Joker. Absolutely. Our final honorable
mention goes to Miggy Mattenkian, who said,
Hey, what's up guys, this is Miggy and my out
of left field casting would be Rowan Atkinson
as Alfred Pennyworth. At first glance, this
is like not a great casting because Mr. Bean,
you know, he's a very comedic actor. But he
actually had a role of Black Adder where he
was like the stuck-up like aristocrat. And
I think that along with like a more serious
like Johnny English type, I think could work
really well for Alfred. So yeah, Rowan Atkinson,
popularly known as Mr. Bean. I think I've only
ever seen him in comedic roles. But I feel like
he's a really good actor. And I think that
a role like Alfred Pennyworth would really allow
him to bring that out. I mean, you could also
just have a comedic Alfred Pennyworth. Yeah,
I mean, to me, that's not as interesting as
just seeing Ron Atkinson going full on thespian
mode, you know? Yeah, full on Shakespeare mode,
for sure. Yeah. I actually don't think this
is too far out of left field. Maybe in the
sense that it would probably never happen, but
you know what? I think he would actually be
well suited to the role if he was ever cast.
I don't think I would question it quite as
much as say, you know, Anya Taylor Joy as Luke
Cage. No, no. I think you could do just as
good a job as Andy Serkis for sure. Great answer,
Miggy. We want to give a special shout out
to Colby Hentges, who said that Jonathan Majors
could play Icon. Yikes. Connor Pierce said
that Kelly Rohrbach could play Power Girl and
Scott Camacho, whose favorite out of left field
casting was actually Michael Keaton as Batman.
But the winner of this week's No Prize is Travis
Bailey, who said. All right, Travis Bailey.
What's up to my twin? All right. Listen Joe's
on to something. All right. She's an alternate
universe Silver surfer, right? So I'm gonna
take you back to issue 12. What if what if Rick
James was the Hulk? All right. I take an AI
generated Rick James, but follow me with this.
What if Britney Spears was the Hulk now she
hawked the Hulk and you can have all the stuff
she got with her father as a All right, he
got cut off there, but I love this answer so
much. What if Rick James was the Hulk? Now,
actually, the official what if issue 12 was
what if Rick Jones was the Hulk? But I googled
this and there was a parody of that issue that
said, what if Rick James was the Hulk? And
it's freaking hilarious. I love the idea of
this. Gamma radiation is a hell of a drug.
Instead of Hulk smash, you'd be like, give it
to me, baby. People would call him super freakish,
for sure. But, uh, Britney Spears as the Hulk,
that's definitely inspired considering both
of the characters have, you know, daddy issues.
I totally see it. Yeah, I think she'd probably
shave her head and then go green and then just...
Act like her normal self. Just dancing with
knives and crazy shit. Jeez, I don't know if
the whole making fun of her shaving her head
thing is a decade too late of a joke, but yeah,
we'll go with that. We'll go with that. So
congrats to Travis Bailey for winning this week's
No Prize. If you the listener want to shout
out winning your own no prize, stay tuned to
later on this episode when we'll be asking
another question of the week. And now that that's
done, on to the news!
Alright, before we get into this I just want
you guys to know that Joseph super butthurt
about me not liking the casting of the Surfer
Surfer. So he's planning on shitting all over
this trailer, but he can do whatever he wants,
we don't care because we all know that this
trailer was awesome. The trailer was released
last week during CinemaCon and there was quite
a bit of news to come out for both Marvel and
DC during this, including the Superman logo
and some footage from the new Captain America
movie. But I think hands down, the biggest
thing to come out. of the entire convention
was the official teaser trailer for Joker Folly-a-doo.
It was alright. When we first heard that this
was going to be a musical, some fans were up
in ire. Again, I was not one of those until
I learned that it was going to be a jukebox
musical. I was actually very disappointed by
that. If you're not familiar with what a jukebox
musical is, it's a musical that has no original
music. It just rehashes pop music essentially.
So I was pretty apprehensive going into this
trailer until I saw it and all of its beauty
and all of its splendor. One of my favorite
trailers of all time was actually the first
trailer we got for the first Joker movie. And
this reminded me a lot of that. In fact, I
would say I enjoyed this trailer more than that
first one. It captured all of the emotion,
but the cinematography here was just so unbelievably
gorgeous as well. Jonathan, why are you so
wishy washy when it comes to this movie? What
are you talking about? First you like it, then
you hate the idea of it, then you like it again,
and then you're like, oh no, I don't wanna
see it. And then you're like, okay, I love it
actually. Well, I was the same way with the
first Joker movie, honestly, like at first I
was like, ah, this is dumb. Why are they making
a Joker origin story? No one wants this. Until
I saw the first trailer and I was totally sold,
this is the case again. We see the trailer start
off with Arthur Fleck in Arkham Asylum. He's
being taken out of his jail cell by Brandon
Gleason, of all people. I don't even know he
was in this movie, but he's, you know, a really
good actor. They take the character of Arthur
Fleck right past Lady Gaga's character, who
seems to be a patient at Arkham as well, which
is really confusing because we know that Harley
Quinzel was actually a doctor at Arkham Asylum,
a psychologist who helped treat the Joker. Of
course, she doesn't stay there throughout the
trailer. We see her actually out and about in
the city of Gotham without the Joker. So I
think she's actually manipulating Kim in this
trailer. That's my theory. Although I've heard
other theories that say she's not actually there.
He's just imagining her in the same way that
Joker had a lot of hallucinations in the first
movie with Zazie Beats character. How she was
always there supporting Kim when in fact she
really wasn't. It's hard to say what's real.
and what's fake, what's a part of Joker's imagination
in this movie. Because early on, we see him
walking through the Arkham Courtyard and the
guards have these umbrellas that Arthur suddenly
imagines very colorful. It's a really beautiful
scene, but also hints at the imaginary world
that Arthur is creating for himself. Once the
character of Harley invites the Joker out,
as if maybe they're going to escape or just
go outside, That's when the music of the trailer
really starts. We see both Joker and Harley
on the rooftop of Hotel Arkham. Apparently,
they're imagining the scene. And they start
dancing, and it just segues into this moment
of chaos, where we see buildings burning down
and the background in ambulances and police
cars driving by. And Joker and Harley don't
seem to care. They're just enamored with each
other, just living life and loving music, it
seems. It's like the Joker dreamed of being
a comedian on stage. in the first movie, but
here it seems like he's fantasizing more about
being a musician on stage, which kind of plays
into Todd Phillips' whole concept for the character
of the Joker. You know, Todd Phillips has said
that he has music in his soul, which is why
he did this kind of dance the first time he
killed someone in the first movie. And it seems
like this Harley Quinn is really playing up
on that. I'm really looking forward to see
how Harley fits into everything in this movie.
So you're looking forward to this movie? Would
you say that the depiction of Harley and Joker's
relationship is accurate to the comic books?
In a sense, I would say that if they're going
the route where Harley is trying to manipulate
the Joker so that she can write a tell-all book,
that's accurate to the comics. That was straight
out of Mad Love. I think, yeah, this will be
accurate for the most part, but it's still
an interesting twist that I love that they're
making for this film. Because it makes the
character of Harley... appear much more intelligent
in the way that she's able to manipulate Joker.
Because oftentimes, you know, Harley Quinn is
the one who suffers from abuse and she's the
one who's manipulated by Joker. But I think
in this film, we're actually going to see them
sort of manipulate each other. That's sort of
my theory. Would you say the Joker is accurate
to the comics? The Joker is accurate to the
Joker film. I mean, this is a sequel. I think
I think by the end of this film, the Joker is
going to Snap more than he's ever snapped before
and he's going to become the Joker of the comics
Okay, so but he's there's a lot of differences
here in the Joker than how he is in the comics,
right? Definitely not as much as silver surfer
being a woman. I know where you're trying to
go But you're willing to accept these changes
though, because it's like an elseworlds like
an alternate universe kind of you know Except
the Fantastic Four movie is not an elseworlds
tale It's the MCU, and the first time you're
introducing a character, it shouldn't be an
alternate version of the character. You know,
it's not like they genderbent Mr. Fantastic
when we first saw him in Doctor Strange and
the Multiverse of Madness. Sure, Captain America
has already been established as a man, so I
think it's okay genderbending him with Peggy
Carter, but it's a mistake to do that with
Silver Surfer. I don't even know why we're talking
about this and need to get over it. Moving
back to the Joker Folio Do trailer. So it's
okay to make changes to alternate universes
from the comics. There's a line you don't cross
and the Fantastic Four crossed that line. I
think the Joker crossed the line too. It was
just something you didn't want to accept until
you actually saw the movie. And since you don't
actually know what your opinions are until
you see things, and maybe even sometimes after
you see things, as is the case with the first
Joker film, maybe you just don't know what you're
talking about. No, I think I do. Another thing
that reminded me of the first Joker trailer
with this trailer was how he's speaking with
his therapist. Arthur Fleck was such a lonely
character in the first movie, so it makes sense
that he could almost start to heal with the
emergence of Harley Quinn. And I think that's
really going to ultimately lead to his downfall
is that when he finds out that she's manipulating
him, he's just going to snap. And I'm kind of
worried about what's going to happen with Harley.
Whatever happens in the film, it definitely
looks like Harley starts to lose her grip on
reality in the same way that maybe the Joker
is in the fact that she's starting to smear
blood on her face and do the whole makeup thing.
It gets pretty wild, but nothing is more wild
and awesome than the final shot, the final scene
of this trailer, which you wouldn't think it
would be because it's essentially just Harley
drawing a smile with lipstick on a glass pane.
But the way it lined up with Joaquin Phoenix's
sinister smile just screamed Joker to me. It
was so, so well shot. Like this entire film.
Holy cow. I also have to commend the people
who made the trailer for their song choice of
Tom Jones, What the World Needs Now is Love.
I think that's the name of the song. Perfect
choice. Love everything about this trailer.
Hopefully I'm going to love everything about
this movie. Because the first movie was really
hard to watch and I'm sure this one will be
too, but I'm totally ready for it. Well Jonathan,
I'm glad to see you admit that you shouldn't
judge things prematurely and maybe wait and
see how they come out before basing your opinion.
And that brings us to our question of the week.
What film are you looking forward to more this
year? Deadpool and Wolverine or Joker Follyadoo
and why? Record your answer at dynamicduel.com
by clicking on the red microphone button in
the bottom right-hand corner of the screen,
which will prompt you to leave us a voicemail.
Your message could be up to 30 seconds long
and don't forget to leave your name in case
we include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a dynamic
duel no prize that we'll post to Instagram.
Be sure to answer before... April 20th.
But I think that does it for all the news from
this episode. Now let's move on to the main
event, where we review the 2013 MCU film, Thor,
The Dark World.
Okay, Thor the Dark World was released in 2013,
directed by Alan Taylor, and it stars Chris
Hemsworth, Tom Hiddleston, Natalie Portman,
and Christopher Ecclestone. Right up top, I'm
going to give you listeners your spoiler warning.
If you haven't seen Thor the Dark World yet,
and you like the character of Thor, definitely
go give the movie a watch before listening
to this spoiler filled review. Now we haven't
reviewed the first Thor movie yet, but I thought
it was an interesting and successful way to
introduce the concept of magic and fantasy
in the very science fiction-y world of the Marvel
Cinematic Universe at the time. I knew that
a sequel of the first film was given after the
Avengers movie and I was looking forward to
Thor the Dark World, especially when they announced
that Alan Taylor would be directing it, a guy
who had helmed some of the better Game of Thrones
episodes. But originally he wasn't going to
direct it, right? It was going to be Patty Jenkins,
the same director who did Wonder Woman. Right,
yeah, but she had a falling out due to creative
differences. Although it was a cordial split
for Marvel, as I understand it. I'll be honest,
when Thor the Dark World came out, I hadn't
seen any of Game of Thrones yet, but I did know
of the show's reputation, and I knew that the
realm of mythological high fantasy was exactly
where I wanted the Thor franchise to go. And
during the marketing of the movie, you know,
we saw that he was going to visit other realms,
and that we'd see the Dark Elves, and needless
to say, I was excited for this movie, but when
I left the theater, you know what? I was still
excited, you know? The film was almost exactly
what I expected and the ending was spectacular
because we saw Loki secretly on Asgard's throne
and we got the very first mention of the Infinity
Gems or stones as they came to be known in
the movies. Like I was pumped leaving the theater.
I even went and saw it in theaters again, and
I guess I never really understood the general
disdain for this movie. Yeah, me neither. Like
I heard this movie was bad, so I never went
to go see it in theaters. I actually did not
see this movie until I think a few days before
seeing Thor Ragnarok, because you essentially
forced me to watch it. And I was glad I did.
I totally do not understand the hate that this
film gets. Yeah, I mean, I'll admit it's been
a good five or so years since I've rewatched
this movie. I don't know if it's because of
how the Thor franchise has devolved with Thor
11th Under, and maybe my mind is just comparing
Thor the Dark World to the current state of
the franchise. But yeah, I really enjoyed watching
this movie again. I feel like Thor the Dark
World is so much more like what an ideal Thor
film should be. Oh yeah, yeah I liked this
so much more than the first movie. I actually
liked this more than Thor Ragnarok even, I
know that's like a lot of people's favorite
Thor movie. But for me, I want to see Thor
in his like Norse mythical element. Taika Waititi
ruined Thor in some ways because they took
the character in such a comedic route that I
don't know if we could ever get back to this
version of Thor that's much more Shakespearean,
much more dramatic. I hope they do, though.
Yeah, I think if they tried to revert back to
this more serious tone, people would be like,
when did Thor become so boring or something
like that? But that's not the case. It's more
like when did Thor become so goofy? Right. So
yeah, I really like Thor the Dark World. Don't
get me wrong, the movie's not perfect. It does
suffer from an underwhelming villain and a
mumbo jumbo-y plot device in the Convergence,
but Thor the Dark World is where I'd really
like to see the franchise return. My favorite
Thor stories from the comics are the ones that
take place entirely or largely away from Earth
within the other eight realms, where we get
to explore Marvel's unique approach to Norse
mythology, which I find fascinating. Stories
like Disassembled, where Ragnarok finally takes
hold. Mjolnir's Song where Thor battles the
Midgard Serpent, Tales of Asgard, and the Surtr
Saga. All awesome. I love when Thor's stories
feel like Lord of the Rings because the realm
of fantasy is kind of unique in Marvel. Like
the mythic fantasy genre isn't exclusive to
Thor because you still have characters like
Hercules and the Black Knight. But Thor is a
great character and his popularity gives Marvel
probably their best opportunity for that kind
of mythical fantasy exploration and world building.
Yeah, especially considering that, like, high
fantasy really came out of Norse mythology,
I would say. Like, the world of Lord of the
Rings owes so much to it that Marvel could
totally play up on that fact. Yeah, high fantasy
as we know it is a mix of, like, Celtic and
Norse mythology. And I'm a huge fan of the Lord
of the Rings. And I feel like this Thor the
Dark World is the closest that Marvel has ever
gotten to that. Yeah, I would say that it's
the closest that anything from Marvel or DC
has ever gotten to that sort of high fantasy
kind of approach. But the cool thing about the
world of Thor too is that it feels so believable
in a way too, which I love. Yeah, I mean, the
world building in Thor the Dark World is a
lot of fun. From Asgard's flying aircraft to
Svartalheim's never-ending eclipse, from Odin's
library room to, you know, the village camps
of Vanaheim. I just had a blast on every one
of those worlds and I wish we got more of that.
You know, none of this new Asgard on Earth
crap where they serve Infinity Cone's ice cream.
Bullshit. Ugh. Asgard has gotten so dumb lately
and it's so lame that they blew it up in the
MCU so they can't like ever go back there.
They gotta find a way to rebuild Asgard so that
the Asgardians can find their former glory
because right now they're just a shell of what
they used to be. The overarching story here
is kind of interesting too where you have this
ancient race of dark beings trying to restore
the reality from before the dawn of light. using
an all-powerful magic artifact during a time
when all the realms align. You know, the setup
is really good for a high fantasy adventure.
Where it all goes wrong is in the climax, and
I think that's what mostly disappointed viewers,
because what was supposed to be the strongest
point of the movie kind of fell flat. In the
final battle between Malekith and Thor, you
know, you have, you know, a bland, underwhelming
villain using this powerful artifact in one
of the most unimaginative ways possible. You
have a bunch of less interesting human side
characters running around adding needless comedic
relief. And while the portals between the realms
added an interesting dynamic to the battle
and gave it some nice momentum, it was kind
of hard to understand where and why and when
the portals were going to take the fight to
another world. And so it felt kind of disorienting
from a narrative and visual standpoint. Absolutely.
I honestly feel like the human characters in
this movie kind of ruined the film. I don't
think you even really needed them. Yeah, but
like I feel like the criticisms of the film's
comedy that I heard when the film came out,
like the jokey scene of Selvick running around
naked at Stonehenge, those nitpicks I feel
like don't hold as much weight now as they used
to considering that scene seems rather minor
compared to the stupidity of where the franchise
is now. Very true. If anything, Thor the Dark
World has just gotten better with age as a film.
I definitely agree and I hope that eventually
over time people online and the social media
community will see how good this movie was
compared to the Takeaway TD films that we got.
Yeah, go back and sample it guys. If it's been
a while since you've seen the movie or if you
didn't like the movie to begin with, you might
find that your opinion has changed on it. I
think for the angle between Thor and his brother
Loki alone, that makes this entire movie. Oh
for sure, yeah. I mean, the brothers had a
good dynamic going in Thor Ragnarok, but I think
in Thor the Dark World they had their best
moment. Let's go ahead and talk about the characters
more in our character breakdown. Starting with
Thor Odinson, played by Chris Hemsworth. Now
I think Hemsworth's performance in this movie
is the most he's ever felt like Thor to me.
You know, I know he prefers his goofy jokes
and ultimately took the character in a much
more comedic route because he found this more
serious Thor to be bland. But as a fan of the
comics, I've never found Thor to be goofy.
To me, he's always been noble, serious, and
yet also zealous in battle. I thought his role
here built off of the first Thor movie pretty
well, where we saw him mature a little bit.
And also he had some good vulnerable moments
in the film, such as when his mother, Frigga,
died or when he was arguing with Loki on Spratlheim.
There's a reason why Verisimilitude was the
theme behind the scenes of Richard Donner's
first Superman movie. It was because you could
totally go the Adam West Batman route with this,
but that's not what he wanted. because he wanted
to treat the character with more respect. And
you know, Patty Jenkins took the same approach
with the first Wonder Woman movie. The word
cheesy was banned on set because they wanted
to treat the characters with seriousness. And
I feel like Alan Taylor took the same approach
with a lot of scenes, probably a majority of
the scenes in this movie. Yeah, and he kind
of grounded things too. I mean, if you look
at Thor's arc, it's really centered around
his love for Jane. From beginning to end, you
know, he dismisses Sif. He watches Jane with
Heimdall. When he sees she's in trouble, he
brings her to Asgard. When she's dying, he
risks it all to have Malekith remove the Aether
from her. And when the realms are saved, he
renounces his throne to be with her. There's
an interesting moment midway through the film
when Loki tells Thor that Jane is going to die
regardless if the Aether takes her or not.
That even if she lives decades longer, the time
would be fleeting to them as gods. And Thor
simply states that he won't be saying goodbye
to her today. You know, it was almost a nice
foreshadowing. to the events of Thor, Love and
Thunder. I will never forgive that fourth film
for butchering Jane's cancer arc the way that
it did because it really had the perfect setup
from this movie. Oh yeah, for sure. Yeah, that
was definitely top of mind as I was rewatching
this because I'd forgotten that the ether made
her sick. Yeah. Speaking of Jane Foster, let's
go ahead and move on to her played by Natalie
Portman. Now Natalie Portman, I thought was
fine here in this movie. Sometimes she could
be a little bit iffy in her acting, especially
with scenes that you could tell she's not quite
comfortable in. but I thought she did pretty
well in this film particularly. Yeah, I thought
she did better here than she did in Love and
Thunder. I believed the romance between her
and Thor. Yeah, where Thor was a fish out of
water in the first movie on Earth, it was interesting
to see that flipped where she was the fish
out of water traveling among Asgard and the
other realms. One of the things that I appreciate
the most about Jane, and I don't know if everyone
appreciates this, but it's one of the things
that I find endearing about her character. is
how she uses science to explain her understanding
of the magic of the nine realms. Like what Thor
calls the Bifrost, she calls an Einstein-Rosen
Bridge. What Odin calls the Convergence, she
calls spatial extrusions and gravitational
anomalies. What they call the Soul Forge, she
calls a... Quantum field generator. Yeah, I
always liked that about her character. Just
the way these like mortal minds could possibly
conceive of this mythological magic, you know?
And I thought it was a particularly nice, subtle
moment when she finally got to travel through
the Bifrost. You got this flash of the scientist
in her just giddy with happiness finally getting
to be inside the thing that she had spent her
whole life studying. And also, I really liked
her wardrobe here. I think Natalie Portman
looked really great in the S. Guardian garb.
And actually, I think everyone looked great
in Thor the Dark World. This movie had the best
costumes out of all the films. It just all
felt very classic. Oh, yeah. Yeah, everything
from the Dark Elves to the different realms
I thought were amazing. Loki has never looked
better. Yeah, and Thor too. He didn't have
like the goofy bleached eyebrows and he had
like longer hair here and just his costume
looked a little bit more grand to me. Yeah,
even when he was walking around in Asgard without
it. Yeah. Let's go to move on to Loki Loffi-san,
played by Tom Hiddleston. Man, Loki was so
good in this movie. Of course, Tom Hiddleston
nailed the performance and as far as I'm concerned,
it was the perfect arc for Loki following his
previous two film appearances. He gets imprisoned,
during which time the only person he ever cared
for, his adoptive mother Frigga, gets killed.
So we see him at his absolute lowest point,
then he teams up with his brother and mortal
enemy for a chance at revenge. and he ends up
still scheming to take the throne at the finale,
which he gets and seems like his highest point.
So there's a real rollercoaster here with Loki.
It was so much fun to watch the story unfold
here. And he's just far and away the MCU's
most interesting character when you think about
how far he's come, you know, through these
Thor films and even through his own television
series. I also love the fact that he sacrificed
himself in the middle of that. Like he had this
like bit of redemption. And I remember the
first time I watched this. I totally did not
see that Loki took the throne from Odin initially.
Yeah, my jaw dropped because I had no idea what
was going on. Svartelheim, when you see him
like take on the role of the Einherjar. I think
I'm pronouncing that right. The soldier guy.
Yeah. And then he goes and reports back to Odin
and he was like, there was a body. And then
there was an interesting moment there where
Odin says Loki. And then the soldier guy smiles.
And I think it's up for interpretation. What
happens there? Either Odin recognizes that
soldier as Loki and is addressing him as such,
or he's saying that the body they found was
Loki. And then the guy smiles because he's about
to enact his spell that casts Odin down to
Midgard, you know. It's a wonderfully ambiguous
moment. That's just peak Loki. Anthony Hopkins
is such a phenomenal actor in this. I still
can't believe he's in the Marvel Universe.
He's too damn good for it. More like too good
for the DC Universe, you mean? Which is why
he's never been in it. But speaking of classic
British actors, let's go ahead and move on
to Malekith, played by Christopher Eccleston.
Christopher Eccleston is a solid actor. When
he was cast as Malekith, I was ecstatic because
even though I've never seen Doctor Who, I knew
of his reputation, and I had seen Eccleston
in some other things. When I saw his performance
though, I was really disappointed at how generic
and bland he approached the role. I don't know
if that was a direction thing or if he thought
that the makeup would do most of the acting
for him, but it wasn't interesting. And that's
a shame because as you learned in our last
episode, the character of Malekith is so interesting
from the comics. Yeah, I mean, I remember thinking
as you were reading his bio, like, is this going
to ruin Thor the Dark World for me? Luckily
it didn't. And I agree with you that he probably
put on the costume and just felt like he was
embodying the character. Although, you know,
British actors tend to be more technical than
method when it comes to their acting approach.
But I don't think it's that bad. Yes, it is
bland, but I think it wouldn't have come across
as so bland if he wasn't around such a colorful
cast of characters, specifically the goofy human
ones. Like Sauron is, you know, pretty bland,
you could argue. But no one complains about
that. Sauron is more of an entity, you know,
than an actual character. Well, a ringwraith
then. I guess also entities. Yeah. Now this
film Malekith's motivation is his fixation on
returning the universe to one of darkness when
the dark elves thrived before the dawn of light.
He tries to use the reality stone to achieve
his goal, but the problem is that even when
he gets the ether, he doesn't particularly
seem as threatening as he should be. No. You
know, for a guy who can warp all reality, he
seems unimaginative and underpowered. Well,
I mean, it was never really clearly established
that he had the reality infinity stone until
the very end of the movie. So, I mean, if you're
just watching this for the first time, you're
not going to assume that he just all of a sudden
has infinite power almost. But yeah, in hindsight,
watching this, oh, you're going to shoot some
crystal shards. OK, they seem to be doing nothing.
I mean, we spent the whole movie as the audience
just dreading what would happen if the villain
got his red juice. And you know, it was underwhelming,
especially the line from Thor during the climactic
battle when he says, You know, with all that
power, I thought you'd hit harder. That horribly
undersold Malekith and his might. You know,
he seemed so much weaker than his henchman,
Kurs, who was beating the shit out of Thor
over on Svartalheim. Right? So it just made
Malekith all the less impressive, which is
something that you don't want for a guy who
already started out pretty bland. Well, how
would you have changed it? Like, what would
you have done? I would have changed the characterization
of Malekith and I also would have rewritten
the climactic battle so that it was more of
a struggle for Thor. He can't be going around
saying lines like, you call that a punch or
something like that, you know, it just doesn't
work. The villain needs to be seen as a legitimate
threat. Now, there are a few other characters
within the movie. You know, you have the human
scientists and you also have the Warriors Three
and the other Asgardians and you have Curse
as well. but none of them had substantial enough
roles within the plot, I think, to warrant
a character breakdown. So let's go ahead and
move into our story highlights.
Our fantasies collide and heroes clash. One
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
DynaMic Podcast Network presents Console Combat,
where video game legends brawl every Monday.
Smash every Tuesday, Max Destruction, where
TV and action heroes battle every Wednesday,
and Sendro World, where anime champions clash
every Thursday. Join us as we speculate on
the matches and, armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge victorious.
Visit dynamicpodcast.com where we settle the
debate and settle the score.
Millennia ago, the leader of the Dark Elves,
Malekith the Accursed, tried to use the power
of the Reality Warping Aether to cast the universe
into darkness during a time when the Nine Realms
were in celestial alignment. He was stopped
by Bor, leader of the Asgardians who caused
Malekith to flee, and the Asgardians hid the
Aether deep underground. This opening scene
was awesome. Dude, it reminded me of the opening
scene to the Fellowship of the Ring. Yeah.
It was so cool to see Odin's father, Bor. and
to see him lead the Asgardians against the
Dark Elves. Just all the world building that
took place in the scene alone had me pumped
for the rest of the movie. I just love the approach
they took with the Dark Elves and the Asgardians,
and like the different weaponry they had and
stuff like that. Like the Dark Elves had their
black hole bombs and red crystals that they
could crush and would turn them into like these
powerhouses. It was almost like, I don't know
why, StarCraft for some reason to me. Yeah,
like it was like the Zerg versus the Protoss
or something like that. It was just really
cool. That's a great analogy. That's really
what it felt like. I don't necessarily love
the more sci-fi angle of the Dark Elves, but
somehow we still managed to work within the
parameters of this mythological fantasy world
building. Yeah, I think Alan Taylor has done
that better than any other director to handle
Thor. Yeah, the look of the Dark Elves to their
masks. That's cool. That's really cool. I guess
I just wish they weren't firing guns. I wish
they were firing bow and arrow type weapons.
Or at least like a, like do a crossbow. Like
meet me in the middle. Right. In the present
day, after the battle of New York, Loki is
imprisoned for attempting to enslave humanity.
With the Bifrost now restored after the events
of the first Thor film, Thor and his friends
travel the realms, restoring peace before returning
home to Asgard. The scene on Vanaheim. was interesting
because you have Thor going up against a cronin,
which is a race of beings that Korg is a member
of. So it's funny seeing this like serious
version of Korg just get his ass kicked by Thor
when he essentially reduces him to rubble.
I wish Thor would do that to Korg. Yeah, I agree.
That's what I felt when I saw that. It's interesting
how each of the realms have their own kind of
geography to them. Like Vanaheim is very much
like the foresty type realm. You know, Jotunheim
is the icy realm, Muspelheim is the fiery realm.
You have Svartelheim, which is like the dark
desert. Midgard, of course, is the planet Earth.
Asgard is the golden city, the golden realm,
you know. Oh, man. Niflheim, which was portrayed
in Thor Ragnarok when Valkyrie fought Hela,
and that was like a land of smoke and mist
and stuff. So many different worlds. Such cool
settings. Yeah, they're really cool. Meanwhile,
on Earth, astrophysicist Jane Foster and her
assistant Darcy stumble upon a gravitational
anomaly in London caused by the Convergence,
which is an alignment of the realms. A hidden
portal takes Jane to the secret location of
the Aether, where it invades her body. Thor
notices her disappearance and travels to Earth
to bring her to Asgard for help. There, Thor
and Jane learn that the Aether will kill Jane
if it's not removed from her body. Now, as
far as plot devices go, The convergence is not
the cleanest. It's a little bit muddy. There
aren't any clear rules to it other than just
sometimes there are these places where you
can slip between the worlds. And that's basically
it. How that corresponds to the floating disks
that appear hovering over a Greenwich during
the precise moment of the convergence and stuff
like that. It's, it's a little bit weird. I
don't know if they quite knew how to depict
it in this abstract way. I just don't think
it was very successful. I saw those as sort
of like tears in reality and like openings to
these other worlds essentially. I didn't think
it was terrible. I think that's what a lot of
people have issue with this film though. It's
simple in concept, but the more you think about
it, I feel like the less it holds up and it's
largely a matter of convenience in terms of
how the plot progresses. Like, of course Jane
just happened to find the portal that leads
to the secret location of the ether. Of course.
Thor and Jane just happen to find the portal
that leads back to Jane's car back on Earth
at the end, you know? Well, I mean, sort of.
The first one I would say, you know, she is
a leading scientist in the world regarding this
kind of stuff. So it makes sense that she would
stumble upon it before pretty much anyone else
except for those kids. You could definitely
say it's convenient. That they found their way
back to their car But they also kind of set
that up earlier in the film in the scene that
we're talking about Where things would go through
the portals and come back to the same location?
So not too convenient. You don't have to spend
so much time defending it man. It's okay It
is a bunch of mumbo jumbo. I'm saying it makes
sense in the story that they set up right in
concept Yes, but I also think that maybe you're
not thinking about as hard as you could be and
for that. I'm grateful I'm thinking about it
so hard. You have no idea My favorite joke in
this whole movie is when the intern to Darcy
throws the keys into the portal and then they
just like don't reappear and she's like, were
those the car keys? That was a solid joke. Yeah,
that was great. Back to the story, the discovery
of the Aether awakens the Dark Elves from suspended
animation. Malekith's lieutenant, Algrim the
Strong, goes undercover as a marauder and infiltrates
Asgard's prison. where he dons the curse armor
and causes a mass breakout. The Dark Elves invade
Asgard looking for Jane to extract the Aether
from her, though Thor's mother Frigga successfully
hides her and is killed in the process. Thor
burns half of Malekith's face with his lightning,
but he is unable to keep the Dark Elves from
fleeing. Asgard mourns Frigga, including Loki,
from his cell. So much to talk about here.
The way they portrayed the curse armor in this
movie I thought was really cool. And he was
definitely as strong as he's supposed to be.
Because curse in the comics is about twice
as strong as Thor. And Thor is stronger than
a motherfucker. So this guy is incredibly strong.
And I think they did a good job of showcasing
that power and just, you know, his ability
to punch his way out of prison, essentially.
Yeah, he literally punched through a force
field. That was wild. Frigga's final fight against
Malekith I thought was badass. She turned into
a total freaking warrior chick just slashing
him across the face and stuff. Rene Russo was
badass with that sword. I don't know if that
was entirely her in all those shots, but I
was impressed. So it was incredibly tragic when
Malekith had cursed Stapper. Yeah, that was
a great scene. I love the fact that they depicted
her as this trickster. It really led credence
to the idea that she had a close relationship
with Loki and maybe like taught him everything
he knows. and gave him reason and justification
for why he would be upset by her death enough
to team up with his rival. The scene when Loki
learns that Frigid died, he kind of takes it
in stride with a stone face and then unleashes
his might subtly just by clenching his fist
and all the furniture around his room goes flying.
You see the storm of emotion that's welling
inside of him. Yeah, totally. Regarding the
fight... of the Dark Elves versus the Asgardian
forces. The Dark Elves are cloaked from Asgard
and from Heimdall in particular. He was not
able to detect their invasion. And when they
fly past his sentry post, I thought the movie
got very Star Wars-esque because you have these
like Viking ship-inspired crafts shooting like
light lasers at these Dark Elf ships that are
almost like flying swords the way they like
crash into stuff. It was incredibly imaginative.
Dude. Those ships are way cooler than TIE fighters.
The Elves ships, they were really cool. I've
never seen anything like that in any sort of
sci-fi spacefaring action scene. You know, it
was really cool. Dude, they did here. Why do
people hate this movie? It makes no sense. They
just need to watch that scene again. Hell,
yeah. What did you think of the funeral scene
when they shot the flaming arrow onto Frigga's
boat and then it turned into stars that floated
up into the cosmos? I thought that was really
heartfelt and a really good way of like reimagining
a god version of a Viking funeral. Yeah, it
was more emotional than I even remembered. I
think it was the music. The movie has a beautiful
score and the theme that's playing as they send
up these like magic light ball, like paper
lantern-esque lights into the sky was just breathtaking.
Back to the story. To prevent another invasion
into Asgard, Thor develops a plan to take Jane
to the Dark World, Svartalheim. to draw Malekith
there where he can extract the Aether and then
Thor can destroy it. Odin denies his request,
believing Malekith obtaining the Aether is too
great a risk. Thor then conspires with his
friends to steal Jaina away in secret, and he
breaks Loki out of prison for his help since
the God of Mischief knows the secret way out
of Asgard. The whole heist scene that happens
in the second act of this movie was incredible.
It's so much fun. Especially because that's
when Loki really comes into play. You know,
and that scene where Thor approaches his brother
and we see him lying on the floor just in agony.
That was a great brotherly moment. And, you
know, when Loki's giving Thor shit and transforms
into Captain America and everything like that,
it's just a series of great moments one right
after the other during this whole heist portion.
Yeah, I agree. My favorite part was where Loki
was like, this is the dumbest idea. You're
taking the biggest ship and you're trying to
escape with it. And then Thor just like pushes
him out of the ship. That was hilarious. That
was great. I had forgotten that Zachary Levi
was in this film. Yeah, he plays Fandral, the
dashing. He was actually recast from the actor
who played the character in the first film.
And he did a great job. He does a fantastic
job. He has a very like Errol Flynn demeanor
about him that just suits the character so
well. Yeah. There was another great scene that
happened around this point in the story where
Thor and Loki are on Svartalheim traveling toward
Malekith and Thor tells his brother like, and
Loki's like, you can trust my rage. I thought
that was fantastic character building and relationship
building. Oh, that and the whole conversation
preceding it, that was fantastic stuff. Right.
Loki blames Thor for him being imprisoned during
his mother's death, but Thor was like, actually
you're to blame for that. And it's just like,
the conflict there is brilliant. Thor and Loki
confront Melekith and the Dark Elves. When it
appears, Loki betrays Thor and cuts off his
hand. However, the illusion is revealed when
Thor's hand reappears as he uses Mjolnir's
lightning in an attempt to destroy the Aether
as it's extracted from Jain. The attempt proves
fruitless however, and Malekith acquires his
prize before fleeing, leaving Kirst to battle
Thor and Loki. Loki kills Kirst with one of
his own gravity grenades, but is stabbed in
the process and seemingly dies in Thor's arms.
Man, okay, so what did you think the first
time you saw Loki's apparent betrayal in this
movie? Dude, I was pissed and shocked. I was
incredibly surprised. I did not see it coming.
But I also thought like classic Loki, you know,
like he can't trust him. But it was surprising
to me just how harsh he seemingly went about
it, where he was like, I'm Loki of Jotunheim.
I asked for one thing, a good place to watch
Asgard burn. I'm like, well, this guy holds
a grudge like none other. The emotions that
just like surged through the audience when watching
this movie the first time when it was revealed
that it was all a trick. and that Loki and Thor
were actually working together. You know, first
you have the relief that Loki's not that big
of a douchebag. Then you have the relief that
it looks like their plan is going to be carried
out and, you know, they're going to destroy
the Aether and save the day and work together.
And it was all just fantastic. And then you
combine that with what happened shortly after
where Loki seemingly dies. And it's nothing
short of a roller coaster. It was so thrilling
to watch. I just loved the drama of it. On
top of that, you have... Loki's real betrayal
where he takes the throne of Asgard. And yeah,
this is like peak Thor and Loki. Guys, like
who dislikes this movie? You're wrong, you're
wrong. I thought it was particularly badass
how Loki seemingly died and how Loki killed
Kurs. Like Kurs was just laying waste to Thor,
you know. He was even deflecting Mjolnir being
thrown at him and stuff like that, because he's
just that strong. But then Loki runs a sword
through Kurs, Kurs not even really being affected.
uses that same sword that's going through his
body to impale Loki, but Loki basically sacrifices
himself to get in close and pull one of Curse's
gravity bombs. It was a fascinating sequence
of events right there. Yeah, honestly, my favorite
part of the whole movie. This whole scene was
just great. Yeah. Back to the story, Thor and
Jane retreat to a cave where Jane discovers
another portal between Svartalheim and Earth.
Back in London, she and Thor regroup with Darcy
and Erik Selvig where they determine the center
of the convergence will be in Greenwich, England.
When Malekith and the Dark Elves arrive, Thor
battles them as Jane and Erik use gravitational
anomaly detectors to help him out. I still
don't understand how the humans were able to
create like portals and stuff with these tool
things. I don't know. It was just, it was too
much. They were MacGuffins for sure. They weren't
created to generate portals. They just happened
to be able to tap into that kind of energy
because they were made to detect gravitational
anomalies. I don't know if the science quite
checks out on that, but you know, that's one
of the issues with this climactic battle to
begin with. You're saying that, you know, there's
mumbo jumbo in this movie. This is really,
I feel like the only thing that's mumbo jumbo.
This is the only thing that doesn't make sense
to me. Yeah. Well, largely also because Thor
was able to use them as such powerful tools
against his enemy. when he was like throwing
him into his arms and then Jane was using her
computer to transport Malekith's body parts
and stuff like that. They were kind of cheating,
I think. Absolutely. I guess is a way to put
it. And I guess you're right that Malekith
was too weak in the sense that Kurs was blocking
shots from Yolner, but it just took one shot
from Yolner to essentially destroy Malekith.
Well, the final shot from Thor didn't destroy
Malekith. It transported him limbless. to Svartalheim
where eventually the ship crashed onto him
and that's what destroyed Malekith. That's fair.
That's true. But we're not quite there yet.
Thor's battle against Malekith goes between
the realms of Earth, Svartalheim, Vanaheim,
and Jotunheim as the Convergence reaches precise
alignment. Thor loses Mjolnir in the fight
and Malekith begins shrouding the universe in
darkness. Thor uses the gravitational anomaly
detectors to teleport Malekith away from the
Convergence and back into the Dark World. The
Elves ship also gets transported there where
it falls and crushes Malekith, destroying him.
Like I just said. In addition to all the substandard
stuff going on during this climax, I didn't
like how they disrupted the action by having
Thor take the underground train to get back
to Greenwich. I thought it was a needless break
that really sapped the great momentum that
they had built up during the battle as they
were just basically flying through all these
different realms, battling each other. No, I
100% agree. It's just that stupid Marvel bathos
that they think is funny. But I'm like, come
on, stop. Yeah, I was like, get back to it,
guys. Hurry up. Hurry up. It turns the climactic
anti-climactic really is what it did. Right.
Exactly. Especially the stuff with Darcy and
her intern, too. Like what we no one cared
about them. We did not need to see that stuff
during the main battle. You know, Darcy, Jane,
Ian, Sylveig, Mew Mew. That was pretty funny,
but unnecessary. Thor returns the Aether to
Asgard where he tells Odin that he denies the
throne and wishes to remain with Jain on Earth.
Odin accepts Thor's request but as Thor leaves,
Odin is revealed to be Loki in disguise. Thor
returns to Earth and reunites with Jain. Meanwhile,
Thor's friends Volstagg and Sif give the Aether
to the Collector to keep it separate from Asgard's
other Infinity Stone, the Tesseract. What did
you think of the reveal when you saw Loki sitting
on the throne in the final shot before the
credits rolled? Dude, I loved that. That was
like jaw dropping, just like, holy shit. That
was such a great villain moment. Like if you
and I ever did a top 10 bonus episodes of like
the best villain moments, that's gotta be up
there. Oh, for sure. Hands down. I remember
during the mid credit scene where we're on nowhere
with the collector, I just thought everything
felt so bizarre, but that's because we hadn't
been introduced to the world of Guardians of
the Galaxy yet, which was totally unlike anything
else that we had seen this point in the MCU.
and the scene still feels really strange to
me. It was directed by James Gunn. The cinematography
is different. Yeah, and that adds to the disjointed
feeling you get when watching it. It really
should have been the post-credits scene. They
should have flipped the post and mid-credits
scenes, I feel. Yeah, yeah. The final end-credits
scene was Thor returning back to Earth and
he and Jane embracing each other, but I think
audiences really needed that type of closure
within the main story itself, not just tacked
on. for sure, especially considering how many
people I still, to this day, see leave during
the credits at a Marvel movie. I'm like, what
are you doing? It's a Marvel movie. But that
brings us to the end of the film. I have very
few bad things to say about it, honestly. I
appreciate this movie more now than I did back
when I first watched it, and I really liked
it when I first watched it. I never quite understood
the flack that it got from fans. This is what
I want my Thor movie to be, essentially. Overall,
the high fantasy worldbuilding and story align
with what the Norse mythological superheroes
adventures should be. Generic villain notwithstanding,
I give this film 4 stars and a fresh rating
on Rotten Tomatoes. Yeah, I definitely think
it's worthy of a 4 star rating. This is the
same rating we gave Man of Steel in the first
Wonder Woman movie. I think it's up there.
I mean, even though the villain is pretty bad
and the humans are kind of annoying, they're
not so annoying to ruin the film. And there
are so many other things that just make up
for it. I think it's a spectacular movie. Definitely
the best Thor movie. I will fight you if you
say it's Thor Ragnarok, because you are wrong.
You don't have to fight me, man. Right there
with you. Sweet. Not that you would win anyway.
Oh, dude, I would totally stop you. That does
it for this review. Let us know what you thought
about the movie by writing to us at dynamicduelpodcast
at gmail.com or by visiting us on Instagram,
which you can find a link to on our show notes.
or by visiting our website at dynamicduel.com.
And on our site, you could also find a link
to our Patreon page, where you could join our
dynamic 2.0 tier and chat with us and fellow
listeners, our fantastic 4 tier, which gets
you bonus content to each month, our X force
tier that makes you an executive producer of
this podcast, or our newest tier that lets
you join our DynaMic podcast network. And guys,
please don't forget to rate our show on Apple
podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser, or on our website.
In our next episode, we will be doing a duel
between the DC villain Psycho Pirate and the
X-Men villain Mastermind. Both of these characters
have a lot to do with like mental illusions,
so it should be fun. And this of course is
in lead up to our review of the animated DC
film Crisis on Infinite Earths Part 2. Right,
which comes out at the end of the month. But
that does it for this episode, we want to give
a big thanks to our executive producers Ken
Johnson, John Sturowski, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin
Belcom, Mickey Montagian, Brandon Estergard,
Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yatin, Austin Wissolowski,
AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Adam Spies, Andrew
Schunk, Dean Molesky, and Devin Davis, our
newest executive producer. Thank you so much
Devin for supporting this podcast and for influencing
what you hear on this show. We'll talk to you
guys next week. Up, up and away. True Believers.
There's a convergence happening right now. In
my pants.