This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
a weekly show where we review superhero films
and debate the superiority between Marvel and
DC by comparing their characters in stat-based
battle simulations. I'm Johnny DC. And I'm
his twin brother Marvelous Joe. And in this
episode, we are reviewing the latest direct-to-video
DC animated film, part two of a three-part trilogy,
Justice League, Crisis on Infinite Earths.
Of course, it's based on a comic of the same
name. Was it as good as part one? We'll let
you know later on in the review. Before that
we're going to break down the comic book movie
news from the past week, of which it's all Marvel
news. We got the Deadpool and Wolverine official
trailer, and we also learned that Kraven the
Hunter has been pushed back to December. As
always we list our segment times in our episode
description, so feel free to check out the
show notes if you want to skip ahead to a particular
topic. Guys our artificially intelligent duel
simulator AJ9K has a quick message for our listeners,
so listen up. Why hello there. Do you love
listening and chatting about Marvel and DC?
Then become a part of the dynamic duel community
on Patreon where you can choose from three tiers.
The dynamic 2-0 tier lets you listen to this
podcast without ads and gives you access to
its Discord chat group where you can chat with
Johnny DC and Marvelous Joe. The fantastic 4
tier gives you that and more with two bonus
episodes each month including bloopers and top
10 shows where Johnny and Joe count down your
favourite Marvel and DC subjects. The X-Force
tier makes you an executive producer of Dynamic
Duel, where every month you help the host choose
what to review and who to fight against each
other. And finally, the Dynamite Podcast Network
tier allows aspiring podcasters to create their
own battle-focused show using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and consultation,
and get you simulation results to announce
on your show. Pitch the twins your show via
email at dyna
them on social media. Check it out at patreon.com
slash dynamic duel. Pip pip cheerio. Thanks
AJ 9k. And thanks to everyone who supports the
podcast. Be sure guys to tune into the shows
and the DynaMic podcast network this week,
including Max Destruction, which pits your
favorite action heroes from film and television
against each other. This week, I believe hosts
Ken and Scotty will pit Mad Max against Jack
Burton from Big Trouble in Little China. Also
make sure to check out the Sinjo World podcast,
where host Zachary Hepburn speculates on fights
between fan favorite anime and manga characters.
There's actually no episode coming out this
Thursday, but if you like anime and manga, definitely
check out his show. On the Console Combat podcast,
hosts John and Dean find out who would win in
fights between popular video game characters.
In yesterday's episode, they found out who would
win between Detective Nick Valentine from Fallout
4 and Detective Cole Phelps from L.A. Noire.
Visit dynamic podcasts dot com or click the
link in our show notes to listen to all of the
shows in the dynamic podcast network. And if
you guys have ever been a fan of dynamic duel,
you owe it to yourselves to check out the rankers
podcast where you can listen to Jonathan and
I take a more holistic approach in their latest
episode to the Marvel versus DC debate. It was
a whole lot of fun. I felt like it was a Marvel
and DC debate that Jonathan and I had been prepping
our entire lives for. So definitely check out
the rankers podcast. In fact, you know, Marvel
fans, if you have no interest in hearing a
review about Justice League Crisis on Infinite
Earths, I'd go check out the Rankers podcast
right now. Honestly, even if you're a DC fan,
like that episode is better than Crisis on
Infinite Earths, part two. I'm just going to
say it's a five star episode. Crisis on Infinite
Earths, part two is not five stars. Definitely
check out the Rankers podcast. But with that
out of the way, quick to the no prize. A no
prize is an award Marvel used to give out to
fans. Our version, the Dynamic duel No Prize,
is a digital award we post on Instagram for
the person that we feel gave the best answer
to our question of the week. Last week, we
asked, what casting announcement for a Marvel
or DC film were you the most hyped about when
you first heard about it and why? And this is
coming off of the lackluster news of... the
Jonathan and Martha Kent casting in the Superman
movie. But we thought it was a fun question.
We got a lot of great answers. So let's go ahead
and run down our honorable mentions as well
as the no prize winner. Our first honorable
mention goes to Travis Herndon, who said, What's
up, Dynamic Dudes? Travis here. Shout out to
my twins. So my pick would have to be Christian
Bale. I mean, when I heard that Christian Bale
was going to be gore to God butcher, I was
excited. I was high. Granted, Christian Bale
didn't look exactly like gore. go into comics
and Love and Thunder was underwhelming to say
the least. But come on, we have to admit we
were all hyped when we heard Christian Bale
as Gore the God Butcher. Yeah, I remember being
thrilled because Christian Bale is such a fantastic
actor and Gore the God Butcher is an equally
fantastic villain for Thor. I thought the next
Thor movie was going to be the next Batman
Begins or something like that. And that did
not happen. We'll say that. Nope, nope, nope.
No, honestly, I cannot admit that I was excited
for Kushra Bell's casting. I felt horribly
betrayed and heartbroken when I learned that
he was in a Marvel movie. I was like, what
are you doing? Well, DC had moved on from his
Batman at that point, so it was only fitting
that he comes over to Marvel's side. I just
wish that the character of Gore would have
been done more justice. Not that his portrayal
of Gore was bad. It was just that the movie
was so. off. If anything, Christian Bale was
actually the best part of Thor 11th Thunder,
but you know, being the best part of a turd
sandwich is still not great. Yeah, he absolutely
was the best part. But I do have to ask you,
how would you feel if like, Toby Maguire came
over to DC and played like Ted Kord or something?
Toby Maguire is probably my least favorite
Spider-Man actor, so I would not care. Okay,
what if Hugh Jackman came over to DC and played,
I don't know, Brainiac? Oh, that would be weird.
I mean, he'd be so covered in prosthetics,
I'd imagine that he'd be almost unrecognizable.
I would be interested in seeing that, for sure.
You only say that because you don't know what
it's like to be heartbroken, like I do. Great
answer, Travis. Our next honorable mention goes
to Gilly Macho, who said, What up guys, Gilly
Macho here. And the announcement I was most
excited for was Jon Berthold as the Punisher.
We've all seen Walking Dead, and I was a big
fan of the Shane character. And when I heard
he was coming to be the Punisher, you knew that
Blood and Gore was coming with him. So yep,
John Berthold as the Punisher. Yeah, I was thrilled
by this news. I had watched the first season
of Walking Dead and that was my first exposure
to the actor, John Bernthold. And when they
announced his casting, I immediately was super
hyped because even though I liked Ray Stevenson
as the Punisher, who played the character most
recently prior to this casting, John Bernthold.
just felt more like Frank Castle to me. You
know, he had that rage that he portrayed so
well in The Walking Dead. And also he seemed
more Italian, which The Punisher is. And it
just felt perfect. Yeah. Like everything you've
said, same, except I think I saw two seasons
of The Walking Dead. John Bernthal was a fantastic
actor. And yeah, I think in all of the fan
castings for an upcoming Punisher film or television
series, everyone was pushing him for the role,
including me. Yeah, I'm really glad that he's
coming back for the Daredevil born again series,
or, you know, he's heavily rumored to appear
again. I think he just captures the character
on a deeper level than any previous Punisher
actor has. For sure. Yeah, absolutely. Great
answer, Gilly. Our next honorable mention goes
to Judson Batty, who said, Hi guys, Judson
Batty here. I would say that the casting decision
I was most excited about was Pierce Brosnan
as Dr. Fate in Black Adam, because I wasn't
too hyped in the movie beforehand. But when
they cast a James Bond actor who was really
good, I knew that at the very least, no matter
how shit the rest of the film turned out to
be, Dr. Fate would be done well. And just really
made me excited for it. Leave it to the Brits
to say that a James Bond actor was the one
they were the most excited for. But you know
what? I am right there with you, man. I am
a huge fan of James Bond as people who have
listened to this podcast for a long time know.
And I was just seething with jealous rage. when
Pierce Brosnan was cast as Dr. Fate because
DC also got Timothy Dalton to play the chief
in the Doom Patrol television series and like
I'm wondering when a Bond actor is going to
join Marvel. Freaking never. I know that's
so heartbreaking. At one point I believe Daniel
Craig was going to play Baldur the Brave and
he had to back out but hopefully they find a
good role for Daniel Craig in a Marvel movie.
He's still my fan cast choice for Despero if
they ever do Despero in a DC movie. I'll take
George Lazenby at this point too. I mean, Sean
Connery is still alive and he's done LXG, so
you think he'd be up for a Marvel movie? Oh,
LXG, another DC imprint film. Damn it! Ha ha!
Ugh, James Bond actors are breaking my heart
over here. But in regards to Pierce Brosnan
as Dr. Fate, yeah, I was super stoked when I
heard this news as well. Pierce Brosnan is
absolutely the kind of quality actor you'd want
in a role that's sort of somewhat generic as
Kent Nelson. He could really bring that character
to life in a way that hasn't been done in the
comics. Also, I knew his voice was going to
be fantastic for the character of Dr. Fate,
and I was not wrong. He was awesome. Yeah, Pierce
Brosnan delivered on the hype for him in the
role. I think the movie gets undeserved flak
because I thought it was pretty entertaining
overall. And I was definitely pleased with Pierce
as Dr. Fate. It's actually a shame that he
won't be playing the character anymore, I think.
Yeah, well, I mean... For two reasons, one
because the character died in the movie and
also because the DCEU is over. But Gilly's
brother Scotty also gave Pierce Brosnan as Dr.
Fate for his answer. So shout out to Scotty.
I thought that was kind of coincidental too.
Yeah, out of all the casting people just really
love Pierce Brosnan. Yeah, who doesn't? But
the winner of this week's No Prize is Colby
Hentges who said, Hey boys, Colby Hentges. The
Marvel DC casting I was most hyped for was
Ryan Reynolds as Wade Wilson. He had done the
van Wilder and the waiting movie. So I knew
he could do the sophomore humor stuff. He did
the blade Trinity. So I knew he could do the
comic book action stuff. You guys, I went into
Wolverine origins. So hype.
Only to be let down so much, at least in that
film. Yeah, so hyped and then so disappointed.
X-Men Origins Wolverine was horrible and they
really fucked up the character of Deadpool.
So it was really nice when seven years later,
Ryan Weld's got the chance to do the character
justice in his own movie. He's pretty much the
perfect casting and he's a fan of the character.
He exemplifies Deadpool to a T. It's actually
hard to imagine. Deadpool now without Ryan
Reynolds voice. I think when I read Deadpool
comics nowadays He just so embodies the character
in a way that few actors are able to do You
know Robert Downey Jr. Did it Hugh Jackman
did it and I think you could add Ryan Reynolds
to that list And now that the MCU has lost
some of their a-list talents like Robert Downey
Jr I really think that Ryan Reynolds is the
biggest name that the MCU currently has in their
acting roster So I'm glad that he's able to
pick up some of the slack with this year's Deadpool
and Wolverine movie. That's true, actually.
Yeah, I wonder if one of the reasons that Marvel
isn't drawing as big of audiences as they used
to is just the lack of star power. It's possible.
An actor like Robert Downey Jr. can draw a
crowd on his own. And nowadays that kind of
pool just doesn't exist quite like it used
to. Which is interesting because some people
accuse Marvel of killing off the movie star.
People were caring more about the characters
as opposed to the actors playing them. But
yeah, maybe now actors matter more than people
realize. So great answer Colby, you win this
week's No Prize. Congrats on that. If you the
listener want a shot at winning your own No
Prize, stay tuned to later on this episode when
we'll be asking another question of the week.
And now that that's done, onto the news!
All right, this past week we got the trailer
for Deadpool and Wolverine. And while the first
teaser focused more on Deadpool and the TVA
and kind of set up the situation that he would
be going through, they only really teased that
shot of Wolverine in the shadows as he stabbed
Deadpool at the end of the teaser. We didn't
get a whole lot of Wolverine action in that
first preview. But in this trailer, they really
build upon the Deadpool and Wolverine relationship.
Oh, yeah, this trailer is almost entirely all
Wolverine, which is fitting considering, you
know, Wolverine shares the title with Deadpool.
So I'm not surprised that they dedicated a
trailer mostly to him. Like, there's very few
Deadpool jokes in this trailer. Right. Yeah.
So it wasn't as funny, but I think it's just
so hype inducing to see Hugh Jackman back in
the role, especially in that comics. Accurate
costume. Yeah, I was actually pretty happy
to see him. with no sleeves, because I didn't
love the yellow sleeves when we first got like
the set photos. But yeah, I'm glad to see that.
I'm just wondering if we're going to get to
see the mask before the movie comes out or if
they're going to make us pay to see it. Oh,
they're probably going to make us pay to see
the mask for sure. The trailer starts off with.
Wolverine in a bar similar to when we very first
saw the character in the first X-Men movie
that came out in the year 2000, which I thought
was pretty fitting. And it was just so jarring
to all of a sudden see Deadpool's stupid face
pop in the shot. And he's like, hey, Peanut,
that was pretty good. And Wolverine's like,
lady, I don't have time for this. Started out
with a bang. But then the trailer kind of goes
into dark territory because we see that this
particular variant of Wolverine, I'm not sure
if it's the same Wolverine that was in the
Logan movie or if it's a different multiversal
version of the character, but Basically, it
seems like he let his entire universe down somehow
by letting the X-Men die. Now, we see a shot
of this version of Wolverine standing, I think,
next to a bunch of tall monuments, maybe tombstones.
They kind of look like some of the Sentinel
ships from the Days of Future Past movie. So
it could be like a Sentinel situation that killed
all of his friends in the X-Men or If it's
the same version of Wolverine from the Logan
movie, then it was actually Professor X who
had like a seizure and killed the rest of the
X-Men. It's hard to say. I'm inclined to believe
that this is not the Logan version just because
it wasn't Wolverine's fault that the X-Men
died in that movie. Well, they can make it Wolverine's
reason that Professor X perhaps had the seizure.
Like he failed to get his medication on time
or, you know, something like that. Something
like that, yeah. I am inclined to think it's
the Logan version only because He suffered
from the same like claw ejection problem that
Rogan had in that movie. Yeah, he had ejectile
dysfunction. Right. Yeah. He doesn't later on
in the trailer, though. And it is glorious
to actually see those claws pop out of his blue
gloved hand with those like little metallic
slits, mirrors, knuckles. It's glorious. Yeah.
Just think him take swipes to Deadpool, which
actually, I guess, is an Easter egg call out
to the first Spider-Man movie. There's quite
a few. Easter eggs in this trailer, like there
was dog pool and Ant-Man's or Giant Man's helmet.
It took me a few viewings to catch quite a few
of them because everything happens so fast.
Oh yeah, there's a huge cast of characters in
this from, you know, Lady Deathstrike, Zazel,
we see Callisto from X-Men 3. There's a ton
of characters here, both from the Fox X-Men
franchise and, you know, with Ant-Man from the
MCU. We even see the guys jump from Ant-Man's
skull into a Dr. Strange portal. So it's possible
that Dr. Strange is even in this movie, which
would be wild to see. That moment when they're
jumping out of the eye into the portal with
Madonna's like a prayer playing, like I got
chills. Like I just, I cannot wait to see this
in the theater. I'm so pumped. I hope it's not
Dr. Strange that makes a cameo. I hope it's
Wong's friend Madison, who like got his sling
ring. I hope it's Wong, now that you said that.
I think that'd be hilarious. It probably will
be the guys everywhere in this phase. He's
made a lot of cameos like She Hulk, Shang Chi
for sure. The movie comes out in theaters July
26th, and all I have to say is, let's fucking
go, let's fucking go. Did this trailer sell
you on the movie? Like, do you want to see another
trailer after this? Yes, I would love another
trailer, actually. Although I don't need one.
I just kind of want some more context into
what the movie is about, because I feel like
we haven't really gotten that too much yet.
Yeah. I didn't like this trailer as much as
the first one, so yeah, I'm still hoping to
get one that really merges the humor of Deadpool
with the action of Wolverine. More so than
either of these two trailers did. I'm sure we
will get another trailer after this, and I'm
sure it'll be more of a story trailer. Yeah,
that'd be cool. Maybe something more with Cassandra
Nova. She was cool to see in this trailer as
well. Yeah, she looks like she's gonna be pretty
formidable. You know, being Professor X's sister.
But speaking of all these different characters
that appeared in the Deadpool and Wolverine
trailer that brings us to our question of the
week.
Other than Wolverine and the characters that
you saw in the trailer, what Fox X-Men character
do you most hope appears in Deadpool and Wolverine
and why? There's a lot to choose from, both
from the Patrick Stewart Ian McKellen era, the
James McAvoy Michael Fassbender era, the previous
Deadpool movies, the Wolverine movies, the new
Mutants movie, there's a lot going on here,
so who do you guys want to see most? Record
your answer at dynamicduel.com by clicking
on the red microphone button in the bottom right
hand corner of the screen, which will prompt
you to leave us a voicemail. Your message could
be up to 30 seconds long, and don't forget
to leave your name in case we include you on
the podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer
and award that person a Dynamic Duel No Prize
that we'll post to Instagram. Be sure to answer
before May 4th. In other news, we learned this
past week that Craven the Hunter, the movie
being produced by Sony in the Sony Spider-Man
universe, has been pushed back from August
30th, 2024 to December 13th, 2024. So it's no
longer a summer release. It's now a Christmas
time release. And I think if they just keep
pushing this movie back, that would be the
best thing for everyone. I mean, this is its
fourth release date, right? I think so. Yeah,
it's been pushed back quite a bit. I know initially
it was supposed to come out for October of
2023. But then I think the studio wanted to
have Aaron Taylor Johnson promote it. and he
couldn't due to the strike at the time. So yeah,
they pushed it back to this year and it just
keeps getting pushed back. Honestly, I wasn't
surprised by this pushback. This fall seems
kind of crowded for comic book films and there
really isn't anything comic book related being
released in December, which tends to be a good
money making month. I just don't know about
this film making money during the holiday season
because it looks like it's gonna be kind of
violent. Yeah, but that might be the best thing
about it, honestly. because as Sony has shown
us with recent releases like Madame Web and
Morbius and Let There Be Carnage, the studio
is just not really great at making the Spider-Man
spinoff movies and it doesn't seem like they're
really going anywhere. At first, Sony was really
pushing the idea of all these movies being
interconnected and they kind of backpedaled
on that, especially since the release of Madame
Web and stated like oh, this is kind of like
in its own separate standalone universe thing
because really nobody's liking these movies.
And if they say that they're all connected,
people are even less inclined to go see them.
Wait, so you're telling me that we're not going
to see Morbius and Vulture and Craven and everyone
team up? It's looking like that's likely not
going to be the case. That's embarrassing. I
feel bad for Sony. Holy cow. I feel bad for
Sony, too. Not really, though. They kind of
shut the bed and they should be forced to sleep
in it now. Yeah. And then eventually just give
the Spider-Man rights back to Marvel. That's
what we want to see, right? Very true. I have
very little hope for this movie, which is a
shame because I am a big fan of the character
of Craven the Hunter. If you want to learn
more about him, if you haven't read about him
in the comics, go ahead and check out our Vixen
vs Craven the Hunter duel episode. But speaking
of James Bond earlier, the rumor is that Aaron
Taylor Johnson is going to be the next James
Bond. So part of me kind of hopes that Craven
the Hunter does really well at the box office
so that he doesn't lose that chance because
I do think that Aaron Taylor Johnson would make
a good Bond. but if this movie bombs, he might
be seen as box office poison. I don't know.
I don't know if I buy him his Bond. I think
he's too short. You know who should be Bond?
Theo James. I was talking about this with a
guy at work. Theo James should be Bond. Fuck
no! That James Franco lookalike guy? What?
I don't like it. Plus, he's like already 40
years old. It wouldn't work. Isn't Aaron Taylor
Johnson like close to 40? No, he's 33. Fuck!
Why do I feel so old? Anyway, off the topic
of James Bond, I guess ultimately I'm pushing
for Craven the Hunter to do well and be good.
It's not, don't worry about it.
But I guess that does it for all the news for
this week. So let's move on to the main event
of this episode where we review the animated
film Justice League, Crisis on Infinite Earths
Part 2.
Justice League Crisis on Infinite Earths Part
2 is the second of a 3-part animated film saga
that itself is the conclusion of a 10-part animated
film universe known as the Tomorrowverse. Though
the Crisis trilogy actually has ties going back
to the previous DC animated movie universe
that began with Justice League The Flashpoint
Paradox in 2013. Now the DC AMU had a phenomenal
and heartbreaking ending. in the animated film
Justice League Dark Apocalypse War, which we
gave a 5 star review, despite the fact that
its ending was somewhat ambiguous. Considering
that it could be argued the Crisis on Infinite
Earth trilogy is 11 years in the making and
there are some rumors it will lead straight
into James Gunn's new DC universe that includes
animated films, I feel like I should be a whole
hell of a lot more excited about Crisis. But
it's really hard to be considering the way the
producers have structured the stories. And
make no mistake, there is a structure, as you
can now see easter eggs across the Tomorrowverse
films and even some DC animated shorts. But
so far, the whole is the sum of its parts,
and if you've been following our reviews of
the Tomorrowverse films, despite a few exceptions,
the parts aren't that great. and are only marginally
made better by the story reveals that come
perhaps too little too late. Now, I don't want
to spoil those reveals for anyone, so if you
haven't seen Crisis on Infinite Earths Part
2, well, I'm guessing you haven't seen Part
1 either, and maybe you're just waiting until
Part 3 comes out later this year to hear whether
the whole thing is worth investing your time.
I can't really say Part 2 is worth your time
because it feels very much like a mere stepping
stone to get to part three. It's just something
you kind of have to get through. And honestly,
I really wish that wasn't the case. Yeah, my
first impression after seeing Crisis on Infinite
Earths part two was that the story seemed to
kind of be treading water as we went into the
third part. The first movie I thought was really
interesting from a narrative perspective with
the Flash kind of skipping through time. The
second movie also did a lot of time skipping.
So it seems to be kind of like a theme within
this trilogy of films to not tell the story
linearly. It just kind of makes everything
a little bit disjointed and hard to follow and
not as enjoyable as it necessarily could be.
Well, yeah, the time skipping in this film happened
only in the first half of it. After that, everything
was pretty much happening in real time or not
real time, but in the present, I should say.
I really wanted to like this movie because like
you, I really liked part one, again despite
its unconventional story structure. The second
film in a lot of trilogies is arguably the
best. You know, the Dark Knight, Empire Strikes
Back, The Two Towers is perfection. This film,
not so much. You forgot Spider-Man 2 and X-Men
2. Hey, you know, that's also valid. But this
film is not better than the first one, though
due to the hit or miss nature of the Tomorrowverse,
I shouldn't be surprised. It is very much the
second act of a three-part story, though the
second act is supposed to be the most exciting
act as it ramps up to the climax. Narratively,
you set up the conflict in Act 1, in Act 2 the
conflict escalates until it reaches its maximum
potential, and Act 3 is a come down from that
high where order is restored. Now obviously
in the trilogy, conflict and action will continue
into the third film. but I feel like this film
didn't pack enough of a punch to get me excited
for the third one. And I honestly have a hard
time reconciling why that is. I mean, the main
characters in this film were legitimately interesting,
I felt. Supergirl, Monitor, Psycho Pirate were
my favorite parts of the film. Like, I found
Supergirl way more interesting in this film
than I did in Legion of Superheroes. And the
central theme of how emotions develop in us
and affect us was fairly strong throughout
the movie. It was just everything with the other
heroes and around the towers that I felt dragged
the film down. Like I hated what they did with
Batman here. He didn't learn any kind of lesson
about teamwork or camaraderie or family, and
he should have by the end. Like the cameos
they had, like Batman Beyond, Commandy, John
Constantine, were all so small and didn't amount
to much, if anything at all. The film just didn't
know how to juggle its characters in a way
that was as satisfying as the strong single
narrative focus that they had with The Flash
in Part 1, or the character ensemble that was,
say, Avengers Infinity War. Or Justice League
Dark Apocalypse War. That movie, I think, had
a huge cast, just as large as this one, but
it just juggled everything better. Yeah, absolutely.
Another problem with the film, I feel, were
the stakes. Like in the first film, you really
felt the threat of the end of the world. a
lot more than he did here, I feel. Like, any
time there was an antimatter wave that passed
over, the threat was pretty much non-existent
for the most part. Yeah, I was never really
nervous for any of the worlds and, you know,
I knew that there were just so many Earths
that the characters could regroup at. No one
single Earth mattered compared to the whole
of the multiverse, you know? So, the movie's
premise kind of works against itself in that
regard. But really, this movie seems to be more
of a character study than anything else, really
focusing on, you know, Supergirl, Psycho Pirate,
and the Monitor. Yeah, and I feel like that's
not a great approach for a massive epic event
film. I mean, it's not like in the comic book
Crisis on Infinite Earths, we got backstories
for like Psycho Pirate or anything like that.
I don't know if it was the right approach here.
It's interesting, for sure, but it doesn't
really lend itself to epic storytelling, I guess.
Yeah. If anything, the character studies take
away from the overarching narrative that you
would expect in a big, multiversal crossover
event. Absolutely, absolutely. Now, I liked
this film. I'm ragging on it, but it wasn't
terrible. It doesn't get me excited for part
three, but it is, as I mentioned earlier, a
stepping stone to get there. So it's something.
Outside of that, I don't have much to say about
the film that I haven't said about part one
and other Tomorrowverse films. You know. The
first act premises are strong, but the story
does always stick the landing. The voice acting
is great. The character designs are great. The
animation can be a little bit sticky. Right.
But yeah, if you've listened to our reviews
of DC animated films recently, you've heard
it all before. Let's go ahead and talk about
the main characters in the movie in our character
breakdown, starting with Supergirl slash Kara
Zor-El. Now, Meg Donnelly does a fantastic
job voicing Supergirl. I was really rooting
for her to play Supergirl in James Gunn's DCU,
but she lost out to Milly Alcock and I'm not
gonna lie, I was disappointed. Yeah, the actress
was great in the Legion of Superheroes movie,
which is really more of a Supergirl movie,
and she was great here. I think she brings a
lot of emotional weight to the character, just
like she did in the Legion of Superheroes animated
movie, which was not a great film, but she
was definitely the best part of that, I think.
Yeah, I agree. We learn that immediately after
Krypton's destruction, Supergirl was begrudgingly
rescued by the Monitor, who had observed the
death of the planet. Supergirl, suffering from
amnesia, was raised by the Monitor for timeless
decades before she realized that he knew about
what happened to her homeworld, at which point
she left him due to his apathy. Despite him
later imparting some of his power to her in
order for her to gather an army to protect the
multiverse, Her distrust and anger toward the
monitor continued to grow, allowing Psycho Pyre
to manipulate her to where she ultimately kills
the monitor. Her arc revolves around loss, you
could say. The loss of her mom, loss of her
world, loss of time with her cousin, loss of
the Legion, and ultimately a loss of control
over everything that's happening in her life
and the universe. and all of that feeling of
loss results in her ultimately losing a father
figure at her own hands. It's pretty tragic.
For sure, yeah. Everything that Supergirl has
gone through has been quite heartbreaking.
I guess I am a little bit confused though what
happened when the monitor imparted some of
his power onto her. I thought that was going
to transform her into Harbinger. It did transform
her into Harbinger. She could just go in and
out of her Harbinger mode when she's traversing
the multiverse. Actually, that's one of the
more interesting changes they d- made to the
crisis story because in the comic harbinger
is Lila Michaels a separate character from
Supergirl and Lila does end up being manipulated
by the anti-monitor into killing the monitor
in the comics but here the way they sort of
wrote around that and having Supergirl angry
at monitor and blaming him for things like the
destruction of Krypton it was really well written
I thought. Yeah, the movie is able to kind of
retcon and streamline the crisis on Infinite
Earth's movie in a really interesting way. For
sure. That's probably the best thing about
it. Even though the execution isn't always successful,
you have to admire the approach. With almost
every film in the Tomorrowverse, you could say
that. Yeah, yeah. It's like everything sounds
good on paper, and then somewhere it just gets
botched along the way, which is unfortunate,
because it's like the Tomorrowverse should be
so much better than it is. It really should
be. It really should be. Moving on to Monitor
aka MaruNoVu, he was voiced by Jonathan Adams,
who delivers a very understated performance,
appropriately so. I thought he was perfect
in this role. And the guy apparently has a lot
of experience playing god-like characters.
Like he's voiced Darkseid, Galactus, Dormammu,
King the Conqueror. He's just a fantastic voice
actor. What a badass. Totally, right? What a
resume. Now the Monitor's arc revolves around
Supergirl and the feelings he develops not just
for her, but life in the multiverse as a whole,
because of her, enter inspirations and criticisms
that spur him to reject his calling and take
action to protect everything. He assumes the
antimatter waves bombarding the multiverse
are a natural phenomena, but by the end he learns
that not only are they coming from a specific
individuel, the Anti-Monitor, but that everything
that has transpired is perhaps his fault. I
imagine the next film will get a flashback as
to why the anti-monitor hates the monitor,
and I'm really curious to see how much influence
recent comics like The Dark Side War or Dark
Knight's Metal will have on the story. Why does
DC feel the need to rip off Marvel and characters
like The Watcher with like this enigmatic race
of beings who are sworn only to observe and
not interfere with the cosmic level events.
The fuck's that about? That's straight from
the Crisis comic. And? All right, let's find
out who came first. Obviously, the Watcher
came first. He came out in the 60s. Crisis was
an 80s book. Be more original is what I guess.
Yeah, I guess he came out in 1982. Damn it.
But I mean, he just looks cooler, you know?
Like, what's with the giant bald head of the
Watcher? Weird. Looks like a big baby. What
do you think it is that Monitor ended up developing
empathy? I think it was because he was never
as close to anyone as he was to Supergirl. He
always tried to keep his distance. But because
of satellite's actions, his sentient spaceship
as it were, he was forced into a position where
he either cared for this young woman that was
rescued or he just callously eject her back
out into space. I don't think he liked the idea
of her death because he was more aware of her
individuel existence compared to the nameless
victims of Krypton. And I think he just developed
what is it called, propinquity. You know, where
you develop feelings for the people you are
closest in proximity to. I think it's as simple
as that. Moving on to Psycho Pirate, aka Charles
Halsted. He was voiced by Jeffrey Arren. And
I know this guy. He was in 500 Days of Summer.
He was in the Ringer, in Garden State, in a
bunch of TV shows. I did not know he did voice
acting and he did a fantastic job with Psycho
Pirate, though, you know, based on his history,
he probably should have had an English accent.
But that aside, yeah, Jeffrey Arendt, great
voice. His voice, I have to say, is pretty damn
haunting. Like, I think out of all the main
characters in this movie, he was the most interesting
every time he was talking about his backstory
or just speaking in general. I was pretty much
hooked. Oh yeah, it was really interesting.
What I found most interesting early on was that
they didn't go with the Roger Hayden version
of the character, like the one I talked about
in our last episode. They went with Charles
Halstead, who they not only made a metahuman
empath, you know, removing any reference to
the Medusa mask, but they also made him a multiversal
entity who's gone by names such as Dr. Spectro
or Rainbow Raider in different universes. Which
was hilarious because we saw Dr. Spectro in
the Blue Beetle animated short that ties into
this film and he's playing with people's emotions.
Yeah, that was interesting. It also serves to
solve one of the questions that you and I had
regarding the Justice Society World War II movie.
Because I remember we were bitching in that
movie about why Psycho Pirate didn't have his
Medusa mask and how like the Medusa mask would
have made a great artifact MacGuffin for that
film and everything like that. But yeah, this
version of the character never used the Medusa
mask. all his empathic abilities were due to
his metahuman nature. Dude, so I was listening
to our review of Justice Society World War
Two in lead up to writing this review, and we
were so wrong about so many things. Like, not
only were we bitching about a psycho pirate,
we were bitching about Wonder Woman and how
she'll probably never be seen in another movie
again. It was just so many things. Well, like,
how are we supposed to know? We weren't we weren't.
But because Justice Society World War Two took
place in another timeline and we weren't sure
how that would fold into like the main tomorrow
versus timeline. But as it turns out, there
really isn't a main tomorrow versus timeline.
You could say it's Earth one. But no, you're
right. We had no way of knowing that this was
going to happen. It does make my review like
pretty obsolete, though, I would say. There
are so many things I got wrong in it. It's embarrassing.
This movie doesn't make me like that movie
anymore. I don't want to say it redeems the
movie, but it does address some of the criticisms
we had about the film. Now the original backstory
they created for Charles Halstead in this film
was wild. His actions in the movie stem from
the fact that he simply hates people because
he's constantly feeling their emotions and feels
that the world would be better if everyone
just felt what he was feeling all the time.
He's an interesting character at times being
somewhat sympathetic. Well, also at times shockingly
evil. And I'd say it's probably an upgrade
to what we got in the Crisis on Infinite Earth's
comic. Yeah. Well, I mean, this origin story
just seemed better than the comics version of
his origin that we learned last week, where
basically the guy just hated his boss and so
became like an expert on emotions or some stupid
shit. It's so dumb. Yeah. That scene where the
dude killed all his classmates and. the German
officers came into the school and they saw all
these students hanging from the ceiling. That
shit was nightmare fuel. Like, I remember watching
that and thinking, like, when the fuck did
this become a horror film? Oh, my God. Oh, yeah,
it was straight out of the horror genre. That
was wild. I do kind of miss the Medusa mask,
though. Like, I generally like a lot of the
character designs, really like the character
designs of the Tomorrowverse characters, but
not Psycho Pirate. I don't like being able to
see his. face as much as I do. I'm used to
not seeing his face in the comics. Well, the
Medusa mask is just such a cool concept, you
know, where it like portrays an emotion that
is projected onto its victims. Yeah, it's just
a great visual that you think would do really
well in a medium like movies, you know, for
sure, for sure. I can't wait to see that adapted
into live action. That'll be so cool. Just
like this liquid gold mask. Hell, yeah. If they
choose to do that, they should. Psycho pirate
is a really great villain that just needs to
be adapted. Heck, based off of this origin,
I could see like a psycho pirate live action
movie, a la The Joker, where it's just like
focused around him. I guess. I don't know. It
could be a horror film. Why not? Hmm. I'd watch
it. I wouldn't because I don't like horror movies.
Where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
DynaMic Podcast Network presents Console Combat,
where video game legends brawl every Monday.
DynaMic Podcast Network Comic Book Titans smash
every Tuesday. Max Destruction, where TV and
action heroes battle every Wednesday. And Sendro
World, where anime champions clash every Thursday.
Join us as we speculate on the matches and armed
with the power of mathematical simulations,
discover who will emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com,
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
But I think that does it for the character breakdown,
now let's move on to the story highlights.
The film begins with Joker and several other
Batman rogues attacking the tower that allows
the planet to become intangible and avoid the
waves of antimatter that are destroying entire
universes. With help from Bat family members
from across the multiverse, Earth-1 Batman
stops the Joker, though Batman disapproves of
the other's help. Now, this was a pointless
opening to the film. Like, I understand that
Batman is a draw commercially, but when you
have him just being a dick to everyone else,
it's not fun to watch. Right. Yeah, you want
to see the Bat family kicking gas, you know,
united and working together. It's kind of a
downer when you see Batman just being an asshole.
Really, the whole Batman storyline was inessential
to the entire narrative. And I don't know why
they kept revisiting it because he seemed no
more important than any other single other universe
that was protecting their own tower. Right,
right, exactly. And in that regard, you know,
cameos like Batman Beyond, which were really
used to help sell this movie in the trailers
and stuff like that, we got really excited.
That all felt kind of hollow and empty when
it just seemed kind of gratuitous. Oh yeah,
man, I was really excited, honestly, for Batman
Beyond, especially because Will Friedle was
returning to voice the role. he only got like
literally two lines. He also voiced Commandy
and he had way more lines as that character
than he did as Batman Beyond, which was unfortunate.
I guess you could rationalize Batman's behavior
in this film though as a sort of coping method
with witnessing the death of James Gordon. He
didn't want to lose anyone else close to him.
Although maybe that's not true because he wasn't
close to that version of James Gordon. and
he definitely wasn't close to all of his adoptive
children from other multiverses. He freaking
admitted to taking Dick Grayson back to the
orphanage in his universe. That's messed up.
Yeah, it kind of makes it feel like not my Batman,
right? Because like, right, my Batman would
take on a ward in Dick Grayson. Who the fuck
is this guy? For sure, for sure. Now in a flashback
to World War Two on Earth Two, Psycho Pirate
converses with an imprisoned Dr. Fate. recounting
his childhood as an empathic metahuman who absorbed,
amplified, and reflected the emotions of those
around him. Another flashback follows that goes
all the way back to the destruction of Krypton,
observed from a distance by the monitor in his
satellite ship, which notices and rescues Supergirl
amidst Krypton's ruin. Why do you think Dr.
Fate gave Psycho Pirate the ability to traverse
among the multiverse? We don't know that yet.
I'm hoping we'll learn that in the third film.
But I'm guessing it has something to do with
either a change of heart that comes from the
Psycho Pirate or some kind of... I don't know.
He's needed for some reason. Like, it's his
fate to be able to traverse the multiverse.
So, of course, Dr. Fate got involved and gave
him that ability. You think Psycho Pirate will
be redeemed in the third film? He certainly
was not in the comic. So, I don't know. I could
see them going either way. Did this scene with
Dr. Fate redeem... the character at all for
you from the Justice Society World War II movie.
A bit. He was much cooler in this film, partly
because we actually got to see him as Dr. Fate
in all of his glory. Now going back to Psycho
Pirates' past, his parents shipped him off
to a boarding school in Bavaria, where he suffered
under the amplified aggression of the school
boys. Over time he managed to control his power
and used it to kill, humiliate, and control
everyone in his school. Meanwhile, Monitor,
initially annoyed by Supergirl's presence,
helped her recuperate and began teaching her
about the multiverse and his ancient race who
observe events in the multiverse. As timeless
decades pass, Supergirl eventually finds her
Kryptonian ship on the satellite and is devastated
when she remembers Krypton's destruction. When
Supergirl confronts Monitor, he reveals that
her younger cousin is still alive as Superman
and Supergirl leaves Monitor, angry, to go to
her cousin. Now I like the rationale they had
for why Superman is older than Supergirl in
this universe. It's because she was aboard
the monitor ship where time does not pass. I
thought that was a great reasoning. Yeah, considering
that she was older when Krypton exploded and
K'Hellel was just a baby. Exactly. The character
of Satellite was pretty interesting. He was
like a more humanized version of Hell 9000
from 2001 of Space Odyssey. Yeah, yeah, he looked
pretty menacing with that like single eyeball.
But it turns out he was just a big old softy
who cared for Kara. He was like, whoops, I
accidentally saved her life. He had more empathy
than the monitor did. And it was almost like
he was trying to teach the character of the
monitor how to care about things. Yeah, I thought
the same thing. You almost have to wonder if
he was being manipulated by the presence at
all, because the specter at the end explicitly
said that the presence wanted the monitor to
feel empathy. Interesting, interesting. Now
the Psycho Pirate recounts his time as a Nazi
pirate captain whose ship sank and while adrift
at sea, discovered Atlantis, using his power
to manipulate Aquaman and his kingdom into being
Nazi allies, as we saw in the film Justice
Society World War II. As Psycho Pirate concludes
his story, he learns that his powers have no
effect on Dr. Fate before Dr. Fate teaches Psycho
Pirate a magic spell that would allow him to
travel to other universes. Meanwhile, As Monitor
observes the first waves of universe destroying
antimatter, he also observes Supergirl's heroic
actions at the conclusion of the Legion of
Superheroes film and is inspired to take action,
summoning her to a satellite once again where
he imbues her with a portion of his power to
allow her to also traverse the multiverse as
his harbinger and collect heroes in order to
save it. Does Dr. Fate usually recite his spells
in Latin? Seems like more of a Constantine thing,
right? Yeah, I don't usually see Dr. Fate,
you know, reciting incantations in the same
way that John Constantine does. That's more
of an occult thing, whereas Dr. Fate is more
like artifact based, I would say. And Dr. Strange
just says a bunch of nonsense, like the hoary
hosts of Hoggeth, like stuff Stan Lee invented.
Yeah, those hosts of Hoggeth are hoary.
As the Justice Society emerges victorious back
in World War II, Psycho Pirate escapes to a
new universe where he's encountered by Harbinger
and asked to aid in the protection of the multiverse.
In the present, Superman witnesses a new wave
of antimatter approaching and heroes from across
the multiverse activate their towers to protect
their universes, including the post-apocalyptic
world of the Atomic Knights, saved by Superman
and Supergirl. the latter of whom is still
concerned with the monitor's initial apathy
toward Krypton's destruction and the erasure
of the future timeline that included her friends
in the Legion of Superheroes, which we saw
at the end of Crisis Part 1. Yeah, I think we
hypothesized at the end of Crisis Part 1 that
anyone who was from a future timeline got erased,
but it turns out that just their specific universes
got erased. Right, exactly, because we still
see characters like Baman beyond. Right. While
Commandi is returned to his own post-apocalyptic
Earth alongside the intelligent ape Solovar
to protect its tower, Psycho Pirate manipulates
Monitor into giving him a portion of his power
in order to more effectively maintain the heroes'
emotions as they continually work to protect
their worlds. As the heroes monitoring things
from the satellite speculate someone may be
behind the waves of antimatter, They also deduced
that they could potentially move all the worlds
to nether space with enough energy. When Blue
Beetle confronts Psycho Pirate, the villain
is transported away by the Anti-Monitor. I have
a question, why does DC have so many intelligent
ape characters? You know, there's Gorilla Grodd,
there's the Ultra Humanite, and now we have
Solovar. Solovar is like Gorilla Grodd's rival
from Gorilla City. That does not answer my
question. Because in DC Comics, you know, there
is Gorilla City and it's entirely full of intelligent
apes that have evolved. Solovar being one of
them. I knew as soon as he showed up that Command
D was not going to have it. Well, yeah, considering
that Command D is based on Planet of the Apes
or was inspired by it, I should say, it was
kind of funny to have Solovar there. But that's
straight from the Crisis comic as well. Wait,
Command D played a role in the Crisis comic?
Oh, yeah. Yeah. Interesting. The Tomorrowverse
was laying all these clues with the shorts
they decided to create and stuff like that as
to the direction that the franchise was going
to go. We just never saw the crisis story coming.
No. As the heroes of the multiverse prepare
for a new wave, this time it leaves behind hordes
of shadow demons on each world that attack
the heroes and the towers. Meanwhile, the Anti-Monitor
promises Psycho-Pirate an entire universe to
control in exchange for helping put a stop to
the Monitor and his heroes. As Batman gets
overwhelmed by shadow demons, members from the
Bat Family from other worlds come to his aid
once again, and together they determine Bright
Light destroys the demons. And once again,
Batman's completely a dick to these guys. As
Wonder Woman, Commandee, and others protect
their towers, Psycho Pirate begins broadcasting
feelings of hate and distrust across the multiverse,
causing heroes such as the Bat Family, Green
Lantern and Dr. Light, and the Amazons to turn
against each other. When Supergirl attacks a
shadow demon, her physical contact with it
allows PsychoPirate to project an illusion in
her mind of her being with her loved ones and
coming to the conclusion that the monitor caused
the destruction of Krypton and everything bad
that has happened since. Now I'm not going to
lie, this whole Supergirl illusion thing was
super confusing because she was talking to PsychoPirate
in one moment. then she was helping her cousin
fight shadow demons in another, then all of
a sudden she's back on Krypton with the Legion
and her mom, then Krypton is kind of destroyed
behind her, and then she's with Psycho Pirate
again. It's weird. As heroes across the multiverse
continue to fight, a homeless man is revealed
to be John Constantine, with help from the Green
Lantern John Stewart. When Monitor confronts
Psycho Pirate about what he's doing, he escapes
to another universe, just as another wave emerges
on the horizon. Many worlds are destroyed, including
the world of the Amazons and Atomic Knights,
though some heroes manage to overcome their
wrath to activate their towers in time. So
Wonder Woman is dead now, right? It's ambiguous.
Her Tiara lived, and she mentioned earlier
that she was immortal, so I don't know if that
means that allowed her to survive. I will give
you a spoiler. In the extras for this film,
they show a preview for part 3 in which she
is still alive. that could take place timeline
wise before she dies here? I have no idea.
But I think that Tiara is a clue that she's
still alive. As the monitor observes everything
that's happening, he is approached by the spectre
who implies that he will suffer for his millions
of years of apathy. When the shadow demons across
the multiverse leave for Earth 1, there they
combine to form a colossal sized anti-monitor.
The emergence of the Anti-Monitor reveals to
the Monitor and the Spectre that everything
that has happened is the Monitor's fault and
as punishment, he allows Supergirl to kill him.
When the heroes attacks on the Anti-Monitor
fail, Supergirl realizes what she has done and
holds the Monitor's dead body. The film ends
with the Anti-Monitor charging up a massive
energy attack, which is hella anti-climactic.
For real. My wife is like, that was the end?
Really? I'm like, any other, you know, they're
setting up a part three, but you're right. It
just kind of ended in a way that didn't feel
like an ending. No, no. I mean, they should
have just ended it with Supergirl holding monitor.
Like they didn't need the whole charge up attack
because if you're not going to finish that,
why then? Why do it? Especially considering
we still don't have a release date for part
three. Like we know it's coming out this year,
but who knows how many months he'll have to
charge that damn thing. It's gonna be one massive
attack. Although the anti-monitor himself seems
less threatening than an anti-matter wave that's
tearing through the universe. Right, especially
considering the fact that the heroes were actually
able to physically, not necessarily harm him,
but affect him. You know, cause like his mouth
is screaming, he's like, ah. Right. But you
know, they couldn't do that to an anti-matter
wave. We'll see how it plays out. I have high
hopes for the next film, the third in the trilogy.
I hope it ends with a bang. But I realize I
have to temper my expectations considering the
past quality of the Tomorrowverse film universe.
Yeah, considering the inconsistent quality of
this series of films, these crisis movies almost
require audience members to have seen every
single movie in the Tomorrowverse to get a
lot of the context behind what's going on here.
Like, even in this film, little things like
the scene of Supergirl trying to find Superman
when she comes back to Earth. You know, we,
having seen Justice League Warworld, we know
that that's where he is, up in space, but someone
coming new to this film wouldn't know that,
and so it would just add to the confusion.
Things like Commandy, you know, if people hadn't
seen that DC showcase short, they'd be like,
who the hell is this guy showing up randomly
in this film? Lots of little things like that.
The investment required of the audience, I think,
is too much. And this trilogy so far has done
absolutely zero handholding. Yeah, and it doesn't
help that a lot of the references, even in
part one, are to some of my least favorite Tomorrowverse
films. Like, there's a lot of references to
Justice Society World War Two. Hated that movie.
Legion of Superheroes. That movie sucked. It's
like, where's the long Halloween references,
you know? Where's the... I guess they did have
Green Lantern beware my power references, because
I liked that movie. But yeah. I mean, at least
you could say the crisis films are better than
most of the other tomorrow verse films. I don't
know how much that's saying, but it's saying
something. They're like midway there. They're
kind of mid overall. I like the first one again.
Yeah. Hopefully part three is going to be the
best in the whole tomorrow verse universe in
the same way that Justice League Dark was really,
really damn good and among the best of the DC
animated movie universe. But in regards to
this film, Despite intriguing backstories for
several characters, the film fails to capture
the stakes or interest of part one as it slowly
ramps up for the finale. We gave part one three
and a half stars. I'm giving this one a notch
below that three stars, right on the borderline
of rotten and fresh. This time I'm leaning rotten
for rotten tomatoes. Right because you know
the tomato meter is a measure of recommendation.
A lot of people view the tomato meter as a
measure of quality. It's actually a measure
of recommendation. And at the end of the day,
I think I would also not recommend this movie,
whereas I would recommend the first one. But
that does it for this review. If you guys saw
the movie, I'd love to hear what you thought
about it. You can reach out to us via email
at dyna or by visiting us on Instagram, which
you can find a link to in our show notes or
by going to our website at dynamicduel.com.
And on our site, you could also find a link
to our Patreon page where you could join our
dynamic two out here and chat with us and fellow
listeners. our Fantastic Four tier, which gets
you bonus content each month, our X-Force tier
that makes you an executive producer of this
podcast, or our newest tier that lets you join
our DynaMic Podcast Network. Please don't
forget to rate our show on Apple podcasts, Spotify,
Podchaser, or on our website. In our next episode,
in lead up to our review of the Netflix series,
Dead Boy Detectives, we are doing a Sandman
tie-in duel because Dead Boy Detectives takes
place in the Sandman universe. we will be pitting
Sandman Wesley Dodds against Madame Webb. Right,
the Julia Carpenter version of Madame Webb,
not the Cassandra Webb version, because she
would be, I think, pretty useless in a fight.
She'd be able to tell how the fight went by
predicting her own defeat, but she wouldn't
be able to do much more than that, you know?
Yeah. But no, I think it'll be a good matchup.
You know, both Wesley Dodds and Julia Carpenter
can subdue their opponents and have premonitions
and stuff like that. I think it'll be pretty
good. But that does it for this episode, we
want to give a big thanks to our executive producers
Ken Johnson, John Swarovski, Zachary Hepburn,
Dustin Balcom, Miggy Mathengian, Brandon Estregard,
Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yaiten, Austin Wazilovski,
AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Adam Spies, Andrew
Schunk, Dean Molesky, and Devin Davis for helping
make this podcast possible. We'll talk to you
guys next week. Up up and away, true believers.
There's a crisis happening right now. In my
pants.