you
Dual Podcast, a weekly show where we review
superhero films and debate the superiority
between Marvel and DC by comparing their characters
in stat-based battle simulations. I'm Marvelous
Joe. And I'm his twin brother, Johnny DC. And
in this episode, we will be finding out who
would win in a fight between the Riddler and
Arcade, the X-Men villain. This is going to
be one of the more unique dual episodes that
we've ever done. We're dealing with characters
that don't really get into physical altercations.
They prefer to fight with their mind. They're
all about prep time. Yeah, these characters
create these elaborate traps for the heroes
they go up against, but also considering the
fact that we don't take environment into account,
we had to get creative when it came to finding
a way to pit these characters against each
other. Yeah, so go ahead and stay tuned to later
on this episode when we actually delve into
this match and run the simulations and find
out who would win. Before we get into that
duel matchup, we're going to go over the news
from the past week, of which there wasn't very
much. We'll be talking about how the John Wick
director, Chats Tihelsky, is going to be directing
the action scenes for the Birds of Prey movie.
As always, you can look up the segment times
in the episode description to go ahead and jump
to whatever topic you wanna listen to. But
before we get into the news, we just wanna give
a quick shout out to Ben O'Neill, who gave
us a second review on iTunes. Yeah, I guess
he has two accounts or something. Or he's just
using someone else's account. I don't know quite
how Apple would feel about that. Hey, you know
what? We got a rating. We got a rating. We got
a rating. We're at 138. We're that much closer
to our 200 ratings on Apple Podcasts. Once we
get to 200 ratings, Ron Tomatoes says we're
eligible to have our reviews of Marvel and DC
films count toward those films tomato meters.
Which is a huge dream of ours. We have wanted
to be film critics ever since we were in high
school. So if you guys can help us get there,
it'd be hugely appreciated. We love putting
this show together for you guys every week.
And if you guys could just give back by doing
that, it'd be fantastic. Yes, please and thank
you. But now that that's done, quick to the
no prize. So a No Prize is an award that Marvel
used to give out up until the 90s to fans.
Our version, the Dynamic Duel No Prize, is a
digital award that we post on social media
that I personally draw for those who we feel
gave the best answer to our question of the
week. Last week's question was, what character
from the Spider-Man comics do you most want
to see Phil Lord and Chris Miller adapt into
a live action television series? And this is
coming off the news that Phil Lord and Chris
Miller, who are the producers of the Into the
Spider-Verse movie, They signed a contract with
Sony to develop several live action Spider-Man
based television series. So we got a lot of
great answers of the shows that you guys would
like to see. The first honorable mention goes
to Anna Kosasa, who gave the answer of Squadron
Sinister and the Grandmaster. Now this was not
an answer that was really Spider-Man adjacent.
I don't consider the Squadron Supreme or Squadron
Sinister to be part of the Spider-Man universe.
It's possible that she may have meant Sinister
6, but she also mentioned the Grandmaster,
so I'm not sure. Either way... A show involving
these characters, especially the Grandmaster,
would be pretty damn incredible. Christian Rubito
also gets honorable mention for his answer
of Hydro Man. Yeah, Hydro Man. I don't know
if he might be the only one that wants a television
show based on Hydro Man. That being said, I
do agree that Hydro Man is severely underrated.
It would have been cool to maybe see him down
the line, like way down the line in a Spider-Man
movie. Although they kind of use that up with
the Elementals from Far From Home. But he's
pretty powerful. Honorable mention also goes
to Caleb Albers, who gave the answer of Spider-Man
2099. He was afraid that this answer was gonna
be like the quote basic bitch answer. And it
was and it was because lots of other people
answered Spider-Man 2099, including Chris Castaneda,
Tim Brown and Matthew Gonzalez. Although Matthew
Gonzalez also mentioned Spider-Punk. What I
really like about Spider-Man 2099, though, is
that in some ways, this is the perfect answer.
And that's probably why so many people gave
it because you have such an opportunity for
like high concept, high octane science fiction
action within this. It could be like Tron.
meets Fifth Element meets Spider-Man. Sold.
Exactly. So many great things, so many cool
things that can be done with a Spider-Man 2099
show. So yeah, great answer, guys. Jeff Miles
Jr. also gets honorable mention for his answer
of Miles Morales and Gwen Stacy. Yeah, he wants
to see that relationship further develop in
a television show, although I think Sony's
gonna prefer to explore that within the Spider-Verse
sequel that they're making. In the animated
universe that they've established. Right. Honorable
mention goes to John Spies for also giving
the answer of Miles Morales. And Harrison Fox
gave the answer of Spider-Gwen, as did Matt
Estes. Honorable mention goes to Joel Seagrave
who said that he wants a Clone Saga television
show, which could be really fascinating. You
know, the Clone Saga was a series from the
90s that Marvel put out that was often derided
by fans because it left us questioning whether
or not Peter Parker was actually, you know,
the real Peter Parker or not. I think that's
kind of a fascinating concept. especially when
it's explored on its own outside of, you know,
everything else that is Peter Parker related.
Just like seeing what they're getting up to,
I think, would make a pretty decent show. It's
interesting how you could explore both Peter
Parker's clones and his multiverse selves. There's
like so many, just so many different versions
of Spider-Man in the Marvel Comics universe.
And I think Joel Segrave mentioned that if
anyone could get that right, it's Phil Lord
and Chris Miller. Yeah, definitely. They're
great writers. Aaron Alexander Jones also gave
the answer of the Clone Saga. Salvador Martinez
gave the answer of a man spider. It's when Peter
Parker mutated into a spider. And he said that
the series could follow Madam Webb trying to
put a stop to him. And he said a twist at the
end could be that man spider fuses with carnage,
which would be so deadly and pretty bad ass.
Ken Johnson gets honorable mention for his answer
of Craven. Yeah, that would be a fantastic
show. I'm not sure quite how it would work.
I guess you would have him like hunting a different
quarry like every week. It could be like, you
know, dog the bounty hunter, but without the
bounty, just the hunter, you know, I totally
see like a fat craving, just like balding spring
bear mace in people's face. Right. Exactly.
They believe that Sony is currently working
on a live action feature length film for this
character and much in the same way that they're
working on Morbius and Venom. Yeah, that's the
rumor. Colby Hentges gave the answer of Superior
Spider-Man, which I think would be a fantastic
mini series. Superior Spider-Man was a great
book. I love the aesthetic. of the character.
Like I wish that was just Peter Parker, like
not Doctor Octopus. Just give all that gear
to Peter Parker. He should have adapted all
those upgrades that Doctor Octopus made to his
whole getup when he became Spider-Man. Right?
Yeah. And finally, Red Hood gave the answer
of Spider-X, Blood Spider, or Ezekiel Sims,
who are probably like the three most obscure
characters in Spider-Man anthology. You know,
having only been in a handful of issues themselves.
Yeah, I think I only know one of those characters.
But you know, a television show is a great way
to explore these characters and develop them
even further. But the winner of this week's
No Prize goes to C.J. Kraft for his answer
of Spider-Man Noir. And the way he described
the show made it seem like basically Sin City.
I would love to see a Spider-Man Noir meets
like Sin City type show. That one just really
captured my imagination. just as much as a Spider-Man
2099 show would capture my imagination. Really,
both of those ideas have equal merit, but CJ
Kraft was the only one that gave the Spider-Man
no answer, so he gave it to him, basically.
Yeah, I love the visual look of what Robert
Rodriguez did with the Sin City live action
movies. It's just so stylish, it's so cool.
And now make it more 1930s and add Spider-Man
into the mix. Boom. So congrats to CJ Kraft.
You win this week's No Prize, so Jonathan will
go ahead and draw. Who are you drawing this
week? I'm drawing Arcade. You're gonna get a
drawing of Arcade that we'll post to social
media, go ahead and check that out. If you,
the listener, want to win your own No Prize,
go ahead and stay tuned to later on this episode
when we ask another question of the week. Now
that that's done, on to the news!
Okay, so the Hollywood Reporter broke the news
a few days ago that John Wick director Chad
Stahelski is going to design and tackle new
action scenes for the Birds of Prey film dropping
next February. Now there's two different ways
you can take this news. Essentially the first
way that I took it was, oh, Birds of Prey, you
know, the movie's in trouble, it doesn't have
good enough action, they're gonna have to bring
in someone to help fix this movie, kind of
like the way they had to fix Rogue One with
Star Wars. Or like World War Z. Yeah. But those
movies turned out great. They did actually.
What's the other way you could take it? The
other way you could take it is that, hey, you
know, a lot of these directors don't actually
shoot a lot of the action scenes in their films.
Like take the Russo brothers, for example,
they use a lot of second unit direction when
it comes to high octane action. That's one
of the reasons why The Winter Soldier was so
good. And guess who directed the action scenes
in The Winter Soldier? Chad Stahelski. What,
he did? Yeah. Holy shit. Yeah, he's also done
Ninja Assassin, he's done The Hunger Games.
He started off actually as Keanu Reeves stunt
double in The Matrix before breaking into direction.
His stunt firm, I think it's called 8711, was
already working on this film, doing the stunts
for it. And they're like, they're doing insane
stunt work right now. If you've seen any of
the John Wick films, you know how crazy their
stuff is. He's directed all of the John Wick
films. He co-directed the first John Wick with
David Leitch, who later went on to work on films
like Deadpool 2. Right, right. What's interesting
here is that he is taking an uncredited role
directing these action scenes. Well, he's not
getting a director credit. I think that's what
they were mentioning. I assume that he's still
going to get credited for his stunt work. I
mean, his firm will, but the shots he's directing
will be uncredited. My interpretation of that
uncredited news would be that he wouldn't get
a co-director credit, given that he's a big
name. Yeah, I guess we'll see when it comes
out. I think this is good news. It is good news.
It is. It is great news. If you're gonna get
any action director to direct your action scenes,
get the fucking guy that did John Wick in Winter
Soldier. In my opinion, he is like the biggest
name in stunt work and action scenes in the
business right now. So hopefully by him taking
this work, maybe he'll get a bigger DC Comics
character to work with in the future. What characters
would you like to see him work with? Personally,
I've always wanted to see a question film. He's
not superhuman, so there'd be an opportunity
for a lot of stunt work. It's pretty gritty.
Yeah. But all of that could also probably describe
the Birds of Prey. So it seems like it's a good
fit. Yeah, the Birds of Prey have never been
really overtly superpowered. So you can get
really grounded with the action. Exactly, exactly.
And actually, I just realized if David Leitch
directed Deadpool, Stahelski should direct
Deathstroke. Oh, that would be sweet. That movie
needs to be made. His action style is probably
more suited to someone like Deathstroke than,
say, the Birds of Prey, because Deathstroke
uses guns. Does anyone from Birds of Prey use
guns? Huntress uses a crossbow. Harley Quinn
uses guns. Oh, that's true. Ultimately, I think
this movie may have the best action scenes
we've ever seen in a DC film. Well, that's a
short bar to clear, honestly. Oh, fuck off.
Name a great DC action scene. Uh, Batman v Superman,
the warehouse scene. That's like the only one.
The only like grounded one. There's plenty of
action scenes. Yeah, that are crap. Oh, oh,
okay. Black Manta versus Aquaman was crap. Okay,
no, that was pretty good actually. Wonder Woman
and the enemy soldiers in the town was crap?
Nah, yeah you're right. They've had a few,
they've had a few. Superman versus Zod was crap?
No, yeah that was totally shit. I can't give
you that one. I wouldn't expect you to know
good action. This all brings us to our question
of the week. What is the most important thing
in a movie?
What is your favorite action scene in a Marvel
or DC film? Post your answer to our Instagram,
Twitter, Facebook, or email us at dyna We'll
pick our favorite answer and draw that person
a dynamic duel no prize that we'll post to social
media. But that does it for all the news. There's
nothing really else too much to talk about that's
not a rumor. So who knows, maybe next week
will be a heavy news week. But now let's get
into our main event where we pit Arcade against
Riddler and find out who will be the champion.
Alright, Arcade versus Riddler. We have a primarily
X-Men villain in Arcade and a Batman villain
in the Riddler. Two characters who primarily
fight using not their fists, but their brains.
And of course we're doing this match now, having
just come off of our review of Batman Hush
last week, in which the Riddler played a pretty
prominent role. He was so great in that movie,
in Batman Hush. So we knew that we had to use
him for a duel in this episode, and who better
to pit him against than Marvel's own suit wearing
puzzling trickster, Arcade. Now if this is
your first time listening to one of our duel
episodes, the way we determine the winner between
these two characters is we run a series of Monte
Carlo simulations using the characters' base
stats. Now these stats are randomized along
a normal distribution which is a bell curve
and that represents all the different variables
that take place in battle. We use the stats
that are given in the Marvel official power
rankings and we extrapolate the DC character
stats from those criteria. And we also incorporate
a few more stats just to make a more robust
simulation. We take this approach because Joseph
and I are both heavily biased in favor of either
DC or Marvel. Right. And this is the most scientific
approach that we could think of to determine
the answer of who would win. Exactly. It was
the same approach that Spike TV did in their
show Deadliest Warrior that was on the air about
10 or so years ago. Probably more than that
now. Yeah. The simulation results give us a
percentage of wins for each character because
There's always one way a character can defeat
another, always a way for Batman to defeat
Superman. Right, so no character ever wins 100%
of the time if we've done our job right in
picking a fair matchup. So we don't consider
fan votes, and we don't consider like extraordinary
feats of strength that are uncharacteristic
for the character. Right. 90% of the time.
It's just these base stats with simulations.
Now before we run these simulations, we like
to go into the histories and abilities of each
character. I think it's my turn to go first
with Arcade. Now I'm not sure how many people
out there actually know a lot about the history
of arcade given that he hasn't been in a whole
lot of comic book issues. I don't remember
him from the cartoon at all. You don't? No.
He was in X-Men Evolution, he was even in Ultimate
Spider-Man cartoon. Oh wow. Yeah, he's been
in a lot of different things. Primarily though,
I think he really works best in the video games.
I remember the arcade boss battle in Marvel
Ultimate Alliance. The whole murder world level
was incredible. He was a villain that was like
tailor-made for video games. What was the name
like, arcade? You would hope so. Right, exactly.
So little is known about the villain Arcade's
early history. Even his real name has never
been revealed. He has told, however, that he
was born to an incredibly wealthy family and
had a lifelong fixation with toys and games.
His father detested his childish hobbies and
abused Arcade when he was young. On his 21st
birthday, his parents withdrew his trust fund,
and in retaliation, Arcade killed his parents
with a car bomb, inheriting all their wealth.
It's unknown if that story is actually part
of Arcade's past or not, or if he made it up
just for his own sick enjoyment. What is known
is that as a young adult, Arcade turned his
enjoyment of murder into a career as an assassin,
charging $1 million per contract. Over time,
he grew bored of killing people using conventional
means, and started using his technological
genius to build elaborate murder traps in a
mobile facility he called Murderworld. He based
his traps on his targets greatest fears and
weaknesses. By vetting his victims and learning
everything about them, he could tailor his deadly
machinations to provide them with the most
amount of despair, while simultaneously providing
himself with the most amount of amusement.
He enjoys watching people die. Though Arcade
loved relishing how much his victims suffered,
he would often laugh at and taunt them through
a loudspeaker, he would always give them a
tiny chance of escape for sport. Though no one
ever escaped. Murderworld made him renowned
in the criminal underworld, and he took on the
codename Arcade. He's a lot like Jigsaw from
the Saw films. Yeah, pretty much. And I guess
like the Riddler from the Arkham games. Yeah,
although Arcade is a little bit more whimsical,
or at least he used to be. Like one of his
most memorable appearances was when he put the
X-Men in a giant pinball machine. That sounds
cool, actually. So Arcade hired two assistants.
Mr. Chambers, his chief engineer, and Miss
Locke, a martial arts expert and field agent,
to lure Arcade's victims into Murder World.
She was also Arcade's lover, and the two often
played deadly games with each other for the
thrill. Over time, Arcade killed numerous conventional
targets and eventually grew bored again, but
a contract to kill Captain Britain led to the
first Murder World escape, and brought a newfound
enjoyment to Arcade, who decided he would dedicate
his resources toward killing superheroes. Not
for the money, but for the challenge.
and teams such as X-Men, X-Factor, and Excalibur.
But although the heroes kept escaping, Arcade
at least managed to avoid capture himself each
time. One day, while recuperating from his
latest failure, he grew angry and stabbed his
lover Miss Locke too deep while they were in
bed playing with a knife. Unable to cope with
the idea that he murdered her, he convinced
himself that Wolverine had done it, and employed
the mutant illusionist mastermind to help him
get his revenge. Mastermind learned the truth
and turned on Arcade, imprisoning him in a
murder world in his own mind. Arcade later recovered
and went on to terrorize superheroes such as
Deadpool, Hercules, and Black Cat, once teaming
up with the mystical villain Nightmare to create
a murder world that was a terrifying labyrinth.
However, Arcade still had yet to keep a hero
from escaping. After learning that most other
villains thought of him as a gimmicky joke,
Arcade grew depressed and decided that playing
for amusement... was less important than playing
to win. He hired a new assistant named Miss
Coriander who helped him build a murder world
in Antarctica using nanotechnology, as well
as a special suit that would grant him god-like
powers within the facility. He captured young
teenage heroes from Avengers Academy, the Runaways,
and Xavier School for the Gifted, and told them
they would have to kill each other, and that
only the survivor would escape. In the Avengers
Arena miniseries, he pretty much admitted that
he stole the idea from the Hunger Games books.
I was gonna say Battle Royale. Yeah, but...
Well... The young heroes instantly rebelled,
but he used his god powers to kill Metal from
the Avengers Academy. Red Raven then tried to
escape, but she broke her neck by slamming
into the facility's barrier. Oh jeez. The teens
fled and hid across Murderworld, creating alliances
just as Arcade hoped. He manipulated the terrain
and drew them toward each other with supplies
and weapons, leading to a hero named Anachronism
killing Kid Brittain. The Game of Death brought
out the dark side of the hero Apex, who killed
Avengers Academy teammate Justin Seifert and
Runaways member Nico Minoru. Although Nico managed
to resurrect herself and in turn killed Apex
and Deathlock it, who is the cyborg daughter
of the creator of the Deathlock program. When
the Avengers began investigating the teens'
disappearance, Arcade used robots wearing the
dead teens' skin to convince them everything
was fine. As more of the teens died... it seemed
Arcade had finally achieved success as a supervillain.
The contest was cut short however when Deathlocket
was revealed to have survived her death and
accessed Murderworld's control panel. But Arcade
managed to teleport away and uploaded the events
of that Murderworld to YouTube, finally earning
him respect among his peers. The story was so
brutal. I highly suggest reading Avengers Arena
if you haven't already. You already know the
ending, but you know, you knew the ending of
Hunger Games. before you saw that or read the
book, so you know, read it. I highly recommend
it. So a few of the surviving heroes from the
Antarctic murder world managed to track Arcade
down by going undercover in the Masters of Evil.
They strapped into the front of a S.H.I.E.L.D.
helicarrier as they flew around on their missions,
and that was the last that he was seen. Holy
cow. Now Arcade has a genius level intellect
and is an expert when it comes to electronics,
robotics, engineering, and design. He even taught
himself to master the She-R holographic technology
that once powered the X-Men's danger room training
sessions. He prefers not to fight, but has
a history involving some hand-to-hand training.
He also has equipped various personal defense
weapons, but instead he prefers to defeat his
enemies in Murder World, as his main weakness
is definitely his intense need for entertaining
mental stimulation. And that's arcade. He has
like super ADD. And you combine that with violent
psychopathic tendencies, and you have a recipe
for disaster. He's a really fascinating villain,
one that I really never gave enough credit
until I read up on him. That recipe for disaster
is pretty close to the recipe that made the
Riddler as well. Really? There's some strong
connections there. Interesting, let's hear
it. Now the Riddler, aka Edward Nigma, is one
of the most notorious and ridiculed villains
of Batman's Rogue's gallery. Born Edward Nashton,
he grew up to an abusive father and absentee
mother. While in school at a young age, Edward's
teacher promised a prize to the student who
could solve a puzzle the fastest. Showing both
compulsive and narcissistic tendencies early
on, Edward broke into the school at night to
figure out how to solve the puzzle in under
a minute, and when he did it the next day, he
was given a book of riddles as a prize. Edward's
intelligence was often praised, but not by his
father, who disliked his son being smarter
than him and often accused him of cheating,
something Edward himself would later in life.
His father's beatings only drove Edward's obsession
with proving his intellectual superiority,
suffering from severe insecurity-borne distress
if he was unable to do so. Like a surprising
many of Batman's villains, the Riddler worked
early on at a carnival, where he used his deductive
skills to cheat the carnival goers out of their
money. Wishing to move up in the world, he
changed his name to Edward Nigma. and climbed
up the corporate world to become the chief
strategist at Wayne Enterprises during Bruce
Wayne's worldwide travels in preparation to
fight crime in Gotham City. With Edward's shady
backdoor schemes and profiteering exposed upon
Bruce Wayne's return, Edward's career was left
in ruins. Wishing revenge against Wayne Enterprises
and all of the idiots in Gotham City, Edward
during a hurricane as the Riddler, making him
the first masked villain of Batman's crime-fighting
career post-New 52. Further threatening the
city with explosive weather balloons, the Riddler's
secret location was eventually tracked down
by Batman, and when the Riddler threatened
to blow up the city unless Batman could solve
twelve of his riddles, Batman surprisingly
answered by punching the Riddler in the face.
That's pretty good. Diagnosed with a form of
obsessive-compulsive disorder, Edward was sentenced
to Arkham Asylum for psychiatric treatment.
To learn more about Batman, check out our Batman
vs. Moon Knight episode. So after proving himself
a valuable criminal profiler and apt informant
of Gotham's underworld to the police force,
the Riddler eventually grew bored at Arkham
and walked out simply by reciting the names
of the guards' loved ones as they confronted
him. Huh. Offering to team up with the Joker
to kill Batman, the Riddler was instead shot
by the Clown Prince of Crime, starting a large-scale
gang war known as the War of Jokes and Riddles,
in which Batman's rogues divided their loyalties
into two factions, the Joker's or the Riddler's.
Batman eventually sided with the Riddler in
an attempt to stem the amount of innocent bystanders
killed in the supervillain feud, though by the
end, Batman nearly killed the Riddler in anger.
and Edward and the Joker were sent back to Arkham.
You can of course learn more about the Joker
in our Joker vs Green Goblin episode. During
one of his stints at the asylum, the Riddler
was freed along with the rest of Batman's enemies
by the villain Bane during the Nightfall storyline,
which you can learn more about in our Bane vs
Iron Fist episode. The Riddler, psychologically
incapable of not leaving clues to stop his crimes,
sent several letters to the Gotham Police Department,
all of which were ignored as the police were
overwhelmed by the other Arkham villains out
causing mayhem. After the Riddler's henchmen
abandoned him after they grew tired of waiting
for the police to fall into his trap, the Riddler
hijacked a local news television show in a
bid for attention, holding the live audience
hostage with a bomb detonator.
He was thwarted by Robin alone after the sidekick
deduced that the Riddler's bomb was fake. Now,
considered an incompetent joke amongst Gotham's
underworld for most of his career, the Riddler
was elevated to a new threatening level during
the Hush storyline when the Riddler bathed
in a rejuvenating Lazarus pit in a desperate
move to cure a malignant tumor that had developed
in his brain. Brought about by the Lazarus Pit,
the Riddler deduced that Batman's real identity
was Bruce Wayne, and he teamed with the villain
Hush to mastermind a plan that nearly drove
Batman insane as Bruce Wayne's loved ones were
targeted by nearly every member of his rogue's
gallery. Batman prevailed in the end and reminded
the captured Riddler that a riddle everyone
knew the answer to was worthless, ensuring that
the Riddler kept his secret identity. During
the Infinite Crisis storyline, the Riddler joined
the ranks of the Secret Society of Super-Villains,
only to be knocked unconscious and put in a
coma by the hero Shining Knight. Waking up
a year later with amnesia, Edward amassed a
small fortune legally as a private investigator,
frequently helping Batman and other heroes solve
crimes for some time, before he was caught
in an explosion during a heroic escapade that
re-triggered his psychosis. Whether he's plotting
schemes against Batman, Green Arrow, or even
The Flash, The Riddler is pretty inconsistent
when it comes to success, sometimes failing
in hilarious fashion and other times proving
himself frighteningly capable and underestimated.
While the jury's out on whether or not he's
as intelligent as he claims to be, and though
he has no powers or physical abilities of note,
he does have a genius level of intellect. capable
of crafting elaborate death traps and lethal
weapons, more likely than not designed around
a question mark motif, like his staff, which
has served successfully as a trigger for various
tricks and snares, and somewhat less successfully
as a combat weapon. That's the Riddler. Yeah,
there were quite a few similarities there.
Two fascinating villains. Let's go ahead and
find out who would win in a fight. Now before
we run the simulations, what we'd like to do
on this podcast is kind of improvise a scenario
and talk about how we think one of these 1000
simulated battles would actually play out.
We don't set any rules for this battle, save
for the fact that the characters don't know
anything about each other when they first meet,
other than that the other one is a threat that
needs to be put down. And the fight takes place
in an environment that plays no bearing on
the match itself. In a non-environment, as it
were. Now these rules would normally apply
to our duel episodes. However, this one, we're
taking a different approach. This improvised
scenario is not actually 100% improvised. Since
these characters fight more with their brains
than with their fists, we did a little bit of
prep work and you'll see what I mean as we
get into it. So the characters start off 50
yards apart from each other on a non-environment
field. Who goes first? The Riddler. Okay. Right
away he goes, riddle me this. So obviously
these characters, like, They don't really fight
hand to hand. So we figure that what they'll
end up doing is they'll end up talking it out
basically and try to figure out exactly which
of them is smarter. Now to that end, both Jonathan
and I have prepared riddles for each other
and logic puzzles to kind of simulate this battle
of the minds, if you will. So the characters,
they sit down next to each other. Arcade pulls
out these taser discs that he usually uses
to strap onto victims that he's luring into
murder world. and he straps a taser disc onto
himself and to the Riddler, and the scenario
is this. The characters each have to answer
five riddles. Whoever gets the most incorrect
gets zapped and electrocuted and dies. And
that's how the speculation is gonna play out.
This is already gonna be a horrible speculation.
I am nowhere near as intelligent as the Riddler.
I'm nervous, I'm super nervous about this.
For Arcade, I didn't develop riddles so much
as theme existing logic puzzles to the X-Men
characters. Riddles, some of them actually are
riddles that the Riddler has actually used
in the comics. Uh-huh. Not all of them, but
hopefully they're clever enough to stump you.
Okay, so let's get into it. Okay, okay, okay.
Riddle me this. Alright. It holds most knowledge
that's ever been said, but is not the brain
and is not the head. To feathers, they're masters,
both bane and boon, respectively when empty
and when full. The feathers make me think it's
like a quill. Is it a pen? No. Is it a book?
No. No, close though. Is it a bookshelf? No.
How many answers do you get? As many as I fucking
need. I'm not as smart as Arcade, okay? Is
it, so it's close to a book? Okay, is it a piece
of paper? Yeah. Is it a letter? Yeah. There
you go. It's paper. Paper. Okay, awesome. Yeah,
writers use like feathered cool pens and you
know, when the page is full of writing, it's
good. And when it's empty, it's not. Okay,
yeah, that's what I figured. Yeah, after like
five tries. I thought it was like when the
pen was full of ink as opposed to when the pen
was empty. Nah, anyway, Arcade does not get
zapped because I got the answer right. Oh gosh.
Now, okay, now Arcade has a puzzle for the
Riddler. At 9 a.m. multiple men caught a cold
and began sneezing at the start of every minute.
Every time he sneezed, he created a duplicate
of himself with the same exact cold. and each
time a duplicate sneezed, it created its own
duplicate. At exactly 9.06 a.m., his apartment
was half full of dupes. At what time will his
apartment be completely full? That's an easy
one. I mean, if he's doubling every minute and
then at 9.06, his apartment is half full, it
means at 9.07, it will be full. Correct. You're
right. Whatever. It was an easy one. It was
an easy one. Yeah. The number of multiple men
doubles each minute. Therefore you can say
that at 9-07 his apartment is full, being half
full the previous minute. Okay, I don't get
zapped either then. Yay. Alright. Riddle me
this. Okay. I'm always moving forward, never
looking back. My end limit, no one knows. More
of me, they lack. Like a river, I do flow.
Like a bird, I fly. Now go on and take a guess.
What, say you, am I? It's either a clock or
time. Motherfucker. Time, yeah it's time. Time?
Yeah, that makes sense. Cause time flies, it
always goes forward, you can never go back in
time. That was an easy one. Okay, yeah, I guess
so. You're right, it was an easy one. I wanted
it to be easy. Alright, alright, next puzzle
for the Riddler. The villain Toad is stuck in
a muddy hole 100 feet deep and is trying to
get out. Every minute he jumps up 25 feet but
slides down 24 feet. How long does it take
Toad to leap out the hole? Oh, this is like
the frog in the well. Yes, except it's Toad
in the hole as opposed to a frog in a well.
Okay, ah, math, okay. It's not that hard of
math. Essentially, he's going up a foot a minute?
Correct. Okay, but by 75 minutes, 75 minutes,
right? Because 75 minutes, all he'll need is
one more jump. Oh, so 76 minutes. Correct,
as 76 minutes or an hour and 16 minutes. Will
take him up to a height of 76 feet at which
point when he leaps he'll leap 25 feet as usual
He'll leap out of the hole and you won't slide
back down nice Always worried for a second I
was gonna do the math on that one right a lot
of people say it'll take him a hundred minutes
for that one and Calculating the one foot per
minute thing, but they don't think about that
last jump. Yeah, okay good Thank you. You're
doing pretty well so far. Okay. I'm trying to
stump you. I'm trying Let's see if I could
do it with this next one riddle me this okay
when I'm quick. I am deadly A rock, shell,
and bone medley. As a man, I'd make you dream
nearby ocean, sea, and stream. Rock, shell,
and bone medley. Makes me think it's like a
wave or something, but what makes you dream?
Sleep? Like what puts you to sleep? Like laying
by the ocean puts you to sleep? No? Is that?
Sandman! Sand! Oh, mother- Yes. Sand? Yeah,
it's sand. Yeah! I was worried about that third
line as I was reading it. I was like, oh, this
is too easy. Yeah, that kind of gives it away.
The whole as a man I make you sleep thing. That's
really the whole riddle. Yeah. Yeah, that's
the whole riddle right there. All right. So
next puzzle for the Riddler. You are Nightcrawler.
You are trying to save Juggernaut, Deadpool
and a Chimichanga from the roof of a burning
building. You have to teleport all three to
the safety of the street below, but you can
only teleport. one at a time. Now you can't
leave Deadpool all alone with the chimichanga
because he'll eat it. You can't leave Juggernaut
all alone with Deadpool because he'll rip Deadpool
to shreds. Now in what sequence can you safely
teleport all three from the burning building
to the street? Can't you just have Deadpool
eat the chimichanga? What's wrong with him
eating the- You have to save the chimichanga,
that's part of the rules of the puzzle. You
have to save the Juggernaut, Deadpool, and the
chimichanga from the burning building through
teleportation. Okay. Again, you can only teleport
one at a time and you can't leave Deadpool
alone with either the chimichanga and you can't
leave him alone with the juggernaut. Okay.
So what's the sequence? Okay, so like okay,
so juggernaut is not gonna eat the chimichanga?
Correct, right. Yeah, he's safe with the chimichanga.
Okay. Okay, so Nightcrawler will teleport Deadpool
first and then go back for juggernaut. Okay.
Okay, so then he takes juggernaut across the
street. But he could take Deadpool back to the
burning building, right? Correct. Yes. OK.
Well, then he takes Deadpool back to the burning
building, grabs the chimichanga, goes back
across the street, leaves the chimichanga with
Juggernaut and then goes back for Deadpool
and brings him back across the street. So all
are safe now. Yep. You got it. You got it.
Fuck. I thought that would be a hard one. It's
just it's just a lot. It takes a lot of back
and forth. Yeah. Basically, if you just remember
that Juggernaut is safe with the chimichanga,
then you kind of work from there. Yeah. Then
it's pretty straightforward. Yeah. Alright,
next. Riddle me this. Reaching stiffly for the
sky, I bare my fingers when it's cold. In warmth,
I wear an emerald glove, and in between I dress
in gold. Uh, reach gloved hands to the cold
sky? Yeah, dressing in green and gold. Yes.
In warmth, I wear- Oh, it's a tree! Or a branch.
Okay, alright. Yeah, it's a tree. It's either
a branch or a tree. That one was obvious. Okay.
I suck. These are way easy. The Riddler is a
horrible, horrible deliverer of riddles. Alright,
Riddler's turn. So Mirage, from the New Mutants,
encounters a bear in a wasteland at night,
where no one else is around. Mistaking it for
the Demon Bear, Mirage runs away to the north
by 20 yards. The bear runs away to the west
by 30 yards. Suddenly, Mirage stops... She
aims her psionic bow directly south and shoots
the bear with a neural arrow. What color was
the bear? What the fuck? Why does it matter
if she shoots him? She would have missed because
he wasn't there to begin with. She aims directly
south and she shoots him. But he's not there
because he's 30 yards west. That doesn't make
any sense. The question is, what color is the
bear, sir? You never said the color. Brown.
The bear is brown. Bears are brown. BOOM you
just got electrocuted! Riddler just got electrocuted!
Zzzz
You sit-a-lin geometry on me. Yeah, actually
Einstein wrote this riddle. Really? Yeah, except
obviously he didn't use Mirage and the demon
bear, it was just a hunter and a polar bear.
First of all, you said a wasteland. Yeah, the
North Pole's a fucking wasteland. Whatever,
fine. All right, your turn. Yay, I'm winning.
Okay, here we go. Last one, prepare to be electrocuted.
Riddle me this. What's the beginning of eternity,
the end of time and space, the beginning of
every end, and the end of every race? I know
this one. What? I've heard this one before.
It's the letter E. Fuck! Right? What? The beginning
of eternity, the end of time and space, time
and space ends with the letter E. The beginning
of every end. Yeah. And the end of every race.
Right. Well look at you! I got them all right!
Alright, here's the last puzzle for the Riddler.
Beast is developing a chemical solution to power
the X-Jet with alternative fuels. His new formula
calls for exactly 4 liters of liquid nitrogen.
The problem is he only has an unmarked 5 liter
Erlenmeyer flask and an unmarked 3 liter Erlenmeyer
flask. How can he use these flasks to measure
out the 4 liters of liquid that he needs? Why
are all of yours involving math? That's what
I want to know. This is barely math. It's like
elementary addition and subtraction math. Okay.
Yeah. So they're unmarked flasks and he needs
four liters. Right. Did you ever see Die Hard
with a Vengeance? This puzzle was in that movie.
Oh yeah? Yeah. Awesome, I should have seen
the movie. I know how to do it. I would fill
up the five liter flask. Uh-huh. And then I
would empty three of the liters. into the three
liter flask. Right, you'd fill that three liter
flask up. Right, all the way to the top. So
I would, I know I would have two liters in
the five liter flask. Right. And three liters
in the three liter flask. Correct. So I just
need to figure out how to get rid of the one
and the three liter. Well, where's the nitrogen
coming from? It's coming from a liquid nitrogen
tank. You can pour liquid out too, is all I'm
saying. Just dump it on the floor, you know.
He has an unlimited supply of liquid nitrogen.
Okay, that's good to know. Okay, so I still
have five liters. I'll empty out the three
liter flask, put the two liters that I still
have in the five liter flask into the three
liter flask. Right? So it's one liter away from
being full. Correct. And there's nothing in
the five liter flask now. Right. Okay, well
then I'll just fill up the five liter flask
and then empty one liter of it into the three
liter flask. So I have four left over in the
five. and I'll just dump whatever's in the three
liter flask. And you have your four liter right
there. Boom, boom. You got it. I'm smart, dude.
All I know is that we've come to the end of
the riddles and the puzzles and the Riddler
was the only one that got any of these questions
wrong. So guess what? Arcade presses his trigger
and the Riddler gets zapped and electrocuted
until he dies. Yeah, except that the Riddler
used a reverse frequency. Analyzer on his cane
what to redirect the frequency to arcade and
he got electrocuted He doesn't have a sucker.
It's a reverse frequency Versus transmission
frequencies shut up. That's cheating. No. Yeah,
that's fine. Well, okay the river cheats Well,
he cheats all the time. Yes What little did
you know that arcade wouldn't dare risk putting
an electrified taser disc on his own body?
Not knowing whether or not he would know the
answers and get out of this alive. So He actually
just projected a hologram of himself right there.
That was a hologram that was answering these
questions. In reality, Arcade's been standing
behind Riddler this whole time, and he just
shoots him with a gun. Oh yeah? Yeah. Well,
little did you know that the Riddler noticed
that Arcade was a hologram through his powers
of deduction, and he knew that the real one
was probably up behind him. What? So before
Arcade could fire that gun, the Riddler spins
around in his chair and uses his cane to knock
the gun out of Arcade's hand. Alright, okay,
so now this is just like a full-on brawl then,
eh? Let's do it! We're not fighting with our
brains anymore? Come at me, bro. So, Arcade
lunges at Riddler and pounces on him, knocks
him off his chair, and starts choking the shit
out of him. How are you gonna choke someone
with a long metal cane, who's hitting you in
the head? Well, Arcade gets hit in the head
and he rolls away, and then... No, he's out.
He's been knocked unconscious. No, no, you
know, he's concussed. He's not unconscious.
But he, like, throws up his fist, and like
this hard light... holographic like boxing glove
on a spring shoots out and punches Riddler
in the face knocking him out cold. Hard light?
Yeah, it's Shiar technology. Okay, well if
Arcade isn't knocked unconscious with the cane,
the Riddler isn't with the boxing glove. That's
fair I guess. And then the Riddler pulls out
a gun and shoots Arcade in the face. Except
Arcade leaps out of the way and he starts flying
using these air stepper shoes that he has,
or he can like walk on air. What the fuck is
this shit? Yeah, he has those. And then he
just drops a bomb onto the Riddler. Okay well
as the bomb is dropping, that's when the Riddler
is like, RIDDLE ME THIS! I see without seeing.
To me, darkness is as clear as daylight. What
am I? Arcade says who gives a shit, and then
Riddler blows up. A bat! And so he swings his
cane like a bat, knocking the bomb back at Arcade.
You got that riddle from Batman Forever. It
was the only thing I could come up with at the
last minute for a bat. Okay, so allegedly this
is the type of bomb that could be batted upwards
Yes. and still not explode. Whatever. We'll
end our improvised scenario there where either
Arcade gets blown up with his own bomb or the
Riddler gets blown up with Arcade's bomb. And
we'll go ahead and run the simulations and
find out which of these characters wins this
match.
Alright, as much as I wanted that to be a battle
of minds, you made it devolve into a battle
of fists in the end. What? Yeah, with your transmitter
reversal device. They had to start punching
each other because they couldn't electrocute
each other. Now intelligence wise, these guys
are probably on par with each other. Now I would
say that Riddler has a higher success rate
in the comics than Arcade. However Arcade frequently
goes up against more powerful heroes than I
would say the Riddler does. For the most part,
the Riddler usually sticks to Gotham City in
Batman, but he's taken his gig to Central City
to fight the Flash before. That being said,
it's pretty rare. Yeah, the rest of their stats
were also pretty comparable in addition to
their intelligence. It's hard to say exactly
what equipment each of these characters has
on them, so we kind of went with what you could
consider default weapons. For Riddler, it included
his cane, as well as some question mark flashbangs
and a gun, a pistol. Arcade, that was even
harder. but we assume that he had some kind
of holographic image inducer, maybe some explosives,
maybe a gun. So that being said, we figured
Arcade could probably deliver a higher damage
level than Riddler at any average given moment.
Correct, because basically he's just dealing
with technology that's a little bit more advanced
than Riddler typically works with. Right. But
in terms of like, you know, strength, speed,
durability... They're average. They're not
typically lifting weights, you know? The only
things these guys are lifting are... Pencils
to fill out their Sudoku. Right, exactly. Alright,
so who do you think won between these two characters?
I'm pretty convinced it's Arcade. Just because
of the few stats where he ranks higher than
the Red Lurin, namely damage and evasiveness,
we figured that his holograms would make him
a little bit more tricky with his illusion casting
and possible force field generation. Right,
again it all comes down to the toys that they're
using at the moment. So that being said...
The winner of the Riddler vs Arcade is... You're
correct, it's Arcade. What a cheater! Arcade
won 651 matches out of the 1000 simulations.
The Riddler only won 349. So it wasn't that
close of a match. No, I'm not surprised. When
one character is higher than another character,
even if it's by a little bit in multiple stats,
it's gonna skew the results in their favor.
By skew, you mean... totally stop, totally annihilate.
What a cheater. Totally win. I'm just in character
right now, what a cheater. That does it for
this episode. Arcade beats Riddler 65.1% of
the time. Go ahead and reach out to us guys,
let us know what you thought about this matchup.
And you can do that on social media, on Facebook,
Instagram, or Twitter. Just visit our website,
dynamicduel.com, and you can get links to all
of our social media profiles. If you visit
our website at dynamicduel.com, you'll also
find a link to our merchandise store, which
is on T-Public. And if you use that link, you
could get a discount on your first order of
t-shirts or phone cases or stickers. Stickers
are awesome. Stickers are fricking awesome.
And they're only like $2. Yeah, definitely give
those a check out. That does it for this episode.
In our next episode, we will be reviewing an
X-Men film, since we're kind of on the theme
of X-Men with the villain, Arcade. We're gonna
be reviewing an earlier X-Men movie. X-Men
Days of Future Past, which I think is one of
the better X-Men films. It's definitely one
of the more interesting and it's certainly novel
in the way that the two X-Men generation casts
kind of meet together in this one movie. So
really looking forward to talking about that
film. Go ahead and watch it again if you guys
haven't seen it recently and we'll be back
next week to go ahead and talk about it. Please
don't forget to share, subscribe, rate or review
our podcast on whatever platform you're listening
to us on. It goes a long way in helping spread
the word about the show. Again we're trying
to get to 200 ratings. specifically on iTunes,
but if you're listening to us somewhere else,
such as Spotify or Stitcher, please don't forget
to subscribe or rate us. Hope you guys enjoyed,
we'll talk to you guys next time. Up, up and
away, true believers.