This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
Welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin brother, Marvelous
Joe. And in this episode, we are doing a duel
between the characters of Blockbuster and Tombstone.
And I know what you're thinking, but you're
wrong. This is not, in fact, a battle. between
a 90s era video store and a frozen pizza company,
it is comic book characters. Obscure ones, but
comic book characters nonetheless. I don't
think Tombstone is that obscure. He's a pretty
prominent Spider-Man and Daredevil villain.
I mean, he was in the, into the Spider-Verse
movie. I totally blocked that. Blockbuster
actually has been in a few animated works before,
so maybe he's not that obscure either. That
said, when I Google Blockbuster, the first thing
that comes up is not the DC character. Same
thing with Tombstone, so fair enough. Now this
duel was specifically requested by our executive
producer, Miggy Mathagean. We'll break down
the characters' histories and abilities and
run a thousand simulations to find out who would
actually win. Before that, we're gonna break
down the comic book movie news from the past
week, of which there was just one news item,
and that was that the Sandman series for Netflix
is ending with season two. Yeah, the day this
episode drops, we're supposed to get the first
teaser trailer for the Fantastic Four first
steps movie that's coming out later this summer,
but, you know, that's just our luck. So next
week we'll be talking about the teaser, but
as always, we list our segment times in our
episode description, so feel free to check out
the show notes if you want to skip ahead to
a particular topic. Guys, our artificially intelligent
dual simulator AJ9K has a quick message for
our listeners, so listen up. Why hello there,
do you want even more from this podcast? Then
become a part of the dynamic dual community
on Patreon, where you can choose from three
tiers. The dynamic two-oh tier gives you access
to our Discord chat server. The fantastic four
tier gives you two bonus episodes each month,
and the X-Force tier makes you an executive
producer of this show. Lastly, The Diner Mike
podcast network tier lets you create your own
podcast using this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny
and Joe will help you develop your show, provide
graphic support and consultation, and get you
simulation results. Pitch the twins your ideas
via email at dynamicduelpodcast at gmail.com.
Check it out at patreon.com slash dynamicduel.
Pip pip cheerio. Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone
who supports the podcast. Guys, be sure to
tune into the other shows on the DynaMic Podcast
Network this week, including Max Destruction,
which pits your favorite action heroes from
film and television against each other. This
week, hosts Scotty and Gilly are finding out
who would win in a fight between the MCU's
Spider-Man and the DCEU's Blue Beetle. That's
right, they're doing a Marvel versus DC episode.
Totally here for it. Can't wait to see Tom Holland's
Spider-Man wipe the floor with Trilla Mardi
Doignes' Blue Beetle. Yeah, that's not gonna
happen. We've run that battle. I'm pretty confident
I know who comes out on top. We ran the comic
book character battle, but who wins between
the movie characters? I'm still pretty confident.
Well you're done. On the Senjoh World Podcast,
host Zachary Hepburn speculates on fights between
fan favorite anime and manga characters. This
Thursday, Zach is going to find out who'd win
between Blade from the Blade anime against
Richter Belmont from the Castlevania anime.
On the Konsole Kombat podcast hosts John and
Dean simulate battles between popular video
game characters. In yesterday's episode, they
found out who would win between Princess Peach
and Princess Zelda. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com
or click the link in our show notes to listen
to all the shows in the DynaMic Podcast Network.
But with that out of the way, quick to the No
Prize! A No Prize is an award Marvel used to
give out to fans. Our version, the Dynamic Dual
No Prize, is a digital award we post on Instagram
for the person that we feel gave the best answer
to our question of the week. Last week we asked
you guys, which actor has given the best performance
in a villain role for a Marvel or DC series?
And we got four answers, so let's go over our
three honorable mentions as well as the no
prize winner. Our first honorable mention goes
to Lee Tapscott, who said, Hi, this is Lee
Tapscott about which actor performances was
the best villain. I think David Tennant as
Kilgrave, aka Purple Man, in the Jessica Jones
series, you grew to hate him and he was perhaps
the first villain we wanted to see the hero
actually kill. Yeah, I mean, this was one of
the answers to beat, right? Kilgrave, aka the
Purple Man from the Jessica Jones television
series, was played masterfully by David Tennant,
who is, you know, a pretty charismatic actor,
but by God, was he easy to hate in the course
of that show. Yeah, I don't know if anyone
else could have played that role besides David
Tennant, honestly. It probably would have ruined
their career, just with all the horrible things
that the character did. Right. But when you
have someone like David Tennant who really choose
the scenery with the role, he can kind of get
by considering the subject matter. His influence
was so lasting in that show that it carried
on within the subsequent seasons of Jessica
Jones. There were only three seasons of Jessica
Jones, but his presence was still definitely
felt. Great answer, Lee. Our next honorable
mention goes to Clive, who said. Hi, this is
Clive from Toronto. Without putting too much
thought into it, the villain that comes to mind
is Deathstroke in the Arrow TV show, specifically
in the earlier seasons. I just remember feeling
like the stakes were really high when this
character was on screen. It really surprised
me when he killed a significant character on
the show, no spoilers, but in that single action,
it showed me that this man was no joke. Yeah,
Slade Wilson aka Deathstroke played by Manu
Bennett in the Arrow television series was
a force to be reckoned with. The story arc of
getting to know the character in the flashbacks
on the island with Oliver Queen to when he became
a full-fledged horror monster type villain
in subsequent seasons where it seemed like no
character was safe from being killed by Deathstroke
was just remarkable. You never knew when or
where he was going to appear and that was part
of why the character was so scary. I've never
seen the Arrow television series, but I've
always heard good things about the Deathstroke
character from that show. And there have been
several live action iterations of Deathstroke.
Like we got him in Titan season two, as well
as like the post credit scene in the Justice
League film. But yeah, Manu Burnett's portrayal
is largely regarded as the best. Yeah, the Arrowverse
version is still the best. Great answer Clive.
Our next honorable mention goes to Mike Williams,
who said, Hi guys, Mike Williams here. I picked
Clancy Brown for Lex Luthor in the Justice League
Unlimited series and Oswald Patton for Modoc.
Have a good day. Yeah, we didn't say specifically
that these had to be live action performances.
So Mike Williams gave us two animated performances,
first with Clancy Brown as Lex Luthor and Patton
Oswald as Modoc. Yeah, Clancy Brown to Lex Luthor
is what Kevin Conroy is to Batman. He's just
the iconic voice for that role. It's hard to
hear anybody else when you read the lines in
the comics. And Patton Oswalt played the character
of Modok so much better than how the character
was portrayed in live action in the Ant-Man
and the Wasp quantumania film. To me, the Hulu-Modok
stop-motion animation depiction of the character
is the quintessential version. Yeah, I've never
seen if Patton Oswalt has ever said anything
about the MCU version of Modok, but you have
to imagine he was pretty embarrassed when he
saw it. Like embarrassed for Kevin Feige and
Marvel Studios. Yeah, they definitely didn't
have to go that route. If I had my way, the
character never would have taken off his faceplate.
Because with the faceplate, it was actually
a pretty cool design for live action. But yeah,
the Modok Hulu series was just fantastic. Great
answer, Mike. But the winner of this week's
Snow Prize is Buster Barnes. Who said? Hi,
guys, Buster Barnes here. And for my pick, I'm
going to go for a bit of an underrated shout,
which is Cronden, who plays Tobias Wail in The
Black Lightning Show, a pretty underrated show
and a very underrated villain. He was menacing,
imposing, intimidating for a guy who didn't
really have any acting credits before this show.
I think he was a great villain and yeah, I
think it's a really underrated performance.
See you guys. Love the show. Yeah. Crandon,
I believe is a rapper. He's a musician by profession,
but honestly, I can't think of anyone better
to play the role of Tobias Whale for the Black
Lightning series. I didn't watch the whole
series, but the episodes I did watch, Cronden
made a fantastic kingpin-esque villain, just
in terms of striking and imposing figure and
intimidation factor. Yeah, I never watched
the Black Lightning television series, so I
only know of his version of Tobias Whale through
the marketing of the show. And yeah, it looked
like it was a pretty good performance. I don't
know too much about Tobias Whale in general.
I do remember that he was in the Suicide Squad,
hell to pay. animated movie and he was pretty
imposing in that as well. But the reason that
Buster Barnes' answer gets the no prize this
week is because Crandon also voiced the character
of Tombstone in the Spider-Man Into the Spider-Verse
movie. So it was a pretty topical answer considering
that in this episode we're pitting Tombstone
against Blockbuster. I thought it was interesting
that Crandon is an albino African-American and
so is Tobias Whale and Tombstone. So he's kind
of like the perfect guy to play and voice those
characters. So congrats to Buster Barnes. You
win this week's No Prize. If you the listener
want a shot at winning your own No Prize, stay
tuned to later on in this episode when we'll
be asking another question of the week. But
now that that's done, on to the news.
So if you remember listening to our last episode,
I mentioned that my most anticipated series
of this year is probably Sandman season 2. I
wasn't sure if we were going to get it, but
it sounds like we are, and that this upcoming
season will in fact be the final season of
the series. Which to me was heartbreaking, because
I know Sandman, the story written by Neil Gaiman,
is a 10 volume series, so for it to end on season
2 felt very premature. and since it's one of
my favorite series, I felt like they were just
making a huge mistake. Initially, I was under
the assumption that the show's conclusion was
coming about because of several sexual misconduct
accusations leveled at Neil Gaiman, and that
may very well be why they decided to announce
at this time that the series is concluding,
but according to Variety, they were actually
planning on ending with season 2 prior to these
allegations coming out. Yeah, the series of
Sandman is like 10 volumes, but only so much
of that story actually deals directly with
the character of Dream, right? Like a lot of
the story is somewhat anthological to my understanding.
So the show producers released a statement saying
that since they're focusing really on the character
of Dream, they're skipping over a lot of the
other stuff and are able to, I guess, tell
his complete arc within this next season. Now
initially I was calling BS on that reasoning.
I thought that was just a political way to say,
hey, we're going to end this series because
of Neil Gaiman's alleged conduct. But according
to Variety, they were hearing from sources
that the series was getting too pricey to continue.
So that's why they decided to focus solely
on Dream Story, which, yeah, there's not as
much to Dream Story specifically in the series
run as you would think for a series titled The
Sandman. So I could kind of buy that. I totally
believe that it's an expensive show because
it does look amazing. All the special effects
and the production value is pretty incredible.
Yeah, the show is very cinematic, very special
effects heavy. I think season one was the most
expensive season of a show that Warner Brothers
had ever produced in fact. So yeah, I guess
this should not be shocking. We did not get
a release date for this season with this news,
although we do know it's coming out in 2025.
We did however get a poster, which is pretty
bad ass all seven members of the Endless on
it. Everyone from death to despair, delirium,
desire, destiny, and destruction. It's pretty
awesome to see live-action versions of each
of these characters, and I can't wait to see
them in the series itself. But with the announcement
that this is the final season of The Sandman,
that brings us to our question of the week.
What is a cancelled Marvel or DC television
series that you most wish would have gotten
at least one other season? Record your answer
at dynamicduel.com by clicking on the red microphone
button in the bottom right hand corner of the
screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long, and don't forget to leave your name in
case we include you on the podcast. We'll pick
our favorite answer and award that person a
Dynamic Duel No Prize that we'll post to Instagram.
Be sure to answer before... February 8th.
That does it for all the news for this episode,
so now let's move on to our main event, where
we find out who would win in a battle between
the DC Villain Blockbuster and the Marvel Villain
Tombstone.
Okay, Blockbuster and Tombstone. These are two
broodish mobster villains. One is the primary
villain you could say for Nightwing and Tombstone,
as I've recently learned, is a villain for
characters like Daredevil and Spider-Man. So
it's kind of fitting because we actually pit
the characters of Nightwing and Daredevil in
a duel prior to this and now it looks like
their villains are facing off against each other.
Oh yeah, I didn't really think about that before
but you're totally right. I don't know much
about the character of Blockbuster actually.
I don't think I've read a single DC comic with
him as the villain. So I'm basically going
into this from scratch. It'll be really interesting
to learn exactly who this character is before
facing off against Tombstone. Basically Blockbuster
looks like they kind of just ripped off Tombstone,
but instead of having like this fade haircut,
it's long hair. Yeah. In this episode, we're
going to find out who would win in a battle
between a mullet and a flat top. But to explain
the methodology behind our duels, let's go to
our sentient dual simulator, Alfred Jarvis
9000. AJ9K, tell our listeners how you go about
determining a winner in our dual matchups.
Yes, of course, sir. The way I determine a winner
between the contestants is by running 1000
Monte Carlo simulations using the characters
statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation is a probabilistic
model used to determine outcomes through random
sampling. In this case, I randomized the statistics
along a normal distribution. as a way to simulate
the many variables that can occur during battle.
The stat parameters are based on the official
Marvel power grid from which the DC characters
statistics are extrapolated. Additional stat
categories are included such as range, damage
potential, versatility and perception in order
to create a more detailed and accurate simulation.
The results of the 1000 simulations provide
a percentage of wins for each character. The
contestant with the higher percentage is declared
the victor. as they have a higher probability
to win any given battle. In an equitable pairing,
neither character should win 100% of the matches.
The comic book stories have shown that there's
even a way for Batman to defeat Superman, so
the confidence rate of my method falls in line
with the precedents that have been established
in the source material. My mathematical simulations
are without subjectivity or bias. Feats are
not the sole consideration, nor are fan votes
tabulated for determination of the winner.
Thanks AJ9K! Before we run the simulations though,
we like to break down each character's histories
and abilities before improvising a scenario
on how we imagine one of the 1000 simulations
would play out beat for beat. And I believe
it's my turn to go first with the Marvel characters
backstory, so let me go ahead and tell you guys
all about Tombstone. Now Alonso Thompson Lincoln
was born in Harlem in New York City, where his
journey into the criminal underworld began
at an early age. As an African-American albino,
he stood out among his peers, becoming a target
for bullying. Rather than shrink from adversity,
however, he turned it into his weapon, training
his body into an intimidating size and using
his natural strength to extort his classmates.
The only person who ever showed him any kindness
was Joseph Robbie Robertson, who would later
grow to work for the Daily Bugle newspaper.
That kindness ended when Robertson, the editor
of the school paper, attempted to publish an
expose on Lincoln's violent behavior. Feeling
betrayed, Lincoln silenced Robbie through intimidation,
a moment that would set the stage for their
lifelong enmity. Lincoln dropped out of school
and dove headfirst into a life of crime. His
imposing stature and ruthless demeanor made
him a natural enforcer, and his reputation
for brutality only grew. As he climbed the ranks
of organized crime, he sharpened his teeth
into points. and trained as a hand-to-hand combatant,
specializing in strangulation. He soon earned
the moniker Tombstone, both for his pale complexion
and the countless bodies he left in his wake.
Tombstone's rise to power led him to Philadelphia,
where he crossed paths with Robbie Robertson
once again. Now a journalist, Robertson witnessed
Tombstone murder a crime informant, but, paralyzed
by fear, chose to remain silent for decades.
working for the likes of Wilson Fisk, the Magia,
and Hammerhead. Despite numerous arrests, Lincoln
always managed to evade conviction, often due
to witness intimidation or the sheer terror
he instilled in those who might testify against
him. Years later, Robertson, haunted by his
past inaction, decided to finally expose Tombstone.
His confession led to Tombstone's first major
incarceration, but it also landed Robbie in
prison for withholding evidence. Tombstone
arranged for his own transfer to the same prison,
where he terrorized Robertson until the intervention
of a fellow inmate, Bruiser. When Bruiser attempted
to protect Robbie, Tombstone brutally murdered
him. However, Robertson ultimately found the
courage to stand up to his tormentor. When
they both escaped prison, he confronted Tombstone
in battle, battling him with a pitchfork and
finally escaping his grip. Tombstone resurfaced
in New York, working under Hammerhead. and
later attempting to assassinate Robertson himself.
However, a fateful accident at an Oscorp chemical
plant changed him forever. Locked inside a chamber
with an experimental gas called DIOX-3, Tombstone's
physiology mutated, giving him near invulnerable
skin, increased strength, and enhanced speed.
While the process made him virtually indestructible,
it also gave him a terrifying stone-like complexion,
cementing his legend as one of New York's deadliest
criminals. With his new abilities, Tombstone
fought Spider-Man on multiple occasions, as
well as other street level heroes like Daredevil
and Luke Cage. He even sought purpose with the
Hand, engaging in an assassination competition
against Taskmaster, only to be thwarted by Daredevil
and the Punisher. You can learn more about
Spider-Man in his duel against Blue Beetle,
Daredevil in his duel against Nightwing, Luke
Cage in his duel against Thunder, Taskmaster
in his duel against Prometheus, and Punisher
in his duel against Red Hood. Over the years,
Lincoln would continuously attempt to carve
out his own empire. He was one of the many gang
leaders present during the downfall of the
Kingpin attempting to claim a portion of Wilson
Fisk's empire. Tombstone also formed alliances
with the Hood's criminal army, flashing with
Mr. Negative in a bid for power. However, he
was repeatedly thwarted by Spider-Man and other
heroes, leading to multiple incarcerations.
Tombstone's personal life remained complex.
He had a daughter, Janice Lincoln, whom he
trained in crime and deception from an early
age. Although he hoped she would use her cunning
for financial gain as a lawyer, she instead
chose to become the supervillain Beetle, much
to his frustration. His relationship with Robbie
Robertson also took an unexpected turn when
Janice began dating Robbie's son, Randy. This
forced the two lifelong enemies into an uneasy
truce to avoid interfering in their children's
lives. Tombstone's reputation as an unbreakable
enforcer was put to the test when he was shot
at his daughter's wedding, revealing that his
bulletproof durability had diminished over time.
This attack ignited a gang war as Tombstone's
rival saw his vulnerability as an opportunity
to seize his criminal empire. Despite his injuries,
he remained active in the ongoing conflict,
working to reclaim lost territory and eliminate
his challengers. His conflicts with Spider-Man
persisted as the wall-crawler frequently disrupted
his operations. Tombstone was also targeted
by law enforcement, including detective Yuri
Watanabe, the vigilante known as Wraith, who
sought justice after he critically injured
one of her colleagues. Despite being temporarily
imprisoned, Tombstone leveraged his deep-rooted
connections to manipulate the legal system and
escape. Powers-wise, Tombstone's body was physically
enhanced through the DIOX-3 chemical, which
grants him enough strength to lift around 6
tons, as well as give him increased durability
with Stoneheart skin and increased resistance
to toxins. He's a skilled marksman with his
commonly used twin pistols, and he's a highly
experienced street fighter. And that's Tombstone.
So was it never explained why all of a sudden
he was able to be shot despite prior to that
having like rock hard skin? Yeah, that was
during a time when his powers were temporarily
diminished. But traditionally, the character
is known for having stone skin, and that's how
he'll be portrayed in this match. OK, convenient.
Blockbuster doesn't normally carry guns. He's
a weapon unto himself essentially. Although
you would think he would, it would make his
life a lot easier. Let me get into Blockbuster's
history. Now Mark Desmond, a frail yet brilliant
chemist, devoted himself to developing a serum
that would grant him immense physical power.
His experiments proved successful, drastically
increasing his strength, durability, and size,
but at the cost of his intellect. The transformation
left him barely capable of coherent speech,
however, turning him into a mindless brute.
His older brother, Roland Desmond, who possessed
a criminal mind and ambitions of wealth and
power, took advantage of Mark's new condition.
Shielding their mother from the truth about
Mark's monstrous transformation, Roland manipulated
his brother into committing crimes on his behalf.
Operating in Gotham City, It wasn't long before
the Desmond brothers caught the attention of
Batman and Robin, who you can learn more about
in their duels against Moon Knight and Daredevil,
respectively. Mark's rampages made him a formidable
opponent, but Batman discovered a way to pacify
him. Years earlier, Bruce Wayne had rescued
Mark from drowning in quicksand. When Batman
removed his cowl to reveal his face, the sight
of Bruce triggered a memory in Mark of the
man who had once saved him. momentarily calming
the beast and preventing further destruction.
After multiple encounters with Batman, Mark
was ultimately set to the Alfred Foundation
for treatment, where scientists unsuccessfully
attempted to find a way to reverse his condition.
Seeking solace, Mark began living a life of
isolation, though his mind was easily influenced.
The Outsider, an enemy of Batman, manipulated
Mark into fighting the Dark Knight again, but
Batman once more at- but Batman once more outwitted
his foe. After his defeat, Mark was transferred
to Star Labs for further treatment. The scientists
there attempted to use radiation therapy to
restore his original mind, but the experiment
failed, seemingly killing him. Mark was buried
in Gotham Cemetery, though it was later revealed
that his death was a sham. Mark had been revived
and left the city, eventually finding work in
a West Virginia mining town. He lived there
in peace, until Batman tracked him down. Initially
enraged at the sight of Batman, Mark's aggression
was neutralized when his fellow miners became
trapped in a cave-in. Working together, Batman
and Mark rescued them, and Mark helped capture
the men responsible for the disaster. Recognizing
that Mark had found a life where he could do
no harm, Batman allowed him to stay in the
town rather than return him to Gotham. However,
Mark would later be recruited into Amanda Waller's
suicide squad, and sent to fight the powerful
entity known as Brimstone. During the battle,
Brimstone burned Mark alive, killing him. Following
Mark's death, his brother Roland Desvend, now
suffering from a rare genetic disorder, sought
a cure for his deteriorating condition. Turning
to experimental steroids similar to his brother's
serum, Roland transformed into the second Blockbuster,
possessing immense strength. by suffering the
same intellectual deterioration as Mark. However,
unlike his brother, Roland regained his intelligence
after striking a deal with the demon Neuron,
who enhanced his mind in exchange for his soul.
With his newfound intellect and strength, Roland
sought to carve out his own criminal empire.
He moved to Bluthaven, a city riddled with
corruption, and systemically eliminated rival
crime bosses to establish himself as its undisputed
ruler. His rise to power coincided with Nightwing's
arrival in the city, and the two clashed with
Nightwing working to dismantle Roland's operations.
After years of conflict, Roland's body began
to suffer from the strain of his immense bulk,
developing albinism and a heart condition as
side effects of his treatments. Seeking a cure,
he traveled to Gorilla City, where he underwent
a heart transplant to prolong his life. He launched
a personal vendetta against Nightwing, systematically
targeting the people closest to him, orchestrating
attacks against Nightwing's allies and loved
ones, and working to break him mentally and
emotionally. During their final confrontation,
a new vigilante known as Tarantula intervened.
With Nightwing exhausted and psychologically
shattered, she executed Blockbuster in front
of him. The police investigation into Roland's
death was minimal, and his criminal empire quickly
crumbled in the wake of his murder. However,
during the events of Blackest Night, Roland
was resurrected as a Black Lantern and returned
to Gotham City alongside other undead villains.
He and other Black Lanterns were ultimately
defeated, however, and his corpse returned to
rest. After the Flash created a Flashpoint
event that reset DC's continuity, Mark Desmond
was reintroduced as a test subject for a mysterious
doctor named Fane. Undergoing procedures meant
to enhance his intelligence, Mark was exposed
to an overdose of a chemical compound that transformed
him into a hulking brew. Rampaging through
Washington, D.C., he came into conflict with
Hawk and Dove before being subdued by Batman
and Robin. You can learn more about Hawk and
Dove in our Hawk and Dove versus Northstar
and Aurora episode. Later, Mark became a member
of the Secret Society, an organization of supervillains
assembled by the Crime Syndicate. He was sent
to battle Lex Luthor's Injustice League during
the crime syndicate's reign over Earth. Roland
Desmond also resurfaced, also taking on the
mantle of Blockbuster, though his version maintained
his intelligence without requiring a deal with
Neuron. He became the leader of Bloodhaven's
criminal underworld, positioning himself as
Nightwing's primary adversary. After Dick Grayson
publicly revealed himself to be a billionaire
and pledged to rebuild Bloodhaven, Roland saw
him as a threat to his control. He attempted
to have Dick assassinated, but failed, as multiple
superheroes came to Dick's aid. When Blockbuster
sought to personally kill Dick, he attacked
the Haven Community Center, leading to a climactic
battle with Nightwing. During the fight, Roland
knocked off Nightwing's mask and discovered
his secret identity. Despite this revelation,
Nightwing defeated Roland in combat. His grip
over Blewd Haven soon collapsed, and his own
henchmen turned against him when they learned
of Blockbuster's corrupt dealings with the private
prison. Fleeing into the city's back alleys,
Blockbuster encountered the villain Heartless,
who had been targeting powerful individuals
in Bloodhaven. Heartless killed Roland, taking
his heart as a trophy, and unknowingly ensuring
that the seeker of Nightwing's identity died
with him. Now powers-wise, both versions of
Blockbuster possess immense superhuman strength,
durability, and stamina. capable of lifting
several tons. Blockbuster is also a formidable
hand-to-hand combatant, and the Roland version,
which is the version I'm going with, is a criminal
mastermind. That's Blockbuster. Okay, so I
mentioned earlier that I wasn't really too familiar
with the character of Blockbuster, having never
read any stories with him, and after that bio,
I'm kinda glad, because that was boring. Okay,
same with Tombstone, like who gives a shit?
Tombstone at least looks cool. Okay, Blockbuster
is not a character that looks cool. Spoken like
someone incapable of rocking a mullet. That's
exactly what a jealous non-mullet person would
say. Fair enough.
Where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
Dynomic Podcast Network presents Konsole Kombat,
where video game legends brawl every Monday.
Comic Book Titans smash every Tuesday. Max Destruction,
where TV and action heroes battle every Wednesday.
And Sendro World, where anime champions clash
every Thursday. Join us as we speculate on
the matches and armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge victorious.
Visit dynamicpodcast.com where we settle the
debate and settle the score.
Now that we've got their histories and abilities
out of the way, let's speculate on how one
of the 1000 simulated matches will go. The winner
is determined by simulations, not this speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how the fight could
play out. AJ9K, what are the rules of our speculation?
Well, I should say there are no rules, other
than the characters have no prior knowledge
of the other going into the fight. All they
are aware of starting out is that the other
character is a threat that needs to be eliminated.
For the speculation... The contestants will
begin approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the
match itself, as no environmental statistics
are considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. Alright
then let's get into it! Blockbuster and Tombstone
meet on the battlefield. Who goes first? I'm
gonna say Tombstone goes first because he has
guns. So with this like creepy ass smile, he's
gonna brandish his two pistols. like spinning
them up and pointing them right at Blockbuster
before smoking that fool like it ain't no thing.
I mean, that's like firing handguns at a charging
rhino, though, because once Blockbuster sees
Tombstone brandish those guns, he's going to
know that he needs to close the gap between
them. And he probably figures that his imposing
size would probably make him like physically
superior to Tombstone. So Blockbuster, he's
going to rush Tombstone and get tagged a few
times. with bullets, sure, but it's nothing
serious enough to stop him from grabbing Tombstone's
guns and just hurling them towards the horizon.
But wait, what makes you think Tombstone's
guns are that easy to grab? Like, Tombstone's
known for his unbreakable grip, right? So like,
Blockbuster tries to snatch Tombstone's guns
from his hands, but Tombstone's gonna use that
moment to straight up kick Blockbuster right
in his Nard sack. And when Blockbuster drops
to his knees in front of him because of the
pain... Tombstone is just gonna pistol whip
him right across the face. No dude, Blockbuster,
he has balls of steel. So he just no sells
that cheap nut shot. And while he's grabbing
Tombstone's guns, he's gonna crush the metal
barrels in his hands. Just rendering them useless.
Before headbutting Tombstone right in the face,
knocking him backward. Headbutting Tombstone
is like the last thing you want to do. Because
one... Tombstone's head is as durable as a stone,
so it's gonna be like headbutting a rock. And
two, Tombstone has sharp ass teeth, so as Blockbuster's
like reeling from giving himself a concussion,
Tombstone's gonna bite one of Blockbuster's
eyes just straight out of his head, and then
he's gonna spit it out, just grinning real creepy
like a shark. Ah! Ah, damn. Well, Blockbuster,
he's pissed. And that's when he's gonna grab
Tombstone by the legs and just start ragdolling
him, slamming him into the ground repeatedly,
like what the Hulk did to Loki in Avengers.
Right, but again, Tombstone's rock hard, so
this doesn't faze him too much. Yeah, dude.
I don't wanna know that. His skin is as hard
as a rock, is what I'm saying. So, you know,
he's durable enough to handle this attack without
being too hurt, and he's just gonna reach into
one of his boots. and pull out a switchblade
that he uses to reach up and shank Blockbuster
right in the gut with. And that's when Blockbuster's
just gonna yeet Tombstone, like, tossing him
like half a block away. And he's gonna pull
out the knife, which, thanks for the weapon,
and he's gonna charge Tombstone and just slam
right into him knife first. Right. Okay, but
the knife is gonna break. Blockbuster is not
a smart villain. Your mom's not a smart villain.
And that's when Tombstone knees Blockbuster
in the gut, you know, making him bend forward,
and then Tombstone's gonna drop his elbow onto
his head, and Blockbuster's gonna fall to the
ground. And for his finishing move, Tombstone's
gonna curb stomp the guy, like not in the figurative
sense, but in the very literal sense, Tombstone's
gonna curb stomp Blockbuster, cave his face
in, and Tombstone wins the match. No, because
when Blockbuster is on the ground and he sees
that he's about to get his head kicked in, he's
going to quickly sweep Tombstone's leg out
from under him, and when he hits the ground,
Blockbuster is just going to shove his fingers
right through Tombstone's eyes, through his
skull, into his brain, killing him, because
I'm guessing his eyeballs aren't rock hard.
Actually, that's, yeah, you would be correct
in that assumption. But like, Blockbuster is
missing an eye, so he's going an eye for an
eye here. but Ni for Ni leaves the whole world
blind. Yeah, Blockbuster probably does not
give two shits about Gandhi. But we'll go ahead
and leave the match there. Either Tombstone
curb stomps Blockbuster or Blockbuster jams
his fingers into Tombstone's brain through
his eyes. Two violent mobster characters, two
violent ways to end this match. But let's see
which one happens by running the stats. AJ9K,
hit it! Inputting data, running calculations,
processing results. Simulations complete. Yeah,
that was pretty gruesome for sure. I figured
this would be pretty visceral because these
characters are pretty straightforward. You
know, they're brawlers. Yeah, they're not going
to hold back either. The stats were pretty
interesting. Blockbuster is faster than Tombstone,
even though Tombstone is pretty quick. Blockbuster,
like you said, is like a rhino and can run really
fast. Blockbuster is also smarter than Tombstone.
Yeah, at least the version I went with is...
The Mark version is super not smart, but the
Roland version actually is very much so. We
did, however, give the edge to Tombstone in
regards to durability, saying he's slightly
more durable than Blockbuster, but also in
regards to versatility, which actually wasn't
too surprising to me, considering Tombstone
will bring weapons into fights. Yeah. And he
also has his sharp teeth, which he used to
like bite things off. Right. He's a biter. Right.
But also because of his weapons. we gave the
range edge to Tombstone as well. Yeah, otherwise,
these characters were pretty much identical.
You know, they had the same evasiveness. We
said they're about the same strength level
and had about the same fighting skill. So with
all that said, Jonathan, who do you think is
winning this match? I'm hoping it's Blockbuster,
although Instagram does not agree with me for
the first time in a long time. The Marvel character
is actually coming out ahead with Tombstone
currently sitting at 51 percent. of the vote.
Well, I'm glad to see that our Marvel Instagram
fans are starting to show up for these polls,
but that's still a little close guys. Like
we really want to be dominating these polls.
So if you're a Marvel fan, be sure to follow
us on Instagram and then vote whenever Jonathan
gets these polls up, you know, at the very
last minute on Sundays when we record. Okay,
that's fair. But let's get the final results
of the match. AJ 9K, the results please. Hey,
you are, sir. Okay, the winner of the duel.
between Blockbuster and Tombstone is... Tombstone!
Gosh dang it! It wasn't a total wipeout, I
think the match was fairly close. Out of 1000
simulated battles, Tombstone won 592, whereas
Blockbuster won 408. In the end, the determining
factors largely were range and durability considering
Tombstone is rock hard. Ugh! What I just I'm
just gonna keep saying that now I don't like
it And I don't like the results of this match
either. I gotta say well you could blame Miggy
for that one. I think yeah, Miggy What are you
doing? You're a DC fan. Come on. I'll say that
thematically It was a good pitch for a dual
matchup But yeah, the Marvel fans on the discord
should all thank Miggy for his contribution
to Marvel's win rate this week Miggy just stay
off discord for a week just stay off of it But
that does it for this duel, AJ9K help close
this out. Thanks for listening to Dynamic Dual.
Visit the show's website at dynamicdual.com
and follow us on Instagram at dynamicdualpodcast.
You can support the show on Patreon at patreon.com
slash dynamicdual and joining a tier that works
for you, or by rating and reviewing Dynamic
Dual on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser or
on our website. Don't forget to listen to the
other shows in the DynaMic Podcast Network,
including Max Destruction, Senjow World and
Konsole Kombat. Our next episode is going to
be another duel episode in lead up to the Captain
America Brave New World review that we'll be
doing in a few weeks. We're going to find out
who would win in a fight between Red Hulk and
General Wade Eiling, also known as the General.
But that does it for this episode. We want to
give a big thanks to our executive producers,
Ken Johnson. John Swarovski, Zachary Hepburn,
Dustin Balcom, Miggy Mathen-Geehan, Brandon
Estregard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yaiten, Austin
Wieselowski, AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Gil
Camacho, Adam Spees, Dean Molesky, Devin Davis,
Joseph Kirstein, Josh Leiner, Mike Williams,
and Oscar Galvez for helping to make this podcast
possible. We'll talk to you guys next week.
Up, up, and away, true believers. Hold the phone.
I thought this was going to be a fight between
a video store and frozen pizza. I want my money
back.