Welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, where we
discuss all things DC and Marvel related, we
review superhero films, and we debate who would
win in Marvel vs. DC matchups. I'm Jonny DC.
And I'm his twin brother Marvelous Joe. We're
formerly known as the DC Marvel Battlecast,
so ignore all references to that in this episode.
And note that our new email address is dyna
You can also find us on Twitter and Instagram.
by searching for Dynamic Dual Podcast. Let's
start the show.
today is Black Canary versus Black Widow. Yeah
that's gonna be a close one. Of all the matchups
that we've had so far I think Black Canary and
Black Widow is probably going to be the closest
match just from putting in the stats. They're
even more similar than Batman and Moon Knight
were. Yeah I think so. So yeah look forward
to that later on. Black Canary is part of a
super team called the Birds of Prey. Another
one of those team members was Barbara Gordon
aka Oracle aka Batgirl. Yeah, so this wasn't
officially released by the studio, but Warner
Brothers kind of goofed. For people who have
seen the movie, they gave them this survey
that was asking them questions like oh, you
know, how would you rate the actors in the
film? was Jenna Malone which we know has been
cut from the film. She'll appear in the rated-r
version. So they're showing people the rated-r
version? No. No? No. But they left it in as
part of the survey by mistake. So people were
like taking screenshots of that. So I mean
again this hasn't been officially released but
the likelihood of it being true is it's she's
pretty much Oracle which is pretty cool. I remember
when they first announced her casting I would
Kelly. That's what my guess was too. I think
that would have been awesome because it's a
different way to portray Robin. Robin has never
been you know taken the most seriously out
of all the superheroes. There's you know there's
always a lot of jokes so it made sense to me
because it felt like that was the easiest way
to kind of get around that kind of stigma that's
attached to the character. But it's all about
like continuity and when you started reading
comics I'm pretty confident in saying that probably
most people's favorite Robin was Dick Grayson
but a lot of
that role into Nightwing. So once you take Dick
Grayson out of the equation, what Robin are
you left with? What Robins? People either like
Tim Drake or people like Damien Wayne. Everyone
loves The Dark Knight Returns. And doing Carrie
Kelly's, I thought it would have been a nice
way to appease fans who sort of have one Robin
preference over another, I guess. Yeah, yeah,
I think it would have been cool. But I'm equally
as happy with her being Barbara Gordon. Yeah,
it would be cool if they eventually do make
a Birds of Prey movie or something. My theory
is that she's probably not going to be Oracle
in the rated R version. My theory is that they
probably do a flashback with the Joker, the
rumors of them having a scene with the Joker
where he's beating Jason Todd to death, the
scene where he's shooting Barbara Gordon in
the spine, paralyzing her, that famous scene
from the killing joke. And speaking of Commissioner
Gordon too, Mortar Brothers recently knows that
J.K. Simmons has been cast as Commissioner
Gordon, which is awesome. I think you'd make
a good Commissioner Gordon, not as good as
a J. Jonah Jameson, but he'll make a good Commissioner
Gordon. I kind of bummed because I think a
lot of people wanted J.K. Simmons to come back
in the role of J. Jonah Jameson for the new
Spider-Man movie by Sony coming out. And now
that's not going to happen, obviously. So that's
a little bummer. But I think that's pretty good
casting. It can't wait for. whenever they make
the Batman movie, I mean, whatever it's called,
if it's just called The Batman, just like the
Ben Affleck directed standalone Batman film.
Think of how many Oscar winners you're gonna
have in there. You're gonna have Ben Affleck,
J.K. Simmons. The Oscars mean nothing to me,
so I'm not impressed. You're gonna have Jared
Leto. You're gonna have Jeremy Irons won an
Oscar. Maybe Chris Terrio, if he goes back to
write it. It's gonna be a very high caliber
film. It's gonna be great. Just when you have
that level of talent, it has to be phenomenal.
Yeah, that budget's going to be almost as big
as the $400 million by BBS. That's not true.
How is Bad Members Superman doing? Actually,
it has the second highest pre-sale record of
all time after Star Wars, which is awesome.
A lot of the way they track pre-sale tickets
is like in the first 24 hours, what percentage
of the available tickets are sold. For Star
Wars, 75% in the first 24 hours. Why do they
track it that way? Why don't they just track
it in terms of dollars? I don't know. Because
they would have a record of that. I'm sure
they do. That's weird. But yeah, so Star Wars
has the highest number. I think it was 70,
I think it was, like it was around 75%. Third
place goes to Jurassic Park, which had 50%.
Fourth place. was I believe Avengers Age of
Ultron. I mean, in Civil War tickets have gone
on sale and I'm actually sure how that did.
I know it didn't do as good as BBS, but Batman
v Superman did close to 60%, I believe. So it's
doing really well. Do you think it'll break
200 million opening weekend? Over under. I think
it's gonna get close to 200 million. Yeah.
And that's what a lot of, you know, like, film
industry commenters are now changing their
prediction to. Yeah, because it used to be like
130 or something. It was between 100 and 140,
essentially. So it should be Deadpool, at least.
Yeah, I'm pretty sure it'll be Deadpool. If
it doesn't, I will laugh. It's going to be definitely
mention it on the next podcast. It should be
beat dead. It's the two biggest superhero icons
in the world. Yeah, but that doesn't just because
they're icons. It doesn't equal box office revenue.
Familiarity as well. Otherwise Man of Steel
would have done way better than it did. Familiarity
brings a lot to the table though. I mean, that's
one of the reasons I think Marvel does so well.
Is because people are familiar with that Marvel
brand. People are familiar with Batman. Those
movies have always been successful. DC doesn't
really have a cinematic brand right now though.
No, but we have the familiarity of our characters.
Well, people didn't go see Man of Steel because
of the bad taste of Superman Returns. But when
you bring Batman into the mix, Batman has always
sold well. So... Yeah, I guess that's true.
What about the familiarity of Sandman? I heard
that movie got delayed. Uh... Well, I mean,
there was no like official start. I mean, you
could say it was delayed. You could say that,
you know, it's still in development. Joseph
Gordon-Levitt, who was attached to definitely
direct and possibly star. Or I think he announced
that he was going to star like the day he announced
that he was departing the project. He's departing
the project. So I can't imagine him as an anime.
I don't know why. Can you? It's weird because
I always imagined him as Nightwing and I was
really pumped when he was in the Dark Knight
Rises. I kind of hoped that they would have
done something with that. In my mind, I'm still
kind of hoping that he's gonna be Nightwing
somehow, somewhere down the line. He's a pretty...
he... no, I don't think that would ever happen.
No. Just because of the Dark Knight Rises. Yeah.
But he is a pretty broad range. I couldn't...
If you give him like, you know, some 80s hair,
dark, long hair. Like a seagull's hair? Not
bad. The Cure hair? Yeah, yeah. Yeah. I could
see him as a dream. You know who I really saw
though was probably like Tom Hiddleston. Oh,
he would be fantastic. He would be a great
dream. He's like almost the new Johnny Depp.
And I say that because, did you ever see Crimson
Peak? It was the new- No, I saw the trailer
for it though. The Guillermo del Toro movie.
Right. That was very much- it was such kind
of like- the spiritual successor to Sleepy
Hollow by Tim Burton with Johnny Depp. I almost
consider them companion pieces because they
have a very similar setting and kind of just
really creepy kind of feel. If you haven't
seen it, you should see it. But yeah, I think
Tom Hiddleston would be great because his character
kind of reminded me of if this movie were made
in the early 90s, it would totally be Johnny
Depp in the role. So yeah, that's a good idea.
Tom Hiddleston is Loki, he'll probably be Loki
for a while maybe. Yeah. But Sandman is so...
I mean, it's part of the DC universe just because
in the comic Sandman, aka Dream, aka Morpheus
interacted with some of the... the characters,
like Marshall Manhunter, like the Scarecrow,
like Dr. Destiny. But he's kind of like, if
anyone's not familiar with Sandman, it was
a comic written in the 90s by Neil Gaiman. And
it was basically just about these... gods,
essentially these just sort of abstract concepts.
The primary character, his name was Dream,
and he was basically the embodiment of thought,
essentially, creativity. And so his stories
were really way far out there, and you could
do almost anything with him. Yeah, I almost
think it would make a better series because
of that fact. Oh, absolutely. within one plot
arc with a series, you could have a new arc
each episode. Yeah, no. Anytime there's this
big new comic book film announcement, I always
tell Barbara, my wife, don't let me die until
this comes out. If they ever did an announcement
for a Sandman TV show. Oh my gosh, yeah, totally,
I just go into like. hyper sleep hibernation.
Oh, speaking of, and speaking of Johnny Depp,
you just made me realize Tim Burton would direct
like the most unbelievable, unbelievably good
version of Sandman or Guillermo del Toro. Yeah.
Or him. I, I don't know. I think Guillermo
del Toro would be better because he, he's just
as dark as Tim Burton, but he's even more mature,
I think. Cause like it would be hard to imagine
Tim Burton directing like a Blade 2 type thing.
But Guillermo can do everything Tim Burton can
do and more, I think. That's probably true.
Plus Tim Burton would probably try and change
it to suit his own story. Like Superman, uh,
lips or whatever. Didn't, um, didn't Guillermo
Detorlo was he attached to direct Justice League
Dark? Is that still in development? Yes. Yeah.
With like, uh, Deadman and Constantine and.
Yeah, that's another big one. I'm ever since
he mentioned that he was writing. That's the
one I'm looking forward to a lot just to see
Constantine on film again done I mean, I don't
want to say done right because I actually liked
the cannot reuse Constantine film Yes, but
you know just more like the comics I guess more
like the Hellblazer character. Yeah. Yeah,
my wife loves The Constantine movie and the
TV show was great too. TV show is really good.
Yeah, I was kind of bummed Well, I kind of it
kind of got kind of well it It kind of suffered
from the same issues that kind of like the Daredevil
show did, I think, where they were trying to
spread out too much story among too many episodes,
or too little story among too many episodes.
So you kind of wanted to keep getting back to
the arc that was introduced in the first episode
of Constantine, I think. And they kept going
off like on different tangents and... and some
of the actors annoyed me and stuff, but it was
a good show. It was a good show. Is he going
to, has he showed up in Legends of Tomorrow
yet? Constantine? Yeah. The actor? No, he was
in Arrow. That's earlier. Yeah. Which was, which
was a nice cameo. It's so hard to say goodbye
to Matt Reeves, the actor who played Constantine
as Constantine because he was spot on perfect.
Cause they do adjust this like dark movie. I
mean. They'll probably go for like some big
name actor like Ewan McGregor or something like
that, which would be fine. Yeah, he would be
good. But, uh, I'm gonna miss... I'm gonna miss
that Constantine. Well, hopefully he like joins...
..the... The Legends of Tomorrow team, down
the line or something. Hopefully. They have
that option. They need a magic user on that.
Yeah, that'd be pretty cool. That'd be a pretty
cool way to use them. So yeah, hopefully Justice
League Dark comes out. You know what's not
coming out this year? Gambit. And who called
it? We called it. I think you called it. Yeah,
I think everyone called it. Yeah, it was definitely
not, it was originally scheduled. Fox had a
schedule for October 7th, 2016 this year. I
think in our first, very first episode, as
we were going down the slate of movies, we mentioned
that it probably was not gonna get released
this year because it doesn't, you know, as I
haven't started filming. They have a director
and a star and a romantic lead, but that's about
it. That's right. Yeah. So it was pushed back.
They haven't said to where yet, although Fox
did announce two untitled Marvel films. One
of them being, pretty much the same date next
year, 2017, October 6th, 2017. And another
one on January 12th, 2018. So, do you think
either of those will be Gambit? My guess is
that, well, okay, so Wolverine 3 is scheduled
for March 3rd, 2017, about a year from now.
And that's kind of, it seems kind of behind
in production. If... If I had to guess, I bet
you Gambit might take that March 3rd spot. Or
if it sticks with... No, but Wolverine's the
March 3rd. If Wolverine 3 sticks with March
3rd, then I bet you Gambit's gonna be released
on that October 6th, 27th date. As far as the
January 12th, 2018, I can only guess Deadpool.
That would be my guess. Deadpool 2? Deadpool
2. Or X-Force? Uh... or X-Force. Yeah. I wonder
what they're gonna do with that. Do you stick
with Deadpool, which has done so well? Or do
you sort of put him in a team dynamic? I think
they'll put him in a team dynamic. He certainly
can join the current iteration of X-Men because
those actors are so young. And it's still in
the past, what is it now? It's in the 1980s.
And Deadpool takes place in the current time.
So I figure the only way they can have Deadpool
meet up with this current generation of actors
is to bring... them from the past into the present.
I didn't even realize that. Like just skip
over the 90s or something. Super tricky. Yeah,
they really screwed themselves over. They did?
Wow. They kind of made their own continuity
gap and they're gonna have to pull like a crisis
on infinite earths or something. But I mean
they brought the original X-Men team from the
comics into the future. Yeah, I wonder if they
would. X-Factor. They can totally do that.
Yeah, and maybe that's what they'll call it.
They'll bring all those younger actors, they'll
just skip over the 90s or something. And did
you hear my phone? Yeah. I just never read
it. I don't know if you could hear or not. They'll
probably skip over the 90s maybe and just bring
them right into like 30 years into the future,
into the present time. And the 2000s. And the
2000s, yeah. I don't know what they're gonna
do. But I mean, going back to the release dates,
I bet you. They've got to be thinking about
working on a Deadpool movie sometime soon,
so I bet you it'll take place in January 2018.
And I bet you it'll be with the team. They
already said that Cable is going to be in it,
so... Yeah, yeah. Well, I also remember that
the Fantastic Four movie, the sequel to the
Fantastic Four reboot, that was originally
slated for July 14th. 2017, so middle of next
summer. So I wonder if they'll... move Gambit
or Wolverine to that date? Probably. There's
so many. Sometimes I just can't believe how
far in advance they're they're, you know, planning
these films. I mean, you look at Marvel's slate,
you look at DC's slate, Justice League, and
then, you know, Yeah, we're going to be old
men by the time Green Lantern comes out. I know.
Yeah, they announced that. Green Lantern may
not be appearing until Justice League 2 at like
the earliest. Like he may not even appear in
Justice League 2. It may be because Justice
League right now I think is slated, Justice
League Part 2 at least is slated for 2019, and
the Green Lantern movie was slated for 2020.
I think that's right. The Green Lantern Corps
movie. What am I saying? Did I say Green Lantern
Corps? Green Lantern Corps is slated for 2020.
Justice League Part 2 for 2019. Which I heard
rumors that there was a cameo. Green Lantern
of Hal Jordan in Batman v Superman So to hear
that it's still gonna be you know like almost
half a decade Before we actually get to see
another film version of him kills me why are
they doing that? Don't do that Yeah, well because
really you want to see like the big DC 7 you
want to see the Magnus Vincent 7 You know on
screen at the same time right which I don't
know. I don't know if we were ever gonna see
that in in Batman Reveals Superman just because
like they sort of leaked like what the flash's
cameo is. Oh they did? Have you heard about
that? I haven't heard about that. I don't know
if I'll say. Well okay here's a spoiler. Okay
so jump ahead like two minutes or two three
minutes. Two minutes. You don't want to hear
this. It won't take long. Okay. Alright and
jump. Okay so his cameo is he appears in Batman's
nightmare sequence. He appears to warn Batman.
So it's sort of like... So Flash can go into
dreams? Well, no, I think it's sort of ambiguous
as to whether or not it is a dream or if the
Flash takes him to the future to show him what
the future's gonna be like if Superman takes
over or something like that. Why would Superman
take over? I don't know. That's a good question.
Wait, is, okay, so is this a rumor or is this
confirmed, this cameo? This is... confirmed.
By whom? People who have seen the film. Okay.
Yeah. Alright. Yeah, it's so hard to stay off
the internet and not read these things. So
I don't have the willpower. I don't do it anymore.
I completely spoiled myself on the first Avengers
movie, and I knew everything that was going
to happen, including up to like all the good
parts. Everybody has such a good reaction to
like when the Hulk like said, puny God and
everything like that. I already knew that was
coming because I read every little thing that
I could about the movie. And so I was not surprised.
It was like I was watching it for the second
time when I watched it the first time. But I
mean, it's still enjoyable. The thing with
spoilers for me is I mean. I'm still able to
enjoy the film when everyone cries foul for
showing doomsday or now even with Spider-Man
Which we'll get to later. I don't care. I'll
still enjoy the film I think there's something
to be said for letting the surprises happen
when they're meant to happen though yeah, and
I purposefully stayed away from all spoilers
for the second Avengers movie and But even like
that flash, it's okay if you're here from when
I said to jump ahead, because I'm not going
to mention what it is again. But even me telling
you about that, does that ruin the film for
you? Do you think it will? Yes. No, it won't.
I don't know, maybe. I still don't believe it,
I don't think. I have trouble... I hope they
don't write themselves into a corner, because...
That kind of scenario seems like you might
write yourself into a corner with that. I have
faith in Chris Terrio. There was an article
recently done by the Wall Street Journal where
they interviewed him and the guy... He's a
great speaker and he really sounds like he knows,
he did a ton of research for these films. And
he's really trying to, he was saying about like
how he wasn't sure he was gonna do Justice
League until he went on set and he saw Jesse
Eisenberg do a scene with Holly Hunter. And
he was like really moved by it, I guess he was
saying. Was it a love scene? No, it's just
so moved by the love making, you just have to
keep writing these characters. He said he felt
like it felt like this really like indie cool
film and he was like I have to keep writing
these characters. Which is cool. The things
he said in that Wall Street Journal article,
which I haven't read the entirety of because
it's behind a freaking paywall, which sucks.
I've read snippets and I want to read the whole
thing, but it seems like a really good article.
They interviewed Chris Terrio and Charles Rovin
and Ben Affleck. some interesting just sort
of like inside information about the whole DC
Cinematic Universe in general, not just Batman
v Superman came out through the article and
it was pretty cool. Cool. So if you do have
that, if you are a subscriber to the Wall Street
Journal, Send us that article. Email us that
shit because I want to read it. Another movie
that's in development that we heard this week
is Venom. Right. But the big thing about that
is that it will be unrelated to the new Spider-Man.
I remember when I... because I heard this information
first, this news first, and I chatted it to
you, or I texted it to you. I just remember
your reaction. I forgot what it was. I was
just like, bullshit or something. You were like,
nooooo! It doesn't make sense why Venom is
such... I mean, he's a good character, and while
you could, I guess... I imagine that if they're
making it unrelated to Spider-Man, they're going
with the new Flash Thompson agent Venom route.
But I mean, even then, do you do Flash Thompson?
Because he's related to Spider-Man, they're
probably going to use... Because Spider-Man
is still in high school. Right, so they're
probably going to have Flash Thompson in the
new movie. It's kind of ridiculous. It's not
going to be related to Spider-Man. Right. So...
It probably can't... I mean, how do you explain
his look without Spider-Man? Maybe it'll be
Eddie Brock or something as the agent. Which
would be stupid. I think... It can't be related
to... It's not related to Spider-Man. I don't
think... I think it's gonna be an original character.
You know, I think this is gonna be... It can't
be an original character. This is gonna be...
Fans will write it. This is gonna be Marvel
slash Sony's version of Catwoman. Oh, like Catwoman
in name only? Right. With Halle Berry. So,
but see, when you just have that, then it's
just a guy with like an alien symbiote who's
just like a suit... He, like, kind of like spawn
or something. Which in itself is not... a terrible
concept, it's an interesting concept, but it's
not a venom. You're ruining the potential for
the character in future Spider-Man movies, I
think. Yeah, I mean, I've heard people say,
some insiders say that they're speculating the
only reason that this isn't happening, which
makes sense to me, is because Marvel has probably,
you know, said like we're not interested in
Venom, like, anytime in the near future. So,
I mean, Sony's probably like, well, we have
this great character in our stable. We might
as well do something with it, make money off
of it somehow. But it's like... Stupid Sony.
They're really stupid. I don't understand.
They're really stupid as studios. Like, if you
read, did you read any of those leaked emails?
I've seen, yeah, I've seen them. I saw so many
just bullshit emails. Like, they have no idea
what the fuck they're doing. It pisses me off
sometimes. I'm hoping this will turn into a
case where... like, you know, fans bitch about
it so much that it ends up just getting pulled.
That's what needs to happen. If you're if you're
listening to this bitch about it, bitch about
it. Be the bitchiest bitch on the whole bitchy
planet. Be the biggest bitch that you know.
Boss bitch. Be the hashtag. Be the head bitch
in charge. You we have to complain. We have
to. If we want. It makes no sense. You want
to save the character, even if they have no
immediate plans with him in the future. Eventually
they will. I mean, now I can't remember. Who's
playing Spider-Man? What's his name? Tom Holland.
You know, he's a young kid He's probably in
it for the long haul. You know, we're gonna
see him grow from a spider boy to a spider-man
I'm assuming so I mean Save that use that potential
save that character For future movies. Well,
you know and make it when people have long art
already long forgotten the Topher Grace Spider-Man
3 version. Yeah. Because there is a good story
to tell there. So... How long do you wait?
I mean, do you wait Green Lantern long? Or...
No, 10 years is fine. Spider-Man 3 came out
in 2007, so if they wanted to... Even if they
threw Venom in the next movie... Holy cow,
I didn't realize it was that far. Yeah, time's
good by quick, man. But even next year, I think
that's fine. It's a whole decade past. So...
yeah. Just when did I talk about fan pitching?
It was like our second or third episode. Yeah.
And it does make a difference. Totally. Yeah.
That's how I think that's how we got Apocalypse.
It's how we got Apocalypse. It does not look
like Iva News. It's how we got Deadpool. It's
how we got the movie Deadpool made. So, yeah,
go out there. And even to an extent like Batman
v Superman, like just, you know, addressing
the whole like this mass destruction issue,
you know. I don't think they could ever be
fixed. Unless Superman flies around the world
and goes back in time. I don't know. We'll
see how it's addressed in Battle for Superman,
but I have a heart, I just don't see how he
could redeem himself, I don't know. Well, Howard,
I mean, okay, so the new Civil War trailer
came out, and right from the beginning of the
trailer, they talk about the destruction that
has been wrought in the past Marvel Cinematic
films. They could be redeemed, but Manifestale
can't. They could be redeemed because they didn't
show an apparent lack of regard for human life
like Superman did. It was his first battle.
Actually, there's been a few interviews. I
forget who did the interview. Who did it? With
Henry Cavill. He was just talking about that
and how this film is sort of a response to that.
When the guy talks about Superman, it just
makes you really appreciate him as the character.
He really understands the character and it's
interesting to hear his approach. When he was
explaining the destruction, he was basically
agreeing that he was an amateur, which sort
of makes the fight against Batman and Batman
v Superman more interesting because he was saying
he's an amateur going up against someone very
well versed in the art of war. And that's why
when people say that Superman... should always
be able to beat Batman. There's no way Batman
should stand a chance. That was sort of his
argument saying, you know, Superman is still
very much new in this universe. But I mean-
Shh, Superman would win. I still... Anyway,
I've always been the advocate every time I
read the Dark Knight returns or something like
that. What are you doing, Superman? Just freaking
kill the guy. If any, he won't because he's
Superman. But I'm always never quite interested
in seeing how those two fight because I always
think it should go another way. It is interesting
to see that they are addressing consequences
in film. I mean, not only with BVS, but with
the new Civil War trailer. It was hard for the
characters to even look at the past. The damage.
The damage, which, I mean. What? Wasn't... If
they can't handle that kind of, those kind
of consequences, they couldn't stand it. They
couldn't handle the DC universe. DC universe
is too much for them. You know what's surprising?
How many people do you think died in Zod's
attack on Metropolis? It's no less than five
million. No. That's not... What? That was a
joke. If you had to put a number on it, how
many people do you think died? Actually, I
think they gave a number for at least the Wayne
Tower collapse. It was in the thousands. So
it was in the thousands? Yeah. Looking at the
Civil War trailer, they did give the actual
figures for each of those battles. Let's see.
Alright, so if you had to guess how many casualties
were in the attack on New York, how many would
you guess? Marvel is so wussy. I mean, they
were like, oh, our heroes have to save everyone.
There can't be any consequences for this alien
invasion. It's because they're good heroes,
unlike some people. That's bullcrap. How many
people? What's your guess? 50. How many casualties?
50. Higher? 100. Lower? Are you shitting me?
74 people on the attack in New York. New York
is a big ass city and there are a ton. of the
Leviathan monster going through building. Really,
Marvel Universe. 74. You know why? Because
they evacuated and they got people to save ground.
How many people do you think died in the Winter
Soldier DC Helicarrier crash? None. 23. All
right, and how many people do you think died
in the Sokovia in Avengers 2? Like one, and
that was Quicksilver. I would have thought
it would have been the fewest, because, you
know, they... They went out of their way to
show how many people there were. 177 people.
177 casualties. So overall, it's just a mere
fraction of the people that died in Metropolis.
I just thought that was kind of funny. So go
Marvel heroes. Am I right? I'm looking up the
current number for what the newspaper and the
second Batman v Superman trailer showed the
death toll as. Oh. It's got a... There was
just one building. Thousands in one building.
Yeah, in the thousands. I forget the exact
number. Yeah. Overall... I can't remember if
it was just one building, or if it was the...
I think it was actually the entire ordeal. It
would have to be in the thousands. Just...
I remember thinking... Oh, thank God they've
knocked down all the buildings. There's nothing
left to knock down. Then all of a sudden, you
know, like they'll come from like, or they
go into outer space and I'm like, oh, thank
God that they're done knocking down buildings.
They'll find space now. And then they found
space. And then they crashed into the satellite.
And then they brought the satellite down right
back onto the exact same city. And the satellite
knocked down like another 10 buildings. It was
it was just nuts. Anyway. I put thousands of
people die when stuff like this happens. I mean,
look at 9-11. That was what I think, like 3,000?
Right, yeah, and I think it's kind of weird
that 9-11 had such a huge impact on society,
in real life, and in a movie where you have,
it's 9-11 times 1,000, and all that results
from it is... Senate hearing with Superman.
It's a congressional hearing. Yeah, but that's
not legislation. That's just a hearing. I mean,
they need to start somewhere. I guess. I don't
know. Hopefully we'll see more along the line.
I'm sure we will. In Civil War we're actually
seeing... legislation and laws being passed
to put these guys in check. We're not seeing
laws being passed in Batman versus Superman.
You don't know it. I don't know that. But I'm
going to assume that because that's what I do.
What would you think of the trailer of the
Civil War trailer? Yeah. It was. It was OK,
I think. It was not it was not my favorite
trailer. I know people are going. just completely
nuts over it. It was not better than the last
trailer. The first trailer was so good. I think
it had to do the music in this trailer. The
first time I saw it, I was actually getting
kind of bored. But it didn't really show that
much new footage. It didn't show that much new
footage. The music was kind of somber and it
was just like a lot of just really serious sounding
dialogue spoken just line by line by line.
It was kind of monotone. The thing that I was
really looking forward to and I knew was coming
because Marvel had announced it the day prior
that they were going to show Spider-Man at
the At the end of the trailer. That's that's
what I was looking forward to so By like, you
know two-thirds of the way through I'm like,
okay, just get to Spider-Man already that's
really interesting gear your take on the whole
trailer because I You know just co-workers
and stuff. They they you know come to me and
they're like, oh what you think? It was so
good, it was the greatest thing ever, wasn't
it? It was so good, I'm like, yeah, it's Marvel.
Don't get me wrong, don't get me wrong. I think
it had some amazing wow moments to it, but
overall I don't think the trailer was
as cohesive as the last one, I think. The last
one, which is really the first one, the last
one, yeah, the first one really clearly defined
the themes and I was excited to see it. and
it had well moments too. Like at the end when
Captain Bucky or taking Iron Man and stuff
like that. This one had a few well moments too.
This one had more well moments I would say.
It had more spectacle. We got to see Ant-Man
on one of Hot Guy's arrows. I kind of wish
they would have saved that for the movie. I
didn't want to see that now out of context
or anything, but that was an incredible shot
in the trailer. I watched that over and over
again. It was like fake. I was actually surprised
how much from this film looked fake. Well,
I'm sure the effects aren't done yet. Yeah.
I think that, I mean, the standout for me other
than Spider-Man, I guess, is Black Panther.
Yeah, you get to see... Chadwick Boseman as
T'Challa. He's in one of those blasts at the
beginning of the trailer. You think his father
died right there? Yeah, I think T'Chaka died
right there. He just became the new king? Yeah,
and I think that's why he's going after the
Winter Soldier. See, what confuses me is occasionally
you'll see in later shots, like when Iron Man
hits Captain America and says, you just started
war, there's this figure in a tube in the background,
and it looks... really similar to the container
that Winter Soldier was being held in at the
beginning of the trailer. So, and this is just
speculation, I don't think this is a spoiler,
but it makes me wonder what... Do you think
they cloned Bucky and maybe it's a Bucky clone
that's causing all this damage and stuff, and
that's why they think he did it and why they're
going after him and all that stuff? Would they
be able to do that? I don't know. I don't know
if they would... go that science fictiony with
that. It's interesting. I've never, I haven't
heard that anyone speculate that. Yeah. No
one speculated that. That's me speculating that.
I think it would make sense for why they would
suspect the Winter Soldier's doing all this
stuff. I do have to admit, like just watching
the trailer, the Winter Soldier's a dick. I
don't know if it's just like clever editing.
Like when he shoots down war machines, like,
oh, that guy's. Well, he had a rifle. It was
just kind of, that's the way it was cut. We
don't know wherever that energy beam came out.
where that came from, I don't know. I'm pretty
sure it was someone on Team Cap. It almost
looks like one of Vision's blasts. Really? I
wonder if Scarlet Witch, again, we don't know
anything about this movie, this is just- You
think she hijacks him? Yeah, I wonder if she
mentally manipulates him. She hijacks him into
loving her? Because we know that she can read
his mind, because she read his mind in Avengers
Age of Ultron. Back when he had Ultron's mind
and she saw that he was gonna cause like damage
and destruction and that's when they eventually
turned on Ultron So we know that vision has
a mind to read so maybe I'm wondering if she
manipulates that somehow Because that would
definitely turn the tide, you know, there are
not a lot of heavy hitters on team cap You can
go up against someone like vision. Yeah, I
was always wondering that I was like Well, who's
team is vision on because that's the thing
that's gonna win Right, and when you combine
that with the Ithmore machine and Iron Man,
I think I can see it going that way. Um, but
yeah, so going to the other big moments in
the film, we saw the, um, it looked like the
raft, um, in coming out of the water. It's
the super, the superhero, supervillain, uh,
prison. It looks like, you know, instead of
the negative zone, because they don't have the
negative zone nor do I think they have the
rights to the negative zone. I think that's
a fantastic four thing with Fox. But so instead
of being in the negative zone, it looks like
the prison is like deep in the middle of the
ocean. And so that was pretty interesting. What
is that? Is that in the comic? A prison? In
the Civil War series, Mr. Fantastic created
a prison in the negative zone to put people
who violate the superhero registration act.
Okay, yeah. So yeah, that was pretty cool to
see. You know what else was cool to see in the
trailer? Spider-Man. That's really what I was
looking forward to, as I just said. And what
did you think of him? I wanna get your thoughts
before I give my thoughts. I didn't know he
was actually gonna be in the trailer. I didn't
see the news saying that he was gonna be in
there. Oh no? I wasn't like... excited when
he was there just but I just don't care about
Spider-Man. He's sort of he's only had like
two movies like good movies out of five movies.
I don't know I'm kind of over the character
really and I think Iron Man has kind of supplanted
him as like the main Marvel uh you know flagship
kind of character sort of like what Superman
is or you know maybe Batman to DC. Um I Okay,
so where my first reactions the costume looked
super CG it did Yeah, I don't know how I feel
about the customer. I feel like Andrew Garfield's
so I ran costume in the second one amazing
spider-man 2 is better Just because I had the
really big eye Lens lenses. I don't like the
small
spider on his chest. I didn't really care about
like the sort of like the updates to the suit
or I had like the blue like bands or stripes.
Oh on the on the deltoids and on the on the
elbows. Yeah I also wasn't a fan of his web
shooters the wrists the bracelets. I keep going
on and on about what I how much I did like those
I mean those are just nitpicks. I'm glad he's
in the movie. it's gonna be really cool to actually
see, you know, the, I think, you know, it's
gonna be Marvel's Spider-Man. Just the voice,
that was a perfect voice. Really? I thought
so. I mean, it's young, it was kind of like
borderline cocky, borderline like unsure, I
thought. It's a lot to read into one line, but
I thought he nailed it. Really, because I didn't
get any hint of cockiness to it. I thought it
was almost a Andrew Garfield kind of take,
where it was almost kind of like, a little shy,
maybe, like, here, everyone. Maybe I just kinda
got the implication of the cockiness just because
like his squint at the end, maybe. Which is
so cool. Okay, the one thing I really did like
about seeing Spider-Man is the way they interpreted
his, they found a way to make his eyes show
emotion, grow big and grow smaller. But it
wasn't, I thought they were probably gonna go
like the Deadpool route. where his eyes were
essentially just CG, but they incorporated something
that makes sense with the story, some kind
of tech, because you could hear the whirring
sound. Yeah, because if you think about it
in Deadpool, that didn't make sense, the way
his eyes moved with the mask. No, it worked.
It worked maybe because the tone of the movie
was, it's not something that you thought about
because he's kind of such a cartoony character
and breaks the fourth wall. You can't really
nitpick it like that. I honestly wonder though,
like, I mean, in all the Batman films, they
never really gave him lenses just because they
wanted to be able to see his eyes so that he
could emote. But I think if, even if he did
the Deadpool route and something like that,
it would still work. I don't think people would
care if Batman's eyebrows moved. I think they
would get over it. But I think you sort of avoid
that controversy. whether they would care with
what they do with Spider-Man. Yeah, I'm a big
fan. So here are my thoughts. I was super excited
when I first saw the web. I was like, oh, OK.
Well, first of all, they nailed the web. I
don't think they've ever got the web wrong,
though. The look of the web looks pretty cool.
Yeah, it's always. After I watched it in hindsight,
so he does the superhero landing, the pose.
He looks really sweet holding Captain America's
shield. And I wonder, it's such a cool visual.
And I wonder if it would... be such a cool visual
if he wasn't holding cap shield. I thought
the costume looked fantastic. I was like, oh,
that's exactly how we should look. It looks
like Marvel Spider-Man with a modern updated
suit. But then, of course I'm going back and
playing that part over and over again. And the
more I watched it, the more I kind of... Obviously
the CGI isn't finished, but I was kind of disappointed
because the suit looked like rubber to me.
It looked kind of balloon-y. And when you have
a character like Spider-Man, whose face is...
very bulbous, you know? I think it's a weird
choice to give him a rubber suit because it
makes it look such like a balloon. It looked
flat. It did look a little flat. I think...
you know, obviously the special effects aren't
finished, so it'll look different in the final
cut. I did get, I did download, you know, the
super, super high res and I maxed it out and
I looked, got a really good close look at the
suit. And actually to my surprise, what I first
thought was rubber and no texture, turns out
that it's texture. It's not rubber. There's
a lot of texture actually. The red portion of
the costume, it's almost like a denim. It looks
like, it looked like a red. denim type of fabric,
but thicker than like what's on your jeans.
So that's pretty cool. And in the blue parts,
I thought those are flat too, but if you zoom
in close enough, it's actually like a Jersey
type material, like a thick Jersey, not like
with all the holes, like a, like a, like one
of those new Reebok hockey jerseys, if you're
familiar with those, the ones that Reebok made
like a three or four years ago. So yeah, it's
like a jersey material, a denim material. It's
very fabric-y. I think it looks pretty cool.
And I hope that texture really stands out during
the course of the film, because I think it's
that texture that keeps it, you know, really
from looking cartoony. Yeah, I don't think
I realized how important texture was in a superhero
suit until Man of Steel. I think, I mean, I
think it started with- Yeah, comparing Superman
Returns and the Man of Steel costume. Well,
I mean, no, if it's- Because Superman Returns
didn't have- any on the blue part. It was all
a really flat and bland. And like, I think it
started with Sam Raimi's version of Spider-Man
because I really liked that costume. I liked
the texture on it. I didn't understand why
they had it. I had read articles that it was
for like. And sort of like a dimension to it,
it makes it look a little bit more interesting
if you had a texture to it. I didn't see that
texture in the in the Captain in the Civil War
trailer on Spider-Man. I think you'll see in
the movie. I mean, I don't know if I saw the
super high rise version. Like I had to take
a really good close look to even see that there
was texture even there. I think that's sort
of. And you know, I thought like the black webbing
was really, it wasn't as pronounced as it was
in previous films. Like in the Sam Raimi- No,
it's thinner. It's a thinner, yeah, thinner
line. Yeah, it was in the Sam Raimi version.
Like it was almost like upraised. It was, yeah.
But in this version, it's not as- It's a little
inset almost. Almost kind of similar to how
the Andrew Garfield suit was. I think that was
inset as well. Although I didn't like- If I'm
ranking the Spider-Man costumes, I will put
the first Amazing Spider-Man movie, that costume
that he had there. The texture was cool, it
kind of reminded me of a, kind of like basketball,
but the design of the Spider-Man outfit was
horrendous. I hate it. Every time I went to
the store and I saw that stupid Spider-Man,
Amazing Spider-Man, with the stupid yellow
eyes, I just wanted to break stuff. That was
a really weird choice. Yeah, I thought you
were saying that was your number one ranked
costume. Oh, no, it's my... You're starting
from the bottom. Yeah, starting from the bottom.
Okay. Yeah, I hated that costume. You could
ask my wife. I was pissed off every time I saw
those stupid yellow eyes. I'm like, Spider-Man
does not have yellow eyes. What the hell are
you thinking? Well, I love the eyes. Fanboy
bitching. Yeah, they changed it for the second
one. I think if I have to pick the very best
version of the Spider-Man costume in movies,
it would be... The amazing spider-man 2 yeah,
I agree because he had the big eyes It seems
like they took a lot of the cues from Remy's
spider-man costume they give it that texture
and it was it was very the classic design and
the blue was a little bit darker and Yeah, I
think it looks fantastic And this suit that
they have is much less the classic look he He
has the external web shooters, which actually
kind of like the look of but his belt is very
much different and his sleeves look a little
bit different. They went much wider on the sleeves
than they typically do. Well, on the red part
on the sleeves, I should say, because Spider-Man
always has the inside of his bicep area and
inner forearm is always blue and the outside
is the red with the webbing. Well, like at
the glove area, he does this. Right, and at
the glove, it becomes full red. It's full red.
So this one... They went much wider with the
outside red web area. And it kind of reminds
me of Captain America's suit, the way they did
the sleeve design in the first Avengers movie.
He had like, most of his sleeve was blue and
they had a small patch of white around the
inner bicep area. And it looks like they're
doing the same thing with this costume. So
that's pretty interesting. I mean, that's not
a nitpick. I think it's a good choice just
because it's different. And we haven't really
seen it before. I guess if I have any gripe,
it's probably the spider. The symbol, yeah,
really small. The belt. The belt, while functional,
because it looks like it holds as spare cartridges
of webbing, it is black. That was my guess
as well. I'm guessing that this suit is- It
wasn't black, it was dark blue, wasn't it?
Was it dark blue? I thought I saw dark blue.
I thought I saw black. But then again, you
saw a high-res version. I didn't. It was black.
Really? Well, that's disappointing. Yeah, it's
black. But it's black containers over a red
belt. So there's hints of red in between. Yes.
Really? Yeah. So I think this suit is the one
that's designed by Iron Man. I don't think
we'll get a version of the Iron Spider like
that was in the Civil War comic where he had
kind of like, Yeah. Doctor Octopus spider legs
coming out of his jaw. Which I have to say,
I liked that suit. Oh. It was a cool suit for,
You know a suit I really liked? It was a temporary
suit, so it was cool. Yeah. I really liked the
superior Spider-Man when Doc Ops took over
Spider-Man. I loved that suit. That was a fantastic
suit. That was a fantastic story, I think.
But no, I mean, just going back to the suit
in the trailer, yeah, definitely had some tech
with it. I'm definitely interested to see how
much involvement Tony Stark had with helping
Andrew Garfield.
kid with low on resources who survives by his
wits, you know, sort of. So to have him, I
don't know, his Marvel debut, you know, come
out with some fancy tech suit, I don't know
how I'm kind of- I'm sure that's not his first
suit. I'm sure the first suit that he shows
in the film is probably before Iron Man, you
know, gets ahold of him and brings him onto
his team. I'm betting his first suit is probably-
kind of like the concept art that we've seen.
I don't know if it's fan art or concept art,
but it's kind of like a hoodie with like goggles
and stuff. It looks pretty cool. Yeah, I hope
that's it because- I totally forgot about that.
For some reason I was thinking that, you know,
when he says underoos in the trailer, which
was funny. It was funny. I was thinking that
was probably gonna be the first time we see
Spider-Man in the film, not Peter Parker, but
Spider-Man, just because it seemed like some
kind of like grand entrance kind of thing. Yeah.
I don't think so. I wonder how much involved
he is. It would be too out of left field if
he just kind of appeared. And there's not anybody
who's not familiar with the character of Spider-Man,
so I don't think people would be like, who
the heck is this guy? But I mean, if there ever
was a person who wasn't familiar with Spider-Man,
and they'd be like, what the heck just happened
in this movie? Where did this guy come from?
Who is he? What's going on? So it wouldn't quite
make sense. So I'm pretty positive that's not
the first time we see him. I'm pretty sure we
will see him in his first, the first incarnation
of his homemade costume. And then it'll go from
there. One last thing about the eyes. I have
always been a huge fan of the thick. black line
around the eyes, like the Alex Ross style of
eyes, as opposed to the really Todd McFarland,
the huge... I like big eyes, but I like the
thick black line around the eyes. I never liked
the really pencil thin around the white. They
had that in the Sam Raimi films. They had that
in... Yeah, the Sam Raimi films, I feel like
that's different. Those felt very much... You
know, they were designed by Oakley. They felt
very much like lenses. Yeah. In the Amazing
Spider-Man, they felt less like lenses and
they had a little bit of texture to them as
well. And those are good. But I think these
will be my favorite eyes just because I really
love the Alex Ross style. of the eyes, I think
you can express more with them. And I'm glad
that they've taken that route because yeah,
you'll be able to show emotion with the eyes
and with the mask, as opposed to the thin line
in which you don't, you can only do so much
with the expression. I was kind of, I kind
of opposite. I was like the big white eyes.
But I mean, yeah, it's a good look. As much
as I griped on it at the beginning when we first
started talking about him, he looks great.
Yeah, I'm excited. I'm excited. Yeah, I can't
wait. I hope he's in the movie. more than just
kind of like a cameo. Like he's, it looks like
he's at the end of the big fight scene at the
airport. And that might be it. I hope that's
not the extent of his action. I don't know
if he'll actually get into, you know, fisticuffs
and or fight anybody else or if, but- I wonder
how much they're gonna show him in like marketing
material. I at least want to see him like take
down some like burglars or something like that,
you know? Yeah. Hopefully. I don't know how
much the, they haven't shown him- anything about
him until this trailer. So I don't know how
much he'll actually appear in marketing materials.
Mike is his own poster. Mike, he'll move. That's
right, because they come out with those posters.
Yeah, he wasn't part of it. He wasn't a part
of it. Those were terrible posters. They were
terrible posters. It was just the profile of
the face. Yeah. Without any masks on anybody.
Yeah, that was interesting. I would have. why
they chose that direction. Was it just to humanize
the whole thing? I would have preferred to
have seen their masks. The Black Panther costume
is still, I think... It's amazing. It's great.
It's great. I really like it. Yeah, I think
they just came out. Sometimes I think they
don't put a whole lot of thought to the marketing
materials. They just put something out there,
you know, to keep the buzz going. Yeah. I can't.
I kind of wondered how much like because, you
know, the day that the trailer came out, the
movie posters came out a few days before. And
it's like, no tickets are on sale. Why are tickets
on sale so far in advance for the film? They're
trying to bite into the Bambi B Superman sales
tickets, I think. But whatever. That's just
paranoia, man. Those posters aren't helping
them sell tickets. I mean, yeah, for sure.
They'll probably come out with more posters
before the release. Yeah. But you know who
had some pretty cool posters? The Daredevil
ones. Those Daredevil posters were pretty sweet.
We finally got a look at Frank Castle's Punisher
Skull on his shirt. Finally. And I think the
skull looks fantastic. I think it's the best
iteration of it. We didn't get to see it fully,
but I mean, from what we saw, it looks really,
it's big, it's like dark. Yeah. In War Zone,
it was kind of subtle and it almost looked like
it was printed onto like a mesh that he wore
over his Kevlar. And it was very angular. It
was very angular. As opposed to like the Thomas
Jane one looked very like organic. Thomas Jane
was very organic. It looked very spray painted,
kind of graffiti style. This one has kind of
that same style, but it's a good combination
of the two. It's not angular, but it's spray
painted over this very angular body armor piece.
Yeah, it's about a body armor. And it kind of
incorporates part of the shape of the body
armor. That's what kind of forms the eyes of
the skull. Yeah. I think that's badass. I think
this is the best looking version of the Punisher
to date, especially hands down the poster version
where he's holding that minigun. with the big
bandolier bullets that's going through it.
That's straight out of the comics. I was so
excited when I saw that. I cannot wait until
the day that these characters show up in a Marvel
film. Although you know what I want? I just
realized this the other day when I was driving
on my way to work. The Defenders show. What
story arc are they gonna go with that? I have
no idea. You know what I want them to do? What?
Secret war. The secret war where Nick Fury recruited
them to overthrow Latveria. Yeah, the Italian
artist did that comic. Yeah, Gabriel D'Otto.
Yeah. I never read the comic, but I remember
seeing the artwork for it. He's a phenomenal
painter. I think that's the way to incorporate
them into the mainstream Marvel Universe if
they're not going to be in the Infinity War.
I think if you do a smaller story with them
where Nick Fury shows up and he recruits the
small band of people that most people don't
know of. They're kind of out of the public
eye. Who was it? Black Widow Daredevil Punisher.
Oh, in the comic? Yeah. In the comic it was
Wolverine, Spider-Man, Black Widow, Luke Cage,
Quake. Who the hell that is? Daisy Johnson,
who's in Agents of S.H.I.E.L.D. She's the main
character. Oh, nice. That's a nice way to tie
in all the different properties. Yeah, I think
that would be fast. I've never heard that mentioned
anywhere, but I think about these things. I'm
like, what a way to work. Well, what are you
going to do after Infinity War? Well, my tie
into that is if they're not a part of Infinity
War, because, you know, the budget or whatever.
I think that people will be like, well, how
come these characters, the Netflix characters
aren't in the movie? And it's like, oh, because
they're on their own secret mission that no
one's supposed to know about them. No one's
supposed to know they exist. No one's supposed
to know about their mission. I think I think
that's the way to do it. You'd have to do it
probably with a black widow, though. Right.
Yeah, that's fine. I'm kind of like sad. If
it doesn't happen now, I'm going to be disappointed
because I feel like my idea was better. Anyway.
Well, I mean, how do you feel about the rift
between the cinematic universe and the television
universe? Like, are they even tied together
anymore? They are tied together, yes. Because
they make direct references to things that
happen in the films. But with the films, like,
I don't know if the films would ever use any
of those characters. That's the question. If
they, I mean, if they ever did, it would have
to be in a big, wide, massive crossover event,
which the Infinity War is. Yeah. So if they
don't show up there, I don't know how, where
they would show up unless they eventually got
their own film. If you really want to expand
your universe, I mean, and make like the biggest
impact you possibly can. with spoilers when
Thanos will probably, should I say, I think
we've said that in a previous podcast. Kills
half the universe. If you show someone like
Charlie Cox's character sitting next to Alexia,
then all of a sudden, he disappears. It's a
great way to pay some kind of tribute to people
who watch the shows. To have them show up in
a film. Only to disappear at all. Yeah, but
I think even fans will appreciate that because...
There were a lot of characters that disappeared
in the comic book story. Like I remember Hawkeye
disappeared and Cersei, I think, was with him.
Although nobody knows. Very few people know
who that is. And if you do, kudos. I don't know
who she is. She's a she's an eternal. I know
who the DC Cersei is, but. Oh, yeah, that's
right. She's a Wonder Woman bad guy. Yeah.
She'll be in the movie. I remember Mary Jane
died as part of the Infinity Gauntlet. There
were a lot of people that disappeared. If they
go along that lines, I can see that working
as well. Is that it for the news? I think that's
everything. I mean, there's a lot more, but
we can't cover everything in the podcast. I
think that's all the big stuff. OK, all right.
Well, as we mentioned at the beginning of the
podcast, we're doing a battle cast for repeating
Black Widow against Black Canary. Should be
exciting. Yeah. Let's get into it. All right.
Attention! Can you hear me? We come from the
future. We are interrupting this transmission.
We are here to save you from shitty audio quality
and just really bad planning overall. I don't
know. At first you sounded like an alien right
there, but you kind of saved it. Alright, so
yeah, what we're doing here is we are going
back to some of these earlier episodes to redo
some of the duels that were initially not very
well plotted. and it was not plotted at all.
It was a different format and poor audio quality.
So we think you, the listeners, deserve better
and also the characters deserve better than
what we initially did in the early days of
this podcast. So we're gonna go ahead and redo
the duel between Black Canary and Black Widow.
The way we do this on this podcast is we take
the characters and we provide you with the
history and powers behind each one. Then we
take their stats and run a thousand simulations
using those numbers. and the Monte Carlo method
to sort of randomize them along a bell curve
that accounts for all the variables that happen
in battle. Once we run the simulations, we
come back to you guys with a winner. Now we're
not going to go ahead and redo the results
of this match, but we are going to provide you
with more in-depth backstories of the characters
as well as go over our speculative scenario
on how we think a fight between the two would
actually go. Our stats are based on the official
Marvel Power Rankings, from which we extrapolate
the DC character stats and to which we also
incorporate a few additional stats that we
think are important to these matches. Right,
right. Let's get started with the histories
of the characters. I think you go first with
Black Widow. Alrighty, so Black Widow is the
perfect balance between superhero and spy, in
that she often goes up against larger-than-life
villains and world-ending threats, but often
does so from the shadows, where she operates
most effectively. I think her appeal mainly
lies in her ability to complete any mission,
no matter how insurmountable the odds, as well
as her crossover potential between fantasy
superhero stories and more grounded tales of
crime and espionage. Not much is known about
Natalia Romanova's life prior to her recruitment
to the KGB as a young woman. As a child, she
was an orphan raised by a Soviet soldier named
Ivan Petrovich, who trained her from an early
age in how to fight and defend herself. She
was a gifted athlete and scholar and gained
recognition. by the Soviet government for her
skill as a dancer in the Russian Ballet. Shortly
after World War II, she was drafted alongside
27 other young females into the covert Red
Room facility, where she was arduously trained
in advanced combat and espionage. They psychologically
manipulated the women into absolute obedience
and utter callousness for enemies of the state.
They also chemically tampered with them through
a Soviet version of the Super Soldier Serum
that would grant them longer lifespans. Which
is why although Natasha is around 80 years
old, she only appears to be in her early 30s.
Dang! One of her trainers in the Red Room was
James Bucky Barnes, who at that point was brainwashed
into the Winter Soldier. They shared a brief
relationship before the KGB arranged for her
to be married to a Soviet test pilot, Alexei
Shostakov. Though soon after, the government
stole Alexei away and told Natasha he was dead.
In reality, they were preparing him to become
the Red Guardian, Russia's version of Captain
America. In the grief over losing her husband,
Natasha dove into her KGB espionage missions
and became known in intelligence circles as
the Black Widow. Her first mission to the United
States was to locate and assassinate Anton Vanko,
also known as the Crimson Dynamo, an enemy
of Iron Man who defected from the USSR. Iron
Man foiled her attempt and consistently stopped
her schemes against him and Stark Industries.
She eventually encountered and recruited Hawkeye
in her fight against Tony Stark, and the two
fell in love. weakening her loyalty to her
country when Hawkeye switched sides and joined
the Avengers superhero team. After the KGB
tried to have Natasha gun down for wavering,
she also switched sides and fought alongside
the Avengers as well. Although she was offered
membership to the team, she declined and was
instead convinced by Nick Fury to join the international
espionage organization known as SHIELD. She
was equipped with a new sleek black costume
and personalized equipment such as her bracelets.
She helped S.H.I.E.L.D. gain intel on organizations
such as Hydra, The Hand, and even her old allies
Communist Russia and China. Russia tried to
get her back on their side, through the revelation
that her husband Alexei was still alive. However,
the offer turned out to be a ruse, and they
tried to kill her again. She destroyed the Russian
intelligence headquarters and returned to the
US to join the Avengers and even become the
team's leader alongside the Black Knight, after
many of the original team disappeared after
the Onslaught Saga. When the heroes returned,
Natasha rejoined SHIELD. Later, while on a mission,
Natasha came into conflict with a Russian spy
named Yelena Belova, who was also trained in
the Soviet Red Room. Natasha defeated Yelena,
completed her mission, and brought her into
SHIELD custody. They swapped faces just like
in the movie Face Off, and Natasha went undercover
as Yelena to stop a rogue Russian general from
restarting the Cold War. Wait, is she the blonde
one? Like the short-haired blonde Russian spy?
Yeah, yeah, Yelena is the short blonde-haired
black widow. A short while later, Natasha was
nearly assassinated by the Russian government
who decided to eliminate all former Red Room
spies. Her investigation into the matter led
her back to her old training facility where
she learned that she and the 27 other young
women were implanted with false memories and
chemically manipulated to follow orders through
pheromone-activated triggers. She also learned
that Nick Fury knew about this and used this
control mechanism to get her to join SHIELD
all those years ago. Pheromone Science was being
used by a modern cosmetics agency to manipulate
women around the world, which Natasha put a
stop to by killing the Russian operative behind
the conspiracy and the CEO of the cosmetics
company. She sided with Iron Man during the
Civil War event and subsequently rejoined the
Avengers where she's mostly been since. Though
she still often spies for S.H.I.E.L.D. and even
at one point assumed command of the organization,
being the highest ranking agent present after
Nick Fury and Maria Hill were both incapacitated.
As far as abilities go, Natasha is among the
top tier of martial artists in the Marvel Universe,
alongside greats like Cat in America and Daredevil.
She is a master in multiple styles of fighting,
including Savat, Muay Thai, Judo, Ninjitsu,
and Kung Fu. Her biological enhancements grant
her peak human physicality in terms of strength,
speed, agility, endurance, and durability.
She is an experienced spy, tactician, hacker,
markswoman, and seductress. Her costume provides
resistance to small arms fire, and allows her
to stick to walls via micro suction cups. Her
specialized bracelets contain a variety of weapons
and gadgets from which she can shoot grapple
lines, gas pellets, and her signature weapon,
a blast of 30,000 volts of electricity called
the Widow's Bite. On her person, she also often
carries combat knives, explosives, handguns,
and occasionally a sniper rifle. That is a lot
of versatility. Yeah, it is. It's like an entire
arsenal. Yeah, she's kind of like the female
Batman. Seems that way. That would actually
be a really good fight, I think. Black Canary
used to carry like all those gadgets, but since
then she really hasn't. She's relied more on
her fighting skill in general and her superpower,
which I will get into. Sweet. Yeah, I don't
know too much about Black Canary. So I just
always see her as the blonde DC black widow
with a sonic voice. I don't know. You have
that turned around. No, I don't think so. All
right, so Black Canary in pre-New 52 continuity,
Dina Laurel Lance. was the daughter of the Golden
Age crime fighter Dina Drake Lance, aka Black
Canary. Wait, they have the same first name
and last name? Yeah, so Dina Laurel is like
a mini, which is like the female version of
Junior. Dina Drake Lance, aka Black Canary,
was a member of the Justice Society of America.
The younger Dina was trained in fighting and
acrobatics from a young age by her mother's
colleague, Ted Grant, a boxing champion and
martial artist who fought crime as the hero
Wildcat. Dinah eventually grew into her mother's
fishnet stockings and took up her mantle as
the new Black Canary against her mother's wishes.
Having been born with a metagene that granted
her an ultrasonic scream known as the Canary
Cry, Dinah quickly established herself as an
adept crime fighter in the streets of Gotham
City and was one of the first members of the
Justice League of America, where she met her
longtime romantic interest Oliver Queen, aka
Green Arrow, who you can learn more about in
our Green Arrow vs Hawkeye episode. Dyna fought
alongside the Justice League for several years,
advancing her martial arts skills by training
with heroes like Wonder Woman and Batman. Eventually,
however, her mother died from cancer caused
by her earlier days fighting alien creatures
with the Justice Society. And Dyna gave up her
crime-fighting career for a time to move to
Seattle with Green Arrow and run a flower shop
called Sherwood Florist. During her time in
Seattle, Dyna was kidnapped and tortured by
a drug dealer she had been investigating. she
lost her canary cry, and the ability to have
children. Green Arrow killed that man that
tortured her while she recovered in the hospital,
and he was with her as she went through counseling.
Though traumatized by the event, she could nevertheless
not stop herself from interfering when innocents
were in danger, and she resumed her crime-fighting
career, though it wasn't long before her and
Oliver parted ways romantically. Eventually,
Dinah was contacted by Barbara Gordon, formerly
Batgirl. but now the wheelchair-bound genius
hacker known as Oracle. The two formed a partnership
that would become the covert superhero team
known as Birds of Prey. Throughout the team's
many rosters, Dinah served as the lead field
agent, equipped with an array of gadgets, including
Canary Cry bombs, that acted as a replacement
for her former power until one of their missions
brought Dinah to a Lazarus pit, and its healing
properties restored her ultrasonic metahuman
ability and the ability to have children. During
her time on the team, she also advanced her
martial arts skills by training with some of
the world's premier assassins and martial artists
like Lady Shiva and Cassandra Cain. After training
with Lady Shiva, Black Canary quit the Birds
of Prey to care for a young girl she adopted
from Asia named Sin, who beforehand was being
groomed to be Lady Shiva's successor. She soon
rejoined the Justice League and was appointed
its leader due to her strategic talents.
and eventually the two were married, though
they separated after Oliver was found guilty
of killing the villain Prometheus for destroying
his hometown of Star City. Dyna stepped down
from her role in the Justice League and rejoined
the Birds of Prey. In post-New 52 continuity,
there's only been one Black Canary, Dyna Drake,
who was a runaway orphan taken in and raised
by an ex-Special Forces agent and martial arts
sensei named Desmond Lamar. After he died from
brain cancer, Dina became the new Sensei of
his dojo and was forced to defend it from street
gangs seeking protection money and ninjas wanting
to take down the dojo. Though she failed to
save the dojo, her talents were recognized by
a man named John Lynch, who recruited her into
a covert special ops unit named Team 7, which
included Slade Wilson, who would later become
Deathstroke, longtime Wonder Woman love interest
Steve Trevor, Amanda and Kurt Lance, whom Dyna
would marry in secret. During her recruitment
to Team 7, Dyna had been secretly tested and
found Medi-Gene positive, so Lynch put her in
the most difficult, dangerous missions in an
effort to trigger her innate power. And it worked!
While on a mission to recover a powerful magical
artifact known as Pandora's Box, she saw her
husband Kurt get shot, and she unleashed a
canary cry equal in power to an array of to
the surprise of Lynch, who initially predicted
her power to be akin to a sonic bullet. Her
scream destroyed the small island they were
working on and seemingly killed her husband.
Team 7 disbanded after the incident and Dinah
started her own crime-fighting team named Birds
of Prey, recruiting members such as Batgirl,
Kitana, and Poison Ivy, though the team later
disbanded after it was revealed that Dinah
was being manipulated behind the scenes by an
amnesiac Kurt Lance with ties to Amanda Waller.
Dyna later joined a rock band named Black Canary
and fought crime as they toured the country.
After which, she met Oliver Queen for the first
time, formed a relationship with him, and was
recruited to the Justice League by Batman. Powers-wise,
Black Canary can use her voice to emit ultrasonic
frequencies capable of disorienting foes or
shattering steel. She could also use it to
launch herself into the air by aiming her voice
toward the ground. Additionally- So, like Banshee,
can she fly? It's more of like a glide. Additionally,
she's one of the most skilled martial artists
on the planet, having mastered multiple forms
of martial arts, including Judo, Jujitsu, Taekwondo,
Wing Chun, Krav Maga, and Dragon-style Kung
Fu, to name a few. She's an agile acrobat and
well-trained in weaponry, espionage, and tactical
analysis. Oh, that's Black Canary. It's always
interesting hearing like both versions of their
origin, like both pre-New 52, post-New 52.
All the post-New 52 stuff is eventually gonna
go away, right? Or what's gonna happen? Uh,
no, I think they're being merged. Like, that's
essentially what happened with Superman. Both
of his continuities have been merged. Like,
literally into one Superman. Oh, okay. Yeah.
Personally, I prefer the New 52 origin for Black
Canary. It seems like she was more of a spy.
in the new 52 universe with Team 7. Yeah, along
with like new characters like Slade Wilson
and Amanda Waller. It's like, you know, those
are well-known characters in DC for being like
spy characters. Yeah, as opposed to just, you
know, growing up as the daughter of a crime
fighter and then, you know, going into her shoes.
Exactly. Yeah, exactly. So now that we've gone
through their histories, we go ahead and speculate
on how we think a fight between the two characters
would go. The rules that we set out for the
match are that the characters start out about
50 yards apart from each other. They don't know
anything about each other than that the other
one is a threat that needs to be put down. Mm-hmm.
We also don't account for the environment.
Or at least we like to speculate that this match
takes place in an environment that has no bearing
on the battle. Because environments can be too
variable. Right. And some characters can win
in certain environments and not in others. Right,
the environment plays too much of a factor
on the fight and we don't take stats for it,
so we just say. that it has no bearing on our
speculation or the simulations that we run.
Right. So let's go ahead and start this match
off. 50 yards apart. Who goes first? I'm gonna
say Black Widow's gonna go first with this
because she's gonna have a sniper rifle. And
so right away she's gonna set up from 50 yards
out, bring her gun up, and then start firing
off shots with her gun. Black Canary used to
carry firearms back when she was a covert soldier,
but since she started her superhero career,
she really doesn't do that anymore. She just,
you know, again, relies on her superpower.
But she's no stranger to being shot at. You
know, like dodging bullets stuff. Yeah. As
to what, you know, whether it's from other covert
organizations or from street crime. So she
knows how to move in a way where she's not going
to be an easy target. Okay. And so she's moving
across the terrain. And she also uses her, her
Sonic screen pointed downward to sort of like
launch herself into the air and kind of like
move faster that way. To become like a harder
target. Yeah. Okay. So she closes the distance
between her and Black Widow. Right. Okay. So
they get in close and they start their fight.
Black Widow is still holding the sniper rifle,
so she's kind of like fighting with that, almost
kind of like a bow staff kind of weapon. Uh
huh. Okay, so yeah, they're fighting, but Black
Canary manages to grapple the rifle away from
Black Widow, and then aim it at her, and fire
off a few rounds. Okay, so she takes the gun
from her, Black Widow does like a few backflips
to dodge these rifle bullets, and fires her
widows by at Black Canary to kind of stun her
arm to drop the gun. Okay. She drops her gun.
And that's when she just fires off her canary
cry. Can't make her drop that. So the canary
cry, is it gonna hurt Black Widow's ears or
is it gonna hit her like a car or something
like that? It's a disorienting cry. So it's
like a low frequency canary cry just to incapacitate
Black Widow. Just to start off? So they're both
kind of stunned from their respective abilities
kind of. Black Canary from her widow's bite
and Black Widow from the canary cry. So at
that point, Black Widow, I think she has more
stamina than Black Canary because she's undergone
those chemical experiments. So she shrugs off
the canary cry pretty quick and she pulls out
a pair of handguns and she starts shooting towards
a black canary with the handguns. So black
canary fires off another canary cry that warps
the medium that the bullets are traveling in
so they go off course. Oh really she can do
that. Yeah, she can sonically force bullets
off course. So the guns are pretty much useless.
Together, you're- I don't know she could do
that. She could do a lot of stuff. It's a pretty
versatile power. All right, so black widow
also has to deal with the oncoming waves that
are going toward her as she's shooting the
gun toward a black canary. So Black Widow does
a cartwheel out of the range of the Canary
Cry, and at which point she closes the distance
again with a flying kick, and like wraps her
legs around Black Canary. Yes, she does. And
like spins around and like throws her through
the air onto the ground. OK, well, Black Canary
just kind of rolls out of it and presses her
own martial arts attack. So they're going to
get it hand to hand again. OK, I can see like
Black Widow is trying to stun her again with
her widow's bite, but Black Canary already
being aware of its existence, keeps like moving
her arm and stuff and. And I could also see
Black Canary trying to use her Canary Cry at
close range, but Black Widow keeps attacking
her from behind and grabs her in a chokehold
from behind so that she can't use her voice.
Okay, well that's when Black Canary just aims
her Canary Cry downward and launches them both
straight into the air. Oh yikes. How are they
gonna get out of that? Well Black Canary can
definitely just fire another blast down to land
softly. So as they're in the air, Black Canary
lifts Black Widow over her and throws her down
to the ground. Oh man. Alright, so Black Widow
is falling toward the ground and I assume that
Black Canary is kind of like slowly gliding
down toward the ground with her Canary Cry.
Right. At the very last second she like shoots
a grapple line that wraps around Black Canary's,
I guess, ankle or something like that. Uh huh.
And like lowers herself gently to the ground
so that, you know, she doesn't splatter. But
with that cable line attached to her leg, Black
Widow yanks Black Canary out of the sky and
slams her into the ground. Okay, but not like
hard because, you know, she just has her Canary
Cry to lessen the impact. Right. Okay. So they're
both on the ground now except now Black Widow
has Black Canary by a grapple line. And so with
Black Canary somewhat restricted like that,
Black Widow shoots a tear gas pellet into her
general vicinity. Does she need a gun to do
that or does it fire from her bracelet? It fires
from her bracelets. Okay. Yeah. So now Black
Canary is on the ground, wrapped with a cable
around her ankle, and surrounded by tear gas.
Okay, well again, Black Canary's had special
forces training so I'm sure she's been in that
kind of training situation before where she's
had to endure tear gas. She kind of like holds
her breath and like unwraps her leg from the
cable and then she leaps out of the gas In
a like a handspring front flip flying kick towards
Black Widow real quick to close the gap All
right, so they're back to hand-to-hand combat
at this point Yeah, but Black Widow pulls out
like one of her knives and straight-up stabs
Black Canary this time. No Black Canary isn't
the most well armored of superheroes. The knife
thing is hard. I wouldn't say she gets stabbed
Maybe she gets like sliced a little bit. Okay
But yeah, I mean that just comes with the territory
of hand-to-hand fighting with someone with a
knife. So Black Canary is sliced a little bit,
it kind of like slows her down just a little
bit, at which point Black Widow straps a explosive
sticky bomb to her back, then- What?! Kicks
off of her, does a few black hand springs as
the explosive goes off, and kills Black Canary.
Okay, but she's wearing a leather jacket. Okay.
So, as she hears the beeping like about to go
off, she takes off the leather jacket and throws
it towards Black Widow. Hehehehe. And to top
it off- She unleashes like a freight train
of a sonic scream towards Black Widow. Okay,
so Black Widow is gonna suffer the bomb explosion
and the canary cry? Right. Except that I say
that Black Canary didn't get the jacket off
in time and it blows up before she could actually
throw it. Agree to disagree. Alright, let's
go ahead and take it to the stats. So we're
gonna go ahead and go back to the future and
leave you guys with the original results of
this match so you can find out who exactly
got out of this situation alive. Awesome. See
you guys. Anyway, let's take it to the computer
show. Let's run the figures. All right. The
fuck was there a duck in the simulation runner?
I don't know how the machine works, man. Sometimes
ducks run there. So the results are in. And
looking at the risk solver add-on, it's going
to be really close. I know that. It is very
close. It's 52.3, which makes this the closest
battle that we've had yet. How is there ever
going to be a closer battle than that after
a thousand simulations? Well, here's the thing.
When I was putting in the numbers, I ran an
average of all the stats, and they came out
to the same number, actually. I'm not surprised.
So, I mean, random numbers are generated between
a standard deviation of that stat number. But
if you just average the base of what we put
in... the average came out the same. So essentially,
they're as equally powerful. So if we were
to run the simulation again, it's possible that
Black Canary would come out on top. Wait, so
Black Widow came out on top. Black Widow did
win. By 52%. Yeah, she won 52.3% of the 1,000
simulations. So we're taking that as the truth.
What the heck? As gospel. That is what happened,
and that's what we're sticking to. So in your
face. Whatever, that's not, that is not in
your face. I'm not running the simulations again.
That was, it's pretty much a coin toss. So
close, it is a coin toss. Wow, will we ever
have a match that close again? Probably, but
we'll see. It would have to be like Hyperion
and Superman or something, I don't know. Just
people that are clones of each other. Yeah,
clones. I mean, they're sort of clones. I thought
her canary kite would have put her out on top,
but it's probably the lethality of Black Widow.
It's not the lethality, it's the... Let me look
at the stats again. Yeah, Black Canary certainly
ranked higher in projectile damage, but Black
Widow's Edge was in, she was slightly smarter
and had a greater accuracy at long range. Oh,
that's, when I say accuracy, I mean marksmanship.
Because Black Canary doesn't use guns. She always
uses Oracle, and Black Widow is kind of her
own Oracle. She's like a master hacker and she's
super smart. She led the Avengers, she's good
at tactics, things like that. Black Canary,
while she's had a leadership role before, I
don't think it's quite to the same extent. No,
no. So there you have it. That was a good match,
holy cow. That was pretty good. So if you're
keeping tabs at home, Marvel is up two one.
That's like a split down the middle win. So
it was like 1.5 versus 1.5. Technically this
one goes in the Marvel books and we'll see what
happens the next time. So next podcast. Next
podcast in two weeks. we are going to be reviewing
Batman v Superman. Are you nervous? No, I'm
so excited. I just, uh, I'm nervous for you.
You know, I can't believe it's only two weeks
away. It's coming up soon. It's going to be
a really long two weeks. Kick off to the DC
Extended Universe. It'll be exciting. Yeah.
Well, we'll join us for that. Definitely tune
in on the next podcast. Looking forward to it.
Yeah, totally. All right. Without further ado,
up, up and away. True believers.