This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
And welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Marvelous Joe. And I'm his twin brother
Johnny DC. And in lead up to Independence Day,
the day after tomorrow, we are going to find
out who would win in a fight between the DC
superhero character of Uncle Sam, the personification
of the US spirit of patriotism. Captain Britain,
the UK's premier superhero. We're taking it
back to 1776 folks, and I gotta say, I think
Britain's gonna win this time. All I know is,
just like in the past, US is totally stomping
on Britain. Like there's no way. Not the Sam's
going down. Never, never fucking America. We'll
see. Before we go over the characters' backgrounds
and put their stats from simulations and find
out who would win, we're gonna break down the
latest comic book movie news to come out this
past week. of which we have three news items,
the first one being the massive amount of set
photos that we've gotten from the Superman film
that's currently filming in Cleveland. We also
got a trailer for Hitmonkey Season 2 and a trailer
for the upcoming animated series Batman Caped
Crusader. As always we list our segment times
in our episode description so feel free to
check out the show notes if you want to skip
ahead to a particular topic. Guys our artificially
intelligent duel simulator AJ9K has a quick
message for our listeners. So listen up. Why
hello there, do you want even more from this
podcast? Then become a part of the dynamic
duel community on Patreon, where you can choose
from three tiers. The dynamic two-oh tier gives
you access to our Discord chat server. The fantastic
four tier gives you two bonus episodes each
month, and the X-Force tier makes you an executive
producer of this show. Lastly, The DynaMic
Podcast Network tier lets you create your own
podcast using this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny
and Joe will help you develop your show, provide
graphic support and consultation, and get you
simulation results. Pitch the twins your ideas
via email at dynamicduelpodcast at gmail.com.
Check it out at patreon.com slash dynamicduel.
Pip pip cheerio. Thanks AJ9K, and thanks to
everyone who supports the podcast. Be sure to
tune in to the other shows in the DynaMic
Podcast Network this week. Including Max Destruction,
which pits your favorite action heroes from
film and television against each other. This
week, hosts Scotty and his brother Gil are
reviewing Independence Day. Naturally. On the
Send Your World podcast, host Zachary Hepburn
speculates on fights between fan favorite anime
and manga characters. The show is currently
on a season hiatus, so this is the perfect time
for you anime fans to catch up on Send Your
World's 40 episode library. And on the Console
Combat Podcast, hosts John and Dean find out
who would win in fights between popular video
game characters. In yesterday's episode, they
found out who would win in a battle between
Raiden from Mortal Kombat versus Thor from
Marvel vs. Capcom. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com
or click the link in our show notes to listen
to all of the shows in the DynaMic Podcast
Network. But with that out of the way, quick
to the no prize. A No Prize is an award Marvel
used to give out to fans. Our version, the
Dynamic duel No Prize, is a digital award we
post on Instagram for the person that we feel
gave the best answer to our question of the
week. Last week we asked, besides Batman, what
character do you most hope to see in the Penguin
Max series and why? And of course this question
was a tie-in to the first trailer for the Penguin
series that will be coming up soon on the Max
platform. We got a whopping two answers. So
let's go ahead and break down our honorable
mention and the no prize winner. The honorable
mention goes to Miggy Matagian who said. Hey,
what's up guys, this is Miggy. And the character
I want to see the most, I most hope to see
in the Penguin is Arnold Flass, Jim Gordon's
corrupt detective partner. He was just like
the first character that came to mind when I
heard the question. Like he's from like Batman
year one. I think it would just be like. Great
for the grounded safe they're taking with the
Penguin because he's like a corrupt, corrupt
detective that sells drugs or takes drugs or
something. Yeah, thanks guys. Yeah, like Miggy
said, Flass is a corrupt detective within the
GCPD. He played a fairly heavy role in comics
like Batman Year One, and we actually saw him
in the Batman Begins movie. He was the fat cop
with the beard. Yeah, he was the guy who was
dropped from the fire escape by Batman in Batman
Begins. Right, exactly. I figured that he would
have played a major role in the GCPD television
series that they were talking about doing.
I think that later evolved into an Arkham series
and I'm not sure where it is right now. But
yeah, it would be interesting to see other police
officers besides Jeffrey Wright's Gordon pop
up in The Penguin. And if any of them popped
up, you would imagine it would be someone like
Flass because he probably has dealings with
organized crime given that he's corrupt. Yeah,
this is a very practical answer given that the
world of the Batman and this Penguin series
is very grounded and very rooted in the crime
genre. Detective Flass is very much a part
of that world and it would make sense for him
to show up. Great answer, Miggy, but the winner
of this week's No Prize is Travis Herndon, who
said, What's up, Dynamo dudes? Travis here.
Shout out to my other twins. So my answer would
have to be Killer Croc. I think he can easily
fit in this Batman universe. You can either
have him be a bodyguard to the Penguin or some
other rival gangster, or even have him be his
own gangster like he was in the comic books
before. He became a muscle for other people,
you know, give him that same sort of like makeup
that he had a suicide squad and bam, you got
yourself a cool killer croc. Yeah. The gangster-esque
killer croc that we got in the suicide squad
actually was not the worst interpretation of
that character. I don't know if you could go
that far with it for a series like The Penguin.
In the comics sometimes Killer Croc is just
depicted as a big guy with a skin condition.
And I think you could definitely go that route
for The Batman, which again, like you mentioned,
is fairly grounded. Honestly, the more bat villains
we get in here though, the better. I would
love to see Matt Reeves' interpretation of all
of them. Yet it's always hard for me to accept
altered origins to characters within a gritty
grounded setting like this because it doesn't
feel true to the comic book origins. So like
if Matt Reeves were to include a character
like Killer Croc within the universe of the
Batman and Penguin, it would definitely be
a different take on the character. Like he would
just be a guy whose teeth are filed into points
or something and they say he looks like an alligator
or something like something really grounded
and lame like that, you know? Maybe like tattooed
scales or something, contact lenses. That would
be lame. If I saw that version of Killer Croc,
I'd be like, Oh, okay. They did it better in
the last cinematic universe. Maybe they could
retain the continuity from the Peacemaker television
series and have Aquaman be a guy who fucks fish.
And Killer Croc is just the offspring of a
relationship between Aquaman and a crocodile.
Considering that was the DCEU, not gonna happen.
Oh, yeah, that's true. The Batman's not in the
DCEU. Okay, makes sense. But also how dare
you for bringing that up again. Everyone forgot
about it, you just reminded everyone. Aquaman
fucks fish. So great answer Travis, you win
this week's no prize. If you the listener want
a shot at winning your own no prize, stay tuned
to later on this episode when we'll be asking
another question of the week. And now that that's
done, on to the news.
Okay, so last week there were leaked set photos
from the Superman movie directed by James Gunn
revealing the full suit of David Cord sweat's
Superman character. Of course, we got our first
look at the character a little over a month
ago in a kind of a bizarre official photo of
Superman sitting down like in an apartment putting
boots on with this like giant space laser in
the background. People didn't love that. We
commented on it and we kind of agreed that
it was unusual. But I gotta say, after seeing
these set photos, I'm actually really loving
this costume. It does look really good. I have
to say, it might be one of my favorites now.
It's very inspired by the new 52 Superman outfit,
but it has the red trunks and of course the
Kingdom Come logo style. So it's a nice amalgam
of a lot of great Superman elements over the
decades. Yeah, my favorite thing I think is
just the colors. You know, Christopher Reeves'
Superman had a very like baby blue with a like
a red cape thing kind of going. Henry Cavill
had something that was much darker in tone.
But to me, this hits a perfect blend between
the two. The red is still very vibrant, but
the blue is not quite as dark. It's a little
bit brighter. And I think it's a great interpretation
of Superman just as this bright symbol for
people to look up to. Well, it's a very colorful
costume, right? Actually, every character that
was revealed in the set photos appears to be
quite colorful in a comic book sort of way.
Like look at Lois Lane, who is wearing purple
and her outfit is very heavily inspired by
what Lois Lane wore in the animated adventures
cartoon. Well, not just that cartoon. Lois
Lane actually wears purple a lot in the comics
as well. But I love the fact that we get to
see her in purple. The actress who plays her,
Rachel Brosnahan. Looks like the character
to a T. I swear she was born to play the character.
I like the colorful cast of characters that
we got from The Daily Planet, including Cat
Grant, Steve Lombard, Jimmy Olsen, Perry White.
They all look really good. Yeah, they all look
fantastic. But my favorite look of the character
that we got besides Superman is actually Mr.
Terrific, a member of the JSA, although I'm
not sure if he's going to be a member of the
JSA in this movie. Mr. Terrific is played by
Eddie Gathegi. Although I didn't really recognize
him from the set photos. The T-mask that he
wears over his face and hairstyle gives him
this sort of different look, I would say. I
can't wait to see like all of the T spheres
moving around him. And I hope they interpret
the character that way. We also got to look
at Lex Luthor, played by Nicholas Holt, who
looks really good in the role with the bald
head. Yeah, it looks like a bunch of scratches
and bruises. It looks like maybe Superman saved
him from an accident or something like that.
But he's also not the only villain we got to
see. We also got to see the engineer. and some
mysterious man in a black costume. We're not
sure who he is, but it looks like they're arresting
Superman along with the military, which kind
of harkens back to Man of Steel. But I don't
know. We'll see how this plays out differently
in this film. The one thing I didn't love from
all of these set photos was actually Clark Kent.
Yeah, the character of Clark Kent looks vastly
different from Superman, which, you know, is
good in terms of the disguise of Clark Kent.
But. his hair is like so freaking curly, it
makes you wonder how his transformation into
Superman is possible with those two vastly different
hairstyles. And I know Clark Kent is supposed
to look dorky, but damn, he looks really dorky.
So you guys were making fun of his look on
the Discord. You were calling him Superm Man.
Right, insinuating that he gets a perm to be
Clark Kent. But I came up with the theory that
the way he gets his hair a little bit more
straight when he transforms into Superman, is
just by heat visioning his hands so they get
really hot and just brushing them through his
hair so it acts like a flat iron. Which is
a horrible theory. Truly horrible. And yet it's
a theory nonetheless. Hahaha. But all in all,
I actually really got excited by all of these
photos. I cannot wait for this movie which
comes out in a year. It's gonna be a really
long year, that's all I know. We don't usually
comment on set photos, but if you guys have
seen them online, you know that they're substantial
enough. to warrant commenting on and also, you
know, a few of them raise interesting discussions
about the plot and the characters, especially
that mysterious man in black photo. But that
brings us to our question of the week.
Who do you think is the mysterious man in black
in the Superman set photos, and why? Record
your answer at dynamicduel.com by clicking on
the red microphone button in the bottom right
hand corner of the screen, which will prompt
you to leave us a voicemail. Your message could
be up to 30 seconds long, and don't forget to
leave your name in case we include you on the
podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer, and
award that person a Dynamic Duel No Prize that
we'll post to Instagram. Be sure to answer before
July 6th. In Marvel News this past week, we
got our first trailer for the upcoming season
of Hit Monkey. This will be season 2, which
will be released on Hulu on July 15th, all 10
episodes. Now, we reviewed Hit Monkey season
1 when it came out, and it was actually a surprise
hit. I don't think you and I had any expectations
of what the Hit Monkey show would be, and we
were really pleased with how the show turned
out. It was a whole lot of fun. We rated it
4 stars, and you can listen to our review of
season 1. Season 2 looks like it's going to
take place right where season 1 left off, where
Hitmonkey and his Hitman ghost mentor Bryce
are fleeing Japan. They go to New York City
and are in an entirely different environment
in this next season. The way the first season
ended, Bryce moved on to the afterlife but made
a deal with Mephisto to come back and resume
as Hitmonkey's personal mentor. It looks like
they just plan on fighting crime in New York
City, but there's a lot of supernatural elements
going down. possibly due to Bryce's deal with
Mephisto, although I don't know if they're gonna
call him Mephisto in the show. I think they're
just gonna call him the devil. But we get introduced
to some new characters, including Eunice, who
is voiced by Leslie Jones. She was Bryce's former
agent. Olivia Munn is gonna be back this season
as Akiko Yokohama, but this time she's gonna
be Lady Bullseye, who's gonna go after Hitmonkey
for his actions in Japan from the first season.
You know, of course, Jason Sudeikis is great
alongside Hitmonkey. They just have a great
dynamic. The show's dialogue is one of its
best features. Actually, the worst feature of
the show is probably the animation, at least
it was for season one. But we didn't really
let that deter us from enjoying the show. But
I have to say that from this trailer, season
two's animation looks like they actually put
a little bit more money into it. I actually
really like the stylish animation of the show.
I think it suits the concept and vibe that they're
giving off. I am... Honestly really pumped
for the show. I didn't even know they were making
a season two until not too long ago Now I was
actually really surprised because I thought
that Marvel Studios was doing away with all
the stuff that wasn't like in their MCU Continuity
so this was a very pleasant surprise Yeah,
hit monkey was a holdover from the old Marvel
television division And I guess it was popular
enough for them to continue the series in a
season two Yeah, I think this was one of two
series that got released through that the other
one being Modok, right? Yeah, but Modok only
had one season, which is also a shame because
I actually really liked Modok. Hitmonkey season
one was great for its action, its tremendous
over-the-top violence, and that humorous dialogue.
It's just a great show. If you haven't checked
out season one, definitely check it out and
then catch up on season two and listen to our
reviews. You only have a few weeks to catch
up on season one because, again, season two
drops on July 15th. On the DC side of animation,
we got our first trailer. for the first season
of Batman Caped Crusader, a television series
that's coming out on Amazon Prime. It was created
by Bruce Timm, who also created the Batman
animated series that began in the 90s, and it's
very much in that same Bruce Timm style, except
it definitely looks like it has a darker, more
noir, more mature approach. Which, you know,
if you know anything about Bruce Timm as a fan
of the comics, He tends to make things that
are a little bit more mature when it's not made
for Saturday mornings. And this definitely
looks like it's a little bit in keeping with
that old Max Fleischer, 1940s kind of style
that he originally wanted to emulate in his
Batman series. This of course follows Batman
in his early years as a caped crusader. So we
get early looks at characters like Catwoman
and Two-Face. You know, we get to see him back
when he was Harvey Dent. And I gotta say, the
character designs... of villains like Two-Face
and Scarecrow go so much harder than they did
in the original animated series. Yeah, they're
very grotesque, almost like the Dick Tracy
villain approach. Yeah, which makes it feel
like so much more pulpy, I would say, and so
much more noir, which I didn't think would be
possible, but it apparently is. The voice cast
for this show is amazing. I'm not too familiar
with his work, but he does a pretty good impression
of Kevin Conroy, I would say. Yeah, he was in
the Legion television series as well as the
first Fantastic Four movie as Dr. Doom's assistant.
Oh, okay. Okay. So he's had quite a few roles
within the superhero world. Catwoman is going
to be voiced by Christina Ricci. This new version
of Harley Quinn is voiced by Jamie Chung. And
Diedrich Bader, who has voiced Batman in shows
like Batman Brave and the Bold and the Harley
Quinn animated series, is doing the voice of
Harvey Dent in Two-Face. Looks like there's
gonna be a ton of action in this show based
on this trailer, where we get to see, you know,
Batman slinking through mist and shadow to
take down gun-wielding bad guys, and there's
like explosions and everything. It's pretty
wild. I expect the show to be really good, because
you know, Bruce Timm has already shown that
he's had an incredible take on the character
from his prior work, but also because it's
produced by Matt Reeves. and JJ Abrams, which
is fascinating. Yeah, Matt Reeves, you know,
being the guy who directed the recent The Batman
movie with Robert Pattinson and JJ Abrams being
a prolific director and producer in his own
right. Early days Batman has always been a
very interesting Batman to me, and I can't wait
to see how this compares to things like Batman
Begins or The Batman. Or Batman Mask of the
Phantasm, which we recently reviewed just a
few weeks ago and also took place during Batman's
early years as a crime fighter. Right, exactly.
All 10 episodes are dropping simultaneously
on August 1st on the Amazon Prime platform.
So if you don't subscribe to that, definitely
make sure you do it by August 1st because we'll
be watching this, we'll be reviewing it, and
I think it's going to be a lot of fun.
But I think that does it for all the news for
this episode, so let's go ahead and get into
our main event where we find out who would win
in a fight between the USA's Uncle Sam and
the UK's Captain Britain.
Alright, Uncle Sam versus Captain Britain. Now
this is the personification of US patriotism
versus the UK's greatest hero. We are taking
it back to the early days of America's history
when they fought for independence from Great
Britain. And we're gonna see if, you know,
that sticks or if, you know, the UK is gonna
be able to annex America again due to the results
of this match. Holy cow, I didn't know that
much was writing on this. Wow, who knew? Yeah,
the battle was not over. This will be the final
bout. We'll see what happens. Winner takes
all. Down with the monarch. Yeah, I don't know
much about Uncle Sam as a comic book character.
So I'll be interested in seeing what the hell
this guy can do. Yeah, honestly, I didn't know
too much about him prior to this. He's actually
pretty fascinating. That said, I don't know
too much about Captain Britain. So honestly,
I don't even know if this is a good matchup.
I don't know if this is gonna be completely
lopsided when it comes to the simulations,
but I think it's gonna be fun nonetheless. To
explain the methodology behind our duels, let's
go to our sentient duel simulator AlfredJarvis9000.
AJ9K, tell our listeners how you go about determining
a winner in our duel matchups. Yes, of course
sir. The way I determine a winner between the
contestants is by running 1000 Monte Carlo simulations
using the characters statistics. A Monte Carlo
simulation is a probabilistic model used to
determine outcomes through random sampling.
In this case, I randomize the statistics along
a normal distribution. as a way to simulate
the many variables that can occur during battle.
The stat parameters are based on the official
Marvel power grid from which the DC characters
statistics are extrapolated. Additional stat
categories are included such as range, damage
potential, versatility and perception in order
to create a more detailed and accurate simulation.
The results of the 1000 simulations provide
a percentage of wins for each character. The
contestant with the higher percentage is declared
the victor. as they have a higher probability
to win any given battle. In an equitable pairing,
neither character should win 100% of the matches.
The comic book stories have shown that there's
even a way for Batman to defeat Superman, so
the confidence rate of my method falls in line
with the precedents that have been established
in the source material. My mathematical simulations
are without subjectivity or bias. Feats are
not the sole consideration, nor are fan votes
tabulated for determination of the winner. Thanks,
AJ9K! Before we run the simulations though,
we like to break down each character's histories
and abilities before improvising a scenario
on how we imagine one of the 1,000 simulations
would play out beat for beat. And I believe
it's my turn to go first with a DC character,
so let me tell you all about Uncle Sam. On
July 4th, 1776, shortly after signing the Declaration
of Independence, three of the country's founding
fathers, Benjamin Franklin, John Adams and Thomas
Jefferson were tasked with creating a seal
for the newly formed United States of America.
Conspiring to imbue their seal with spiritual
and mystic power, they gathered ten other occult-minded
men from the other colonies to form a group
of thirteen, including a rational alchemist
and patriot named Taylor Samuel Hawk, who led
them in a mystic ritual to forge a spirit of
liberty and freedom. of the American Dream
itself. The Thirteen successfully bound the
spirit to a powerful talisman, which became
engraved with an eagle on one side and an eye
of providence surrounded by thirteen stars
on the other. The talisman was entrusted to
the care of Taylor Samuel Hawk, known as Samuel,
who soon became embroiled in the Revolutionary
War. While helping a wagon train of supplies
get to George Washington and his troops, he
was spotted by a group of Hessians. German
soldiers who had been hired by the British crown
to help stop the colonial uprising in America.
Risking his life to distract the Hessians from
following Washington's supply wagons, Samuel
goaded the Hessians into following him, though
they eventually caught up and beat him, and
left him for dead. Dying with the American talisman
in his hand, the spirit of America awakened
and merged with Samuel's body.
known only as the Minuteman, who crossed the
Delaware with and fought alongside Washington.
After the Battle of Yorktown, the spirit faded,
but would return when needed. In the War of
1812, the spirit was known as Brother Jonathan,
who rallied American troops once again to defend
against British retaliation. At the start of
the Civil War, the talisman was split into
two pieces, resulting in the and Johnny Reb,
spirits of the North and South. By the 1870s,
the two halves of the talisman eventually came
into possession of a man named Samuel Augustus
Adams, a New York cartoonist who criticized
a powerful and corrupt Democrat politician
named William M. Tweed, aka Boss Tweed, who
had Sam Adams assassinated. As Sam lay dying,
both talisman halves in hand, the spirit of
America bound itself to him. creating the first
incarnation of the enduring entity known as
Uncle Sam. Wait, is Uncle Sam the propaganda
character actually based off of Sam Adams? It's
a different Sam Adams, not the one you're thinking
of. Not the guy who makes the beer? No, not
that one. I see. A second incarnation of Uncle
Sam emerged during World War I, when the spirit
of America was once again bound to a dying
American patriot. And a third incarnation emerged
in World War II, during which time he had a
young sidekick named Buddy Smith. After Japan's
attack on Pearl Harbor, Uncle Sam created and
led a superteam known as the Freedom Fighters,
which later became a part of a larger wartime
superteam, the All-Star Squadron. After World
War II, racial division, political assassinations,
and foreign wars, among other things fragmented
the American talisman into smaller and smaller
pieces over the decades as postmodern America's
sense of self deteriorated. Eventually, an
occult group known as the National Interest
performed a ritual to create a sinister spirit
known as Legal Entity to collect all the fragments
of the American talisman. Eventually, they
succeeded, though their ritual to summon the
American Dream produced instead a corrupted
version that called itself the American Scream.
This entity, however, was defeated by a new
spirit of America, one formed by thirteen American
individuels across the spectrum of race and
age that were joined together in a Native American
ritual to form an entity known as Patriot.
Over time, Patriot became the new incarnation
of Uncle Sam, who formed a new version of the
Freedom Fighters. though it wasn't long before
he and the team were seemingly killed by the
secret society of supervillains. The spirit
of America survived, however, and Uncle Sam
later emerged from the Mississippi River. Disturbed
by the violent natures of his former teammates,
who now all worked for a US military organization
known as Shade, or the Superhuman Advanced
Defense Executive, Uncle Sam convinced them
to defect from Shade and join him in protecting
people as the Freedom Fighters. Eventually,
the Freedom Fighters and Shade joined forces,
and Uncle Sam became the new head of the organization.
After the Flash reset DC's continuity, the
multiverse was re-established, and on an alternate
universe of Earth-10, or Earth-X, the Nazis
were never defeated and they conquered the planet.
In that world, Uncle Sam and his Freedom Fighters
fought back against the Nazi occupation of America,
though on a day known as Red Friday, they were
all killed. including, seemingly, Uncle Sam,
who faded away. Believing Uncle Sam was still
alive, Adolf Hitler became obsessed with finding
him, as did a new incarnation of the Freedom
Fighters that eventually formed, who were inspired
by the old team and managed to awaken the spirit
of America when they blew up a version of Mount
Rushmore with the faces of Hitler and other
prominent Nazis carved into it. At that moment,
the spirit of Uncle Sam rose from a grave within
an extra-dimensional realm of ideas known as
the Heartland, home to other national personifications
such as Britannia, Marianne, Hispania, and Johnny
Canuck, all of whom had also seemingly died.
Alongside the freedom fighters, Uncle Sam managed
to deal enough lows to the Nazis to awaken
the other personifications and save the planet
from Nazi rule. And that's Uncle Sam's backstory
so far. Uncle Sam possesses super strength,
speed, and durability commensurate with the
United States' faith in the ideals of liberty
and freedom. Typically, he's been shown to
lift around 50 tons, though he can lift proportionately
more when he grows in size. He can grow as
tall as a skyscraper and shrink to 6 inches.
He could also generate portals to teleport
himself and others to and from the Heartland
and he has limited clairvoyance and telepathy,
able to hear and speak through other people's
minds, remotely perceive major events going
on within the United States, and sense the location
of important patriotic artifacts such as the
Declaration of Independence. He is, in a sense,
immortal, in that even though his body can
be killed, his spirit will find a new host body
as long as American patriotism exists. And
that's Uncle Sam. You would have to think that
Uncle Sam in this current political climate
is probably weaker than he's ever been though,
right? So he's just going to be a pipsqueak
by this point. Dude, I freaking love America.
What are you saying? How dare you? That is
as political as the show will ever get. Thank
goodness. That said, nowadays, you know, Uncle
Sam would probably be splintered too. One would
be called Megaman and the other one would be
called the Progressive. I'd read that comic,
honestly, that'd be pretty interesting. I just
gotta say that Captain America will always be
a better symbol of American freedom than this
Uncle Sam guy will ever be. WHAT? Just for the
record. Oh my gosh, he's literally Uncle Sam.
Who cares? Steve Rogers. And I'll say that no
one can represent the UK quite like Captain
Britain. Let me get into his backstory. Now,
Brian Braddock was born in Malden, Essex in
the United Kingdom. His father was Sir James
Braddock, a champion of the realm of Avalon.
which is similar to the realm of Asgard where
Thor is from, but Avalon is Celtic in nature
as opposed to Norse. Ser James Braddock was
a knight who was sent by the wizard Merlin
to Earth's realm in order to sire the hero Captain
Britain, who would serve as the guardian to
Avalon's gateway hidden within the British Isles.
Ser James sired a pair of twins, Brian and
his sister Betsy. While it was his sister Betsy
that would develop mutant abilities and later
be known as Psylocke, It was Brian that would
eventually take on his birthright to become
Captain Britain. You can learn more about Psylocke
in her duel against Gorilla Grodd. Brian's
time to don the mantle came shortly after his
parents died. While he was attending Thames
University in London, a mercenary named Reaver
and his crew raided the physics research lab
that Brian was studying at in order to steal
the experiments. Brian fled the scene on his
motorcycle, but was chased down by the mercenaries
and rode Bleeding and dying, Brian was visited
by the wizard Merlin and his daughter, known
as the Lady of the Northern Skies. Telling
him that he could live to serve as Great Britain's
protector, they offered Brian a choice between
two magical artifacts. The Sword of Might, or
the Amulet of Right? Seeing himself as more
of a scholar than a warrior, Brian chose the
Amulet of Right, which transformed him into
Captain Britain. and bestowed on him great strength
and the Star Scepter which allowed him to fly
and create magic force fields. The Mercenary
Reaver happened upon the scene and grabbed
the other artifact, the Sword of Might, which
transformed the Mercenary into an armored knight.
Brian fought and defeated Reaver and his mercenary
crew, passing his first challenge as a hero.
He would go on to fight other threats to Great
Britain, including Lord Hawk, the Black Baron,
and the Lurker from Loch Ness. He partnered
with other heroes such as Captain America to
defeat the Red Skull who had come to Great Britain.
During a flight over the English Channel, Brian
was attacked by Merlin's foes, the Nether Gods,
who forced his plane to crash into the water.
He washed ashore on Cornwall Beach, where the
hero known as the Black Knight discovered him,
and the two traveled to Camelot in Avalon, where
together they saved King Arthur's former kingdom
from the evil wizard Mordred. After returning
back to Earth, Brian's abilities were altered
by Merlin so that the magic power of his amulet
and scepter were imbued into Brian himself,
letting him use his powers without the need
of magic artifacts. At one point, he gave up
his Captain Britton mantle and passed it on
to his sister Betsy, who at the time had not
yet joined the X-Men and was not quite ready
for the task. She nearly died in battle with
an assassin called Slamaster, forcing Brian
to kill the villain. He resumed his mantle
as Captain Britton. and his sister soon joined
the X-Men, where she became the quintessential
hero, Psylocke. When several of the X-Men, including
Psylocke, apparently died, Brian was distraught
and was inspired by Nightcrawler to form a British
mutant team called Excalibur. The initial Excalibur
team consisted of Captain Britain, Nightcrawler,
the mutant Kitty Pride aka Shadowcat, Brian's
lover Megan, who was a mutant shapeshifter descended
from mythical fairies, and an alternate universe
version of Jean Grey and Cyclops' daughter from
the Days of Future Past timeline called Rachel
Summers, who also went by Phoenix. Excalibur
quickly became Britain's premier superhero
team. When they traveled to the US to aid the
remaining X-Men against the Goblin Queen, Brian
learned that his powers were linked to the British
Isles, and that the further he journeyed from
them, the more his powers waned. He was then
given a new costume, which acted as a battery
of sorts, storing mystic energies from Great
Britain so that he could more easily use his
powers away from his homeland. This inadvertently
caused Brian to grow in size during a time
of cosmic convergence, when multiple realities
aligned and Brian's suit absorbed the mystical
energy of a multitude of Great Britons. The
Excalibur team used this excess energy to defeat
a wizard named Necrom, who tried to use the
convergence to become omnipotent. Brian later
learned that his sister Betsy was alive. and
that she had used one of Merlin's artifacts,
known as the Siege Paralys, to let her and several
other X-Men escape death through a mystic portal.
Brian later married Megan in a ceremony in Avalon,
and Excalibur disbanded. After being attacked
by warriors from Avalon, they journeyed to the
realm where Brian received a message from his
father, Sir James, that as Captain Britain,
Brian was the rightful heir of Otherworld,
which was a magic dimension that housed the
realm of Avalon. Wielding the blade of Excalibur,
Brian and Megan ruled over Otherworld for a
time, passing the Captain Britain mantle to
a British woman named Kelsey Lee, offering her,
in a moment of near death, the choice between
the Sword of Might and the Amulet of Right.
She chose the sword and served on the Avengers
until the team was disassembled by the Scarlet
Witch in a fit of madness. Brian eventually
returned to Earth and formed a new Excalibur
team.
They tried to invade Avalon through the Siege
Perilous portal in order to control Earth's
magic. Brian and Excalibur fought and defeated
the aliens, and went on to stop other threats
such as the vampire Lord Dracula, whom you can
learn more about in his duel against Andrew
Bennett. Brian left Excalibur for a short stint,
which at this point was rebranded as MI-13.
He joined the Avengers, and later, a secret
group of influential heroes called the Illuminati.
When Captain America's history was rewritten
by the reality warping Cosmic Cube so that
he was a secret member of Hydra, Captain Britain
led a team of European heroes to fight against
Hydra's takeover of America. You can learn more
about this event in our Commander Steel vs
Captain America duel episode. After the mutant
population established their own nation on
the sentient island of Kakoa, Brian visited
his sister Betsy, who at this point had resigned
the Psylocke identity to the Japanese assassin,
Quanan. Together, Brian and Betsy journeyed
to Avalon, where Brian was put under a spell
by the Arthurian sorceress Morgan Le Fay. Betsy
claimed her brother's amulet of right to reassume
the Captain Britton mantle. She formed her
own version of the Excalibur team and defeated
Morgan Le Fay, leaving Brian to claim the Sword
of Might, and he took on the new title of Captain
Avalon, his current moniker. I assume Betsy
is going to retain the title of Captain Britton
from here on out. considering she can no longer
be Psylocke, and considering she's more popular
than her brother, Brian. But since we've already
done a duel with Betsy slash Quanan as Psylocke
against Gorilla Grodd, for this duel against
Uncle Sam, I'll be going with Brian as Captain
Britain. Powers-wise, Captain Britain gains
his abilities from the magical energy stemming
from the gateway to Avalon located in the British
Isles. Traditionally, that meant that the longer
the time and distance he gets from Great Britain,
the weaker his power. However, this limitation
has been resolved by the Lady of the Northern
Skies through the use of magic. Captain Britain
has enough strength to lift around 100 tons.
He has enhanced agility and enhanced durability
through a magic invisible force field that
encases his body. He occasionally projects this
force field from his body as a ranged attack.
Captain Britain can fly up to sonic speeds and
has enhanced hearing and telescopic sight.
Finally, he has a genius level intellect as
an accomplished physicist and engineer. And
that's Captain Britain. I thought for some reason
his power set was way different. I thought
he like shot lasers and stuff for some reason.
No, you might be thinking of Vindicator, who's
like the Canadian version of Captain Britain.
Oh, maybe. Yeah. Who the hell is Union Jack?
Isn't he a guy? Yeah, he's also a British hero,
but he's not Captain Britain. They all look
alike. Well, I mean, yeah, they both wear the
British flag, but you should try not to be
racist. Freaking red coats. All of them. I don't
think Uncle Sam would appreciate what you're
saying. Dude, Uncle Sam loves punching red coats.
It's what he does.
Our fantasies collide and heroes clash. One
Podcast Network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
DynaMic Podcast Network presents Console Combat,
where video game legends brawl every Monday.
Dynamic Duel, where comic- Smash every Tuesday,
Max Destruction, where TV and action heroes
battle every Wednesday, and Sendro World, where
anime champions clash every Thursday. Join
us as we speculate on the matches and, armed
with the power of mathematical simulations,
discover who will emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
Well now that we got their histories and abilities
out of the way, let's speculate on how one
of the 1000 simulated matches will go. The winner
is determined by simulations, not the speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how the fight could
play out. AJ and IK, what are the rules of
our speculation? Well I should say there are
no rules, other than the characters have no
prior knowledge of the other going into the
fight. All they are aware of starting out is
that the other character is a threat that needs
to be eliminated. For the speculation... The
contestants will begin approximately 50 meters
apart in a nondescript environment that will
have no bearing on the match itself, as no environmental
statistics are considered in my simulations.
The contestants must earn victory on their own
merit. Alright then, let's get into it. Uncle
Sam and Captain Britain meet on the battlefield.
Who goes first? I'm going to say that Captain
Britain goes first because he can, you know,
fly up to Sonic's speeds. So he's going to
start off by blitzing Uncle Sam and he's just
going to rock that old man. with the massive
haymaker. Elder abuse. Actually, I don't think
Uncle Sam is that old. I think he just has
white hair, but I think he's actually like a
middle-aged man. But anyway, Uncle Sam, you
know, he gets knocked down, but he's gonna get
back on his feet. He's gonna dust himself off
and roll up his sleeves. And he's gonna be like,
all you've done is awaken a sleeping giant
and he's going to grow. into his giant size
right away and grab Captain Britain like he's
an action figure and just crush him in his grasp.
He'll try to crush him in his grasp, but Captain
Britain's force field is gonna keep him from
getting crushed. So he's gonna slip out of
Uncle Sam's grasp and then he's gonna fly over
his head and Captain Britain's gonna grab Uncle
Sam by his back collar and he's gonna flip this
geezer right onto his ass with a big ol' massive
crash. Okay, but From the ground, Uncle Sam's
gonna swat at Captain Britain with his top
hat and actually he's gonna trap him in it.
And Uncle Sam's like, all men are created equal,
except for you, pipsqueak. And he's just gonna
throw his hat on the floor and just stomp on
it, just crushing Captain Britain beneath his
boot. Oh, wow. Oh, geez. All right. But Captain
Britain is strong enough to burst out of this
hat and he's gonna catch Uncle Sam's boot as
it's trying to stomp on him. And then he's gonna
like Mario 64 him. He's gonna swing him around
and around and around by the leg. And he's just
gonna release him, which is gonna send Uncle
Sam tumbling across the battlefield. And that'll
probably cause him to shrink back down to his
normal size. And that is when Captain Britain's
gonna follow up and fly over to Uncle Sam,
who's on the ground, and he's gonna teabag him.
Just like dunk his nuts right on his face repeatedly.
And he's gonna be like, tea time, tea time.
Uncle Sam's gonna be like... No taxation without
representation, bitch. And he's going to grab
Captain Britain by his nuts and just throw
him into the harbor. Harbor? What harbor? The
the Boston Habba. Duh. There's no environment
here. I don't know what you're talking about.
Captain Britain gets thrown by his sack, but
he's going to land on the ground. Probably feeling
a little bit sick to his stomach. You know,
probably feels like he's going to puke. Yeah.
And while Captain Britain is recovering, that's
when Uncle Sam. is gonna run up to him and just
start pounding him with his fists, yelling,
for life, liberty, and the pursuit of kicking
your ass! Boom! Captain Britain is knocked
out. No, because before Uncle Sam can knock
Captain Britain out, he's gonna project his
force field as a projectile. It's gonna blast
Uncle Sam away, and then Captain Britain's
gonna follow that up with a flying kick to Uncle
Sam's dumb goatee. Actually, Captain Britain,
he's just going to fly and kick straight into
the heartland because Uncle Sam's going to
generate this swirling red, white and blue portal
that Captain Britain just essentially falls
into. So now they're both in Uncle Sam's dimension,
this like idealized Norman Rockwell-esque farm
with like bald eagles in the sky. But in this
world, Uncle Sam, he has some degree of reality
manipulation. So he's gonna summon like a whole
bunch of firework explosions that just blast
Captain Britain. He's like, give me liberty
or I'll give you death. Is he speaking quotes
like that? Sometimes. Alright, so Captain Britain
is getting blasted by these fireworks, but
to avoid them, he's gonna use the Siege Perilous
artifact from Merlin to transport himself and
Uncle Sam to the realm of Avalon. And once they're
there, the lady of the lake, she's going to
throw the sort of might to Captain Britain.
He's going to catch it and then run the blade
right through Uncle Sam's torso, just impaling
him and ending the match. Wait, so the Siege
Perlis is an artifact? Yeah, yeah, it's like
a brooch that grows to become a doorway. Yeah,
and Eagle snatches it from Captain Britain before
he could even use it. So what? The match was
already over. I don't know what to tell you.
Well, if the eagle snatches it before they
can transport to Avalon, then that means that
this eagle just exploded in the fireworks as
they're going off. Hey, that eagle died for
his country, sir. That eagle is a patriot.
I'm going to say that the actually the eagle
died from the firework explosions before it
could snatch the siege perilous. So, yeah, Captain
Britain wins. He takes them both to Avalon
and then Uncle Sam gets impaled. OK, I guess
we'll leave the match there. Either Uncle Sam
gets impaled by the Sword of Might in Avalon,
or Captain Brain gets bombed by a whole bunch
of fireworks in the Heartland. Let's go ahead
and input the character stats, run the simulations,
and find out which of these events happens when
we come back with a winner. AJ9K, hit it! Inputting
data. Running calculations. Processing results.
Simulations complete. Alright this was a pretty
close match, you know, considering that neither
of us really knew much about the other character.
but the executive producers picked this one
out and I think it was a good call. Yeah, I
mean, powers wise, they were pretty similar
and that, you know, they're both really strong
and they could even teleport to like other fantastical
realms, that's crazy. But stat wise, they were
similar as well. Yeah, we said they had about
the same fighting skill and versatility, but
we said Uncle Sam is faster, more durable, stronger.
and capable of more damage and also greater
perception because he has like limited omniscience
over the country. Right, exactly. We also said
Captain Britton was more evasive. He had a greater
range because Uncle Sam has no projectile attacks
basically. And surprisingly, Captain Britton
was more intelligent than Uncle Sam. So taking
all of the stats into consideration, Joseph,
who do you think came out on top? I think that
this is the day Britton finally wins. I think
they're going to get their sweet revenge for
what happened all those centuries ago. And America's
going down. Why do you hate America, sir? I
don't hate America, but I do love Marvel. And
Marvel has Captain Britain, who I'm representing
in this match. You're a traitor to your country?
Well, I mean, I'm not the only one who thinks
that Captain Britain will win because according
to the Instagram poll results, it's an even
split 50-50. That's only because I put the poll
up late because we're recording a little bit
early and not enough Americans have seen the
poll yet. But let's find out who won. AG9K,
the results please. Hey Yuasa. The winner of
the matchup between Uncle Sam and Captain Britain
is... Uncle Sam, bitch! We lost again. Dude,
you're American. What are you talking about?
Uncle Sam won 546 out of the 1000 matches or
54.6% of the time compared to Captain Britain,
who won 45.4%. That's pretty close, though.
It was close. Too close, if you ask me. You
don't think there's any bias at play here with
having America win on the 4th of July, is there?
Well, I mean, unless AJ9K is biased, unless,
you know, math is biased. I guess math just
loves America. And you know this is actually
really fitting because this upcoming week I'm
traveling to our nation's capital Washington
DC. I'm putting a new meaning to DC in Johnny
DC and I would have been really embarrassed
if I had to show my face there with Captain
Britain winning. I mean you should probably
never show your face anywhere if we're being
honest. Dude my face looks like your face. Ah
shit that was a self burn wasn't it? I guess
that does it for this duel. AG9K, help close
us out.
or by rating and reviewing Dynamic Duel on Apple
Podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser, or on our website.
Don't forget to listen to the other shows in
the DynaMic Podcast Network, including Max
Destruction, Senjo World, and Console Combat.
In our next episode, we will be reviewing a
Marvel animated direct-to-video feature, Hulk
Versus. Right, and the executive producers
chose that movie to review because it features
a Wolverine versus Hulk fight and Wolverine
is going to be appearing in the Deadpool and
Wolverine movie coming out at the end of this
month. So look forward to that. But that does
it for this episode. We want to give a big
thanks to our executive producers, Ken Johnson,
John Swarovski, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Balcom,
Mickey Mathen-Geehan, Brandon Essergaard, Nathaniel
Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Austin Wieselowski, AJ
Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho. Adam
Spies, Andrew Shunk, Dean Molesky, Devin Davis,
and Joseph Kirsting for helping make this podcast
possible. We'll talk to you guys next week.
Up up and away, true believers.