you
a weekly show where we review superhero films
and debate the superiority between Marvel and
DC by comparing their characters in stat-based
Battle simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe and I'm
his twin brother Johnny DC And this is our 91st
episode and part of the official countdown
to our 100th episode Which we have a special
treat planned for you guys, but no hints just
yet in this episode We'll be talking about who
would win in a fight between Clayface Venom.
Yeah, it's in preparation for our Venom review,
which comes out this Friday. That came up like
really quick Yeah, I kind of snuck up faster
than I thought it would for some reason I was
thinking like mid-october, but no it's this
Friday that it's coming out So it's weird because
we've been talking about this movie forever
and yet it still snuck up on me, right? Right.
So yeah, look forward to that Venom movie review
next week, but in this episode again It's a
dual episode and we'll get all up into that
later on after we go over the comic book movie
news over the past week So we'll be talking
about the Dark Phoenix trailer and some of
the other fox fuckery that's going on with release
dates and stuff like that. There was some casting
for the Birds of Prey film. We got Huntress
and Black Canary cast. We got a new trailer
for the Titans show that's on DC Universe in
the US, but apparently it's also moving to
Netflix internationally. And finally, there
was a new trailer for the Runaway season two
that's coming to Hulu. And we'll just talk briefly
about that. Yeah, and just quick heads up,
we are... off our Patreon hiatus. Yeah, we're
back with the bonus content coming out every
Thursday for our patrons. It's only two bucks
a month to sign up at patreon.com slash dynamic
duel. So if you're interested in getting more
content from us, definitely do that. We've
been talking for a while now about how the reason
we went on hiatus for Patreon during the month
of September was because we were working on
kind of like a secret project as it were. And
also because we wanted to reevaluate sort of
what content we did. for Patreon and how we
released that content. We're still trying to
figure that out, but in the meantime, we do
have bonus content for you guys. Yeah, basically
our current patrons will get an exclusive first
look at the bonus stuff that we're putting together
right now. If you go to our Patreon page, you'll
notice that we have a goal to reach 25 patrons,
at which point we'll print out physical copies
of the Dynamic Duel No Prize that we award to
a listener every week. So again, visit patreon.com
slash dynamic duel and help us reach that goal.
And speaking of no prizes, It's No Prize time.
So No Prize is an award that Marvel used to
give out up until the 90s to fans. Our version,
the Dynamic Dual No Prize, is a digital award
that we post on social media that I personally
draw for those who we feel gave the best answer
to our question of the week. Last week's question
was, what MCU character do you most want to
see get their own limited series on Disney
Play and what particular storyline do you hope
to see with them? And this is coming up the
news from last week that the Disney Play streaming
app will feature original limited series starring
the characters and actors from the MCU films,
which was exciting news. So we got a lot of
great answers on this one. It was so damn hard
to pick a winner from the selection of answers,
but, you know, gun to my head, I had to choose,
so that's what we did. But first up, honorable
mention to Karen Diekmann, who gave the answer
of Rocket Raccoon. It's the perfect answer.
I would love to see a limited series just based
off Rocket Raccoon going off of his history
as an experiment. You know? Andy Freeman gets
honorable mention as well for answering Gambit.
I'm not sure if the X-Men characters are going
to be a part of the MCU by the time this rolls
out. Well, I mean, I think it's a great way
to introduce these characters prior to introducing
them in the films. Like, establish their backstory
right away in their own individual limited
series, and then show them on the films as a
team unit. And honestly, I know we're going
to be talking about the Gambit movie later on
in this episode, but at this point, the movie's
been pushed back so far. already that you may
as well just forget about the movie and throw
it on the small screen. In an ideal world that
would happen. Yeah. Also honorable mention
to Mitchell Phipps, who gave the answer Quicksilver,
which yeah, absolutely. We did not get enough
Quicksilver in Avengers Age of Ultron. Right.
It would be great to find out more about the
character. I'm still hoping they resurrect him
in the next Avengers film. Right. But if they
don't, what's great about this is- you could
still bring those characters back to do these
shows. Yeah, it's possible that you may have
that version of Quicksilver in the announced
Scarlet Witch limited series that they're gonna
do on Disney Play. Yeah, maybe. But yeah, I'd
like to see Quicksilver also get his own show.
That'd be cool. Also honorable mention to Jace
Crump, who gave the answer Winter Soldier. Oh
god, that would be so fantastic. To like follow
him through the years, since the 1940s when
he became the Winter Soldier. Yeah, it'd be
like a spy show. Yeah, so fantastic. That would
be a great, great time. Also honorable mention
to Jacob Bell who gave the answer the Hulk and
he specifically was looking for the planet
Hulk storyline It's probably like his like lost
days while he was on Sakaar. Right? Yeah prior
to Thor arriving on that planet I think that
would make for some pretty interesting viewing
as well She's gonna see like Hulk's rise through
the gladiator ranks Yeah, and you know becoming
a favorite of the Grandmaster and stuff like
that. Yeah, that would be so cool Also honorable
mention to Dan Baker who gave the answer of
M'Baku who's the leader of the White Gorilla
Clan in the Black Panther movie. I can't see
how you could not do a series with him and
see the White Gorilla Clan evolve through the
ages until M'Baku became the king and see just
what, kind of like the day-to-day life is there.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. And our final honorable mention
goes to Ariana Quadra, who actually gave my
favorite answer in Adam Warlock, because who
knows if we're gonna get Guardians of the Galaxy
3? And this may be a fantastic opportunity
to see, like, that dangling thread that may
never get picked up of Adam Warlock. I'm still
convinced that we are going to get Guardians
of the Galaxy 3 because it's the studio has
stated that they're working off of James Gunn's
script. They just need to find a director and
I don't think there's a timetable for that.
I have a feeling we're going to see Adam Warlock
in the third Guardians of the Galaxy movie.
So that's why I didn't pick it for my favorite
answer. That being said, if there's never a
Guardians of the Galaxy 3 movie ever made,
then yeah, I would love to see an Adam Warlock
movie and see exactly where. You know that
storyline picks up after the after credits scene
in Guardians 2. The winner of the no prize
for this week though goes to Adrian Maines who
gave the answer of Thanos. He wants to see
a Thanos limited series involving the character
taking place prior to the events of Infinity
War and in his early history. Which I think
would be fantastic. Like I'd love to see like
Thanos's early days on Titan and the death of
the planets and just sort of his rise to power.
Yeah, life as a space pirate and things like
that. That would just be utterly fantastic.
He is definitely one of the more like intriguing
villains to come out in a superhero film. And
yeah, he's in he's intriguing in terms of, you
know, his character and his philosophy and
things like that. We got to know him pretty
well in that Infinity War movie, but we didn't
learn much more about his history. So let's
see that. Yeah. Congrats to Adrian once again.
And if you, the listener, are interested in
winning a dynamic duel, no prize. Keep listening
to the rest of the episode where we'll give
this week's question of the week. With that
out of the way, onto the news.
Alright, so the first trailer for the Dark Phoenix
film dropped this past week. And, you know,
it wasn't quite the shit show that I thought
it was going to be, but it's still not necessarily
what I'm looking for from the X-Men franchise.
It doesn't look poorly directed. Like, the
cinematography looks good. Oh yeah, Simon Kimberg
actually, he did better than I thought he was
going to do with a lot of these shots. Yeah.
The cinematography at times almost looks artful.
throughout the course of this trailer, and that
might be the most surprising thing. Yeah, there's
not a lot of special effects in this trailer,
but it still looks pretty cool. Yeah. That
being said, I don't know if it looks good. That's
true. The trailer starts off, we see young
Jean Grey as she's meeting Professor X, and
we see the accident that results in her ending
up an orphan and going to stay at the mansion.
Now that deviates slightly from the comics,
as we know, if you listen to our Phoenix versus
Raven episode and the comics, Jean Grey, was
present as her best friend died and was hit
by a car and telepathically experienced her
friend's emotions as she died. In this case,
they kind of made young Jean Grey to be a little
bit more of a sinister character than what I'm
used to seeing. Yeah, she's definitely dark.
They definitely put the dark in Dark Phoenix
in this film. Yeah, like, I guess the question
I have regarding the character of Jean Grey
in this film is, is she actually evil? Because
that's not, that was never the case in the comics.
In the comics, we know that she was trapped
underwater and about to die. but a cosmic entity
known as the Phoenix Force came down, saved
her, like wrapped her in a cocoon of energy,
and then took on her form and pretended to
be her, and was easily corrupted and super powerful.
And it wasn't really Jean Grey. It was just
a manifestation of Jean Grey by the cosmic entity
known as the Phoenix Force. Right, right, right.
The initial idea that Claremont had when writing
the Dark Phoenix storyline was that the Phoenix
was actually Jean Grey reaching her utmost.
potential of her mutant powers and it corrupted
her. And then only later on when they wanted
to bring her back in the comics was it retconned
that it wasn't her at all. That it wasn't her
at all. It was just this manifestation. And
so that original concept that Claremont had
for the Dark Phoenix was explored in the X-Men
The Last Stand film. Yeah. Where Jean Grey reached
her like her peak power and it corrupted her.
Exactly. So we've seen that side explored. We've
seen the story before. Yes. I was hoping that
in this version of the Dark Phoenix story, it
would take on the more true-to-the-comics approach.
And that may be the case because we do get some
shots in the trailer of them like in outer
space. That's not going to be the case because
we have already seen her become the Phoenix
in the last Apocalypse movie. That's true. So
it's going to be her. It's not going to be
this cosmic force. She might be empowered through
these cosmic rays or something like that in
space. I'm not sure exactly what's going on
in that last shot, which actually looks amazing.
All this. fire or radiation or something. Oh
yeah, that's the coolest shot in the film for
sure. Like being absorbed into her? Yeah. Yeah,
I don't know what's going on there. I mean,
it couldn't be the Phoenix Force going into
her, right? Because we've already seen that.
They would have a lot of explaining to do in
the apocalypse. Right, because she manifested
the firebird in that last movie. So it's bizarre.
I don't even think they know what they're doing.
Speaking of the last movie, where the fuck are
those awesome costumes that they had at the
end of that film in this movie? They're back
to like their first class costumes. Yeah, it's
kind of like a mixture of their first class
costumes and the costumes that they had during
Grant Morrison's run on the comics. I'm super
bummed about that. I was really looking forward
to seeing, you know, the early 90s era X-Men
costumes like they had in the comics. Like
the Jim Lee costumes. Yeah, those were so cool
in the comics and it's just a wasted opportunity.
It's like they wanted to save money or something
like that. One thing I've noticed about this
trailer is that like all of the voiceover, like
dialogue is like really subdued. Yeah, like
Jessica Chastain's character. Like I know they're
like talking in a church, but like she's like
barely getting her voice out of her mouth and
the same thing with like Charles later on,
oh my God, you're right. Now that I think about
it, like 80% of this dialogue is just above
a whisper. They're like, I can't believe what
you did. She's changing into what? And it's
like, the rage. Even when the action is going,
it's pretty interesting. Yeah, exactly. Doesn't
get me excited for it. Like, I mean. If they
want to get me excited, like, should I have
some? Well, you want them to yell or what? I
don't know. I think it may just be the approach
that they took in regards to the editing of
this. I think they wanted it to be a slow burn
kind of thing. It's too slow. I'm sure the whole
movie won't be like that. We see Jean visit
Magneto on the mutant island of Genosha. Oh,
really? Yeah, I'm not sure why she goes to
visit him because he does stay in the trailer.
Like, you didn't come here asking for advice.
You came here looking for permission. For what?
To be a bad person? It raises a good question.
Permission to do what? Like, what does she want
to do? Does she want to be evil? If that case,
I have huge problems with that because that's
not the gene that I know. Right. I didn't know
Genosha was in this film. That's pretty cool.
It doesn't look like Genosha. That's how you
didn't know it was Genosha. But you see the
island and then, you know, she goes onto it
and Magneto's living there with other mutants.
It is Genosha. It's just nothing like in the
comics because in the comics, Genosha is this
big futuristic kind of mutant haven city. And
it gets destroyed. Yeah, by Sentinels. And yeah,
this place looks like a dump, honestly. It
does. They saved some money on that for sure.
We get our first look at Jessica Chastain as
this alien person. Still not sure who it is.
I guess Simon Kimberg was saying it's an amalgam
of different characters within the Marvel universe.
Dumb. I couldn't tell you which characters.
Why don't you just use the characters that you're
given? Why do you have to make shit up? Like,
damn it. Exactly, it's kind of hard to tell
what kind of role this character is going to
have. she must be pretty important, especially
with an actor like Jessica Chastain behind
her. I'm guessing she's the movie's primary
antagonist. Yeah. I'm guessing. It seems like
she's trying to manipulate Dark Phoenix in some
way, to what end I have no idea. But yeah,
we see Jean Grey pull off some telekinetic feats,
like tossing cop cars into the air and knocking
a helicopter over and things like that. And
just basically dealing with a lot of stress,
it looks like. Yeah. And everybody's getting
mad at Professor X for inhibiting her psychic
abilities at an early age. Right. But, you know,
I mean, he did it in the comics, so he didn't
really. do that in the comics so much as he
blocked her telepathy completely at an early
age until he felt that she was mature enough
basically to use those powers responsibly.
That's why she had just telekinesis for a long
time in the comics. So yeah, this whole mental
manipulation thing has precedent, but they seem
way more pissed at him here in these movies.
Yeah, like Hank, I'm still so sick of seeing
Hank McCoy not as Beast and Mystique not as
Mystique. Right. Not Blue? It sucks, man. It's
like, if they don't care enough about these
characters, it really makes me not care. It's
like a really big important part of the character.
More so with Beast than Mystique. Well, Mystique
is supposed to be mutant and proud. Right.
And Beast, the whole tragedy of the character
is that he can't cure himself and that he is
uncomfortable with the creature that he is.
So yeah, you're taking away this depth from
these characters that is so vital to who they
are. What are these rates going back to Marvel
again? Exactly. Fuck. You know who does look
pretty spot-on? Ty Sheridan as Cyclops. I think
as he's kind of aged over the years since he
was first cast as Cyclops in these movies,
I think he's kind of grown into a young James
Marsden basically, but almost buffer, you know?
He has that confident demeanor about him, I
think. I think he's great as the character.
Toward the end of the trailer, Magneto says,
you know, I've seen evil and I'm looking at
it now and we see Jean Grey kind of giving off
this evil look with these cracks in her face,
really reminiscent of X-Men The Last Stand.
Well, we've seen this look in early promotional
photos where like she has fire around her and
again the cracks in her skin. So I wasn't surprised
to see that. I am again disappointed that they're
going the same route it appears. I don't know,
this whole thing, I feel like they should just
not be doing it. They shouldn't. Right. And
you know, the very last shot of the trailer
says Dark Phoenix, February 14th. Now the fucking
day after this trailer dropped, they changed
the date to June 7th. Why, Fox? Why? What are
they doing? I have no idea. The day after this
trailer dropped. It's like, did they not know
that they were planning this release date? And
if so, why release the trailer when they did?
Why not just wait a day and make sure that the
date is changed? Exactly. It's like they released
it without knowing what they were doing. I'm
not sure if this was like a part of the New
York Comic Con. release like it was released
just for that or if this is attached to any
kind of film and theaters right now, it might
be attached to Venom. I wouldn't be surprised,
but if it is, it's gonna confuse the shit out
of everyone. Yeah, they're gonna need to change
the trailer that they sent out to be attached
to other films. Yeah. And that wasn't the only
release date that they changed. Fox was originally
going to have Alita Battle Angel, which is
a Japanese comic opening alongside Aquaman this
December,
I don't know what the fuck that's about either.
I mean, it was probably a good idea to move
Alita Battle Angel away from Aquaman and Bumblebee
because those both come out that same day and
they're definitely hitting the same target audience.
Yeah. But to replace it with a PG-13 version,
or what is allegedly a PG-13 version of Deadpool.
Yeah, that's the rumor. Is bonkers in my mind.
Who wants that? The appeal of the Deadpool movies
is how crass the character is. If you take
away the R rating, you take away a lot of the
appeal of those films and that the characters
bite. And apparently they're shooting some new
footage where Deadpool is reading a bedtime
story to Fred Savage, I think. Right. Yeah.
Brian Reddell's released some kind of still
of that, like on his Twitter. Yeah. It's in
the same vein as The Princess Bride. Exactly.
But is that additional footage enough to warrant
going back to the theater to see this? Because
I already have the Super Duper cut and the theatrical
cut at home. It's like, yeah, is this like
another film that we have to review? How different
is it going to be? I don't know. I guess we'll
have to go. fucking watch it in theaters. Again.
Even though I have the movie at home. I'm fucking
watching Aquaman. I don't know what you're doing.
I'm gonna watch Aquaman. You go watch Aquaman,
I'll go watch Deadpool because I'd rather see
a Marvel movie anyway. What you've already
seen, what you've already paid for several times.
Oh God. I don't know what Fox is thinking.
I think they're trying to make as many fuck
ups as possible before handing the rights to
these properties over to Disney. What's the
cash grab? They don't give a fuck. It's a huge
cash grab. They're trying to cement all of these
projects and get as many projects out as they
can, including Gambit. Yeah, including Gambit,
which has gotten a new release date. Yet again,
it's going to be released March 13th, 2020,
which is so late. It's like I already want
the X-Men to be with Marvel by that time. Right.
Exactly. Well, the deal with Disney will go
through at the end of this year, which puts
this Gambit film like at the last possible
moment prior to the Disney switch over. So I'm
hoping that this film actually gets delayed
yet again, and then just struck off the calendar
completely. Especially the way that Simon Kimberg
has been describing the film recently. Like,
I think initially they were talking about it
being like, some kind of like, a heist film.
But now he's describing it as like a romantic,
sexy comedy. What the hell? I think they may
be trying to play into Channing Tatum's strengths
as a comedic actor in that regard, but I mean...
That's gonna come through in the character
anyway, because the character of Gambit has
a lot of charm. And if you've read any of the
Gambit solo series, there's humor in them as
well. You don't have to go all out into the
comedy genre with this film for it to be appealing.
I was much more interested in this project
when it was described as a heist film, since
Gambit, he's a thief. So that would have been
great. I don't know what this is gonna be. It
sounds like it's gonna be like 21 Jump Street
in the X-Men universe. I know, it's gonna get
Jonah Hill as like the blob or something like
that. Right? Actually, I might go see that.
As like a fan project, that would be just absolutely
fantastic. But as like an official, uh, like
canon kind of thing. Yeah, that's not something
I'm too interested in at all. You know what
Fox made no mention of? Was New Mutants. That's
true. That's still scheduled to come out next
year and I guess that's still the case since
they didn't mention it being moved or anything
like that. In the end though, you would have
to think that them moving the X-Men Dark Phoenix
from February to June means that they have
more confidence in the film as a summer blockbuster.
Well, I heard that they're doing it to reach
a good spot in the Chinese film calendar, at
least scheduled, because there was like another
film that it was going up against, a Chinese
film, that was gonna give it too much competition.
Okay, yeah, the Chinese market is huge now,
so that makes sense to me. But yeah, that one
pretty much does it for all that fox fuckery.
I'm so done talking about it. Oh my gosh. Onto
DC news. Mary Elizabeth Winstead has been cast
as Huntress and Journey Smollett Bell has been
cast as Black Canary in the Birds of Prey film,
which I'm really excited about Mary Elizabeth
Winstead as the Huntress. I think she's gonna
make a fantastic Helena Bertinelli. And you
can learn more about the Huntress in our Huntress
versus Jessica Jones match. But I think she'll
make a really good mafia princess. Oh yeah,
Mary Elizabeth Winstead has been making the
rounds of fan casting for years now. So it's
cool to see that she finally got a role as
a superhero. Yeah, what I also like about her
is that she's a lead actress, right? If you
look at films like Cloverfield Lane or Scott
Pilgrim? She was the female lead for sure.
The Thing. The Thing, there you go. Does she
come across as Italian to you? Sure, why not?
She can. Okay, I'm excited about this casting.
The other casting, not so much. I have no idea
who Journey Smollett Bell is. She doesn't really
look the part, does she? Not necessarily. I
mean, I knew that they were gonna go for a diversity
casting with one of these roles. Uh-huh. And
I mean, if you put a blonde wig on her, I'm
sure she'll make a perfectly badass Black Canary.
I'm not unhappy with this casting choice. By
race-bending the character though, are you
taking the word black and Black Canary and changing
its meaning? Because are they gonna think now
that she's called black canary because she's
black are people gonna be saying well Why don't
you just call her canary? Why do you why does
she have to be black canary because her skin
is black? They better not do that. I hope people
understand that this character has existed
For a really long time since the 50s. Yeah,
probably around longer than a lot of them have
been alive So there's precedence for her name
as black canary, you know, someone's gonna
bring it up if they haven't already but I don't
know, I hope people just don't make a big deal
about it. My biggest concern with her is not
the color of her skin at all, it's that I'm
afraid she's not lead actress material. Well,
Black Canary is like the leader of the Birds
of Prey in the comics. Sort of, I mean, it's
either between her or Oracle, but we already
know Oracle isn't in this film, so when it came
to this casting, I thought they were going
to go with someone who could really, really
hold their own film. A-list actress. Exactly.
And that really has me concerned. I know that
this was always going to be Margot Robbie's
show in a way, but I always kind of saw this
film as like an introduction to the Birds of
Prey characters, at which point Margot Robbie's
Harley Quinn could kind of step away and we
would still have this franchise of the Birds
of Prey. But it's like, how does Margot Robbie
exit this franchise after sort of like, you
know, seeding it and we're left with these
actresses? I was hoping for more. She might
be a standout. Maybe that's why she was cast.
There were auditions. She has to be. Yeah, I
mean, there's fierce competition for all of
these roles. Yeah, now I'm wondering if the
reason why they did the race spending for the
Black Canary character was because they didn't
want two statuesque blondes on the team, and
they wanted to diversify the look a little bit
more, which I'm all for. But yeah, you're right
regarding the actresses themselves, because
Harley Quinn shouldn't probably stay a permanent
member of the Birds of Prey team. So if they
decide to carry this on forward as a franchise,
You have to cast an additional character on
the team to take the place of Harley Quinn.
Yeah, who is another strong leading actress.
Maybe like maybe it's Oracle. That's my assumption.
Absolutely. Now I'm not so sure where this franchise
is going. Harley Quinn may be a part of it
for however many sequels they have for this,
if it's a success, which kind of bothers me
because I really wanted her to become a part
of Gotham City Sirens. Right. And she's part
of Suicide Squad 2. Exactly. She can't be in
everything. Yeah, she can't be a part of the
villain's team and also be part of this group
of heroines. Ideally not. It's contradictory.
They set her up as such a villain in Suicide
Squad. Yeah, I mean, a compelling one who definitely
could have a redemptive arc, but she can't stay
there. Right, that's not the nature of the
character. Not at all, not at all. But this
all brings us to our question of the week.
Who would you have cast as Huntress and Black
Canary? Post your answers to our Instagram,
Twitter, Facebook, or email us at dyna We'll
pick our favorite answer and draw that person
at dynamicduelnoprize that we'll post to social
media. Yeah, we're looking for really interesting
fan castings here, it's a lot of fun to think
about. Let's move on to the second trailer
we got for The Titans Show. Yeah, what's really
interesting about it was that it was a Netflix
trailer. And Netflix was saying, it was like,
it's an original show only for Netflix. I was
like, what are you talking about? No, it's not.
I mean, I understand that this trailer was
probably meant for international audiences,
because in America, this won't be on Netflix.
That we know of. I mean, we don't know that
yet, do we? Yeah, we do know that. It's only
been secured for international distribution.
Oh. Right. I was assuming that after it ran
its course on the DC Universe streaming app,
that it was gonna make its way to Netflix for
everybody else to see it. No, it's only gonna
be international. Interesting. Because DC Universe
is not, apparently not going to be, an international
product. Okay, gotcha. So they still want to
release this series to international audiences
and the way they're going to be able to do
that is through Netflix. Gotcha, gotcha. But
it's not a Netflix original, once again. Yeah,
it was a story trailer. Like the first trailer
that we got was much more of like a teaser,
kind of giving the vibe of the overall show.
But this one delved a lot deeper into the story
that we're going to get. Yeah, absolutely. It
starts at a police station when they're examining
Robin like on these screens. I guess it's first
appearance in Detroit. Which I'm surprised
they chose the city of Detroit because as far
as I know, the Titans have never been based
in Detroit. The Titans tower was in Manhattan,
like an island off Manhattan, I believe. Uh
huh. So or at least Bloodhaven, you would think.
Yeah, it was surprising. But, you know, we
get better looks at like Dick Grayson's arc
as to like why he left Batman and things like
that. And also Ravens. Those two seem to be
like the biggest parts of the show. Biggest
characters. Definitely. We also got better looks
at Beast Boy's powers in action and Starfires.
Yeah, apparently Beast Boy has to get naked
to use his powers, which was revealed a little
bit more in a clip that they released as part
of a series of four clips earlier before they
dropped this trailer. But, uh, that, that bothers
me to some extent for sure. Um, how does he
do it in the, in the comics? Like, don't, don't
worry about it. He doesn't wear clothes when
he becomes an animal. And when he comes out
of animal form, he has clothes again. How does
that work? Don't worry about it. It just happens.
All right. But no, we see some very like Rosemary's
baby scenario that's played out around Raven
and her mom and like this like cult that's
coming after her. This whole thing essentially
seems to be the rest of the Titans coming together
to help Raven. Like even Starfire says, I've
been looking for you. You know, I'm here to
protect you in the trailer. Yeah. So our first
time hearing Starfire speak, she definitely
doesn't come across as this naive kind of alien.
She's coming across as Hardened protector kind
of figure. Mm-hmm. I don't know. I'm not sure
quite what to make of her yet in the role Mm-hmm,
but everyone else seems to be pretty decent
except for I forget the actress's name who
plays Raven I'm still not sold on her. Yeah,
she delivers a few of those lines pretty awkwardly
I think it seems so much like younger than everyone
else and I know the actress is so that's probably
why yeah Maybe they like try to set up some
kind of like romantic flirtation between her
and Beast Boy in this trailer and I couldn't
understand what they were saying. It was a
little cringe-worthy. I was like, what are you
guys doing? You like each other's hair? Okay,
all right, cool. We did see that Beast Boy's
skin only turns green when he's about to transform,
which kind of sucks. That's a budget thing.
It is absolutely a budget thing. And it seems
like the only thing he could turn into is a
tiger. That's the only thing we see him transform
into in this trailer. Who is the cult of people
that are going after Raven? I assume it's some
kind of like Trigon worshipping cult. Like Brother
Blood's cult. It's probably exactly what it
is, which is kind of cool that we get to see
Brother Blood as an antagonist and definitely,
you know, hearkens back to the comics. But I'm
not 100% certain. All in all, that's pretty
much it for the trailer. I think it got me a
little bit more excited for the show. I mean,
it debuts pretty soon here at New York Comic-Con.
So we're definitely gonna get our first impressions
of it. It was definitely a better trailer than
the first one that we got. I agree. There was
no fuck Batman in it. So already a plus. It
should have been the first one that they released.
in all honesty, but perhaps they didn't have
the effects done in time or whatever. I agree.
Yeah. Speaking of television shows going direct
to streaming services starring a group of teenagers,
we got the trailer for the second season of
Runaways. Now if you've been listening to this
podcast for a while, you'll know that I was
not a fan at all of Runaways season one. I
think they botched the concept of the comic
book series in itself and the fact that in
the show they weren't even really Runaways until
the very last episode. It was more of just
a high school teen drama with some elements
from the comics. However, in the second season,
judging from the looks of this trailer, it looks
to be much better. There's a whole lot more
action going on. They're actually using their
powers. They're actually runaways this time.
They're actually fighting their parents. It
was kind of like a cool showcase overall to
see, like, what each character could do. Right.
And it looks like for the second season, they're
releasing all the episodes at once. So while
I'm not. Still too terribly excited for the
show because the first season left such a bad
taste in my mouth. You know, I'll watch the
second season and if it's good, we will be reviewing
it on this podcast early in January sometime
or maybe later in January since there's so much
kind of bottlenecks toward the end of this
year. Wait, when is this released? This is being
released in December, December 21st actually.
Okay, okay. The same day that Aquaman comes
to theaters. Okay, of course. I should have
known. Why did I even have to ask? Damn it.
So yeah, we'll be getting our Marvel superhero
action two times that day with both the untitled
Deadpool movie and the runaways so dumb So
dumb I should have known I got excited when
Daredevil was Magically not gonna be released
on the same day as the DC film, but now this
a fucking course. Yep But no, I have to say
that the special effects for the second season
look pretty fantastic Yeah, they look better
than the titan show That's for sure. It does.
It looks like it has a movie special effects
budget, especially with old lace He looks a
lot better in this trailer than he did in season
one I think yeah, and we see Chase use the fistagons
and we see Carolina with her powers That looks
that always looked amazing actually that looked
pretty good in season one, too But everything
just looks better I guess is what I'm trying
to say if you haven't seen the Marvel Runaway
season 2 trailer yet Go ahead and check it out
on YouTube. I'm gonna say If you were a fan
of the Runaways comics and haven't seen Runaway
season one yet, don't even bother. Like maybe
check out the first episode and then we'll all
watch season two together and see what that's
like. Okay, I was gonna ask you, like if we
are gonna review this on the show, am I gonna
have to watch the entirety of season one? I
would recommend that you don't do that because
you'll be bored out of your fucking mind. Because
if you were gonna say yes, I was gonna be like,
uh, hell no. I would recommend seeing the first
episode actually because that's that was pretty
much Runaway's issue number one right there
Oh really and then from here just assume that
they run away and are dealing with the stuff
that they are now in season two Okay, I can
do that. Yeah, so yeah, that's pretty much all
I have to say about that trailer and with all
the news out of the way Let's go ahead and get
into our duel where we pick clay face versus
venom and see who would actually win in a fight
Let's do it
Alright, Clayface versus Venom. Why did we pit
these two characters against each other? Well,
because the Venom movie was coming out and you
asked me who would be a good match against
Venom. And I've always wanted to see Clayface.
A lot of people pit Bane against Venom. To
me, that's not even a match. And a lot of people
pit Sandman against Clayface, which I think
is almost too equal of a match. I mean, I feel
like that would result in a 50-50 split. So
I feel like this Venom versus Clayface fight
has enough variables in it. to actually be
a toss-up, but in a good way. Like I have no
idea who's actually gonna win this. Right,
yeah, I have no idea either. And I also think
that there's some similarities between Clayface
and Venom that you'll hear in the profile for
Clayface. They'll be like, oh yeah, this is
a good match. They both have freaky faces, they
both have like fluidic bodies. They can both
shape shift, you know. There's a lot of similarities
in the powers, but also enough differences
to make this just interesting enough, I think.
Yeah, yeah. Plus I think it's a great kickoff
to the Halloween month. They're both villains.
This is sort of our villain episode of the
year. Typically, we reserve that for our Halloween
episode, but it's coming a little bit early.
Yeah, because, well, we'll be reviewing Daredevil
season two around that time just before Halloween.
So, yeah. Yeah. So if you haven't listened to
one of our dual episodes before, the way we
determine the winner is we take each character
stats and we run them through a thousand simulations
using a probabilistic model known as the Monte
Carlo method, which is used practically in
a lot of different ways, such as through artificial
intelligence and risk assessment and stuff
like that. Basically what it does is it randomizes
their stats along a bell curve in a standard
deviation. It compares the numbers and the one
with the higher numbers over a thousand times
basically is the winner. Right. Yeah, we get
a percentage of wins. So it's math. There's
no bias. There's no fan votes. We don't take
into account uncharacteristic feats of strength.
It's just base stats based off of the Marvel
power rankings, which are official. And we
extrapolate the DC stats from that same criteria.
Right. And sometimes we also throw in additional
stats. depending on the match, if we think those
attributes are vital to the fight or not. Right.
But before we get into the simulations and the
stats and everything like that, we like to
go into the histories of each character and
then after that speculate on how we think a
battle scenario between the two characters would
actually pan out. So let's go ahead and start
with the history of Clayface because I'm interested
in hearing about this because I don't know
too much about the character and he's always
been one of I think Batman's more formidable
villains and because he actually has powers,
you know? Yeah, yeah. He's definitely an iconic
villain. I remember seeing him for the first
time in the comic and just really liking that
villain. He's a really, really interesting villain.
But Clayface is actually the name of Batman
super villains used by about 10 different characters
in DC Comics. What? Yeah. I thought it was
the actor guy from the animated series. Yeah,
except that they used the name of a different
Clayface for that character, the actor character
that is Clayface. I'm not sure why. Okay, interesting.
Yeah. So the original Clayface was a Golden
Age character named Basil Carlo, created by
Bob Kane in 1940. Carlo was an actor known for
playing a disfigured villain named Clayface
in a popular horror film called Dread Castle.
It's kind of like Boris Karloff who played,
you know, the mummy in Frankenstein. Yeah, it
was partially inspired by him. Okay, but in
the film he wore a grotesque mask for the role
and when he found out that the film was being
remade without him, He was driven mad and donning
the clay face mask went on a murder spree.
Wow. He killed several actors of the new film's
cast until he was stopped by Batman and Robin
and imprisoned in Arkham Asylum. Decades later,
a treasure hunter named Matt Hagen discovered
an underground cavern that contained a glowing
rainbow colored protoplasm. That was actually
the name of the character in the animated series.
Right. So having accidentally fallen into the
pool of the protoplasm, Hagen emerged with a
malleable clay-like body and, with effort,
became capable of shaping his body into any
person or object he could visualize. The effect
lasted for only about 48 hours, at which point
he would regain his normal form until he once
again submerged himself in the protoplasm. Hagen,
the new clay face, went on several robberies
before he was captured by Batman, who had discovered
Hagen's underground cavern and destroyed it.
Hagen broke out of prison and using a small
supply of the protoplasm he had stored before
the cavern was destroyed, he was able to synthesize
a lesser version of the protoplasm that gave
him transformative abilities for five hours.
This synthetic version, however, took a toll
on his body and he eventually had trouble holding
any shape, forcing him to retire. Oh wow. A
start-up scientist named Preston Payne took
an interest in Hagen as he was seeking a cure
for his own chronic hyper-pituitaryism, which
results in physical deformities. After injecting
himself with an enzyme from Hagen's blood, Payne
gained the brief ability to transform his appearance,
though it wasn't long before he began losing
control over his form and found that his physical
touch caused others to melt into a blob, a new
ability for this new clay face. Payne developed
an exoskeleton containment suit to hold his
form. but realized that he needed to touch
and liquefy others in order to somehow transfer
his own physical suffering of slowly melting.
His guilt drove him insane, and he hid in a
wax museum where he conversed and fell in love
with wax figures before he was found by Batman
and treated at Arkham Asylum. Hmm, wow. Now
a woman named Sandra Fuller became the new Clayface
after a terrorist cult led by the villain Cobra.
researched and recreated events that created
some of Batman's most dangerous rogues. Fuller,
who had hated her own face, agreed to undergo
the Clayface procedure, and subsequently gained
the ability to transform her shape without the
danger of losing control over her form, nor
the time limit that the now-deceased Matt Hagen
suffered from. The original Clayface, the Golden
Age actor Boris Carlo, was not dead, however,
and Fuller visited him out of curiosity as
he languished in a prison hospital. Concocting
a plan to get revenge on Batman, Carlo recommended
to Fuller that she and Pain join forces to defeat
Batman. Fuller broke Pain out of Arkham, and
Carlo injected himself with the blood of both
clayfaces to become the ultimate clayface,
with all of their abilities and strengths. The
three clayfaces, calling themselves the Mud
Pack, took on Batman. and his team of outsiders,
only to fall when Karlo's powers were overloaded
and he became merged with the ground beneath
him. Payne and Fuller on the other hand fled
the fight, fell in love while they were on the
run, and had a child named Cassius Clay Payne,
who would later grow into a fifth version of
the Clayface character. Wait, Cassius Clay,
why does that sound familiar? It's Muhammad
Ali's real name. Right. Yeah, that's interesting.
It was a play on words. Huh. when a cataclysmic
earthquake struck Gotham City, turning it into
a no-man's land. He emerged now with strong,
sharp quartz crystals growing out of him, and
would have defeated Batman too if it hadn't
been for Mr. Freeze claiming the right to killing
the Dark Knight and interfering. Karlo eventually
teamed up with Poison Ivy to help feed the
remaining people of Gotham during No Man's Land,
but he was sunk into the ground once again
after he tried to double cross Ivy. Karlo later
emerged as a Wonder Woman foe, after he deduced
that he could absorb some of her power since,
at the time, her origin involved her being
fashioned by the Amazons from clay. You can
learn more about Wonder Woman in our Wonder
Woman vs. Thor episode. Karlo's plan worked.
Actually, he became much stronger, and Wonder
Woman was de-aged to a teenager for a time.
Karlo was returned to a standard clay-faced
self when he was tricked into a train car with
Wonder Woman. and her sidekick Donna Troy used
the Lasso of Truth to spin the car like a centrifuge,
causing Wonder Woman's Clay to separate from
his own. Weird. After unsuccessful stints as
a member of the Injustice League and Secret
Society of Supervillains, Karlo felt defeated
and disillusioned with the villain lifestyle.
Seeking to reform, Clayface became a valuable
ally in Batman's Gotham Knights team during
the post-New 52 slash Rebirth era. of DC Comics,
up until his eventual death at the hands of
Batwoman to prevent him from going off on a
rampage. So as mentioned earlier, Karlo is
the ultimate Clayface. He can control his shape,
size, and density and alter his form to mimic
anyone else, right down to their DNA. He's super
strong and durable and has a corrosive touch
that can liquefy and absorb others if he chooses.
to create sentient sections of himself that
can bond with other humans, turning them into
clay things with shape-shifting abilities. Like
zombies? I was thinking more like symbiotes.
Oh, okay. Well, Venom doesn't really do that.
No, well, my clay face in this match won't,
because I'm going with the, probably the most
popular clay face, which is Basilcarlo. Okay.
Cool, all right. Well, his power set is actually
not too similar to Venom's. except for the
fact that they could both shape shift. But yeah,
that was a fairly interesting backstory. A
lot of stuff in there that I had no idea and
each Clayface character seemed pretty unique
and interesting on their own. Yeah, yeah. And
yeah, they're all kind of tied together. Right.
So yeah, let's go ahead and get into Venom.
So Venom's a cool badass character, first and
foremost, I think because of his appearance.
My exec and Todd McFarland did a great job
with Venom's design. His monstrous shark-like
grin with rows of sharp teeth are the stuff
of nightmares. and his null holds barred violent
approach to attacking his enemies, be he a
villain or an anti-hero, is a unique alternative
to the more morally grounded superhero fare.
Venom is not bound by any sort of societal principles.
He will literally tear your head off and eat
your brain, all in the name of protecting the
innocent. And who else does that? I think he
fulfills a particular sci-fi horror niche, the
Xenomorph of the Marvel Universe. Oh yeah.
And like the Xenomorphs of the Alien movie franchise,
Venom's backstory began on an alien world hatched
from an egg discovered by scientists. These
particular scientists were Kree aliens who
studied the hatchlings called Klintar, the alien
race that Venom is a part of. Klintar are symbiotic,
fluidic beings that need to attach to other
lifeforms for survival, and in exchange grant
their host immense power. As a species, they
were created in the universe's infancy by a
primordial deity named Null, as a biological
weapon against celestials and their creations,
a way to dominate all other life forms. Kind
of like Galactus. I would say that Gnall and
Galactus are allies in that regard. Through
the millennia, the Klintar species rebelled
from their creator's goal in an effort to lead
a more peaceful existence, though individual
symbiotes can easily become corrupted if their
host is malevolent and full of hate. To that
end, the symbiotes try and bond with hosts that
are pure of heart. In instances in which members
of the race are corrupted, Those Klyntar are
exiled and cut off from the Hivemind. And just
a heads up for the purpose of this backstory,
when I say Venom I'm referring to the symbiote
itself and not just his merger with Eddie Brock
because in the comics he wasn't referred to
as Venom until that joining. So yeah, Venom
is the symbiote in this story. The Kree used
the symbiotes they found to empower their deep
cover spies during the Kree-Skrull War. Venom
was attached to and trained with a soldier named
Telkar, but lost his first host, when Telkar's
ship crash-landed on an icy planet. Venom then
bonded with an alien warrior who used the symbiote
to commit genocide on his ice planet, exposing
Venom to hate and rage, corrupting him. After
leaving that host, he managed to unite with
some of his Klyntar brethren, though they unfortunately
were also corrupted. Venom, despite all his
rage and suffering, was different from his
corrupted siblings in that he desired to bond
with and protect his hosts instead of dominating
and eventually draining them. Venom's siblings
rebuked him for this and confined his formless
body in a machine-like prison, a contraption
that was later incorporated into Battleworld.
Battleworld was an arena-like planet composed
of hundreds of other planets by an all-powerful
being called the Beyonder, who pit Marvel heroes
in a secret war against villains to see who
would win in a fight of good versus evil. While
on Battleworld, Spider-Man came across Venom's
prison, thinking the device would upgrade his
damaged costume. Venom was released and bonded
with Spider-Man who was unaware of the symbiote's
existence or nature, but did discover that
his new black costume made him much more powerful.
After the events of Secret Wars, Venom was
brought to Earth attached to Spider-Man whom
he found to be the perfect host as he was pure
of heart. In fact, the symbiote relished in
this new bonding and would often control Peter
Parker's body to fight crime while Peter was
sleeping. After time, however, Peter grew wary
of his new costume's abilities and seeming aggressive
autonomy. and had it examined by Reed Richards
of the Fantastic Four, which revealed Venom's
true nature as a sentient alien symbiote who
wished to permanently bond with Spider-Man.
Shocked by this revelation, Peter rejected
the symbiote and had it imprisoned in one of
Reed's containment modules. Venom escaped,
dejected, and angry, and tried to reunite with
Peter by disguising itself as one of his red
and blue suits and forcing itself onto him.
Geez. Peter swung to a nearby church whose
large bells rang to sound the hour. The Venom,
being a corrupted symbiote, was defective against
powerful sonic waves and fire, and the bell's
reverberations weakened Venom into removing
itself from Peter. The symbiote dragged itself
to the church's lower levels where it bonded
itself onto Eddie Brock, a ruined investigative
journalist who had recently been discredited
by Spider-Man. Eddie was also suffering from
terminal cancer and had just been divorced
from his wife after the loss of his job. The
two's resentment of Spider-Man transformed
them into the ultimate villain. with Eddie's
hatred at the time further corrupting Venom,
who was intent on either killing or reclaiming
Peter. They fought several times, resulting
in Eddie being incarcerated and separated from
Venom. The symbiote rescued Eddie from prison
and inadvertently left behind an asexually produced
offspring that bonded with an imprisoned psychotic
named Cletus Cassidy, who was serving 11 life
sentences for murder. The bonded pair became
known as Carnage, who was extremely corrupted
and went on a months long killing spree across
New York. Venom and Spider-Man had to join forces
temporarily to defeat him using Madison Square
Garden's PA system, as Carnage was also vulnerable
to heavy sonic waves. Venom and Spider-Man
formed an uneasy truce as Venom left for Eddie's
hometown of San Francisco. There, Eddie tried
to steer Venom's urges for violence toward fighting
criminals and protecting a homeless society
living underground. Through this vigilantism,
Eddie also sought to feed the symbiotes' hunger
for adrenaline and hormones, such as phenethylamine.
which is found in the human brain. Occasionally
Venom would commit acts of cannibalism for nutrients,
which horrified Eddie. Venom was later captured
and separated from Eddie by the Life Foundation,
an organization bent on ending life on Earth,
except for those who could afford to save themselves
through the Foundation's fallout shelter. They
experimented on the symbiote and forced it to
produce five offspring, Riot, Lasher, Phage,
Agony, and Scream, all of which were bonded
to the Life Foundation's mercenaries. Eddie
was able to re-bond with Venom and defeat the
new symbiotes with help from Spider-Man. After
a long time protecting the innocent and feeding
the symbiote, Eddie grew too weak to continue
as the host of Venom, and the alien sought out
a new one. For a while, it attached itself
to Mac Gargan, aka the Spider-Man villain known
as Scorpion. Gargan was defeated, however,
and the symbiote was removed and contained by
the US military. They studied it in a new super-soldier
program and granted it to Peter Parker's old
classmate, Colonel Flash Thompson. The bonded
pair became known as Agent Venom, though the
symbiote was chemically lobotomized most of
the time in an effort for the government to
control it. Flash and Venom went into space
as a new member of the Guardians of the Galaxy.
While out in the cosmos, the no longer lobotomized
Venom journeyed back to his home planet of Klintar
where he was able to rejoin the hive mind and
cleanse himself of his corruption. The symbiote
has since returned to Earth, was separated
from Flash by the US military, and found its
way back to Eddie Brock. who again uses it
as a vigilante hero. But it's not corrupted
anymore. Correct. So would you say he's still
a Spider-Man villain? No, more often than not,
recently he's teamed up with Spider-Man than
fought against him. Usually it's other symbiotes
that they're fighting against now, nowadays.
Like Carnage? Right, or Venom's clone, or something
like that, you know? So as a Klyntar symbiote,
Venom's powers largely depend on the host he
possesses, though for this fight, he will be
bonded to his longtime host, Eddie Brock. Venom
has a number of innate abilities as well as
the abilities of any superpowered being he bonds
with. Venom's fluidic biomass can extend tentacles
and tendrils, or form into more hardened shapes
such as spikes, blades, and hammers. He can
also shapeshift to render different outer appearances
and even blend into his surroundings like a
chameleon. Since Venom preferred Spider-Man's
power set when he was bonded to him, Venom
has copied that genetic code and carried forward
those powers onto his subsequent hosts like
Eddie. This includes lifting strength. of around
25 tons, which is actually superior to Spider-Man's.
Wall crawling and web shooting, though he doesn't
actually shoot web fluid, it's just thin strands
of his own mass. Venom is incredibly durable,
able to resist gunfire on his own, and resist
even greater impacts when shifting his mass
to thick and vulnerable areas. He's taken blows
from Juggernaut before. Venom physically and
telepathically bonds with Eddie to provide
a 360 degree view for instant danger notifications,
kind of like Spider-Sense. And if Eddie does
get lethally injured, Venom grants an accelerated
healing factor, so powerful that it actually
staved off Eddie's cancer for a long time. And
that's him. Wait, so Venom can change color?
Yes, he can, yeah. I didn't know that. Why didn't
I, I feel like I should've known that. I guess
he did in the cartoon. Yeah, he's able to change
his outward appearance for like different clothing
looks, and everything like that. He can almost
turn invisible, practically. Well, Clayface
can change color as well, and like, you know,
turn his arms into weapons and all kinds of
stuff. But can he turn invisible, like Venom?
Invisible ish. Yeah, you could just turn it
into the ground and then and then what are you
gonna do? Okay, damn it, but just to recap
Venom's Weaknesses are fire and sonic waves,
right? But he actually expunged those weaknesses
when he was cleansed by the Clintar because
the pure Symbiotes don't have those weaknesses
Okay. Yeah, and Clayface's weakness really is
being frozen. Really? Yeah, okay. I don't think
any of those things will come into play in this
speculation. I don't think so. I mean, I don't
know. We'll see how it goes. Okay. Yeah. I'm
not saying Venom can freeze somebody, but I'm
not entirely sure that Clayface can't produce
fire through like Flint or produce a large,
you know, sound reverberations or something
like that. Oh, I didn't think about that. Hmm.
I think the biggest disadvantage that Venom
has going into this is that he actually has
a host body. Right. Whereas Clayface. If you
put a stake through him, there's nothing there.
Yeah, he can't be impaled, Clayface, because
his entire body is clay. So he could go essentially
intangible, whereas Venom can't. However, Venom
has some tricks up his sleeve that I think
Clayface does not. Okay. All right, so let's
get into this. So the rules that we set up
for this speculative scenario are that the characters
start about 50 yards apart from each other.
They don't know anything about each other than
that the other are threats and they need to
be taken down. And the final rule that we set
up is that they fight in a non-environment
location or a location in which the environment
does not play any factor into the battle itself.
Right, because we don't take stats for the environment.
We don't take that into account because it's
too variable and different characters can win
in certain environments and not in others.
Right, this fight were taking place in the Arctic
Tundra or whatever Venom would easily win.
Right, because it's too cold for Clayface. Exactly.
So we just cancel that out as a factor completely
and just say, No environment for the fight.
All right, so let's go ahead and get this started.
They start off 50 yards apart, who goes first?
Well, actually, I think I'm gonna start this
one off. I think Vanim's gonna go first just
because he has this kind of wild, bloodthirsty
nature to him, although it's not quite as bloodthirsty
anymore, but he's very aggressive. So he's
gonna start charging Starling with his tongue
whipping about toward a clay face in an effort
to just pounce on him. Okay. Which he does.
Venom pounces on Clayface? Yes. Well that was
a huge mistake. Okay, so Clayface just like
envelops Venom and just like constructs his
body into like a hard spherical kind of like
shell that just contains him. He's gonna suffocate
him. Well, okay, so Clayface's body, he's made
of individual particles, right? Because the
symbiote suit can actually filter oxygen to
its host in unbreathable environments such
as space and underwater. So- How, what? So it
basically pulls whatever oxygen is available
between the grains of sand that clay face is
made out of and filters it to Eddie Brock Okay,
at least for a duration long enough for venom
to be able to escape which he does so by just
punching outward He's super strong. He's you
know, he can lift 25 tons. I think he's stronger
than clay face Oh, he starts breaking him apart
basically. Clay face is pretty strong and he's
also pretty durable, but he could only get as
durable as you know, like brick which I know
venom is strong enough to punch through So yeah,
it doesn't surprise me that he breaks out of
this. Yeah, so yeah, he's punching out, he cracks
this sphere that Clayface created and just
basically leaps out. And at that point, Clayface
starts deforming from this sphere into like
this pile of goo and Venom coats the goo pile
with his symbiotic webbing. Like tendrils?
It's fibers, basically, fibers of the symbiote
mass that ensnare it, like a really strong
net. Okay, well, I mean, that doesn't really
do anything because he can't like... wrap up
the bottom of Clayface, because that's already
touching the floor. So Clayface could like
expand his size. So basically he just like grows
and just like tosses it to the side. Clayface
can also squeeze through the holes and the netting.
Yeah, he could absolutely do that as well.
Yeah. And that's when Clayface creates like
a huge like hammer fist and just swings his
like really rubber-like arm just towards Venom
and just knocks his hammer right into the side
of him. Real hard. So right before the hammer
hits Venom, Venom shifts his biomass. over
to the side and creates kind of like a shield
to protect himself from the hammer. So it just
primarily hits that thick biomass shield and
doesn't really hurt Venom too much. It probably
sends him flying because of the impact, but
it doesn't hurt him because the impact is mostly
absorbed. So at that point Venom creates a huge
scythe with his arm and he slices Clayface's
hammer arm in half. So Clayface doesn't have
the hammer arm anymore. So yeah, that puddle
of clay just falls to the ground. quickly moves
to the rest of his body. So he's whole again.
And as the pile of clay that was the hammer
is going back to the main body of Clayface,
Venom creates his own hammer fist and takes
it right towards Clayface's face and smashes
it in. Okay, so Clayface's face gets smashed
in, but like his face just like wraps around
the hammer. And then Clayface just like rolls
up Venom's arm like a sleeve thing, and then
travels right up there. It gets right up close
to him. And then like creates like a sharp
blade out of his hand and just drives it right
into venom. Oh shit Okay, so venom screams
out in agony and he breaks this spike that clay
face created to impale him and leaps backward
And he pulls the spike out of him and venom
is able to actually heal Eddie Brock with his
healing factor But Clay face knows that there's
a human core to him now So he's gonna be going
for that for that human core. So he's gonna
be going with the bladed stuff now. Yeah Well
Venom could play that game too, he shoots out
these little tiny barbed projectiles that like
stick into Clayface and actually do jack shit.
That's when Clayface just like absorbs them,
then he fires them right back out at Venom.
Actually Venom could do the same thing. Like
there have been moments where like he's been
shot at with bullets, and he like absorbs the
bullets through his flesh, and then like spits
them back out at the guy that shot at him.
Clayface has done like that exact same thing
as well. Really? Yeah. Well, so okay so...
Clayface shoots these symbiotic barbs back at
Venom and Venom just stands there and the barbs
reabsorb back into his body. Okay so Clayface's
goal is to get to Eddie Brock and touch him
with his corrosive touch. Okay. So basically
that's what he's gonna try and do. He's gonna
turn his hand to a sharp object again, just
a point, and just drive it once again into
Venom. But once he reaches Eddie Brock, he touches
him and it corrodes him. Except as Clayface
is reaching for Venom, Venom uses his super
agility to... evade being touched by the spike
and what he does is he creates these two huge
axe blades with his hands and He closes the
distance to clay face and he swipes across Cutting
clay face into three separate parts that fall
to the ground Okay, and as clay face his body
is reforming That's when venom takes the opportunity
to detach itself from Eddie Brock and assimilate
clay face as a venom clay face What yes, I
don't think you could do that. Yeah, he can
do that How is Clayface a sentient life form?
Yeah. Well then he can be assimilated by the
symbiote. Holy shit. So Venom assimilates Clayface
and he's able to telepathically connect to Clayface's
brain and tries to shut him down. Okay. I think
Clayface, he's powerful enough and maneuverable
enough. I mean he himself is a liquid form.
It's like trying to mix like oil and water.
So I think he could escape the symbiote. Like,
what is it gonna fuse to? His spine? What does
it fuse to? There's nothing to fuse to. Like,
Clayface doesn't have a brain? Is that what
you're saying? It's- He has a brain, but it's-
it's malleable. Gotcha. Well, I don't know!
Okay, here's what happens. Okay. As Venom was
trying to assimilate Clayface, Clayface realized
what this thing is, that it's like a parasite,
and learns all of its weaknesses. But then he
escapes! Because Venom can't assimilate Clayface's
form. Okay. So now he knows that he's weak to
sound. But I already told you that he's not
that weak. If anything, he's more weak to fire
than he is sound over the years. Okay, so as
the Venom symbiote was making its way back to
the helpless Eddie, Clayface turns his fists
into flint rocks and he bangs them together
and starts creating sparks. And then creates
an eventual- The sparks aren't gonna set anything
on fire if there's no Tinder. You're just creating
sparks, right? He sets Eddie's hair on fire.
I don't know. So Eddie Brock is running around
screaming because his hair's on fire. He stops
to drop some rolls, puts the fire out, and
then he's Venom again. This is almost a more
impossible fight than I could have imagined
just because I completely forgot that Clayface
is intangible and that he doesn't have a human
body within all the clay. And he's like completely
intangible, like you can't just move through
a wall. Right. But like, he is like, things
can move through him. Exactly, exactly. Gotcha.
Well, do you want to take this to the stats?
Yes, I'm very curious. Alright, let's see who
officially wins this fight between Clayface
and Menom.
And we're back. Not too many surprises here,
we found as we were combing through the stats
and extrapolating Clayface's stats. Yeah, I
guess the largest surprise for me personally
was just how durable and evasive Clayface is.
You know, he's nearly indestructible. Right.
Nearly. He does have like the weakness of cold,
you know, but we said there wouldn't play a
huge factor within this fight. No, and in terms
of evasiveness, he is basically intangible,
but he's also not difficult to hit because he
knows he's intangible. Because he knows that
most physical attacks aren't gonna even hurt
him. Right. Everything just kind of goes through
him. Right. So he's elastic, but he's intangible,
but he's also extremely dense. So he has a
lot going for him. When he wants to be, yeah.
Yeah, he has a lot going for him defensively.
Exactly. And offensively, too. He has a lot
of damage potential. Attacks from him are basically
like getting a boulder dropped on you. Right.
What he's lacking in, compared to Venom, at
least, is fighting skill and strength. And strength.
Yeah, Venom's stronger than Clayface. Not much
stronger. Yeah, there's not a huge gap there,
but there were only just a few disparities
between these two characters. For the most part,
I think it was a pretty good match because,
yeah, a lot of this was similar. Yeah. Because
they're both defensive powerhouses with strong
offensive capabilities. Yeah, for sure. And
they're just so malleable that it's just impossible
to come up with a scenario. So we're gonna let
the stats determine the winner for us. So the
winner between Clayface and Venom is... Venom.
Ugh. Out of a thousand matches, Venom won 594%
of them. So you know, it was fairly close. That's
close. I thought it would be closer. Oh, you
did? I thought it would actually be further
apart. Really? Yeah. It's essentially like
60%. Yeah, pretty close to that. Clayface only
won 40.6 of the matches. So 406 out of a thousand.
Ugh. So good match, good match. You know, yeah.
I'm happy with the results of this one. It's
been a while, I feel like, since. I've won one,
so. So put this on the scorecard for Marvel.
Congrats to Venom, I guess. I mean, he has his
new film coming out. Wonder when they're gonna
make the Clayface film. They're never gonna
make a Clayface film. You know why? Because
they're not greedy. That's why. You know why?
Because Clayface sucks. Nope. Just like the
rest of DC. What? The only Batman villain that
could get their own movie is Joker. What makes
me think Spider-Man's gonna get any more villain
movies? Oh, I don't know, actually. This might
probably be the only villain movie that's made
of my hands. Oh wait, I guess they are making
a Kraven movie, never mind. Well, no, there's
a Morpheus movie in the works too. So there
you go. Although I guess there is a Gotham City
Sirens movie in the works or is that canceled?
I don't know. Who knows? Who knows anymore?
So that does it for this episode. Congrats
to Venom for kicking the utter shit out of Clayface.
And jokes on you, Clayface doesn't shit. Let
us know what you guys thought about this match
by writing into us on Facebook or Instagram
or Twitter or email. You can find links to contact
us via all those means by visiting dynamic
duel dot com. a site in which you can also find
a link to our merch store. Yeah, at our merch
store, we have a bunch of different T-shirts
and mugs and pillows and stuff like that, which
are decorated with artwork that we've drawn
up for our no prizes in the past. And also,
don't forget, you can get bonus content for
this podcast by visiting Patreon.com dynamic
duel. Again, this Thursday, we will be releasing
the first sneak peek at the secret project
that Jonathan and I have been working on for
the past month. And please don't forget to
rate, review, share and subscribe our podcast
on whatever platform you happen to be listening
to us on, especially if you're listening to
us on iTunes, because we have a goal right
now to reach 200 ratings. Right. And last week,
we didn't get any new ratings. So please step
up, guys. If you're listening to us on your
Apple podcast app, please rate us. And not
only you, please ask to borrow any other person's
iPhone that you know and ask to open their
podcast app and give us the rating as well.
Yeah, if we could get to 200, we get to be
official Brown Tomatoes critics, and our reviews
and film ratings get to count for the aggregate
score, and that would be awesome. Yeah, that
would be super awesome. So in our next episode,
we will be reviewing the Venom film. Super looking
forward to it. It's a huge question mark in
my mind. I have no idea if it's gonna be good
or bad. I haven't read any of the reviews.
It could go either way. I'm excited to see which
way it falls, good or bad. I guess I'm excited.
I don't know. I haven't really seen too much
marketing for it, honestly. Yeah, not too much
in the past few weeks, but looking forward to
it. Looking forward to talking to you guys
again next week. And until then, up, up and
away, true believers.