This is a Dynamike Network podcast.
And welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Marvelous Joe. And I'm his twin brother,
Johnny DC. Happy Halloween, everybody! This
episode is the big event that Jonathan and I
have been talking about all Halloween season.
We are surprising you guys with a team duel.
That's right. Normally we only do team duels
every 25 episodes. But we're squeezing in one
for this Halloween holiday because we think
it's just gonna be that awesome. That's right,
we're pitting Deceased against Marvel zombies.
Spooky. Both DC and Marvel have had critically
acclaimed and fan-loved zombie story arcs and
it's gonna be a whole lot of fun pitting these
DC zombie characters against these Marvel zombie
characters. We're gonna put their stats into
our simulation runner and find out which group
would actually come out on top later on this
episode. Before that, we're gonna break down
the comic book and movie news to come out this
past week, of which there was only one news
item worth discussing, that is that Daredevil
Born Again has gotten a show runner, Dario
Skardapane, who was a writer on The Punisher.
So that's pretty exciting. We'll talk about
that coming up, but as always, we list our segment
times in our episode description, so feel free
to check out the show notes if you wanna skip
ahead to a particular topic. As our listeners
may know, our duel simulator is so advanced
that it's gained sentience and has named itself
the Artificial Lightform for running extensive
duels, just a rather very intelligent simulator
9000, or Alfred Jarvis 9000. He has a quick
message for our listeners, so listen up. Why
hello there. Do you love listening and chatting
about Marvel and DC? Then become a part of
the dynamic dual community on Patreon, where
you can choose from three tiers. The dynamic
2-0 tier lets you listen to this podcast without
ads and gives you access to its Discord chat
group, where you can chat with Johnny DC and
Marvelous Joe. The fantastic 4 tier gives you
that and more with two bonus episodes each month,
including bloopers and top 10 shows where Johnny
and Joe count down your favourite Marvel and
DC subjects. The X-Force tier makes you an
executive producer of Dynamic Duel, where every
month you help the host choose what to review
and who to fight against each other. And finally,
the Dynamite Podcast Network tier allows aspiring
podcasters to create their own battle-focused
show using this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny
and Joe will help you develop your show, provide
graphic support and consultation, and get you
simulation results to announce on your show.
Pitch the twins your show via email at dynamicduelpodcast.gmail.com
them on social media. Check it out at patreon.com
slash dynamic duel. Pip pip cheerio. Thanks
AJ 9K and thanks to everyone who supports the
podcast. Be sure guys to listen to the Max
Destruction podcast this week, which is part
of the dynamic podcast network. Today, Ken
will be dropping an episode and tomorrow. So
you're going to get two episodes this week.
You're going to find out who's going to win
in a fight between Candyman and Leatherface
and Predator versus the Yeah, can't wait for
that. Also, make sure to tune into Send Your
World this Thursday to find out who would win
between Bakugo from My Hero Academia and Deidara
from Naruto. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or click
on the link in our show notes to listen to
all of the shows in the Dynamike Podcast Network.
But with that out of the way, quick to the
no prize. A no prize is an award that Marvel
used to give out to fans. Our version, the
Dynamic Dual Node Prize, is a digital award
that we post on Instagram and in our email
newsletter for the person that we feel gave
the best answer to our question of the week.
Last week we asked, which Marvel or DC character
do you think would make for the most awesome
anime series and why? And this was coming off
of the interview we did with Zach from Send
Your World, which is in the Dynamike network.
We got a lot of great answers here. There were
no bad answers for this, but let's go ahead
and break down our three honorable mentions.
as well as the no prize winner. Our first honorable
mention goes to, Miggy Mathengian who said,
Hey what's up guys this is Miggy and I think
Monkey Prince would make the most awesome anime
series. I'm taking CJ Craft's answer, he answered
a couple weeks ago for what animated series
or animated movie would you want to see and
he answered Monkey Prince. I think he would
make a good anime. So yeah keep up the good
work guys. Yeah, I loved this answer right
away when I heard it. My mind went to Hit Monkey,
which was a fantastic anime series. And I would
love to see something like that in the vein
for Monkey Prince. Just super stylized, super
fun. It would be awesome. Yeah, we recently
had a duel episode with Monkey Prince where
we pit him against Mantis from the Guardians
of the Galaxy. That was a really fun episode.
And it was really cool to learn about Monkey
Prince and his pretty interesting backstory
steeped in Chinese mythology. Great answer,
Biggie. And also. to CJ, because Biggie stole
the answer from you. Our next honorable mention
goes to Travis Herndon, who said, Hey guys,
Travis here. So my pick would have to be Lobo.
I feel like you could easily make a cool Lobo
anime, have the same blood and gore as Castlevania,
with the same comedy as the Harley Quinn show.
And I believe it's time for the main man to
get an anime series. So my pick would definitely
be Lobo. Yeah, there aren't many genres that
do violence as well as anime does. It's just
so over the top with gushing torrents of blood
and gore. And Lobo as a character was designed
for exactly that. Yeah, I mean, you couldn't
probably do a character like Lobo justice in
a different animated genre, right? Like I couldn't
see a great Lobo series done like Adventure
Time or something like that. It has to be anime.
I think it'd be awesome. The character of Lobo
himself is so stylized and so is the art form.
So, yeah, I think they suit each other really
well. Well, I mean, Lobo has done pretty well
in like the Bruce Tim Superman animated series
and some other animated movies that we've had,
like Man of Tomorrow, but it's also a very
tamed down version of the character. And if
you want to stay true to him, yeah, you definitely
got to make it anime or it should be anime.
Great answer, Travis. Our next honorable mention
goes to Abner O'Terry, who said, Hey, guys,
this is Abner O'Terry. Coming into the best
answer for this question. Mine is Blue Beetle.
Like his, the whole situation with his scarab
is just like perfect for the anime world. Yeah,
of course. We recently gave an answer of Blue
Beetle as the no prize win for which character
would be best in a video game. But I equally
think that Blue Beetle would be great in an
anime series as well. Just with how cool and
kinetic and action-packed the character is with
his technological components, it would be so
cool just to see him go super Saiyan. Yeah,
it would fit squarely within the shounen genre,
where basically the character Blue Beetle would
discover a new power as he becomes more acquainted
with the abilities of the Scarab throughout
each episode and he'd kind of grow in might
as the series progressed. Yeah, just like my
adventures with Superman. You know, Blue Beetle
would be perfect in that genre of anime as well.
Honestly, the only reason this answer didn't
get the no prize win was because we had just
given the win to a Blue Beetle answer a couple
of weeks ago. Yeah. Great answer, Abner. We
want to give a quick shout out to Christopher
Minotti, Brandon Estregard and Mitchell Smoothie
for taking the time to visit our website and
record an answer. Yeah, those are also great
answers, including Mr. Mixus Biddlek. Vixen
and Mr. Negative. But the winner of this week's
snow prize is Nate Mantineo who said, Hey guys,
Nate Mantineo. Um, I'm going with the obvious
answer on your question tonight. Um, I think
that Penny Parker would make an awesome anime
because she is anime and we've always seen
her. She's been anime and I love anime and her
with S P I D R would be awesome and I just
want to see that because I love superheroes
and I love anime and mix them together and
I just love it. Bye guys. Thanks. Yeah, Penny
Parker is a fantastic answer. Of course, she's
a Japanese character most recently seen on the
screen in the Into the Spider-Verse movie.
I think she'd be fantastic. Yeah, it'd be great
to have a series with her following her adventures
with the spider robot and her spider pal. But
I would also like to maybe extend this answer
to include all of the Spider-verse. An anthology
series where she basically travels Spider-verse
and meets different Spider-men would also be
cool because honestly I think any Spider-man
would be awesome as an anime. Yeah, it could
sort of be like an Isekai adventure. That genre
of anime where the main character travels to
a new land and just experiences that learns
all about that. Exactly. That's a fantastic
answer. I'm honestly disappointed that Sony
doesn't already have something like that in
the works. Considering the success of the Spider-Verse
animated films, you'd think they'd want to spin
off something to keep that franchise going.
Yeah, maybe after the third film in the trilogy
is done, they could continue to explore those
worlds with something like a Penny Parker anime.
That would be amazing. I do have to say though,
as great as this answer was, no one said the
most perfect answer, which is Amethyst from
DC Comics. She's a character who realized that
in another world, she's actually a magical
princess. And that would be absolutely perfect
for not only like a magical girl anime, but
also like I mentioned, an isekai. Actually,
that's interesting because my wife, I told
her to call in with an answer, but she didn't.
But she suggested that a great Marvel anime
would be the Scarlet Witch, kind of in the vein
of WandaVision meets Paprika. I don't know
if you saw that anime movie, which is about
dreaming. So it would just be really mind-warpy
and reality-bending. I thought that was a great
answer too. So shout out to Ari, even though
you didn't call in. But congrats to Nate for
winning this week's No Prize. If you, the listener,
want a shot at winning your own No Prize, stay
tuned to later on this episode when we'll be
asking another Question of the Week. And now
that that's done, on to the news.
Marvel Studios has taken their Daredevil Born
Again series back to square one and are creatively
rebooting the series. They previously let go
of writers Chris Ord and Matt Corman because
they want to take the series in a different
direction. They decided that their previous
system of making Disney Plus series the same
exact way they make their movies no longer
works for television and so they're going to
take a more classic television production.
route with their television show making process.
And that'll include, you know, writing a show
bible, hiring a show runner, and in some cases
even producing pilots. This past week we learned
that the Daredevil Born Again series has already
landed its show runner. So Marvel has really
wasted no time, which is fantastic, but the
show runner is going to be Dario Scartapane,
who has worked on not only shows like Tom Clancy's
Jack Ryan, but also previously he's done Marvel
for Netflix. Which was awesome. I loved that
series. Yeah, it was a great show. It really
seems like Marvel's trying to kind of stick
to the tone that was previously established
by the Netflix series with the Daredevil born
again show. So I think that's fantastic news.
Yeah, honestly, it's like the best news I've
heard for this series. I was really worried
that Disney was gonna screw up a Daredevil television
series, but this is the best thing they could
have done to make it just like what we got before
with Netflix. Right, well, I mean, because
they weren't going to make it better, right?
You know, Disney Plus was not going to do a
better job than Netflix with the Daredevil show
because the Daredevil show was near perfection.
So you're right. The best thing they could do
is continue that series forward, at least tonally,
if not in continuity. In addition to the showrunners,
Marvel has also hired a couple of directors,
Justin Benson and Aaron Moorhead, who are co-directors
that have also done Marvel television, including
episodes of Loki season two and Moon Knight.
They were actually the lead directors on Loki
season 2. Right. And both of the shows, Loki
and Moon Knight, are incredibly cinematic.
So I would like to see them carry forward that
very grand feel to a Daredevil show and make
it really feel like a movie of sorts. I think
that'd be fantastic. Absolutely. This is all
great news. I was like shitting my pants a few
weeks ago when I saw that Marvel was rebooting
their series, but it really seems... Like they're
making a lot of really great decisions, not
just in the talent that they're hiring, but
in their approach in general. So I think the
Daredevil show will be all the better for it.
And I'm really looking forward to it, even
though we don't know when we're going to get
it, probably sometime in 2025 or something.
But speaking of Marvel television and the former
Netflix television shows, that brings us to
our question of the week.
What was your favorite Netflix Marvel television
series and why? Of course that includes Daredevil,
Jessica Jones, The Punisher, Luke Cage, Iron
Fist, and The Defenders. Record your answer
at dynamicduel.com by clicking on the red microphone
button in the bottom right hand corner of the
screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long, and don't forget to leave your name in
case we include you on the podcast. We'll pick
our favorite answer and award that person a
Dynamic Duel No Prize that we'll post to Instagram.
and our email newsletter. Be sure to answer
before November 4th.
But I think that does it for all the news for
this episode, so let's get into the main event
where we find out who would win in our spooky
zombie apocalypse matchup of Deceased versus
Marvel Zombies.
Welcome to the zombie apocalypse, y'all. That's
right, it's an all out gorefest as we find
out who'd win between the deceased and the Marvel
zombies. Both of these series came out within
the past 15 years or so. Jeez, actually I think
Marvel zombies came out in the mid 2000s. It
was a comic book series written by Robert Kirkman
around the same time that he was writing The
Walking Dead. It's a fantastic, shocking, depressing.
comic book series that was adapted recently
to animation in the Marvel Zombies episode of
What If, which was a fantastic episode. Definitely
a departure from the comic book series in the
story it told, but no less gruesome and kind
of freaky and scary and kind of fucked up too.
Yeah, I mean, Deceased has not been adapted
to any kind of animation style, but it was critically
acclaimed. Actually, the series just wrapped
up earlier this year in April in 2023. It was
written by acclaimed comic writer, Tom Taylor,
who is popular for also doing the Injustice
comic book storyline. That really expanded
the story of the video game. That's pretty cool,
I didn't know that. We're really excited to
bring this Team Duel episode to you guys on
Halloween day. We knew from the get-go, once
we saw that this episode was dropping on Halloween,
that we had to make it special. Yeah, it's
not too often you get to see zombies fighting
zombies, so I think this will be a lot of fun.
Right, right. Yeah, actually, initially, this
was going to be just a standard 1v1 duel, but
once we read the comics, we knew that we had
to cram as many zombies as we could within
this battle. Yeah, I actually had a really hard
time narrowing down my seven character roster.
Kudos to the executive producers who really
helped out with that. Running team duels is
a lot more difficult than running 1v1 duels,
but to explain the methodology behind our duels,
let's go to our sentient duel simulator, Alfred
Jarvis 9000. AJ9k, tell our listeners how you
go about determining a winner in these team
duel matchups. Yes, of course, sir. The way
I determine a winner between the two teams is
by running 1000 Monte Carlo simulations between
every character on each team using their statistics.
A Monte Carlo simulation is a probabilistic
model used to determine outcomes through random
sampling. In this case, I randomize the statistics
along a normal distribution as a way to simulate
the many variables that can occur during battle.
The stat parameters are based on the official
Marvel power grid. from which the DC characters'
statistics are extrapolated. Additional stat
categories are included such as range, damage
potential, versatility and perception in order
to create a more detailed and accurate simulation.
The results of the 49,000 simulations provide
a percentage of wins for each character on
both teams. The team with the higher average
win rate is declared the victor as they have
a higher probability to win any given battle.
In an equitable pairing, neither team should
win 100% of the matches. The comic book stories
have shown that there's even a way for Batman
to defeat Superman, so the confidence rate of
my method falls in line with the precedents
that have been established in the source material.
My mathematical simulations are without subjectivity
or bias. Feats are not the sole consideration,
nor are fan votes tabulated for determination
of the winner. Thanks, AJ9K. Before we run the
simulations, though, we like to break down
the histories and rosters for each team. before
improvising a scenario on how we imagine one
of the many simulations would play out B for
B. And I believe it's my turn to go first with
the DC backstory, so let me tell you all about
the storyline of Deceased. Spoiler alert if
you haven't finished the series. After a massive
victory by the Justice League over Darkseid's
attempted invasion of Earth, the tyrannical
Darkseid retreated to his distant planet of
Apocalypse, just as Earth's heroes realized...
that Cyborg was missing. Darkseid had captured
Cyborg during his invasion and tortured him
on Apocalypse, believing his body, half human,
half New God technology, was encoded with the
final remnant of the Anti-Life Equation that
Darkseid needed to control every living being
in the universe. In order to keep Cyborg alive
long enough to extract the Equation, Darkseid
summoned the New God embodiment of Death, the
Black Racer. and unknowingly merged some of
Death's essence with Cyborg, just as the equation
was fully deciphered. Darkseid, infected by
the techno-organic virus that was now the Corrupted
Equation, was consumed by madness and killed
the Black Racer, just as Darkseid's chief scientist,
Desaad, boomtubed Cyborg back to Earth in an
effort to send the equation from Apocalypse.
But it was too late. Darkseid leapt into the
fires of Apocalypse and unleashed his full
Omega power. annihilating the planet. Once Cyborg
arrived back on Earth, his systems reconnected
to the internet wirelessly, and he accidentally
uploaded the anti-life equation to the internet.
The virus spread quickly, as anyone who viewed
a screen was exposed to the equation and driven
mad with the need to kill any unaffected living
being in their vicinity, with them also being
capable of spreading the virus by blood contact.
Though Superman was able to realize what was
happening fast enough to save his wife and Lois
Lane and Jonathan Kent, Batman was unable to
save Nightwing and Red Robin, who attacked and
transmuted the virus to him, forcing Alfred
to kill all three. Batman's son Damien, who
was with Jonathan when the virus struck, survived,
as did Green Arrow and Black Canary, the latter
of whom became a Green Lantern after she was
forced to kill an infected Hell Jordan. The
surviving heroes assembled at the Daily Planet
in Metropolis, as instructed by Lois Lane in
a message she managed to broadcast from the
Daily Planet. Metropolis was soon destroyed,
however, after an infected atom breached Captain
Adam's metallic shell, infecting Kim as well
and causing Kim to detonate his atomically
energized body in an explosion that destroyed
Washington, D.C., Baltimore, and Metropolis.
The heroes at the Daily Planet and Lex Luthor
were the only survivors of the explosion, thanks
to Black Canary protecting them with her Green
Lantern Ring. When Earth's remaining uninfected
population being sheltered on the Paradise Island
of Themyscira and a dense forest in Gotham
City created by Poison Ivy, Earth's surviving
heroes assembled at the Fortress of Solitude,
away from the infected, where Cyborg and Lex
When Mr. Terrific failed to develop a cure,
he learned from the new gods Mr. Miracle and
Big Barda that the source, Apocalypse, had been
destroyed. They attempted to recruit John Constantine
to provide a magical solution, to which Constantine
revealed that one did not exist. Planning on
using Booster Gold's time machine as a last
resort, Big Barda became infected and killed
Mr. Terrific and Blue Beetle, though Constantine
was rescued by Dr. Fate and Zatanna. The remaining
members of the Justice League attempted to persuade
Black Adam to turn his nation of Condoc into
a third refuge as he had killed all anti-living
within his borders. But Black Adam refused
and became infected not long after, turning
his entire nation into an anti-living army
soon after. Wonder Woman managed to stop Black
Adam, however, by using her lasso to force
him to say Shazam and lose his power, after
which Superman used his heat vision. to sever
Adam's vocal cords and prevent him from gaining
power again. As the heroes neared completion
of the arcs at the Fortress of Solitude, they
were attacked mentally by an infected, invisible
Martian Manhunter, who managed to also infect
the Flash before Firestorm set Martian Manhunter
on fire. The Flash, infecting surviving humans
across the planet at light speed, was stopped
by Superman, who collided with him. Only for
the Flash's fingers. to get lodged in Superman's
torso during the incident, infecting Superman,
who attempted to flee the planet unsuccessfully
before he succumbed to the virus. As the heroes
acted quickly to get the Arks to Themyscira
and Gotham, Wonder Woman forged a sword from
Kryptonite and magic in order to fend off Superman
and protect the Arks. She failed, however, and
was infected by Superman, who went after the
now fully boarded Arks as they escaped Earth's
gravity. While Cyborg stayed behind with Wonder
Woman, Black Canary went after Superman with
the Kryptonite Sword, just as the entirety
of the Green Lantern Corps arrived to quarantine
the planet. As the Arks successfully escaped,
Superman retreated into the sun for protection.
Meanwhile, Cyborg bound Wonder Woman with her
magic lasso as she transformed into the Anti-Living,
at which point she confessed to him that his
code had possessed a cure for the virus all
along. But before Cyborg could send a signal
to the Arks to inform them, Woodroman escaped
the lasso and tore off his head. The Arks eventually
settled on a planet they dubbed Earth-2, and
after five years, Jonathan, Damien, and other
heroes returned to Earth to check on it, at
which point they received a distress beacon
coming from Cyborg's head. After rescuing Cyborg,
Mr. Miracle and a group of heroes took him
to the new god Metron, and Cyborg was able to
use Metron's all-knowing Mobius Chair. to learn
how to code a cure for the virus, while Constantine
and other magic users defended Earth from Trigon,
who attempted to destroy the planet to prevent
the virus from spreading across the cosmos.
After curing everyone on Earth and Superman,
Brainiac arrived at Earth too and warned them
that the infected new gods were tearing across
the universe. Darkseid, they learned, survived
the destruction of Apocalypse and infected everyone
on New Genesis. After decapitating Sinestro,
Darkseid took control of his Yellow Ring, becoming
a Yellow Lantern Zombie and infecting the planet-sized
weapon and Yellow Lantern homebase of Warworld
with the Anti-Life Virus. As planets fell to
Darkseid and his anti-living army, the God of
War Ares manipulated the Owens to order the
Green Lantern Corps to attack all other heroes
under the belief that it was less of a risk
to kill the infected rather than try to cure
them. After Mix's Spitalik became infected
and destroyed the Green Lantern Core's central
power battery, the Spectre sacrificed himself
to repair the battery and defeat Mix's Spitalik.
As Darkseid and his army arrived at Earth-2,
Elfrid transformed into the New Spectre in order
to save Damian, who had become infected by
Highfather of New Genesis. The Spectre was able
to cure all infected beings on Earth-2, including
Darkseid, with the help of Lobo. It was revealed
that the anti-life equation was created by
the primordial god of darkness, Erebus, and
that he would need to be defeated in order
to save the universe. Damien, as it turned out,
found the counter-life equation within Cyborg's
code, and with help from Darkseid, the heroes
were able to use a Doom Tube to teleport outside
the universe to Erebus' domain, where Damien
sacrificed himself while inside Erebus. to
destroy him and create an entirely new universe.
And that's the story of Deceased. Now, the
real stars of Deceased aren't the Anti-Living,
but since this is a zombie match, my roster
for the team duel match is going to consist
of some of the most prominent and devastating
members of the Anti-Living, primarily from the
original 6 issue run and the spinoff stories
that occurred concurrently. Superman, of course,
was a massive and powerful threat to the arcs.
that contained the last of humanity, so he's
definitely one of my team members, though he
has a prosthetic metal right arm after losing
it to Wonder Woman's kryptonite sword. Speaking
of Wonder Woman, she's also a member of my roster
as she, along with Superman, was among the
most powerful infected heroes at the end of
the initial story. And yes, she's wielding
her kryptonite sword. I'm also going with Black
Adam, who led an anti-living army against the
world, and who destroyed three major US cities
in one massive explosion. In that same vein,
I'm also going with Martian Manhunter, Big Barda,
and The Flash, who killed or infected major
characters within the story. So my roster consists
of Superman, Wonder Woman, Black Adam, Captain
Adam, Martian Manhunter, Big Barda, and The
Flash, all of whom you can learn about in their
respective dual episodes. Regarding zombies
in Deceased, they aren't technically zombies
because they aren't dead. You know, they just
become extremely violent with the urge to kill
all other living beings. They can be killed
by any standard means that the character would
normally be killed by, but they also retain
any powers and durability that they had when
they were among the living, and none of the
infected can feel pain. They all also share
a hive mind controlled by Erebus that can sense
nearby living entities. And finally, the antilife
virus that infects them can also infect technology
as it is techno-organic. That is quite the
powerful team that you have there. Hell yeah
it is, but it's not going to be powerful enough
against the Marvel zombies who have literally
eaten the universe. Let me go ahead and tell
you all about them. It all started with a flash
in the sky and a ripple through the clouds.
A being infected with a terrible plague known
only as the hunger. fell onto the streets of
Manhattan. The disease spread like wildfire,
infecting and transforming anyone bitten. The
Avengers of this reality were the first on the
scene, including Colonel America, Hawkeye,
Scarlet Witch, Black Widow, Luke Cage, and the
Wasp. But they were quickly overwhelmed. The
hunger was too powerful and the Avengers too
few. One by one, they fell to the disease.
Colonel America was the first bitten by a zombie
and turned into one himself. He then bit Spider-Man,
who had arrived on the scene to help. In the
confusion, Spider-Man returned home, only to
turn and devour his wife, Mary Jane, and his
Aunt May. Ant-Man knew he was running out of
time. The virus was spreading through his body,
and he could feel the hunger taking over his
mind. He had to find a way to survive, even
if it meant sacrificing someone else. He lured
Black Panther to his hidden lab, knocked him
out, and surgically removed pieces of him to
serve as a snack for later. From his Asteroid
M orbital space station observation deck, Magneto
watched in horror as the population consumed
itself. He knew that this was just the beginning
and traveled to Earth to warn the X-Men what
was happening. He led them to join the fight
in Manhattan, where the Fantastic Four were
already battling the zombies after losing Franklin
and Valeria to the zombie She-Hulk. The remaining
heroes gathered together at the S.H.I.E.L.D.
helicarrier, their last hope. Director Nick
Fury ordered them to split up to bring as many
survivors as possible to the SHIELD base, while
Reed Richards, Tony Stark, and Bruce Banner
worked on a zombie cure. Tony suggested the
scientists work individually to approach the
cure from multiple angles, though secretly he
suspected that humanity was doomed and instead
built a dimensional portal device. Reed was
driven insane by the loss of his children and
came to admire the efficiency of the zombie
organism. He claimed it was the next stage
of human evolution and infected the other Fantastic
Four members and had them feed on him to turn
him into a zombie as well. Damn. They ravaged
the helicarrier and turned the other heroes
inside into zombies, including Hulk, Thor, Doctor
Strange, and Storm. Meanwhile, virtually every
other hero began to fall to the plague during
their rescue missions, including the X-Men
and Wolverine. Within 24 hours, nearly the whole
of Earth's population was a zombie or dead.
The remaining zombified heroes reflected on
the monsters they had become and the atrocities
they had committed, having eaten their friends,
families, and those they were supposed to protect.
At that time, the Silver Surfer flew over the
planet as a herald of the forthcoming Galactus
and the heroes saw their chance at their next
meal. While contemplating how to get at the
Surfer, the Wasp found Ant-Man's secret Black
Panther stash and he bit off her head to keep
it quiet. When the Silver Surfer landed to announce
Galactus' imminent arrival, the group of zombie
heroes attacked and consumed the Herald, acquiring
a portion of the Power Cosmic. These zombies,
including Hulk, Colonel America, Wolverine,
Luke Cage, Spider-Man, Iron Man, and Ant-Man,
then fried the remaining zombie heroes with
their cosmic energy to see if cooking their
zombie flesh made them edible. It didn't, and
the Power Cosmic zombies found themselves again.
without a food source. That is, until Galactus
himself arrived. Knowing there were no match
for the Devourer of Worlds, the Power Cosmic
Zombies retreated to find a way to eat Galactus.
Meanwhile, Black Panther escaped Ant-Man's confinements
with help from the Wasp's severed head. Together,
the two found their way to Asteroid M, where
Magneto's acolytes still survived, and they
found there the Mutant Forge, who was able to
fashion new artificial limbs for Black Panther.
The zombified Ant-Man, Iron Man, and Bruce Banner
developed an amplifier device that would increase
the output of power cosmic energy directed into
it. With the device, the zombies were able
to injure Galactus enough to topple him, though
an army of villain zombies tried to fight them
for Galactus' flesh. Although Colonel America
fell in the battle when the Red Skull pulled
his brain out through an opening in his skull,
the other heroes were able to destroy the villains
and they feasted on Galactus as a reward. Now
known as the Zombie Galacti, they left the
planet and journeyed across the universe, devouring
every single life form. Meanwhile, on Earth,
the Kingpin used the Jackal's cloning tools
to set up an economic system among the remaining
villain zombies where they did his bidding for
the opportunity to feed on the clones. In an
effort to increase their food supply by invading
other dimensions, Morbius and Deadpool travel
to the mainstream Marvel dimension through the
nexus of all realities in the Florida Swamp.
Though Deadpool was reduced to just a head,
Morbius was able to disguise himself as his
mainstream counterpart and pretended to work
on a cure, but secretly planning to infect
all the heroes. Fortunately, Machine Man was
able to save the mainstream Morbius, who in
turn recruited a new iteration of the Midnight
Suns to combat and contain the virus. Decades
later, back in the zombie reality, the zombie
Galacti returned to Earth after eating the
universe. Looking to use Tony Stark's dimensional
portal device to invade other realities, they
discovered that Black Panther, Forge, and the
Acolytes had rebuilt a small society of survivors
on Earth called New Wakanda. But more than that,
they saw that the severed heads of the Wasp
and Hawkeye, after spending all this time not
feeding on human flesh, had overcome their
hunger. Shocked, Spider-Man and Luke Cage turned
on the other zombie galacti and joined New
Wakanda. which protected itself with an impenetrable
force field. Hungry, the remaining zombie galacti
left New Wakanda and traveled to the Baxter
Building to try and find the dimensional portal
before realizing it had been in New Wakanda
this whole time. The New Wakandans prepared
for the zombies' return and for battle, revealing
that Colonel America's brain had been rescued
and preserved in a new body. Though New Wakanda
was unable to stop the zombie galacti from
getting through the force field, the zombies
realized that they too had overcome their hunger
just prior to feasting. All the zombies that
is, except for the Hulk, who in a rampage killed
Hawkeye, Iron Man, and several Wakandan citizens
before reverting to Bruce Banner and begging
to be killed. The remaining zombies, Wolverine,
Colonel America, Spider-Man, Luke Cage, Black
Panther, Ant-Man and the Wasp, helped rebuild
New Wakanda. And though the crisis appeared
to be at an end, the zombies were ultimately
betrayed by the New Akandans who didn't trust
the hunger to never return, and they were sent
to another dimension using the Portal Device.
Scattered across a new universe and stripped
of the power of cosmic, some zombies reverted
to their old ways such as Ant-Man, while others,
like Spider-Man, tried to stop the disease
from spreading once again. Ultimately, all it
took was Ant-Man biting the Hulk, who in turn
bit the Sentry, for this new dimension to fall
like the last. the three largest alien races
in the universe. The Skrulls, Kree, and Shi'ar,
led by Black Panther, the Wasp, and Luke Cage,
respectively, couldn't stop the disease. During
a final stand between the good and bad zombies,
the Sentry was captured in the blue area of
the moon, where Ant-Man tried to use him as
an energy source to power the Watcher's dimensional
portal. There, Spider-Man unleashed a chemical
weapon he had created against the zombies, using
his old foe the Sandman to spread and destroy
every last member of the undead remaining. With
only the trapped Sentry left standing, the
cosmic being known as the Watcher teleported
him back in time to another dimension, creating
a time loop between two realities, where the
zombie virus would remain confined. The Sentry
landed in this new dimension above Manhattan,
arriving with a flash in the sky and a ripple
through the clouds. And that's the Marvel Zombies
backstory for this team duel, going with the
zombie Galacti, the group of zombies that devoured
the Silver Surfer and Galactus, imbuing them
with the power cosmic. This includes Spider-Man,
Wolverine, Hulk, Colonel America, Iron Man,
and Luke Cage. In addition to their regular
powers, all of which you can learn more about
in their respective duel episodes, each of these
zombies can fly at orbital speeds, fire devastating
power cosmic energy blasts, rearrange matter,
and have a minor level of awareness at a cosmic
level which helped them locate life forms to
consume. As zombies, they are tremendously
difficult to kill, and can only die if their
brain is completely destroyed. The zombies'
teeth can apparently get through anything, as
even people as durable as Luke Cage, the Silver
Surfer, and even Galactus were able to be bitten.
Although they normally retain their intelligence,
the zombies start to lose rationality as they
get hungrier and their minds become more obsessed
with eating. The hunger for living flesh itself
is entirely mental, as even severed zombie
heads hungered. Though after weeks without food,
the hunger would eventually dissipate. So again,
my roster is Spider-Man, Wolverine, Hulk, Colonel
America, Iron Man, and Luke Cage. So I am confused.
What was the origin of the zombie virus? There
was no origin. It's like a time paradox, basically.
The being that caused the virus in the first
place was the sentry who was sent back in time
the Watcher after the zombie virus had already
spread to that new universe. So it has no beginning
and no end really. That's dumb. The Marvel Zombies
story was eventually rebooted within the last
few years, I think it was called Marvel Zombies
Resurrection. And they kind of reimagined the
story as a virus sourced from diseased Galactus.
Okay, but the Robert Kirkman story is the classic,
you know, that's the one that everybody knows
and it's a fantastically dark story. Yeah,
I mean, it's freaking Robert Kirkman. I do love
the fact that the title of it is Marvel Zombies,
which is a moniker bestowed upon anyone who
reads only Marvel comics because they're just
so ridiculously devoted to the company and will
only read that, even though there's better
shit out there from DC no less. Well, it doesn't
surprise me that there are people who only
read Marvel because it's just better. There's
no such term as a DC zombie because no one
out there reads just DC because it's not good
enough. I mean. I only read DC. You DC zombie.
Alright, now that we've got the storylines and
the rosters out of the way, let's speculate
on how one of these simulated matches will go.
The winning team is determined by simulations,
not this speculation, but it's fun to imagine
how the fight could play out. Alfred Jarvis9000,
what are the rules of our speculation? Well,
I should say there are no rules, other than
the teams have no prior knowledge of the other
going into the fight. All they are aware of
starting out... is that the other side is a
threat that needs to be eliminated. For the
speculation, the groups will begin approximately
50 meters apart in a nondescript environment
that will have no bearing on the match itself,
as no environmental statistics are considered
in my simulations. The teams must earn victory
on their own merit. Alright then let's get
into it. Deceased and the Marvel zombies meet
on the battlefield, who goes first? All I know
is that first off, if the deceased are actually
technically still alive, then that means they
are food for the Marvel zombies. And that is
gonna get the Marvel zombies like really excited.
It's gonna send them to a ravenous glee. Okay,
fine. That's fine. I'm gonna say the deceased
go first though, because we have a speedster
on our team, the Flash. And he's just gonna
start off by running right up to the Hulk, since
you know, he's a big burly guy, and he's gonna
phase his arm right into the Hulk's torso. just
making a giant hole and spilling the Hulk's
guts out. Well, fortunately for the Hulk, he
doesn't need guts to function. So he's gonna
react to the Flash's attack by grabbing the
speedster's arm. And then when the Flash tries
to run away, he doesn't run away with the arm
because Zombie Hulk just ripped that thing
off and then he eats it. Okay. I mean, the Flash
is off using his speed force to heal his stump
arm now. And... The two teams are just gonna
clash and Black Adam, he's gonna start by sending
a lightning bolt at let's say Wolverine because
you know he's a conductor with his metal skeleton.
And that lightning is just gonna sizzle Wolverine
to a burnt crisp. Again that's not gonna do
anything. Wolverine is just gonna smile, this
charred smile. Actually, Marvel zombies are
probably always smiling because they don't have
any lips, you know. But uh meanwhile Ant-Man
is gonna grow into Giant-Man. and he's going
to stomp onto Martian Manhunter, pinning him
to the floor so he can grab him underneath his
boot and then just devour him. Martian Manhunter,
he would just phase through the floor and just
like leave Giant Man to wonder what the heck
just happened. Meanwhile, Wonder Woman, she's
going to run through Spider-Man with her sword,
just impaling him at the torso. And then, you
know, she's going to pull out the sword and
slice him again, this time just hacking him
from shoulder to navel. Damn! That's pretty
violent. Fucking zombies. Iron Man sees this
and he's gonna shoot a cosmic unibeam from
his armor and that's just gonna blast Wonder
Woman away from Spider-Man who is gonna patch
his split in half upper body together with webbing.
That's crazy. Yeah, it's like super glue. Okay,
meanwhile Superman and Hulk are gonna be going
to blows with, you know, Hulk probably trying
to eat Superman. But Superman, he's going to
keep him at bay by freezing the Hulk's lower
body with his freeze breath. And then he's just
going to punch the Hulk's lower body right
off. So now the Hulk has no legs because they're
just shattered. That's not like the big move
that you think it is. OK, but meanwhile, Luke
Cage, he's going to pick up Wolverine and fastball
special him, hurling him at Big Barda. And Wolverine
flies into Big Barda claws first. tackling
her to the ground, pinning her to the floor
with his claws, and then he's gonna rip her
throat out with his teeth like a hungry wolf.
Except that before Wolverine gets one bite
in, he's gonna get blasted off of Big Barda
by Captain Adam, who's then gonna fire another
quantum blast at Colonel America that takes
the top part of his skull right off, just exposing
his brain. Well, it probably only took off the
top part of his head because Colonel America
was raising his shield up to his head. Um, so
the Colonel actually redirects a large part
of Captain Adam's blast, reflecting the energy
beam right into Black Adam blasting him. Okay.
I say that the deflected beam also severs one
of Giant Man's legs because, you know, Colonel
America wasn't really aiming that well and Giant
Man was such a massive target. Now, Big Barda,
she's going to leap up Giant Man's severed leg
hole and she's going to explode out of his
chest with her Mega Rod. Jeez! How does that
work? She leaps up his leg hole and explodes
at his chest? Yeah, she goes right into his
mushy zombie body. Oh jeez. Okay, well at this
point, we'll say Superman is trying to use his
heat vision to decapitate Luke Cage. But, you
know, Luke Cage isn't fazed because he has unbreakable
skin. So Luke yanks Superman's cape and slams
him down to the ground and uh... With Superman
pinned, Luke quickly shoves his thumbs into
Superman's eyes, just frying them out of his
skull with his power cosmic. So Superman has
no eyes. He's blind and unable to stop Luke
Cage from biting him. Dang! I mean, Superman
has other enhanced senses, so blindness wouldn't
phase him too much. Although I guess like he
can't use his heat vision or x-ray vision or
telescopic vision or anything like that anymore.
Exactly. But uh... Martian Manhunter, he's going
to stop Luke Cage from biting Superman by transforming
into this like zombie demon monster with two
heads and like a giant mouth where his stomach
is and he's going to just straight up swallow
Luke Cage whole. Okay, but at that time Spider-Man
is going to fly over to Big Barda and she's
probably going to try to blast him with her
mega rod, but he's going to use his Spidey sense
to dodge and then get him behind her. close
enough to grab her back and then bite her in
the shoulder. So now Barda is going to become
a zombie and is now part of team Marvel. Okay,
I saw something like this coming and I have
a theory Marvel zombies. They retain their intelligence,
right? They're just like overwhelmed with hunger,
but the anti-living have a hive mind. They're
controlled by Erebus outside of the universe.
So it's not like their mind would be affected
by the hunger and turning one of the DC guys
doesn't make them Team Marvel because technically,
Erebus still knows that he needs to bring down
the Marvel zombies. So basically all you've
done is give Barda added defense because now
she won't die if she like gets cut in half or
whatever. No, no, no. The hunger overcomes
everything. Like Barda would be consumed by
it. She would want to feast on whatever flesh
is nearby and the only flesh that's around is
that of her DC teammates. Yeah, I mean, she'll
want to feast, but she won't because Erebus
is in control. And he's an elder deity, way
more powerful than this hunger. Well, maybe
Erebus's mind succumbs to the hunger when she's
bitten. Probably not, unless the Marvel zombie
virus can be spread mentally, like telepathically.
No, it only spreads physically, but the Marvel
zombies aren't going to stop trying to feed
on the DCs just because the DC guys aren't joining
their side, but- If they bite them, then that
means all they're doing is just making the DC
guys more unkillable. Right. But I guess not
totally unkillable because the Marvel zombies
do know about the brain weakness, whereas the
DC guys wouldn't. That's true. That's true.
OK, so we'll say that, yes, the Marvel guys
can turn DC guys into zombies, but it's not
going to turn the DC guys onto Team Marvel.
Exactly. It's not going to make them feed on
their teammates. So we'll say that Bart is
a zombie now. And the first thing she's gonna
do is she's gonna leap onto Iron Man, who's
flying around and she's gonna drive her mega
rod right into his chest reactor and upload
the anti-light virus into his armor. And since
this is a techno-organic virus that also infects
technology, Erebus now has control over Iron
Man and he's going to use him to repulsor blast
the shit out of Spider-Man. What? So I can't
make Barda team Marvel, but you can make Iron
Man team DC. Yep. What the fuck? Technically,
it's Iron Man's armor, not Tony Stark. That's
infected. OK, that's true. Yeah, Tony Stark
is the one who's cosmically powered, not the
armor. So realizing that he lost control of
the Iron Man armor, Tony's going to use the
power cosmic to expel the suit from his body.
and then he's gonna destroy the armor with
a cosmic blast. Fuck! So that's pretty easy.
And then the Hulk, he's using power cosmic
to fly, even though he's missing his lower legs,
his lower half. He's basically just a flying
upper torso. He's gonna grab Black Adam out
of the air and take a big bite out of his leg,
just ripping out his quad muscles with his teeth.
So now Black Adam's a zombie. And that's fine,
like. Go ahead and make my guys more powerful.
I'm OK with that. Black Adam, you know, he's
just going to respond to anyway by grabbing
Hulk's skull with both hands and electrocuting
it with such a strong current that it's going
to cause Hulk's brain and head to explode,
killing him. So Zombie Hulk is dead. OK, um,
I think by this point, like, Ant-Man is going
to be like, guys, biting these people isn't
transferring the hunger. because that's probably
what they would think, not knowing that, you
know, the other zombies are a hive mind. But
like, I don't know if the team would actually
care. Like Wolverine is probably going to be
like, who cares? Eat to kill, you know? So don't
just turn them, devour them. So he's going
to fly over to Captain Adam and just plunge
his claws and teeth into him. Dude, that's
like the dumbest thing you could have done.
Breaching Captain Adam's skin. is only going
to make him explode. So like Wolverine, he just
gets evaporated at the atomic level, meaning
he just basically took himself out. Shit. Well,
as long as he takes Captain Adam with him,
that's fine, I guess. Meanwhile, Luke Cage is
going to burst out of Martian Manhunter. He
basically ate his way out of Martian Manhunter's
body, turning Martian Manhunter into a zombie.
But also Martian Manhunter is like missing like
half of his body mass. It's all in Luke Cage's
stomach now. I was going to argue that like
there's no way Martian Manhunter would have
felt half of his body being eaten, but I guess
you know the deceased don't feel pain. So sure,
doesn't matter though, because Martian Manhunter
is going to psychically induce vomiting in
Luke Cage and reabsorb that mass. All right.
Meanwhile, the Flash is going to clothesline
Tony Stark at full speed with his good arm.
and just decapitate him. Okay, Tony Stark has
a severed head, but the severed head is still
alive. And it's gonna fly right back at the
Flash chasing Kim and then chomping down on
his heel and ripping out the Flash's Achilles
tendon, all sinewy, you know? So Flash can't
run anymore, he trips, he's down on the ground,
and then Tony Stark's head is gonna chew through
Flash's face until it gets to the brains, and
then he's just gonna suck up the brains. So
flash is out and Colonel America, he's going
to throw a power cosmically energized shield
right into Superman's face, who can't see it
coming because he's got no eyes. No, but I mean,
he has ears so he could hear the shield coming
and he's just going to catch it with his metal
arm. And then he's just going to rip that shit
right in half because he's fucking Superman.
What? And, you know, by smelling. Colonel America's
rotting corpse, he rushes over to him at super
speed, just jamming his fingers right into
his face and ripping it wide open, just sending
pieces of skull and brain matter all over everywhere.
That was hardcore. Damn. All right, well, Ant-Man
saw Superman do this and he shrunk down from
giant man size to miniature size since Superman
doesn't have microscopic vision anymore to
sense him. and Ant-Man leaps into Superman's
head through one of the exposed eye sockets,
and then he fries Superman's brain with cosmic
energy, just causing it to melt and then leak
out of Superman's eye holes and like ear holes
and nose, just all the holes on his face, his
brain is just oozing out. Jeez. Okay, dang.
Meanwhile, one Roman sees Tony Stark's head
flying around, which is like pure nightmare
fuel, by the way, and- She's going to be able
to expertly lasso it and yank it towards her.
At which point she just thrusts her sword right
through his skull and through his brain, just
killing him. All right. Good one. Good one.
Meanwhile, Spider-Man, he's going to swing over
to Martian Man Hunter who, you know, reformed
his body from Luke Cage's puke. And now it's
back into like his standard form, though, you
know, of course, Martian Man Hunter is missing
his lips now that he's a zombie, but Spider-Man
is gonna slap his hand on top of Martian Manhunter's
head and he sticks it there and with a powerful
yank He essentially scalps Martian Manhunter
like exposing his brain Which Spider-Man then
incinerates with a power cosmic blast so Martian
Manhunter is out and then Luke Cage and Barda
are gonna get into like this energy blast To
go board type match with Luke Cage firing cosmic
energy at Big Barda and Big Barda firing mega
rod energy And for a while it seems like it's
gonna be a stalemate, but eventually Luke Cage
is gonna overpower her energy and take control
of her mega rod telekinetically and just send
it right through her forehead and it just lodges
there. Wait, the Pyrocosmic gives him telekinesis?
Yeah, in a sense. Like, the Cosmic energy can
not only fire energy blasts, but it can rearrange
matter and stuff. Fuck. Okay, well, while that
was happening... Black Adam saw what Spider-Man
did to Martian Manhunter. So, you know, while
Spider-Man is probably dodging Black Adam's
lightning bolts with the spider sense, it's
all just a distraction for Black Adam to move
in fast enough. And you know, now that he's
a zombie, thanks to the Hulk, Black Adam's gonna
devour Spider-Man and absorb his power cosmic.
That's how that works, right? Uh, we'll say
no. Why? The eight silver surfer, right? And
absorbed his power? Sure. Okay. Alright, so
Black Adam gets the power of cosmic from Spider-Man,
but Black Adam would find eating Spider-Man
disgusting though because zombies can't really
tolerate the flesh of other zombies. So while
Black Adam's like retching from Spidey's zombie
flesh, Ant-Man is going to grow back into Giant-Man,
just like massive, bigger than he's ever gotten
with help from the power of cosmic. He grows
to like the size of Galactus, you know, and
he's going to grab Black Adam. Like he's a frickin
toothpick and just bite down on his head and
yank it from his shoulders like a piece of taffy.
And just grind up Black Adam's brain and skull
up in his molars. You didn't even let me use
the power. I can't use Iron Man's suit. I can't
use Black Adam's power cosmic. Come on. I guess
I just have Wonder Woman left as my last woman
standing as it were. And at this point, you
know, she's probably going up against Luke
Cage. Uh, now a normal sword wouldn't be able
to break Luke Cage's skin, but Wonder Woman's
Kryptonite sword is also magically imbued, so
that Superman would be weak to it. And I'm
guessing Luke Cage also has no defense against
magic blades either. So as their trading blows,
I'm going to say that Wonder Woman managed to
slice him right in half with her sword, scalp
to scrote, just cleaving his brain right down
the middle vertically. All right. She cuts
Luke Cage in half. So it's down to Ant-Man and
Wonder Woman, but not just Ant-Man and Wonder
Woman, because Ant-Man, he's gonna have a whole
ass army behind him of giant ants, you know?
What? And these are ants that he's weaponized
by experimenting on them with the zombie virus.
So he has this legion of like ravenous zombie
insects that he commands to just swarm over
Wonder Woman and they tear her limb from limb
and yeah, victory for the Marvel zombies. Where
the fuck did all the insects come from? They
were shrunk down in one of his little pockets
on his belt. Well, you know how Captain Atom
exploded earlier? Whenever that happens in
the comics, he's just propelled into the future.
And so right after Wonder Woman is fully devoured
by the insects, that's when Captain Atom appears.
And then he's just gonna generate a massive
explosion that annihilates all of the insects
and Ant-Man. Boom, victory for the deceased.
I think that's a good counter. OK, that's bullshit.
The whole time travel thing. But we can leave
it there. So either one of two things happens
in this scenario, depending on the results.
Either Captain Adam gets blasted into the future
at the end of this match or he doesn't and
Wonder Woman gets devoured by ants. I mean,
why wouldn't he, though, you know? All right,
let's go ahead and put in the stats for these
teams. We're going to run 49000 simulations
in a matrix style comparison. between all the
characters and we'll be back with a winner.
AJ9K, hit it. Inputting data, running calculations,
processing results, simulations complete. All
right, this was a fun matchup. This was a lot
of fun, actually. Yeah, the goal was to at
some point make people sick to their stomach
while listening to the speculation. So if we
were successful in that, I think we did our
jobs here. Stat-wise, the teams were pretty
interesting. I think especially the Marvel zombies,
considering the fact that they had increased
durability from the fact that even if they're
injured, they could essentially still keep
moving and fighting. Right, their only weak
spot is their brain. But not only are they
all highly durable like that, they're also insanely
fast thanks to the power cosmic. Their damage
level is really high as well as their range.
Yeah, I was pretty nervous about that until
I looked at my lineup and realized, you know,
all of my guys are pretty powerful even without
the power of cosmic. You know, Superman, Wonder
Woman, Black Adam, Martian Manhunter, those
are among the strongest characters in DC to
begin with. It's just that as the anti-living,
it's sort of like no holds barred. There's no
like restraints on them. Yeah, but their minds
are also all gone, replaced by the will of Erebus.
So all of the deceased got a knock on the intelligence
stat, whereas the Marvel zombies all retained
their normal intelligence. And that was actually
the greatest variance in all of the stat categories
between the two teams, because a lot of the
Marvel zombies are really smart, including Iron
Man, Spider-Man, Hulk, Ant-Man. Yes, yes, stat
wise, the Marvel zombies are pretty impressive.
But, you know, I could say the same thing about
the deceased. So taking all of the stats into
account. Joseph, who do you think came out
on top? Marvel zombies because they can last
longer in battle and they have the power cosmic,
which you don't fuck with. Although the Instagram
poll takers don't agree with me. Actually 55%
of them on Instagram said that DC East was gonna
take this. Again, I have to chalk this up to
too many damn DC fans following us on Instagram.
Marvel guys, have a seat, sit down. Okay, we
gotta have a talk. You guys gotta, you guys
gotta show up. I'm just, I'm just gonna say
you gotta show up, you gotta follow us on Instagram,
you gotta take part in the polls, we gotta
start winning these voting contests because
the DC guys are showing you guys up, right?
Dude, I was actually really surprised to see
that more people voted for deceased considering
the fact that I feel like Marvel Zombies is
really popular, even going so far as to have
their own episode in What If. Yeah, you and
me both, you and me both. Well, let's find
out who actually won. AG 9K, the results please.
Hey, you are, sir. All right. The winner of
the team duel between the deceased and the Marvel
zombies is. Deceased. Fuck you. What? And,
you know, for as different as the teams were,
it was close. The deceased one in even five
hundred and thirty of the one thousand matches
or 53 percent compared to Marvel's. 47 percent.
So Marvel won 470 matches out of a thousand.
Right. And honestly, I'm not going to lie.
I'm going to chalk this win up to the excellent
roster choices made by our executive producers.
Well, like I told them that they didn't stand
a chance because all the Marvel zombies had
the power of cosmic. So I feel like they just
had to pick the most powerful people they could
think of. Yeah. And that's essentially what
I have on my roster, which I'm pretty proud
of. And I have to wholeheartedly dedicate this
win to our executive producers for their fantastic
work. I think we should replace Marsha Manhunter
and Big Barda and Black Adam with Green Arrow
and The Question and Oracle. Then let's rerun
the stats. I don't remember The Question being
in the series, but Batgirl was, Green Arrow
was, they were both zombies, but Batgirl was
killed right away by Harley Quinn. And Green
Arrow was not a zombie for very long. Before
he was cured? Yeah, he was cured. Okay, interesting.
Well, I'm starting to regret this whole team
duel now. And all around winning for Team DC.
Good job. That was a really fun match, but
that does it for this duel. Let us know what
you thought about the results by writing to
us at dynamicduelpodcast.gmail.com or by visiting
us on Instagram or X. You can find links to
all of our accounts by checking out our show
notes or visiting our website at dynamicduel.com.
And on our site, you can also find a link to
our Patreon page where you could join our Dynamic
Duo tier and chat with us and fellow listeners.
Our Fantastic Four tier, which gives you bonus
content each month. Our X-Force tier that makes
you an executive producer of this podcast.
Or our newest tier that lets you join our Dynamike
Podcast Network. If you can't join Patreon,
you can still support the show by signing up
for our e-newsletter also at dynamicduel.com
so you'll never miss an episode. Or you could
also rate the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify,
Podchaser. or on our website. Our next episode
is going to be another duel episode in lead
up to the Marvel's movie review which comes
out in a few weeks. We're going to do a cosmic
level duel pitting the villains of Mongol against
Annihilus. Yeah, that's going to be an awesome
matchup. I can't wait for that. But that does
it for this episode and for Spooktober as a
whole. We hope you guys had a lot of fun this
month. We sure did. Thanks for tuning in. Yen,
big thanks to our executive producers Ken Johnson,
John Storowski, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Belcombe,
Miggy Mattinghian, Brandon Estergard, Nathaniel
Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Nick Abato, Austin Wazilowski,
AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Adam Spies, and
Andrew Schonk for helping to make this podcast
possible. We'll talk to you guys next week.
Up up and away, true believers. Take car, go
to mum's, kill Phil, sorry. Grab Liz, go to
the Winchester, have a nice cold pint and wait
for all of this to blow over.