This is a Dynamike Network podcast.
Hi and welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast,
a weekly show where we review superhero films
and debate the superiority between Marvel and
DC by comparing their characters in stat-based
battle simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe. And I'm
his twin brother, Johnny DC. And in this episode,
we're going to find out who'd win in a fight
between the multiversal characters of Rocket
from Milestone Comics and Spider-Gwen. from
Marvel Comics, but from an alternate universe.
Yeah, this is the second week we're pitting
multiversal characters against each other.
Of course, last week we pit Ultraman against
Hyperion. This week we wanted to do a Spider-Girl
type episode in lead up to our next episode,
which is a review of Madame Web, which takes
place, you could say, in an MCU adjacent universe
made by Sony. Right, yeah, we're trying to
squeeze in these multiversal duels, considering
that both Madame Web and the recent DC animated
movie that came out, Crisis on Infinite Earths,
deal with comic book and movie multiverses.
Both of these characters are pretty awesome,
so I'm really interested in seeing who will
win. But we'll figure that out later on. Before
that, we're going to break down the latest
comic book movie news to come out this past
week, including the incredible trailer that
we got over the Super Bowl for Deadpool and
Wolverine. That's the name of the movie now.
It's no longer Deadpool 3. It's Deadpool and
Wolverine. Can't wait to talk about that. We
also got confirmation. from Matt Shackman who's
gonna direct the upcoming Fantastic Four movie
that Pedro Pascal is indeed confirmed to be
playing Mr. Fantastic. Yeah, a lot of big Marvel
news this episode. As always, we list our segment
times in our episode description, so feel free
to check out the show notes if you want to skip
ahead to a particular topic. Our artificially
intelligent dual simulator AJ9K has a quick
message for our listeners, so listen up. Why
hello there. Do you love listening and chatting
about Marvel and DC? Then become a part of
the dynamic dual community on Patreon, where
you can choose from three tiers. The dynamic
2-0 tier lets you listen to this podcast without
ads and gives you access to its Discord chat
group, where you can chat with Johnny DC and
Marvelous Joe. The fantastic 4 tier gives you
that and more with two bonus episodes each month,
including bloopers and top 10 shows where Johnny
and Joe count down your favorite Marvel and
DC subjects. The X-Force tier makes you an
executive producer of Dynamic Duel, where every
month you help the hosts choose what to review
and who to fight against each other. And finally,
the Dynamike Podcast Network tier allows aspiring
podcasters to create their own battle-focused
show using this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny
and Joe will help you develop your show, provide
graphic support and consultation, and get you
simulation results to announce on your show.
Pitch the twins your show via email at dyna
or by reaching out to them on social media.
Check it out at patreon.com slash dynamicduel.
Pip pip cheerio! Thanks AJ9K, and thanks to
everyone who supports the podcast. Guys, be
sure to tune into the Max Destruction Podcast,
which is part of the Dynamike Podcast Network,
which pits your favorite action heroes from
film and television against each other. This
week, hosts Ken and his wife put together a
Valentine's Day episode, where they all find
out who'd win in a fight between Lisa from Weird
Science and Hollywood from Cool World. Battle
of the Babes. And on the Send Your World Podcast.
Host Zachary Hepburn speculates on fights between
your favorite anime characters. Zach's a little
under the weather this week, so there will
be no new episode of Send Your World this Thursday,
but that'll give you guys a chance to get caught
up on past episodes if you're not already. And
on the Console Combat Podcast, hosts John and
Dean find out who'd win in fights between your
favorite video game characters. In yesterday's
episode, they held their very first championship
matchup between Scorpion for Mortal Kombat
against Ezio from Assassin's Creed. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com
or click the link in our show notes to listen
to all of the shows in the Dynamike Podcast
Network. But with that out of the way, quick
to the No Prize! A No Prize is an award Marvel
used to give out to fans. Our version, the
Dynamic Duel No Prize, is a digital award we
post on Instagram for the person that we feel
gave the best answer to our question of the
week. Last week we asked... Who has been your
favorite Supergirl actress across film and television
and why? And this is coming off of the news
that Millie Alcock has been cast as Supergirl
for James Gunn's DCU. We got four answers,
so we're going to break down the honorable mentions
before revealing this week's no prize winner.
Our first honorable mention goes to Travis Herndon
who said, Hey guys, Travis here. So my pick
would have to be the Supergirl from the Flash
movie, although she's not the one that we all
know with the blonde hair and the skirt. was
a pretty bad ass version of Supergirl and honestly
it's a shame that we won't see her in this James
Gunn DCU but hey, hey maybe the actress might
come back as I don't know maybe like Wonder
Woman's daughter or something but she's my
favorite she's just an all around badass Latino
hero. Yes so Sasha Kaia played Supergirl in
the recent flash film that came out last year
she didn't have the largest role in the movie
but the time she did have on screen. I thought
she did a phenomenal job with. Yeah, she didn't
look like your typical super girl who is portrayed
in the comics, usually as having long blonde
hair and wearing a red skirt and stuff like
that. But I thought Sasha Kaia fucking killed
it as this analog to Henry Cavill's Superman
within this newly created timeline that The
Flash started when he went back in time. Yeah,
the character herself is actually based on
a design from the Injustice comics. She was
Superman's daughter. And I thought they nailed
that design. perfectly. She looked incredible
in the movie. So great answer, Travis. Our
next honorable mention goes to Miggie Mathingian,
who said, Hey, what's up, guys? This is Miggie.
And my favorite Supergirl actress would probably
be Summer Glau. I think that's how you pronounce
it. From Superman, Batman, Apocalypse. I think
she just had the best job or did the best job
displaying like a full range of emotions from
her fear and confusion from first landing here
on Earth. to her grief at the death of her friend
and to her anger at fighting Darkseid at the
last battle. Thanks guys. Yeah, Superman Batman
Apocalypse is an animated film that was based
on a comic run written by Jeff Loeb, if I'm
not mistaken. It was a fantastic run. It reintroduced
the character of Kara Zor-El to the main DC
continuity. And yeah, it was a great like origin
story for the character. They did a great job
adapting it to the animated film. And there's
been a lot of great actresses to do voiceover
work for the character of Supergirl. In this
movie, in DC Superhero Girls, in the Superman
animated series, they've all done a fantastic
job. And the recent Legion of Superheroes film
that takes place in the Tomorrowverse. Oh,
that's right. That was voiced by Megan Donnelly,
the actress who almost became Supergirl in
live action. Now we haven't reviewed Superman
Batman Apocalypse yet, but it is definitely
on our list of animated DC films to eventually
get to. We only have about like 50 projects
left to review for Marvel and DC that aren't
new, so not too many. I imagine we'll get through
quite a few this year considering how few theatrical
releases DC and Marvel are putting out. Yeah
for sure. Great answer, Miggy. But the winner
of this week's Snow Prize goes to two people.
both Abner O'Terry and Peter Troll who both
gave the same answer. And they said, Hey guys,
it's Abner O'Terry. My answer is Melissa Pinoist
because she was able to be funny and smart
and her relationships with her adopted sister
and the rest of the cast were just phenomenal.
Hey guys, it's Peter. My answer for the best
Supergirl. is probably Melissa Benoist from
the CW show. I thought she looked the part,
I thought she played the part very well, and
something about those CW shows just really have
a grip on my heart. But also, I may be a little
biased because I thought she was cute and maybe
had a little crush. But yeah, Melissa Benoist
is my choice. Thanks, guys. So, normally I like
to give points for originality here, but it
was really hard not to award the answer of Melissa
Benoist! Because yeah, who doesn't have a crush
on her? She did a fantastic job in the role
of Supergirl. Honestly, I think she's the best
actress to play the character ever. Well, she
certainly has had the most substantial role
as Supergirl, considering she had so many seasons
on her own television series. Right, as compared
to someone like Helen Slater who had her own
movie, but the movie was terrible. The Supergirl
show wasn't for the most part. Yeah, here are
the first few seasons. Like all of the DCCW
shows were actually pretty good. Yes, yeah,
that is correct. So congrats to Abner O'Terry
and Peter Troll. Both of you win this week's
no prize. If you, the listener, want a shot
at winning your own no prize, stay tuned to
later on this episode when we'll be asking
another question of the week. And now that that's
done, onto the news.
All right, this past week, right before the
big game, we got the official teaser for the
upcoming Deadpool and Wolverine movie. Now,
you know, we've been calling it Deadpool 3
this whole time, but it was announced with this
teaser that the movie is officially called
Deadpool and Wolverine. So they split the billing.
That's pretty cool. The trailer was great.
I'm so excited to get into this. Yeah, the name
is kind of smart, I would say, just because
of how big of a name Wolverine is. I would still
say as popular as Deadpool is, His name isn't
quite as big as Wolverine, so I think that's
a huge selling point. And what's funny is that
earlier this year, Hugh Jackman released a video
and he inadvertently called the movie Wolverine
and Deadpool, so I wonder if that's going to
be kind of like a running gag where they kind
of fight over who gets top billing. Yeah, that'd
be great. The teaser trailer starts off with
Deadpool's birthday, and everyone from X-Force
is there, including Shatterstar, Pete, Doepinder's
there, Vanessa's back. It looks like At the
end of Deadpool 2, he used Cable's time sliding
device to basically save all of his friends.
Yeah, I was really surprised to see characters
like Shatterstar, but definitely implied that
yeah he probably broke some TVA rules saving
all of his friends from death. Which is why
the TVA shows up at his house and we get one
of the best gags in the entire Deadpool franchise
just in this teaser where he's like, is that
supposed to scare anybody? Piggings not new
to me, friendo, but it is to Disney. and he
looks at the camera breaking the fourth wall.
So good. And it was in continuity because we
saw him be pegged in the first Deadpool movie
on International Women's Day. So good on them
for sticking to the established canon. It was
also a nice way to just right off the bat address
the whole purchase of Fox by Disney between
Deadpool 2 and 3. Well, actually they address
that in Once Upon a Deadpool. Oh, I never saw
that. Yeah. Well, it was the PG-13 of Deadpool
2 that they released around the holidays when
Deadpool 2 came out. He basically stated in
that movie that the reason they wanted to do
a PG-13 version was because of Disney. Okay.
Yeah, I wonder if that's canon. I don't know,
but I'm glad to see that this movie obviously
will not be PG-13. I'm glad that Deadpool is
sticking to its hard R roots. Because honestly,
Once Upon Deadpool wasn't that great. It was
okay. But in this teaser, Deadpool gets taken
to the TVA. where he's talking to some guy.
I kind of wish that the guy in the chair talking
to him was Mobius, who is a character played
by Owen Wilson in the Loki television series,
but it's not. He's some British dude. There's
a great gag there where he tells Deadpool that
he sold himself while unconscious, and he's
like, I wasn't unconscious, where am I? So
good. Dude, that's not just some dude. That's
fucking Matthew McFadden, the recent Emmy winner
for Secession. He's a fantastic actor. I don't
give a fuck who that is. You will you will
the guy is just an incredible actor. I think
he's gonna kill it in this role Yeah, sure.
You still should have been Mobius. I mean isn't
Owen Wilson supposed to have a cameo in this
movie Yeah, but like, you know, he could have
had a substantial role here I don't know what
kind of story they're setting up but apparently
Deadpool has to help save the MCU For some
reason and he calls himself Marvel Jesus, which
is kind of funny I don't quite know what the
threat is though because we see him take on
the TVA itself for a vast majority of this
teaser. There's a lot of quick shots of him
like suiting up and then we see him in this
swanky place, what appears to be a Magi-Pore
casino because we see him approaching Wolverine
in his Patch persona from behind. So that's
pretty cool. We're going to see Hugh Jackman
not only in his comic accurate Wolverine get
up, but we also get to see his alter ego of
Patch. How do you know it's Patch? Because Wolverine's
persona of Patch wears a white suit. Oh, okay.
I just love the suit up scene where it's like
something from Batman Forever or Batman and
Robin or just different like closeups. But there's
also a scene where like someone's like slapping
his ass just like randomly tossed in there.
And then Kim doing the splits and like sliding
upwards and doing like a dance move. I felt
that, I felt it. I was like, hell yeah. It
looks like actually both Deadpool and Wolverine
get pruned. and go to the void at the end of
time, where it's kind of post-apocalyptic. We
see the 20th century Fox logo there, just in
the sand. We do see what I think is Eliath for
a brief shot, taking out one of the TVA members.
And I think a vast majority of the film takes
place in the void. And it seems like the film
was mainly about escaping it. Which is honestly
pretty cool. I love the fact that we get to
see other X-Men characters there, like fucking
Pyro. That was a surprise. Yeah, Aaron Stanford
as Pyro makes a guest appearance here. That
was great. Cool to see him back. I can't wait
to see everyone back. It's gonna be the No Way
Home of X-Men movies. And it seems like it's
gonna be even bigger than that. Well, I mean,
the X-Men franchise has already had its No
Way Home movie in days of future past, where
you got a merger of the two big franchises,
like with James McAvoy and Patrick Stewart and
Michael Fassbender and Dean McKellen. But Deadpool
3 also has the other. task of merging the Foxverse
with the MCU. It looks like a whole lot of
fun. I really like the last shot where Deadpool's
like injured, hurt on his back and he's like,
don't just stand there, Harry Ape help me up.
And Wolverine unsheathes his claws and he's
like, oh never mind, I'm fine. Great way to
segue into the title card of the film, which
again revealed the new title Deadpool and Wolverine.
As well as the release date, which we all know
of July 26th. It's coming out this summer. Cannot
wait. I'm so hyped for it. I hope a lot of
people saw this trailer and are also hyped as
well because, you know, a lot of people are
kind of souring on the MCU as a whole and it'll
be great to have them back. Yeah, it does kind
of seem like this movie will in fact be Marvel
Jesus. It'll save the MCU. Right. It almost
makes me wonder if like Ryan Reynolds has been
telling Kevin Feige that, yeah, make these
upcoming Marvel projects like really sucky so
that my movie can save it. Obviously, that's
not the case, but it almost feels that way.
I was wondering if the TVA is like, oh, these
projects have been sucking. Like we need you
to save it. And he's like, yeah, I'm going
to save it. I do have to say that I'm kind of
bummed that they didn't show the last shot
of Wolverine in costume as brief as that was
during the Super Bowl teaser, because, you
know, it was much shorter what they showed on
television. And then they were like, see the
full trailer online. I hate when they do that.
I know it's a way for the studio to save money
because those Super Bowl commercial admin, it's
are pretty pricey. But still they should have
shown that specific shot because everyone who
saw that would have gotten totally pumped up.
Now you gotta save the money shot for later.
It's just a teaser. Just tease them and keep
them coming back for more. We'll see Wolverine
in costume and I bet you it'll be in the next
trailer that we get. Hopefully, it will be.
You're probably right. But the teaser trailer
looked great, super pumped. It was super funny.
And that brings us to our question of the week.
What has been your favorite Deadpool joke out
of all Deadpool media? There's been a lot of
them out there. There was the video game, the
Deadpool movies, there's the Deadpool comics.
What made you laugh the hardest and why? Yeah,
even the Deadpool teaser trailers. Why not?
Record your answer at dynamicduel.com by clicking
on the red microphone button in the bottom
right hand corner of the screen, which will
prompt you to leave us a voicemail. Your message
could be up to 30 seconds long, and don't forget
to leave your name in case we include you on
the podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer
and award that person a dynamic duel no prize
that we'll post to Instagram. Be sure to answer
before February 17th. In other news from Marvel
coming out this past week, we got a confirmation
not only from the Screen Actors Guild of America,
but also the director of Fantastic Four himself,
Matt Shacman, that Pedro Pascal has been cast
as Reed Richards' Mr. Fantastic in the upcoming
Fantastic Four film. Now... This has been rumored
for a couple of months now. The news was previously
dropped by Deadline, I believe, or Variety.
They reported that Pedro Pascal was in talks
to play the character. But you know, when the
director tweets out that the actor is playing
the role, it's pretty much confirmed. Loathe
as I am to say that Pedro Pascal got the role
because I was really hoping for John Krasinski
to return as Mr. Fantastic from his cameo in
Dr. Strange and the Multiverse of Venice, but
I am a Pedro Pascal fan. Yeah. The dude is hella
cool. Like when I grew up, I wanna be Pedro
Pascal. He does not necessarily look the part
of Reed Richards, at least not as I know him
from the comics. That's not to say that the
man cannot play this role. He looks like him
enough, and I think he can act the shit out
of this role. Oh, absolutely. Honestly, if
you had to give me a choice between who's more
charismatic, Pedro Pascal or John Krasinski,
Pedro Pascal. Honestly, I feel like... The whole
reason he was cast was sort of to be like a
new Robert Downey Jr. esque replacement for
the MCU. Yeah, maybe. I mean, you want as many
charismatic lead actors in these franchises
as you can get with all the actors that you
have at your disposal. Someone like Pedro Pascal
is certainly more charismatic than say Adam
Driver, who was previously rumored to be offered
the role of Mr. Fantastic. And honestly, yeah,
I am glad that Pedro Pascal got it over Adam
Driver. He's a little bit older, but, you know,
not as old as, say, Robert Downey Jr. Yeah.
Now, Pedro Pascal is no stranger to the world
of comic book movies. He did play the villain
of Maxwell Lord in the Wonder Woman 1984 film.
And he was one of the best parts of that movie.
Yeah, sure. Well, I mean, I guess there was
no good part of that movie, honestly. Shut the
hell up. But I think Pedro Pascal will make
a better Reed Richards than he did Maxwell Lord.
I'm sure he'll nail the role. Yeah. Now, joining
Pedro Pascal. Rounding out the Fantastic Four
cast, allegedly is Vanessa Kirby as the Invisible
Woman. Which is perfection. I woulda know, I
don't think I've seen her in anything. She
was in The Crown. I'm ashamed that I know that.
Um, but no, she's fantastic. I think she's
gonna be great in the role. Joseph Quinn will
be playing the Human Torch, who I'm also not
familiar with, and I hope I'm pronouncing this
right, Ebon Moss-Bachrock will be playing the
Thing. who I am familiar with because he played
Micro in season one of the Punisher Netflix
television series. I mean, he's no Michael Chiglis,
but he's a good actor too. They all look the
parts. It's a really interesting cast. I'm sure
that they'll nail it. None of this has officially
been confirmed, but it's all but confirmed,
we'll say. So an exciting time to be an MCU
fan. I hope as soon as they release this news
officially, that Marvel also produces a screen
test of what the costumes look like. Cause I
want to see Pedro Pascal, you know, with the
gray temples in the blue suit. Think it'd be
awesome just to get a feel for it. Yes, absolutely.
I bet you will see that at this year's Comic-Con.
Hopefully that'd be cool. Honestly, like I'm
hella jealous this week. They have such like
cool news for Marvel. Where's the DC news?
Like where's the Joker, Valiant Dude trailer?
Where's like the Superman screen test? Come
on. I want a Superman teaser poster at the very
least. Like yesterday. That's not going to
happen because DC is dumb. And Marvel's the
best. And they just reminded everybody of that
this week. And your silence right now speaks
volumes. I'm just quietly seething and plotting
your demise. Ha ha ha.
But I think that does it for all the news for
this episode, so let's go ahead and get into
our main event where we find out who'd win in
a fight between the multiversal characters
of Rocket and Spider-Gwen.
Alright, Rocket versus Spider-Gwen, also known
as Spider-Woman, also known as Ghost Spider,
but colloquially best probably known as Spider-Gwen.
We're pitting her up against Rocket, who is
a character from Milestone Comics, best known
as the sidekick to the hero Icon, but she also
had a stint in the Young Justice animated television
series. Right, which is a series focused around
sidekicks, and so yeah, she played a role in
the show. She's a prominent black character
as all milestone media superheroes are because
it's a black-owned comics company that focuses
on creating and fostering great BIPOC characters
in comics. So we also figured that this was
a great tie-in to Black History Month. We've
never done a milestone comics character before.
They're quasi-multi-versal. They were for a
time brought into Prime DC continuity. But
yeah, I thought she counted as a multi-versal
character. And the reason that we thought this
would be a good match and our executive producers
agreed was due to their power sets both being
based around basically speed and durability
with some range based attacks. Exactly. Yeah.
So let's get into it to explain the methodology
behind our duels. Let's go to our sentient
dual simulator Alfred Jarvis 9000. AJ9K tell
our listeners how you go about determining
a winner in our dual matchups. Yes, of course,
sir. The way I determine a winner between the
contestants is by running 1000 Monte Carlo simulations
using the characters statistics. A Monte Carlo
simulation is a probabilistic model used to
determine outcomes through random sampling.
In this case, I randomise the statistics along
a normal distribution as a way to simulate
the many variables that can occur during battle.
The stat parameters are based on the official
Marvel power grid from which the DC characters
statistics are extrapolated.
damage potential, versatility and perception
in order to create a more detailed and accurate
simulation. The results of the 1000 simulations
provide a percentage of wins for each character.
The contestant with the higher percentage is
declared the victor as they have a higher probability
to win any given battle. In an equitable pairing,
neither character should win 100% of the matches.
The comic book stories have shown that there's
even a way for Batman to defeat Superman. So
the confidence rate of my method falls in line
with the precedents that have been established
in the source material. My mathematical simulations
are without subjectivity or bias. Feats are
not the sole consideration, nor are fan votes
tabulated for determination of the winner.
Thanks AJ9K! Before we run the simulations though,
we like to break down each character's histories
and abilities before improvising a scenario
on how we imagine one of the 1000 simulations
would play out, beat for beat. And it's my turn
to go first with the DC character, so let me
tell you all about Rocket. Now Raquel Irvin
was born and raised on Paris Island, the poorest
neighborhood of the fictional city of Dakota
in the alternate universe of Earth 1993, aka
Earth-M, aka the Dakotaverse. Paris Island was
notorious for its high crime rates and violent
gang warfare. which culminated in a massive
war and riot between all of the gangs in the
neighborhood on one night known as the Big Bang.
That same night, knowing the police would have
their hands full, Raquel's boyfriend Noble and
his friends drove her to the wealthy Dakota
suburb of Prospect Hills to help burglarize
one of its mansions. Though Raquel was a bright
15-year-old girl as an aspiring writer, the
idea of getting her hands on a typewriter or
computer proved too tempting. and she agreed
to join them. Though they believed they were
stealing from a rich white man, in reality,
they were stealing from Augustus Freeman IV,
a black corporate lawyer who was secretly an
ancient and superpowered alien stranded on
Earth. Augustus confronted the youths, surviving
multiple gunshots and flying to catch those
attempting to flee, including Raquel. Freeman
let them go on the condition that they told
no one about him and promised never to steal
again. Inspired by what he could do, Raquel
later went back to Freeman's mansion with sketches
of him and her in superhero costumes, encouraging
him to use his powers to help his community
as a superhero named Icon, while making her
his sidekick or partner, Rocket, so that she
could have adventures to write about. Freeman
was reluctant initially, but was inspired by
Raquel and Dakota's recent upheaval during
the Big Bang to adopt the superhero identity
of Icon, and gift Raquel with a belt made from
alien technology that would allow her to fight
alongside him. Despite initially being mistaken
for criminals during their first mission to
rescue Dakota's mayor, Thomasina Jefferson,
Icon and Rocket successfully saved the mayor
from a mutated monster known as Payback, who
revealed to them that during the night of the
Big Bang, Mayor Jefferson authorized the local
police department to use an experimental tear
gas that was laced with a radioactive marker
that would allow them to subdue and later track
the gang members involved. Instead, the tear
gas killed all but a small minority that either
mutated or developed special powers. While
Icahn investigated Payback's claims as a lawyer,
Raquel dealt with the realization from Icahn's
superhuman senses that she was in early-stage
pregnancy. Though Noble and her mother Sandra
encouraged Raquel to have an abortion, Raquel
decided to keep the baby. After several adventures,
including taking on the Big Bang-powered gang
known as the Blood Syndicate, Raquel was forced
to give up superheroics and allowed her best
friend Darnice to assume the mantle of Rocket
for a short time. Raquel eventually gave birth
to a son, whom she named Amistad Augustus Irvin.
While Raquel was on maternity leave, Freeman
found a way to return to his home planet, supporting
Raquel with a trust that provided her monthly
checks while he was away. When an alien threat
known as Oblivion arrived on Earth to kill Freeman,
Icon returned to Earth, as did Raquel as his
partner, Rocket, once again. Upon Oblivion's
defeat, Freeman decided to remain on Earth,
and Raquel continued as his partner while also
raising Amistad. Though Raquel and Freeman
often clashed, due to their conflicting political
viewpoints, Raquel did develop a close relationship
with another teenage hero of the city of Dakota,
Static. As in Static Shock? Yeah, I mean, the
name of the cartoon was Static Shock, but the
character's name is Static. That's right, he's
a milestone character. Yes, yeah. Now during
the final crisis, when the villain Darkseid
acquired the anti-life equation in DC's Prime
Universe, the existence of the Dakotaverse
was threatened. though a being known as Dharma
managed to merge the city of Dakota into DC
Prime. Though Freeman remembered Dakota once
being part of a separate universe, Raquel and
other members of Dakota were unaware of the
merger, and Raquel remained Freeman's partner
in the new continuity that was created. In the
new DC universe, Icon was a member of a secret
organization of superheroes known as the Shadow
Cabinet, who were attacked by the Justice League
while on a mission to Metropolis. At the behest
of Icon, Rocket joined the Shadow Cabinet and
helped protect its agents from the League, going
toe to toe with Batman. The two teams eventually
joined forces to defeat the villain Shadow Thief,
and Icon and Rocket returned to Dakota, which
they continued to protect. In post-Flashpoint
continuity, Raquel's origin remained largely
unchanged, though upon Icon's and Rocket's initial
mission to stop the drug trade, their actions
ended up nearly crippling the global economy.
In response, the United States government hired
an alien assassin known as Mr. Lord to kill
Icon and Rocket. With help from Static, Icon
and Rocket were able to bring down Mr. Lord
instead. Now powers-wise, Rocket is equipped
with an inertia belt made from alien technology
from Icon's escape pod that crash-landed him
on Earth over a century ago. The inertia belt
generates a usually invisible field around
rocket that absorbs the kinetic energy of anything
that crosses its surface, allowing rocket to
store that energy for a variety of uses, including
powerful energy punches, the ability to redirect
that energy into thrown projectiles or focused
energy beams, and high speed flight and maneuverability.
Rocket can also surround opponents in an inertialist
field, preventing them from moving or even
breathing, though this uses a large amount of
her stored energy and can only last for a few
seconds. Any use of the energy stored by her
belt drains some of its power. And that's Rocket!
I don't know much about the Milestone universe.
I completely forgot that static is a part of
it, and it makes me think that we gotta get
static in a duel sometime. Yeah, I would say
Static and Icon are kind of the flagship characters
of Milestone, although there's also Hardware.
Now, the experimental tear gas that the mayor
used on the gang members, is that the same
mutagen that transformed Static's rogues gallery?
Yes. Yeah, they go into the Big Bang on the
cartoon, although it's a little bit different.
Interesting. Pretty cool character. I'm interested
in seeing how this fight will go out, especially
with that inertia belt. But Gwen Stacy's got
some tricks up her sleeves. Let me go into her
backstory. In the Marvel Comics Multiverse,
in the timeline of Earth-616, Gwen Stacy was
Peter Parker, aka Spider-Man's, first true
love. The two met at Empire State University
and began dating, however she was tragically
killed by the Green Goblin who threw her off
the George Washington Bridge. You can learn
more about the Green Goblin in his duel against
the Joker, and more about Spider-Man in his
duel against Blue Beetle. Gwen's death was a
defining moment in Spider-Man's life where
he realized the full extent of the loss he could
experience as a hero. However, in another universe,
Earth-65, Gwen's Stacey story went a little
different. Born in Forest Hills and Queens
to Helen and George Stacey, Gwen also experienced
loss from a young age when her mother died,
leaving her dad, an NYPD captain, to raise her
as a single father. To cope with her grief
and overbearing home life, Gwen rebelled from
her ballerina dancing lessons to take out her
frustrations playing the drums. At Midtown High
School, she became good friends with several
students, including the shy but brilliant Peter
Parker, the rebellious but affluent Harry Osborn,
and the outgoing Mary Jane Watson, the latter
of whom also shared a love of music and formed
a band called the Mary Janes with Gwen and their
friends Betty and Glory. One day, Gwen was
bitten by a genetically engineered spider by
random chance, altering her physiology and
granting her the powers of a spider. Though
she initially thought she could use her powers
to win money for her band in a charity wrestling
match, she stumbled upon a thief who was about
to kill Ben Parker, her friend Peter's uncle.
After saving Ben's life, she was inspired instead
to use her new ability selflessly and became
a masked crime fighter by the name of Spider
Woman. As Gwen's heroic reputation throughout
New York grew, she was gifted a pair of web-shooters
by the retired superhero, the Wasp. Gwen struggled
to balance life as a student, rock musician,
and superhero, but her misfortunes came to a
head during her school prom where she was set
to perform with the Mary Janes. Her friend Peter
Parker idolized Spider-Woman and believed he
could become a hero and avoid being bullied
if he could also get similar superpowers. After
experimenting with lizards, Peter turned himself
into a mindless lizard-like creature that crashed
the prom. Unaware that the lizard was her friend
Peter, Gwen asked Spider-Woman beat the creature
despite its pleas to stop. The lizard, severely
injured, reverted back to Peter Parker, who
died from his wounds in Spider-Woman's arms,
his last words stating that he just wanted
to be special like her. Shocked at what she
had done, Gwen fled the scene branded a murderer.
She was pursued by the police, including her
father who saw Spider-Woman as a criminal.
Haunted by Peter's death, she learned that with
great power must come great responsibility
to not abuse that power, and she sought redemption
through helping others. She came out odds with
the Kingpin of Crime and his right-hand man,
a villain named Daredevil, who was the leader
of the Hand Ninja Clan. Looking to appease Spider-Woman
and bring them into their fold as an ally,
the Hand went after police captain George Stacey.
After thwarting the murder attempt, Gwen was
held at gunpoint by her father and was forced
to reveal her secret identity to him. Unable
to arrest his daughter, Captain Stacy asked
her to leave before he changed his mind. Shortly
after, Gwen was recruited to join other spider-powered
heroes from across the multiverse to band together
to defeat a vampiric race of beings known as
the Inheritors who were intent on consuming
those representing the Spider Totem in order
to prevent their prophesied destruction. She
enjoyed seeing Peter Parker alive and well fighting
as Spider-Man in multiple universes, as well
as getting to know fellow Spider-Heroes Jessica
Drew and Miles Morales, both of whom you can
learn more about in our Queen Bee vs Spider-Woman
and Batwing vs Spider-Man duels, respectively.
After their battle, Gwen ended up returning
to her universe and made up with her father.
When the Marvel multiverse collapsed in on itself
in a series of universe-ending incursions,
villain Doctor Doom used the usurped power of
the all-powerful beings known as the Beyonders
to save everything by fashioning a Patrick planet
of all universes called Battleworld. You can
learn more about this in our Doctor Doom duel
against Superman. Finding herself in the domain
of Arachnia, Gwen teamed up with other Spider
heroes such as Spider-Man Noir, Spider-Ham,
and Spider-Man India to form a team called the
Web Warriors who together defeated the Sinister
Six and Mayor Norman Osborn. Gwen and the team
would go on to travel across the then restored
multiverse to defend the Web of Life and Destiny,
which was a construct of fate previously overseen
by the mysterious Madame Web that was the source
of her precognition and the source of the Spider-Sense
powers shared by Spider-Heroes. For a brief
period, Gwen stayed in Earth-616 to visit Jessica
Drew, where she learned more about the mainstream
Marvel universes Gwen Stacy and Peter Parker.
Returning to her home timeline, Gwen discovered
that her former friend Harry Osborn had gone
mad with guilt that he couldn't prevent the
death of Peter Parker and had sworn vengeance
on Spider-Woman. He took a modified version
of Peter's lizard formula and transformed into
the Green Goblin, fighting and unmasking Spider-Woman.
When it was revealed that his enemy was also
his former friend Gwen, the formula caused him
to lose control. With an assist by Captain
America, Gwen was able to administer a serum
suppressant and the Green Goblin was defeated.
However, shortly after, Gwen lost her own powers
after receiving a similar suppressant. Meanwhile,
at OzCorp, a scientist named Elsa Brock combined
the company's spider research with her work
on an alien parasite and Peter Parker's formula
to inadvertently create the Venom symbiote,
which ended up bonding with Gwen, transforming
her into Gwenem and restoring her powers. You
can learn more about Klintar symbiotes in our
Clayface vs Venom and Lobo vs Carnage dual
episodes. The symbiote had a vicious hold on
Gwen that compelled her to unleash her inner
anger on her enemies and even allies. Fearful
of her own actions, she surrendered herself
to the international law enforcement agency
known as SHIELD where she was imprisoned for
a time. Discovering how to control the symbiote,
Gwen rejoined the Web Warriors and renamed
herself forming a slight romantic relationship
with fellow Spider-Hero Miles Morales. Looking
to learn more about the symbiote, but unable
to find Dr. Elsa Brock, Gwen traveled to Earth-616
to have it studied by the mainstream Spider-Man.
She ended up staying on Earth-616, where she
pursued a degree at Empire State University.
And that's her backstory. Powers-wise, Spider-Gwen
has Spider-based abilities granted to her by
the genetically altered Spider that bit her,
and later, the genetically altered symbiote.
With these enhancements, she has increased
speed, agility, durability, and strength, able
to lift up to 10 tons. She can stick to any
surface, and can fire symbiote-generated webbing
to ensnare enemies and swing from buildings.
The symbiote also lets her camouflage her appearance,
hence the name Ghost Spider, grants her a healing
factor, and she can generate small symbiotic
offshoots that resemble spiders that she can
use to scout environments. In addition, Ghost
Spider has a precognitive spider sense that
warns her of oncoming danger and wears a pendant
that allows her to travel the multiverse. She's
a reasonable detective having learned investigation
tips from her father and is a talented musician
and former ballerina. Because she is the host
of a modified Klyntar symbiote, she is weak
to extreme heat and sonic based attacks. Wait,
who says you gotta go with this Venom version
of the character? That is the existing and long-standing
version of the character. Is this the version
with like the teeth all over the hood? That
was her outfit when she first got the Venom
symbiote. Yes. But ever since she started going
by Ghost Spider, she has gone with her traditional
Spider-Woman outfit. OK, interesting. Didn't
I realize that she had a symbiote that kind
of changes things? We'll see how this goes.
Yeah, I mean, it's a nice way to differentiate
her from Spider-Man, you know. Miles Morales
has his bioelectricity and his ability to turn
invisible. Gwen has her symbiote powers. Like,
her universe's version of the Klyntar are basically
alien spiders, and her suit is basically comprised
of those small spiders. Interesting. Yeah,
she calls them gummy spiders, and she uses them
to gather intel. It's pretty cool stuff. She
uses the symbiote in a way that, like, none
of the other symbiotes have used it.
But now that we've got their histories and abilities
out of the way, let's speculate on how one
of the 1000 simulated matches will go. The winner
is determined by simulations, not this speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how this fight could
play out. AJ9K, what are the rules of our speculation?
Well, I should say there are no rules, other
than the characters have no prior knowledge
of the other going into the fight. All they
are aware of starting out is that the other
character is a threat that needs to be eliminated.
For the speculation, the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a non-descript
environment that will have no bearing on the
match itself, as no environmental statistics
are considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. Alright
then let's get into it. Rocket and Spider Gwen
meet on the battlefield. Who goes first? I'm
gonna say Spider Gwen starts this match off
because like, Rocket can't do shit anyway without
having absorbed any kinetic energy. No, no,
rocket's starting off this match with a sizable
amount of kinetic energy already stored up.
Nice try. But Spider Gwen's gonna go first anyway.
She's gonna leap into the air and she shoots
a pair of web strands on each side of rocket.
And she's gonna use them like a slingshot to
just fling herself right into rocket with a
flying kick. But it's like a graceful ballerina
flying kick. Okay, so. Spider Gwen, you know,
she's probably strong enough to knock Rocket
back with an attack like that, but it's not
going to hurt her because, you know, the energy
from the attack just gets absorbed into Rockets
and nourish her field, which she's going to
use to bounce back and rocket herself right
into Spider Gwen, delivering a kinetic energy
punch that's just going to send Gwen flying.
But you forgot, my friend, that Spidey sense
is a thing. Oh, my God, that Spider Gwen has.
So she's going to dodge this oncoming attack
from Rocket. with some like mid-air splits type
stuff. And she's gonna shoot a web line that
sticks to Rocket and Rocket gets redirected
from the web line and gets slammed right into
the ground. Would Rocket's field block the webbing?
I mean, even if it did, it would still stick
to the field. No, it doesn't work like that.
I'm guessing like the webbing probably doesn't
hold much kinetic energy actually, because it's
not like when they stick to people, they impact
the people. So sure, let's say the webs get
through Rocket's field, when she's slammed
into the ground, like again, it's not going
to hurt Rocket. She's just going to absorb
the force of the ground hitting her and gain
more energy. But the impact of the ground against
her inertia field does break some stones loose
from the ground, which Rocket is just going
to pick up and hurl at Gwen like bullets. Spider
Gwen's just going to like bullet time dodge
that shit, you know, like Beatrix type stuff.
OK, we'll dodge this. Rocket, she's gonna fire
off a focused beam of kinetic energy like a
laser, which is, you know, a lot faster than
bullets. So Gwen for sure gets tagged and knocks
to the ground. Okay, uh, I mean, but Gwen's
durable, you know, she'll take this kinetic
force blast, like a champ, and she gets knocked
down, she'll just perform this like backward
somersault into like a back handspring and
she's back on her feet. No biggie. But then,
using her symbiote, she's gonna camouflage
herself. to blend into the environment that
they're in, so Rocket can no longer see her.
Ooh, good move. Okay, I mean, Rocket's probably
a little freaked out and looking around because
she knows that she's vulnerable to stealth attacks,
right? So she's gonna take to the air and she's
gonna shoot up into the sky just to keep her
distance. Oh, too late though. Suddenly Rocket
gets yanked down as she tries to take off. and
gets pulled back toward the ground where she
lands in this giant sticky web net that traps
her and prevents her from moving. Shit. Uh,
we're gonna test the strength of these webs.
As soon as Rocket gets trapped, she's gonna
blast herself sideways, like trying to pull
herself free from the webs. And as Rocket's
trying to free herself, bam! Spider-Gwen reappears
and straight up kicks Rocket right in the face.
And Rocket's like, out of my face! Okay, actually
that kick... just gave her the extra amount
of energy she needed to break free of those
webs. And she's going to quickly fly at Gwen
and trap her in an inertialist field. So Gwen
is frozen there for a few seconds, just unable
to move or dodge this kinetic punch that's so
powerful that Rocket's going to spend all of
her stored kinetic energy to deliver it. And
this punch could like knock back Icon and destroy
a building. So Gwen essentially explodes from
the force of it. Match over. Actually, at the
very start of the match, you know, when Gwen
first made contact with Rocket by kicking her,
Uh huh. At that point, Gwen actually imparted
several symbiote spiders onto Rocket that have
been crawling over her, making their way into
Rocket's inertia belt and just gumming up that
technology and making it useless. So when Rocket
goes in for this like powerful kinetic punch
killing blow, she's actually just powerless.
She has no more power. Doesn't work. And then
at that point, Spider Gwen is freed from her
inertialist field and lays an everloving beat
down on Rocket. And that is how this match is
won. Actually, I don't know, Spider Gwen gets
punched before the spiders ever make it to her
belt. So, yeah, that's what actually happens.
But yeah, we'll leave the match here. Either
Rocket delivers this explosive kinetic punch
that just vaporizes Spider Gwen or Spider Gwen
managed to get these gummy spiders onto Rocket
early in the match that gum up her alien technology
belt, rendering her powerless and defenseless
against Spider-Gwen's fatal barrage of attacks.
To find out which of these scenarios happens,
let's plug in the stats for these characters,
run the simulations, and come back with a winner.
AJ9K, hit it! Inputting data. Running calculations.
Processing results. Simulations complete. Alright,
so- These characters are actually pretty similar
in more ways than I thought. Like they both
wear outfits that are alien in nature. They're
both highly agile. They could both trap their
opponents. But there were a few differences.
Like we said, Rocket is actually faster than
Spider Gwynn. Right. And more evasive as well,
considering she's constantly wearing essentially
a force field. However, we did say Gwynn was
more durable and stronger than Rocket. Yeah,
when it came to the physical stats. Gwen definitely
came out on top because Rocket is just a human
after all. That said, she does pack quite a
powerful punch, capable of some pretty powerful
attacks, so we gave her the edge damage level
wise. When it came to fighting skill, intelligence,
versatility, they basically balanced out. We
said that Rocket has a greater range, but Spider
Gwen has greater perception due to not only
her spider sense, but also her symbiote spiders
that can feed her intel. So taking all of this
into account, who do you think came out on
top? Joseph? I have no damn clue. This is an
interesting one. I can't really tell based
off the stats who's going to win. I thought
this was a pretty good match. Honestly, I'm
pulling for Spider Gwen, though, and Instagram
agrees with me. Sixty five percent of the people
who participated in our poll picked Spider Gwen
to win this fight. Well, that's just because
Rocket has yet to be in a film. Milestone actually
is making a few animated projects, I believe.
So hopefully that changes soon. But let's find
out if you're right. AJ9K, the results please.
Hey, you are, sir. All right, the winner of
the matchup between Rocket and Spider-Gwen
is Spider-Gwen. Hell yeah. She won 58.3% of
the 1000 matches or 583 matches total, as compared
to Rocket who won 417. All right, so what was
the stat that gave Spider-Gwen her greatest
advantage? It was two of them. It was perception
and strength. Now, Rocket is strong when it
comes to punches, when it comes to like lifting
strength, not so much. And I mean, Spider-Sense
is conceptually hard to overcome. I feel like
Spider-Gwen could just dodge Rocket's attacks
all day long. I mean, it's not like Spider-Gwen
can do much to hurt Rocket either. Well, I
mean, except for the whole stealth attack thing.
Shit. Yeah, I guess this makes sense. And it
makes sense that Marvel would win like every
fight, right? It never makes sense to me when
Marvel loses. Marvel is just better as you learned
here today. I didn't learn shit. That does
it for this duel. Let us know what you thought
about the results by writing to us at dynamic
dual podcast at gmail.com or by visiting us
on Instagram, which you can find a link to
in our show notes or by visiting our website
at dynamic dual dot com. And on our site, you
could also find a link to our Patreon page where
you could join our dynamic two tier. and chat
with us and fellow listeners. Our fantastic
four tier, which gets you bonus content each
month. Our X force tier that makes you an executive
producer of this podcast. Or our newest tier
that lets you join our Dynamike podcast network.
Please don't forget to rate the show on Apple
podcast, Spotify, Podchaser, or on our website.
Our next episode is one that I am dreading.
We're gonna review Madam Webb, and I don't wanna
see that crap. It looks so bad. I hope it's
not. Yeah, I don't even have my tickets yet.
But it's probably going to be. Yeah, I don't
even have my tickets yet. Yeah, I gotta get
my tickets, gotta go see the movie. We'll talk
all about it next week. Fingers crossing it's
at least watchable. But that does it for this
episode. We wanna give a big thanks to our executive
producers, Ken Johnson, John Swarovski, Zachary
Hepburn, Dustin Balcom, Miggy Mathingian, Brandon
Anstragard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yeaton,
Nick Abonto, Austin Wisselowski, AJ Dunkerley,
Scott Camacho. Adam Spies, Andrew Schunk, and
Dean Molesky for helping to make this podcast
possible. We'll talk to you guys next week.
Up up and away, true believers.