This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
Hey and welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast,
a weekly show where we review superhero films
and debate the superiority between Marvel and
DC by comparing their characters and stat-based
battle simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe. And I'm
his twin brother Johnny DC. And in this episode,
guys, we're going to find out who would win
in a fight between DC's The Monitor and Marvel's
The Watcher. Now we're coming straight off of
our review of What If Season 3 in which The
Watcher Uwatu plays a prominent role, and the
executive producers figured now was as good
a time as any to use that character in a duel
and find out who would win when we put him
against DC's equivalent. Yeah, for a while there
we were considering doing anti-Monitor or maybe
Metron against Watcher, but we voted on Monitor.
This speculation will get pretty interesting.
Yeah, we'll find out who will win between those
two characters later on this episode. Before
that, we're going to break down the comic book
movie news to come out this past week of which
there was none. You get nothing. You stole fizzy
lifting drinks. Good day, sir. Yeah, there's
a ton of rumors going on out there right now
in regards to both the DCU and MCU, but nothing
really concrete. We will be breaking down this
week's no prize winners and giving a question
of the week though. As always, we list our segment
times in our episode description, so feel free
to check out the show notes if you want to skip
ahead to a particular topic. Our artificially
intelligent Duel simulator AJ9K has a quick
message for our listeners, so listen up. Why
hello there, do you want even more from this
podcast? Then become a part of the dynamic
Duel community on Patreon, where you can choose
from three tiers. The dynamic two-oh tier gives
you access to our Discord chat server. The fantastic
four tier gives you two bonus episodes each
month, and the X-Force tier makes you an executive
producer of this show. Lastly, The Diner Mike
podcast network tier lets you create your own
podcast using this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny
and Joe will help you develop your show, provide
graphic support and consultation, and get you
simulation results. Pitch the twins your ideas
via email at dynamicduelpodcast at gmail.com.
Check it out at patreon.com slash dynamicduel.
Pip pip cheerio. Thanks AJ and AK and thanks
to everyone who supports the podcast. Be sure
guys to tune into the other shows in the DynaMic
Podcast Network this week including Max Destruction
which pits your favorite action heroes from
film and television against each other. This
week, hosts Scotty and Gilly are finding out
who would win between Homelander from The Boys
and Omni-Man from Invincible. It's a big one.
On the Send Your World podcast, host Zachary
Hepburn speculates on fights between fan favorite
anime and manga characters. Zach is off this
week, but make sure to check out his latest
episodes if you have not already. On the Console
Combat podcast, host John and Dean simulate
battles between popular video game characters.
In yesterday's episode, they found out who
would win between Jax from Mortal Kombat and
Jack 8 from Tekken. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com
or click the link in our show notes to listen
to all of the shows in the DynaMic Podcast
Network. But with that out of the way, quick
to the no prize. A No Prize is an award Marvel
used to give out to fans. Our version, the Dynamic
Duel No Prize, is a digital award that we pushed
on Instagram for the person we feel gave the
best answer to our question of the week. Last
week we asked you guys if you could recast any
other DCEU actor in a DCU role, who would it
be and why? And this is coming off the news
that Jason Momoa has been cast as Lobo in James
Gunn's new DC movie universe. having previously
been in the DCEU of course as Aquaman. We got
a total of four answers, so we have three honorable
mentions to go over before revealing this week's
no-price winner. Our first honorable mention
goes to Colby Henches, who said, Hey boys,
Colby Henches. If any DCEU actor were coming
back, I'd like to see it be everybody's favorite
Flash Thompson, Joe Manganiello. He only got
to be Deathstroke for like two seconds on screen.
I'd love to see him come back as Deathstroke,
but if we're recasting, I think he'd be a great
Midnighter in the upcoming Authority movie.
Yeah, Deathstroke is an A-tier villain in DC
Comics, not only for teams like the Titans,
but also the Justice League. I would love to
see him in action on screen in a way that we
haven't before, like on the small screen with
the Titans show or even Arrow. And yeah, Joe
Manganiello was definitely robbed of the opportunity
to play that badass character in a movie. No
one quite has had it as bad, I think, as Joe
Manganiello. So I think he would be great in
the role. I think he deserves to be seen. Yeah,
100%. I also would have hated him as Midnighter,
but I would let him choose what role he wanted
to play. Great answer, Colby Hentges. Let's
go ahead and move on to our next honorable
mention given by Miggy Matangian, who said.
Hey, what's up, guys? This is Miggy, and if
I could recast a DCEU actor in the DCU, I would
probably go with Keirsey Clemens as Miss Martian.
She played Iris West previously. I think she
just kind of has the vibe to like play an innocent
character who's secretly hiding something. I
could also see Jack Dylan Grazer as Beast Boy.
Thanks guys. Yeah, those are both great options
for young heroes within DC. I totally get what
you're coming from with Kirsi Clemens. Kind
of having those doe eyes makes her look innocent
and cute like you mentioned. I don't know if
you mentioned the cute part. I added that part.
But yeah, Miss Martian should be cute. Jack
Dylan Grazer as Beast Boy 2 is also a top choice.
I will miss Ryan Potter in the role, but yeah,
Jack Dylan Grazer has all of the qualities
that I think you would want in a Beast Boy actor.
If Keirce Clemens was Ms. Martian, who would
you cast as Marsha Manhunter? Oh, Dennis Haysbert.
Terrific voice, great actor. I think you would
be perfect. That's a good call, that's a good
call. Great answer, Miggy Mathenkean. Our next
honorable mention goes to Brandon Estregard,
who said. Hey guys. If I was able to bring
back one actor from the DCU, it would have to
be Eldris Hodge. I would cast him as Icon,
and for bonus I would cast Bailey Bass as Rocket.
Yeah, Eldris Hodge is another great actor that
I will definitely miss if he's not brought back
for James Gunn's DCU. I think he would make,
like, really any great superhero. I would love
to see him as Icon, because I would love for
there to be an Icon movie. That would be a fantastic
story to put on the screen, for sure. Icons
like Superman, but he's different enough where
I think audiences would really latch onto it.
I'm not familiar with Bailey Bass. I guess she
was an avatar, the second one. But yeah, from
the looks of it, I think she would be a terrific
Rocket as well. Yeah, we pit Rocket against
Spider-Gwen in a Duel episode. If you guys want
to learn more about Icon and Rocket. But great
answer, Brandon Estregard. The winner of this
week's No Prize goes to Noah Terry, who said,
Hey, guys, so if I could recast any TCU actor
into the DCU, it would be Asher Angel aka Billy
Batson as Nightwing. I think that he can definitely
act with heart. He's no stranger to action
and he would just be a great fit to see him
in Batman, the Brave and the Bold. So that's
my answer. Thanks, bye guys. Yeah, I cannot
wait to see Nightwing on the big screen. He's
a really important character. You know, besides
the Trinity, I think he's probably the fourth
most important character in DC comics. And Asher
Angel definitely has the look for Nightwing.
He may be a little young for the character,
but hey, if that's the case, there's always
Red Hood. By the time the movie comes out, he'll
be old enough. Do you think he would do as
good of a job as Dick Grayson as Chris O'Donnell
did? Yeah, that's not even a question. I'm
not concerned about that. My big concern is
can he do a better job than Brenton Thwaites
from the Titan series? because Brenton Thwaites
is a phenomenal actor and he did way better
than was even necessary for the character of
Dick Grayson in Nightwing in that show. That's
true, yeah, he would be the guy to beat. He's
by far the best Dick Grayson on screen. Great
answer, Noah Terry, you win this week's No Prize.
If you, the listener, want a shot at winning
your own No Prize, stay tuned to later on this
episode when we'll be asking another Question
of the Week. And now that that's done, on to
the news. There is no news. That's right, nevermind.
On to the question of the week.
What Marvel or DC theatrical film are you most
looking forward to in 2025? That of course
includes Superman, which is DC's only theatrical
release this year, Captain America Brave New
World, which releases in just about a month,
The Fantastic Four First Steps, or Thunderbolts.
Let us know which one you guys are most pumped
to see in theaters in 2025. Record your answer
at dynamicduel.com by clicking on the red microphone
button in the bottom right-hand corner of the
screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long, and don't forget to leave your name in
case we include you on the podcast. We'll pick
our favorite answer and award that person a
Dynamic Duel No Prize that we'll post to Instagram.
Be sure to answer before January 18th.
But I think we're ready now to go ahead and
dive into our duel and find out who would win
in a fight between DC's monitor and Marvel's
watcher.
Alright, the Monitor versus the Watcher. Now,
as I mentioned earlier, we're doing this episode
as a tie-in to the review of What If Season
3, which we spoke about last episode. At the
end of that season, the character of the Watcher,
also known as Uwatu, kicks all kinds of ass.
He throws down against the other Watchers, and
it was really a sight to behold. It was a great
way to close out the show, despite the fact
that it kinda goes against the pacifist ideals
of the character. So this will be an interesting
duel to get through in pitting two guys who
are basically sworn to inaction against each
other. Yeah, that's more of a watcher thing
than a monitor thing. But yeah, these are essentially
two characters who weren't created to interact
in any way. They were just created to observe.
So in determining how these characters would
fight, we had to get kind of creative. Yeah,
we've gotten creative in a few of our duel
episodes before. Like if you listen to the Riddler
versus Arcade, those are two characters. who
don't really throw down a lot. You know, they
use their mind in the battle, which is always
hard to speculate on. So we ended up coming
up with riddles to give each other to see who
had the strongest mind. In the Mephisto versus
Sandman duel episode, there was a game that
was played between Sandman and the devil in
the Sandman comic book series that we decided
to run with for that duel speculation. And that
was a lot of fun. And even if you look at our
most recent duel episode, the one we did at
the end of last year, where we pit dog pool
against ace the bat hound. That was a different
take. We put them against each other in a dog
show because we didn't really wanna see two
dogs tearing each other apart like in an actual
dog fight. So we've gotten creative with this
stuff before and I'm really excited to show
you guys how we're going to pit these two observers
against each other and test their observational
skills. Yeah, I'm looking forward to that. I'm
also looking forward to just giving the backstory
of the monitor because giving the backstory
of the monitor. is kind of like giving the
backstory of the DC universe as a whole. So
I kind of feel like this is a special episode.
That's gonna be a really boring story. You could
fuck you, fuck you. To explain our methodology
behind our duels, let's go to our sentient Duel
simulator, Alfred Jarvis 9000. AJ 9K, tell
our listeners how you go about determining a
winner in our Duel matchups. Yes, of course,
sir. The way I determine a winner between the
contestants is by running 1000 Monte Carlo
simulations using the characters statistics.
A Monte Carlo simulation is a probabilistic
model used to determine outcomes through random
sampling. In this case, I randomize the statistics
along a normal distribution as a way to simulate
the many variables that can occur during battle.
The stat parameters are based on the official
Marvel power grid from which the DC characters
statistics are extrapolated. Additional stat
categories are included such as range, damage
potential, versatility and perception in order
to create a more detailed and accurate simulation.
The results of the 1000 simulations provide
a percentage of wins for each character. The
contestant with the higher percentage is declared
the victor as they have a higher probability
to win any given battle. In an equitable pairing,
neither character should win 100% of the matches.
The comic book stories have shown that there's
even a way for Batman to defeat Superman. So
the confidence rate of my method falls in line
with the precedents that have been established
in the source material. My mathematical simulations
are without subjectivity or bias. Feats are
not the sole consideration, nor are fan votes
tabulated for determination of the winner.
Thanks AJ and NK. Before we run the simulations
though, we like to break down each character's
histories and abilities before improvising a
scenario on how we imagine one of the 1000
simulations would play out. Beat for beat. And
I believe it's my turn to go first with the
Marvel character, so let me go ahead and tell
you guys all about Uwatu the Watcher. The Watchers
are one of the most ancient and advanced races
in the Marvel Universe, originating billions
of years ago. Known initially as the Luminous,
they were revered for their vast knowledge
and cosmic power, capable of transforming their
bodies into light and traversing the universe
in an instant. Their altruistic mission began
with the noble goal of sharing their advanced
knowledge to uplift less developed civilizations
and foster universal progress. However, their
first attempt to aid the planet Prasilius by
introducing nuclear technology ended in catastrophic
failure. The Prasilikans weaponized the knowledge,
plunging the world into a devastating nuclear
war that annihilated their race. Ashamed and
burdened by guilt, the Luminous took a solemn
vow to observe and record the universe without
interference, renaming themselves the Watchers.
Relocating to various parts of the cosmos, they
built an extraordinary repository of knowledge
called the Acycopedia Universum, and established
their sacred code of non-interference. Over
millennia, they became cosmic chroniclers, silently
witnessing the unfolding history of the universe,
preserving its secrets, and standing as eternal
guardians of knowledge. The lessons from Priscilla
Kiss forever shaped their philosophy, instilling
a deep-seated fear of unintended consequences
and their cosmic responsibilities. Among the
Watchers, Uatu was uniquely drawn to the complexity
and resilience of Earth and its solar system.
Establishing his base in the blue area of the
moon, Uatu faithfully upheld his duties for
millennia. His father, Ikor, was a staunch
advocate of the Watcher's Code, shaping Uatu's
early understanding of their mission and instilling
in him a deep sense of responsibility. Despite
his upbringing, Uatu developed a profound fascination
with humanity and its capacity for both greatness
and destruction. The unique Duelity of human
nature with its boundless potential deeply resonated
with Uatu, fostering a strong emotional connection
with Earth's inhabitants. Uatu's first recorded
interaction with humanity occurred in 1602,
when a temporarily displaced Captain America
threatened to unravel the time stream. Uatu
revealed himself to an Elizabethan-era Doctor
Strange who was instrumental in facilitating
Captain America's return to his rightful time,
thus preserving the integrity of the timeline.
This event marked the beginning of a long history
of subtle interventions that would define Uatu's
role as Earth's watcher. In modern times, Uatu's
fascination with humanity deepened when the
Fantastic Four ventured to the moon and discovered
his citadel. You can learn more about the Fantastic
Four in their duel against the Justice Society.
Uatu observed the Fantastic Four's battle against
the Russian scientist known as the Red Ghost
and his Super Apes, a conflict he allowed to
play out as a test of their mettle and unity.
Impressed by the Fantastic Four's victory,
Uatu began to subtly intervene in critical events
on Earth, justifying his actions as necessary
to safeguard the planet from existential threats.
His involvement with the Fantastic Four established
a precedent for future interactions with Earth's
heroes, further intertwining his destiny with
theirs. Among Uatu's most significant violations
of the Watcher's Code was his involvement in
humanity's first encounter with Galactus, the
world's devouring cosmic entity. Using his
advanced technology, Uatu attempted to cloak
Earth from Galactus' detection, and later guided
the Human Torch to Galactus' worldship to retrieve
the Ultimate Nullifier, the only weapon capable
of deterring the World's Devourer. You can learn
more about Galactus in his duel against the
Spectre. Though Galactus ultimately spared Earth,
Uatu's actions drew the attention of his fellow
Watchers, leading to a trial that found him
guilty of repeated interference. Despite their
disapproval, Uatu's love for humanity compelled
him to continue observing Earth and its heroes
closely, often justifying his defiance by the
planet's unique potential and his belief that
Earth held a special place in the cosmos. Over
the following years, Uatu played a pivotal
role in more events. He warned the Fantastic
Four of threats like the Molecule Man and the
Overmind, assisted the Avengers in battles against
time-traveling foes such as King the Conqueror,
and provided invaluable guidance during crises
like the Kreisgrul War. Yet Uatu's compassion
extended beyond humanity. He offered aid to
extraterrestrial allies like the Silver Surfer,
and intervened in cosmic disputes that threatened
the stability of the universe. His penchant
for continuing to bend the rules led to increased
conflict with other Watchers, including his
nephew, Eren. As a young Watcher who had not
yet been assigned a station, Eren also broke
the Watcher's code and schemed to manipulate
the Fantastic Four to create a pocket universe
that he could rule on his own. Uatu ultimately
subdued Eren, an act that sacrificed his own
status among the Watchers, as they stripped
him of his title and exiled him from their
order. Despite his exile, Uatu's bond with Earth
remained unbroken. He continued to witness
humanity's triumphs and tragedies. However,
Uatu's history took a tragic turn as a citadel
on the moon was attacked by a group of villains
who sought to plunder his vast repository of
knowledge. Uatu was gravely wounded and one
of his eyes… containing the secrets of everything
he had observed was stolen. Nick Fury, senior,
seeking to prevent further misuse of the Watcher's
knowledge, confronted the injured Uatu, who
after being attacked had now become more steadfast
in his code of non-interference. When Uatu refused
to divulge his attackers identities, Fury took
the drastic step of killing him with a gamma
irradiated bullet and taking his remaining
eye. This granted Nick Fury all of Uatu's knowledge,
and he reluctantly inherited his role as Earth's
observer, now known as the Unseen. You can learn
more about Nick Fury Sr. in his son's duel
against Rick Flag. However, Uatu was later miraculously
resurrected from his own eye when the Unseen
happened upon some ancient alien relics. Uatu
reclaimed his role as the Watcher and employed
the now- powerless Nick Fury to act as his agent
against a newly discovered renegade faction
of Priscilla Kins, the same race believed to
have destroyed themselves all those eons ago.
As they were now waging a war against the Watchers,
Uatu traveled to his home planet of T-37X to
call the other Watchers to action. Yet they
still vowed not to interfere so as not to repeat
the mistakes of their past, and the Watchers
imprisoned Uatu. Using a device called the
Apex of All Realities, which could see what-if
worlds, they made Uatu watch an alternate reality
in which he had not helped the Fantastic Four
against Galactus. He saw that not only would
Earth have repelled the World Devourer on its
own, but the planet would have developed into
a scientific utopia. Distraught, Uatu was soon
rescued by Nick Fury, and he later learned
that alternate Earth would have eventually been
destroyed by its own technology. As the Priscilla
Kins poisoned the Watcher's
who merged with the apex of all realities to
become the one and only Watcher. He used his
increased power to restore the Priscilla's home,
and reinstated Nick Fury Senior as Earth's
new Watcher. And that's his backstory. Powers-wise,
the Watcher, like every member of his race,
is considered a cosmic-level being with vast
power and knowledge. Though he's sworn to inaction,
he will occasionally take the minimal steps
necessary to prevent large-scale death and
destruction. Among his vast power set is omniscient
level cosmic awareness and senses, immortality,
telepathy on a global scale, teleportation on
a universal scale, invisibility, illusion casting,
time travel, flight, vast durability, size alteration,
vast cosmic energies that can create blasts
on a global scale or shields or other constructs.
He also has an extra-dimensional portal that
he can use to see into alternate realities.
He is all-knowing, he's all-powerful, and today
he's gonna kick all kinds of monitor ass. Bro,
the Watcher is like monitor light. What are
you talking about? If by monitor light you mean
gonna totally stomp all over monitor's ass,
then yeah. No, you don't know what light means,
apparently. You'll get what I'm talking about
when I go over the monitor's backstory.
was one of three cosmic siblings created by
Perpetua, a celestial being known as a Hand
that hailed from the greater omniverse. The
Hands were tasked with creating multiverses
within the omniverse using anti-crisis energy
from the source, God essentially, intended
to pass their energies back to him upon completion.
Perpetua, however, defied her purpose, forging
a multiverse fueled by negative crisis energy.
the DC Multiverse, designed to perpetuate itself
through cycles of crises and rebirth that would
keep her alive. Perpetua shaped her multiverse
into three distinct realms, dark matter of creative
potential, positive matter of constancy and
order, and destructive antimatter. To oversee
these realms, she created her three sons. Marnovu,
the Monitor, was charged with safeguarding the
positive matter realm. and preserving the universes
within it from existential threats. Alpheus,
the World Forger, crafted potential universes
within the Dark Matter Realm. Mobius, the Anti-Monitor,
governed the Anti-Matter Realm, tasked with
ensuring the light of creation did not breach
the boundaries of the Greater Omniverse and
alert the Source. Curious about the Greater
Omniverse, Marnovu peered into it and its other
multiverses, becoming aware of his mother's
crime. When he confronted Perpetua, she revealed
her intent to remain as their multiverse's eternal
protector and shared her vision of omniversal
conquest. To achieve this, she merged Martians
and humans to create an army of perfect and
immortal beings known as Apex Predators, genetically
designed for endless warfare. Horrified and
fearing the judgment of the source, Marnovu
rejected his mother, who unleashed her Apex
Predators on him. Marnovu eventually united
with Alpheus and Mobius to oppose their mother.
In their Promethean galaxy, they created a colossal
tuning fork tower in an attempt to communicate
with the Omniverse to expose Perpetua's crimes,
and though she attempted to intervene by unleashing
her army on them, her sons were successful.
The source responded by sending a cosmic raptor,
a manifestation of judgment, to confront Perpetua.
Perpetua and all of her power were imprisoned
within a source wall made up of her apex predators,
a boundary that marked the multiverse's edge.
Rather than destroy Perpetua's creation, the
multiverse was reset, including the three brothers,
with Marnovu coalescing over time on the moon
of Oa in the Prime Universe and Mobius on the
moon of Chord in the Antimatter Universe.
sought to destroy him, beginning by conquering
the antimatter universe and subjugating the
citizenry of Kord into becoming his army. He
transferred the most loyal of Kord's inhabitants
into shadow demons and corporeal extensions
of his will, while drafting others into his
army of Thundererers, warriors equipped with
devastating lightning bolts. Marnovu, aware
of his brother's actions, eventually went to
war with Mobius in a universal battle between
the barrier of their universes. that spanned
a million years. Their feud eventually ended
in a stalemate, leaving both the monitor and
the anti-monitor inert and trapped in a state
of dormancy. For nine billion years, they remained
motionless, forgotten by the countless worlds
their battle had once threatened. Eventually,
Krona, a curious scientist from the planet
Maltus, sought to know the origins of the universe,
and in his experimentations, fractured the
newly stabilized multiverse into infinite parallel
universes. Though Corona mistakenly believed
he had created the multiverse, his actions merely
revealed its existence to his reality, destabilizing
it further. The Malthusians suppressed the story
of Perpetua, fearing the consequences of her
legacy. Pariah, a scientist from a fringe universe
like Corona, unintentionally discovered the
anti-matter universe, accidentally unleashing
it into his own and destroying it. This act
also awakened Mobius, as the antimatter universe
expanded to fill the void of the one Pariah
destroyed, increasing Mobius' domain and power.
Re-amassing his army and sending universe-destroying
waves of antimatter into the multiverse, Mobius
determined that to defeat Marnovu, he could
gain infinite power by destroying the now infinite
multiverse. Sensing Mobius' resurgence, Marnovu
also awoke and prepared for the coming crisis.
Establishing a base in space, he used advanced
technology to study the multiverse and identify
champions capable of defending it. Among these
was Harbinger, a girl he rescued and empowered
to serve as his emissary. As Mobius's antimatter
wave began consuming universes, Marnovu devised
a plan to preserve what remained. He constructed
colossal tuning fork towers to stabilize surviving
Earths, which were at the centers of each universe.
tasked his champions with defending these devices.
Harbinger was sent to retrieve the infant Alexander
Luther Jr, the last survivor of Earth-3, whose
parents sent him in a rocket ship to Earth-1
during an antimatter wave, turning him into
a being made of both positive and antimatter.
Mobius, however, subtly corrupted Harbinger
by possessing her multiversal counterparts
with shadow demons, and successfully tricked
her into killing the monitor. Marnovu foresaw
her betrayal, however, and used his death to
power the Tuning Forks, merging Earth-1 and
Earth-2 into a netherverse shielded from Mobius.
The sacrifice allowed the defenders of the
multiverse to regroup and ultimately defeat
Mobius, the Anti-Monitor, collapsing the infinite
multiverse into a single, unified reality known
as New Earth. Although New Earth streamlined
the multiverse into a cohesive timeline, traces
and memories of their original multiverse lingered.
The re-emergence of the multiverse began during
another crisis event caused by Alexander Luther
Jr., who believed the New Earth was flawed.
Using the remains of Mobius's armor, he constructed
a tuning fork tower to split New Earth into
multiple universes in an effort to find a perfect
one. His actions, though ultimately thwarted,
destabilized reality. and led to the creation
of a finite multiverse of 52 parallel Earths.
This restructured multiverse gave rise to a
new race of monitors, fragments of Marnovu's
essence, each overseeing a specific Earth.
Unlike Marnovu, these monitors were not unified
by a singular purpose. They developed indiviDuel
personalities and often clashed over their roles.
Bob, the monitor of New Earth, championed empathy
and collaboration between the universes. In
contrast, Solomon, the monitor of Earth-8,
pursued the violent eradication of multiversal
anomalies, or people who existed outside their
intended universe. Solomon's genocidal stance
divided the monitors and led to internal strife
within their order and without, creating enemies
against their kind that included the being
known as Monarch, who forced superpowered beings
across the multiverse into gladiatorial matches
to determine the strongest among them. for an
army that he was building to eliminate the
Monitors. The conflict escalated when Solomon
attempted to absorb Bob's essence to augment
his own power, resulting in Bob's death and
destabilizing the Monitor Collective. Amid
this chaos, Monarch's actions led to the destruction
of Earth 51, whose Monitor, Nyx Uotan, was
banished to Prime Earth for failing to protect
his universe. Stripped of his powers, He lived
as a human until regaining his memories and
becoming a superhero known as Super Judge.
During the supposed final crisis event, Nix
became one of the last surviving Monitors,
assembling an army of supermen from across the
multiverse to defeat Mandrake, a corrupted
Monitor. Despite their victory, Nix lamented
the Monitor's failures and allowed their civilization
to fade. In post-Flashpoint continuity, unbeknownst
to the resurrected Marnovu and Mobius, Their
brother Alpheus had been killed by his pet dragon
Barbados, who had been responsible for devouring
newly forged universes too dark to exist. Barbados'
abandonment of his duty led to the formation
of the Dark Multiverse, champions from which
were led by Barbados in a war against the Multiverse.
Though Barbados and his army were defeated,
the war eventually resulted in a crack within
the source wall that freed Perpetua. sought
to reclaim her multiverse. Marnovu, Mobius,
and a newly reformed Alphius merged to form
the Ultra Monitor in a desperate bid to stop
their mother, but Perpetua regained her strength,
turning Mobius against her brothers by granting
him the anti-life equation that allowed him
to control his brothers. With help from the
Green Lantern John Stewart, who you can learn
more about in our Green Lantern vs Quasar duel
episode, Marnovu and Alphius were freed from
their and Alpheus sacrificed his life to protect
Marnovu and his allies from a universe destroying
attack from Perpetua. To help stop his mother,
Marnovu hid shards of Element X, the metal used
to forge universes, for the forces opposing
his mother to find when Perpetua and the Batman
Who Laughs took over reality. You can learn
more about the Batman Who Laughs and his duel
against Cosmic Ghost Rider. This helped Wonder
Woman defeat both, after which the hands of
the Multiverse recreated. DC's multiverse.
And that's his history so far. Power-wise, the
Monitor Marnovu wields immense cosmic power,
including multiversal cosmic awareness that
enables him to perceive and understand the
infinite dimensions and realities that comprise
the multiverse. His abilities include matter
and energy manipulation, teleportation across
universes, and control over space-time itself.
He wields the dimensional superstructure of
the universe. one of seven forces of the universe,
granting him partial control over the fabric
of reality, though his power is diminished
outside of the sixth dimension. While he's immortal,
he can be destroyed, though he'll reform within
the sixth dimension. His size can shift from
human scale to planetary proportions, and his
precognition provides glimpses into possible
futures. His one weakness is that his strength
and power is intrinsically tied to the stability
of his domain. should the universes of the
multiverse be destroyed, his power would diminish.
Well, it's too bad for him that Uatu is gonna
basically destroy all of his multiverse and
then just leave him powerless. That doesn't
sound like something Uatu would do. You know
what Uatu would do? He would fucking fall asleep
while listening to that story because it was
so long and so convoluted and boring. No, yeah,
that was way better than Uatu's history, I'm
sorry. Way better. Way more epic. What is going
to pull a harbinger and kill monitors ass just
like she did? You forget that the monitor gave
Harbinger a shit ton of power. So now, bro,
what an idiot. What an idiot. Well, monitor
is going to pull a Nick Fury and just shoot
the watcher with a fucking bullet. Hey, that
was before he was the one and only watcher.
So, OK, well, Harbinger killed monitor before
he was the ultra monitor. I don't know.
where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
Dynomic Podcast Network presents Console Combat,
where video game legends brawl every Monday.
Dynamic.com. Comic Book Titans smash every Tuesday.
Max Destruction, where TV and action heroes
battle every Wednesday. And Sendro World, where
anime champions clash every Thursday. Join
us as we speculate on the matches and armed
with the power of mathematical simulations,
discover who will emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com,
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
Now that we got the histories and abilities
out of the way, let's speculate on how one
of the 1000 simulated matches will go. The winner
is determined by simulations, not our speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how this fight could
play out. AJ and IK, what are the rules of
our speculation? Well I should say there are
no rules, other than the characters have no
prior knowledge of the other going into the
fight. All they are aware of starting out is
that the other character is a threat that needs
to be eliminated. For the speculation... The
contestants will begin approximately 50 meters
apart in a nondescript environment that will
have no bearing on the match itself, as no environmental
statistics are considered in my simulations.
The contestants must earn victory on their own
merit. Alright then, let's get into it. Monitor
and Watcher meet on the battlefield. Who goes
first? Well, since neither of these cosmic
level beings are really known for fighting,
we thought we would take a different route
with this duel by challenging each other on
what they're known for. observing. To that
end, the Monitor and the Watcher have come to
the match prepared with certain events from
DC and Marvel's history in order to test their
opponents' observational skills. It's a contest
of watching, essentially, or since this is a
podcast, listening. Yeah, how good is the other
character at perceiving the events of their
respective universes? In a way, we could all
be considered Watchers and Monitors of Marvel
and DC as consumers. of Marvel and DC films
and shows, and that we observe what happens
without taking action and chronicling their
events in our fanboy minds. Right, so Jonathan,
as the DC monitor, will be presented with four
audio events from DC's past, same for me as
the Marvel Watcher. The task will be to identify
the four events given to us, and the one who
correctly identifies more events will be the
winner of this speculation. And to add a twist
to the challenge, Each event presented to the
opposing character will have some sort of commonality,
be it a thematic throughline or some other
connection. Both the Watchers and the Monitor's
ultimate test will be to deduce this commonality
in order to win. So let's get started. The Watcher
presents the Monitor with an event from the
DC Universe. Okay DC Monitor, here is your first
event. This city is mine.
Okay, I have no idea whose voice that is. The
city is mine. So a city is involved. It sounds
after that there's like a dragon like screaming
and it's just like attacking all these people
and destroying some kind of city, I'm assuming.
But at the very end, there's like this robotic
cybernetic kind of sound. It can't be cyborg.
This is not Justice League. There's some kind
of giant monster there. Shazam Fury of the Gods
had a dragon. Aquaman had a giant carathen.
The Suicide Squad had Starro. Oh, is that the
thinker who's saying the city is mine? You
can't just name every movie and every monster.
Okay. I think I know what scene this is. Okay
this is the climactic battle of the Suicide
Squad when Starro is confronting the Suicide
Squad telling them that the city belongs to
him and all of his minions that have Starro's
on their faces begin to attack the Suicide Squad.
That is correct. Yes. Oh, good gosh. This is
the Star of the Conqueror scene from the Suicide
Squad when Star of the Conqueror attacks Corto
Maltese. And the computerized sounds that you
hear at the end are Amanda Waller's crew waking
up to find out that there's a freaking Kaiju
that's been awakened. Gotcha. Okay. So one
point for me, apparently. Yes, one point for
you. Okay. So now it's the monitor's turn to
present the Watcher with an event from Marvel.
This one is Easy Money. I hear a man saying
no, and I hear cityscape sounds, and also a
very distinctive scoring, music-wise. The event
in question is when Otto Octavius realizes
that the metal arms have been grafted to his
body, and he escapes out into the city and
attacks a taxi cab before fleeing into the night.
Right, what movie is that from? That is from
Spider-Man 2. Great job, you had a way easier
time with that one than I did. Well, I'm just
a better observer, I guess. But now it is the
DC Monitor's turn again. Here is your next
event.
Come on, start moving now people, let's go!
The boss wants us out of the building, so let's
make it happen! Jack!
Okay, I'm hearing a car chase, it sounds like.
And there's a lot of destruction and structures
crumbling. Two guys are talking. It definitely
sounds like Ben Affleck. Sounds like there's
a lot of chaos and destruction going on and
someone's driving. This has to be the opening
to Batman v Superman when Bruce Wayne is racing
to Wayne Enterprises during Zod's attack on
Metropolis. That is correct. from Batman vs
Superman, a point to the DC monitor for that
one. Two for two. Gotta say, Hans Zimmer's score
during that film, still really iconic. Moving
on to the second challenge for Uwatu. Here is
the second event for Marvel.
Are you even pulling? Are you on my team? Just
represent, pull! Alright, let's go! NNNN
Good Steve, no pressure.
Come on, Cap. Okay, I'm hearing a lot of voices.
I'm hearing people struggling. I'm hearing
some whimsical music. This is another pretty
easy one, I think. This is the scene when the
Avengers try to lift Thor's hammer from Avengers
Age of Ultron. That is correct. One more point
for the Watcher. Congrats. All right, it is
now the DC Monitor's turn for the next event.
Okay, that's definitely from a Superman movie.
I think it's from Superman the movie. Is this
the destruction of Krypton? That is correct.
Yes, this is the destruction of Krypton from
Superman the movie. Yeah, this is the scene
where we see all of the Kryptonians sort of
falling into the fiery chasms that are now what's
left of Krypton. And after the planet explodes,
we see the baby hell else ship zip by the camera.
Correct. Yeah, good job. All right. The DC
monitor gets another point. You're three for
three so far. I freaking got scared at the
beginning of the clip, I'm not gonna lie. Alright,
the monitor is now presenting Uatu with Marvel's
third event to recall. I shall miss you, my
friend.
What the fuck is that from? Okay, I hear what
sounds like Professor X saying, I will miss
you, my friend. And then a lot of people saying,
I'm sorry. Ooh, this is a tough one. I don't
immediately recognize what this is from. Maybe
I'm not correct and that's not Professor X.
Oh, I know what this is from. Okay, the I'm
sorry suddenly makes sense now. This is from
Doctor Strange and the Multiverse of Madness
when Black Bolt erases Doctor Strange from
that timeline. Right, a multiversal Doctor Strange
from the multiverse, where Professor X and
Black Bolt and Mr. Fantastic are all part of
this council. That was a great challenge right
there. I'm ashamed to say that I didn't immediately
get it because I'm sure some of our listeners
will, but I'm glad I pulled it off in the end.
That's three points for me so far. For you,
the DC Monitor, I present you with your final
challenge. The only way to save the world from
ever happening. Take this.
Okay, I'm pretty sure this has to be from the
flash just because someone's telling another
guy to run and there's like this electrical
sound. I can't pinpoint the scene though. I'm
not sure who's telling him to run, I think.
I want to know what the guy gives the runner
when he says take this. What is that? Obviously,
this has to be from a film where something
just catastrophic happens and time has to be
rewritten. That's why my guess is it's the
Flash, but it could also be Zack Snyder's Justice
League. Why can't I recognize that voice? That
frigging kills me. I feel like this is from
an animated film. Is this from Justice League
Dark Apocalypse War? It is not. No. Okay, well
then it's gotta be from the Tomorrowverse.
This has gotta be from Justice League Crisis
on Infinite Earths, part one. I'm guessing.
Fuck you.
I feel like I could see the scene in my head.
I just have no idea what movie it's from or
who's on the screen. It's just shadows really.
The voice belongs to Thomas Wayne and it is
from the end of Justice League the Flashpoint
Paradox. When he says take this he's handing
Barry Allen a note to his son Bruce Wayne. You
know I should have known this I feel really
stupid because of course that's what it's from.
For that particular round I award you no points
and may God have mercy on your soul Jonathan.
I need that. Well, that's three out of four
for the monitor. Let's see how Marvel's The
Watcher fares with this fourth and final event
that I'm hoping is the most difficult.
Okay, I hear animals attacking each other. I
hear a dog getting slapped. And I think there's
really only one movie that happens in, and that
would be the Hulk dog fight from the 2003 movie
Hulk. You think you're better than me? I think
I'm a better Watcher than you, yeah. Okay.
Well, maybe not. Let's see if you pass the ultimate
test, Mr. Watcher. What do all four of these
events have in common? Well, why don't you tell
me first? There was the climactic battle against
Starro at the end of the Suicide Squad. There
was the opening to Batman v Superman with Bruce
Wayne driving to Wayne Enterprises during Zod's
attack. So I guess cities are being destroyed.
There was Superman the movie with the destruction
of Krypton. And then I guess there was the
destruction of an entire universe in the Flashpoint
Paradox. So the theme is destruction? That
is correct. Yeah. cosmic level events of mass
destruction. Yeah. Gotcha. Okay, cool. So I
guess I win ultimately. Even though I got one
wrong. For the Watcher, the events that were
presented to him were Doctor Octopus's awakening,
you have the Avengers trying to lift Thor's
hammer, you have Black Bolt destroying Doctor
Strange, and you have Hulk fighting against
the Hulk dogs. This commonality is much harder
for me to determine. I cannot think of a single
damn thing, especially with the Avengers party
kind of throwing a wrench in there. I know
that two of the movies were directed by Sam
Raimi. The other one was directed by Joss Whedon.
The other one was directed by Ang Lee. One of
the movies came out in 2003. One of the movies
came out in 2004. And then you have 2015 with
Age of Ultron and Dr. Strange came out in 2022,
I think. Are you Googling this shit? No. Get
off Google. I'm not fucking Googling. That's
all in my brain, motherfucker. I cannot think
of the commonality between those. Is there,
I honestly have no idea. I have no idea. So
you admit that you're inferior as a watcher.
No, I mean, I got all the events correct, but
what's the commonality between them? Are you
ready for the answer? I am ready for the answer.
All films were scored by Danny Elfman. Ah,
shit! Of course they were. Yeah, you're totally
right. Oh, that was a good one. That was really
good. Yeah, yeah, the Spider-Man Sam Raimi franchise,
the 2003 Hulk movie, Multiverse of Madness,
and Avengers Age of Ultron were all scored by
Danny Elfman. Although for Age of Ultron, he
was one of many composers on that film. But
that, though, that was a sneaky ass commonality
between all the events. Well, I guess since
the Watcher failed the true test of this whole
matchup, the Monitor wins. And yet it was the
watcher who was able to correctly identify
every event that happened. So really, the watcher
wins. That doesn't matter. You have to look
deeper at things. Yeah, just like how apparently
you didn't look deep enough at the flashpoint
paradox to remember what the fuck happened in
that movie, obviously. You're the one who cheated
by pulling out a direct-to-video animated film.
Who does that? Uh, DC does that. A lot. They
put out a lot of- direct to video animated films.
Blame them. Yeah, but I don't remember any
of them. You don't remember the Flashpoint Paradox,
which is one of DC's best animated projects?
That's fair, that was really good. It honestly
just makes you sound dumb. Like you explained
everything about the plot of that movie without
getting the movie. I mean, the monitor got
everything but the title of the project. So
maybe the watchers dumb. Maybe the watchers
tired of your shit and just shoves the monitor.
Oh, oh, look, who's suddenly getting all confrontational.
Mr. I swear not to intervene, you know, monitor.
He's going to respond by shoving the watcher
back, but with energy beams from his hands that
just like yeet the watcher into outer space.
I mean, the watcher has interfered before, like
when necessary. Right. And he's all too happy.
right now to interfere with the monitor's face
by rearranging it. So yeah, the watcher gets
blasted back into the cosmos, but suddenly he
disappears in a flash of light and he reappears
behind the monitor. But now he's the size of
a whole planet. And he's going to shoot down
energy beams from his eyes that just disintegrate
the monitor. Yeah, I mean the monitor saw this
coming due to his precognition and cosmic awareness.
So the monitor blocks the eye blast. by beaming
in this massive structure, this tuning fork
tower between him and the Watcher's lasers
before they reach him. And this tower absorbs
those lasers along with all of the Watcher's
energy just draining him so now he's just this
giant floating husk in space. Except that when
the Watcher attacked Monitor, he also telepathically
read his mind and learned all of his secrets.
including his knowledge about this power draining
antenna. Okay, so as the Watcher's power is
being drained, he has a contingency plan. You
know, he has this massive comet from the far
reaches of the solar system fly in and plow
right through that antenna, like a bullet through
a gas tank, just unleashing the antenna's energy
in like this sun-sized explosion, and the monitor
dies in the blast. So the match is over. No,
except that the comet actually just passes
right through the antenna because once they
had enough of the watcher's energy, the antenna
sent out this frequency throughout the universe
that shifted it into the sixth dimension where
the watcher is like nothing but an infant and
the monitor can control reality. So the monitor,
you know, he's aboard his ship and he simply
presses a button on his console and the watcher
ceases to exist. Match over. Okay, so the monitor
is a cold-hearted bastard who would erase an
infant? Wow. And the Watcher looks like a big
baby! I mean, the Watcher, I'm pretty sure,
is powerful enough to like, you know, thrive
in the sixth dimension. So like, right as the
monitor is about to press that eraser button,
all of a sudden time freezes, okay? And the
Watcher is going to peer into a what-if universe
that's called, what if the monitor was a weak,
punk-ass loser? And all of a sudden the fight
gets transported there. where the Watcher just
kills the monitor with a backhand slap. You
know, ending the match. Sixth dimensional time
freezing? That is horseshit. Why is that horseshit?
Because it's the sixth dimension, like time
does not even exist. I'm pretty sure it does.
Why are you so confident that the Watcher can
even comprehend anything he's seeing in the
sixth dimension? Because he's the fucking Watcher.
That's why he's pretty damn powerful. Again,
horseshit. I say the monitor is a more advanced
being than the watcher. So there's no way the
watcher is going to be able to peer into any
other kind of reality from the sixth dimension.
He's just going to get erased. Oh, we're just
going to take your word for it that he's a more
advanced being than the watcher? Sure. Yeah.
Well, let's find out by taking this fight to
the stats. Okay. We're going to go ahead and
plug in their stats, run the simulations and
see which one wins.
Processing results simulations complete. All
right, these guys are super powerful. Definitely
reflected in the stats because all their stats
were almost maxed out. There were a few discrepancies.
We did say that the watcher was more evasive
because he's a little bit more elusive and
behind the scenes than the monitor. And you
know, the watcher often goes invisible. The
monitor is a little bit more concrete. Right.
The monitor though, we said has a lot more
toys at his disposal. He's always carrying around
six dimensional technology that he uses, whereas
the Watcher, he has his Citadel and some of
the items stored there help him out, but largely
he acts through his own power. We also said
that the monitor had a greater perception than
the Watcher because his cosmic awareness extends
across universes and even out into the greater
omniverse. Yeah, yeah, we said that the monitor
essentially observes more than the Watcher.
The Watcher largely relegated to Earth and its
solar system, traditionally speaking. But for
everything else, including intelligence, versatility,
strength, durability, they were all even. The
strangest stat had to be fighting skill. We
had no idea what the heck to do for that one,
but we figured whatever we gave them, they would
be basically even. Yeah, they've both been
known to throw down very, very rarely. So yeah,
fighting skill was a hard one to tabulate for
them. With all that said and done though, Jonathan,
who do you think is going to win this match?
I think it's going to be the monitor and our
Instagram poll takers agree with me. So far.
Yeah, they are giving the monitor a 54% edge
over the watcher. Last time I checked the watcher
was ahead in that poll. What the hell? It is
kind of surprising to me that the watcher is
not ahead right now considering we just got
off of what if and he was a major player in
that. Well, I mean, I guess the monitor was
in the recent Justice League Crisis on Infinite
Earth's trilogy of films, as well as the Arrow
vs Crisis on Infinite Earth's crossover event.
That's true. Anyway, what does Instagram know?
Let's get the final results of this match.
AJ9K, the results please. Hey Yuasa. Okay, the
winner between the monitor and the watcher
is... The monitor. Hell yeah! It was very close.
Out of 1000 simulated matches, the monitor
won 554 battles, whereas the watcher only won
446. So it's 55.4% over 44.6%. I'm not surprised.
I knew the watcher was powerful, but I also
figured the monitor just operated at a bigger
scale. And the stats sort of reflected that.
Well, I mean, if the monitor is so perceptive,
how come he didn't know... what the fucking
end of the Flashpoint paradox was. No, no,
you're comparing Mar Novo to Johnny DC. That's
not a fair comparison. Yeah, I guess you're
right. Johnny DC is not that great. Yeah, neither
is Marvelous Joe because he couldn't find the
connection between all of the different four
movies. I may be observant, but I'm not smart.
That's fair. Well, that does it for this duel,
guys. AJ 9K, help close this out. Thanks for
listening to Dynamic Duel. Visit the show's
website at dynamicduel.com and follow us on
Instagram at dynamicduelpodcast. You can support
the show on Patreon at patreon.com slash dynamicduel
and joining a tier that works for you, or by
rating and reviewing Dynamic Duel on Apple
Podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser or on our website.
Don't forget to listen to the other shows in
the DynaMic Podcast Network, including Max
Destruction, Senjo World and Console Combat.
In our next episode, we will be doing a review
of the first season of Creature Commandos,
which is also kicking off James Gunn's DCU.
You do not want to miss it and our thoughts
on it. But that is it for this episode, we want
to give a big thanks to our executive producers
Ken Johnson, Jon Sturowski, Zachary Hepburn,
Dustin Balcom, Mickey Mathangian, Brendan Estergard,
Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Austin Wasilowski,
AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam
Spies, Andrew Schunk, Dean Maleski. Devin Davis,
Joseph Kirsting, Josh Leiner, Mike Williams,
and Oscar Galvez for helping make this podcast
possible. We'll talk to you guys next week.
Up up and away, true believers.