This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
Hi and welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast,
a weekly show where we review superhero films
and debate the superiority between Marvel and
DC by comparing their characters and stat-based
battle simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe. And I'm
his twin brother Johnny DC. And guys, we are
in the eye of the storm of what Jonathan and
I are calling review hell right now. We still
have three more DC things to review because
DC sucks and that is Suicide Squad
We've been reviewing so many things that we
haven't done a duel episode since over a month
ago with Atrocitus vs Juggernaut, but this episode,
we're getting back to it. We're going to find
out who would win in a fight between Arsenal
and White Widow. Arsenal was formerly Speedy,
sometimes also known as Red Arrow, but he's
the protégé of Green Arrow, whereas White Widow
is the protégé of Black Widow. And her real
name is Yelena Belova, and you know probably
all about her from the Black Widow movie. She's
played by Florence Pugh. And if you're a fan
of CW's Arrow, you'll know Roy Harper because
he was played by Colton Haynes. Nobody watched
that show. Hey, if we're naming actors, why
can't I? But before we get into the characters'
backstories, run the simulations, and determine
who would win in a match-up between the two
characters, we're going to break down the comic
book movie news from the past week, of which
there was only one interesting news item. And
that was that James Spader is returning to
voice Ultron for the upcoming Vision. Disney
Plus television series. As always we list our
segment times in our episode description so
feel free to check out the show notes if you
want to skip ahead to a particular topic. Guys
our artificially intelligent duel simulator
AJ9K has a quick message for our listeners,
so listen up. Why hello there, do you want
even more from this podcast? Then become a part
of the dynamic duel community on Patreon, where
you can choose from three tiers. The dynamic
two-o tier gives you access to our Discord
chat server. The fantastic four tier gives you
two bonus episodes each month. And the X-Force
tier makes you an executive producer of this
show. Lastly, The Diner Mike podcast network
tier lets you create your own podcast using
this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe
will help you develop your show, provide graphic
support and consultation, and get you simulation
results. Pitch the twins your ideas via email
at dynamicduelpodcast at gmail.com. Check it
out at patreon.com slash dynamicduel. Pip pip
cheerio. Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone
who supports the podcast. Be sure to tune into
the other shows in the DynaMic Podcast Network
this week, including Max Destruction, which
pits your favorite action heroes from film
and television against each other. This week,
the Macho Twins are pitting The Penguin from
Batman Returns against Big Boy from Dick Tracy.
It's a great matchup. Yeah, cannot wait for
that one. On the Send Your World podcast, host
Zachary Heppern speculates on fights between
fan favorite anime and manga characters. This
Thursday, Zach will be reviewing Sailor Moon.
Cosmos and on the console combat podcast hosts
John and Dean find out who'd win in fights
between popular video game characters and yesterday's
episode John and Ken determined who would win
between link from the Legend of Zelda and Roxas
from Kingdom Hearts visit dynamic Podcasts
calm or click the link in our show notes to
listen to all of the shows in the dynaMic
podcast network But with that out of the way
quick to the no prize A no prize is an award
Marvel used to give out to fans. Our version,
the Dynamic Duel No Prize, is a digital award
that we post on Instagram for the person we
feel gave the best answer to our question of
the week. Last week we asked, which upcoming
DC Studios film or show are you most looking
forward to and why? Of course in the week prior,
we asked what MCU project you were most looking
forward to and we only got two answers. This
time we got so many more! because so many more
people are looking forward to DC stuff. Well,
DC fans are insecure, but also we got quite
a few answers that said, no one cares. I'm not
looking forward to any DC project because DC
sucks. Well, I mean, doesn't that prove that
Marvel fans are insecure? Like, why even call
in with that answer? Because it's fun to dunk
on DC. It's fun to be butthurt. OK. We have
three honorable mentions and a no prize winner
to get through. So our first honorable mention
goes to Travis Herndon. Who said? What's up,
dynamic dudes? Travis here. Shout out to my
other twins. So my answer would have to be the
Creature Commandos. Just like the Guardians
of the Galaxy, I am very surprised to even see
this sort of D-list superhero group be in a
theatrical universe like this. So I'm excited
for the show. I'm excited to be in the live
action series. So yeah, Creature Commandos is
going to be cool. It's going to basically be
DC's Guardians. Yeah, I'm really looking forward
to this kicking off James Gunn's DC Universe.
I know it's going to be animated, but I still
feel like it'll set the tone for a lot of what's
coming, considering that James Gunn wrote it.
Plus, the creature commandos are just a really
cool team. I love the concept of like a super
team of these borderline universal monster
type characters, and I think it's going to be
a lot of fun. Yeah, we might just have to squeeze
in a duel with the creature commandos around
Halloween time. Yeah, maybe. Great answer,
Travis. Our next honorable mention goes to Lizzie
Dyer Arnie, who said, It's Lizzie. And of course,
the DC series that I'm most looking forward
to is the superhero you've never heard of,
Mr. Booster Gold. He's got definitely the most
unique origin story. He's a college football
player from the future who gets expelled for
illegal gambling. And he works as a security
guard and steals some stuff from the Superhero
Museum. and then he comes back to our time
to become a superhero. He is just such a fun
guy and I love him. Yeah, Booster Gold, of
course, is an upcoming, I believe television
project from DC Studios. Rumors are heavily
pointing to Kumail Nanjiani to play the lead
role of Booster Gold, which I don't hate because
it's a very comedic role and he's a very comedic
guy. And also there'd be an awesome blow to
Marvel because he of course was one of the Eternals.
Yeah, he was Kingo. in the Eternals movie.
I thought he was an awesome Kingo. I know that
he'll make an awesome Booster Gold and it would
be really interesting to see who they would
cast as Blue Beetle. You know there's the Jamie
Reyes Blue Beetle and then there's the Ted Kord
Blue Beetle. And since James Gunn said the
movie version of Blue Beetle would be making
his way into the new DCU and in that movie
they made reference to Ted Kord, I think it
would be a lot of fun seeing who they cast
as the Blue Beetle Booster Gold duo. Yeah, I'm
still rooting for Jason Sudeikis, but we'll
see if that happens. Great answer, Lizzie. Our
final honorable mention goes to Scott Camacho,
who said Scotty Macho here. One I am looking
forward to only because of my son's namesake
is Batman, Brave and the Bold. I really want
to see what they're going to do with Damien
Wayne. Batman, Brave and the Bold. Gilly Macho
here. And this is mine. DC sucks. Shut the
fuck up, don't fricking come in here. DC's up.
Dude, I know all about embarrassing twin brothers.
Let me tell ya, it's rough. Gilly, you're my
boy. Thank you so much for that. Way out of
line, way out of line. Batman Brave and the
Bold is gonna be awesome. I'm still really
hoping, honestly, that they bring Robert Pattinson
into the DCU. Probably not gonna happen, but
I can still hold out hope because they haven't
really announced any casting news for this
film yet. That said, I'm still really looking
forward to it because we may finally get a
Batman and Robin in live action on the big screen
that works. The way you could do it with Robert
Pattinson is have his fling with Talia Al Ghul
happen, not when he's Batman, but while he's
training around the world. So when he was younger,
that way it's still believable that Batman
could still have a child. Yeah, and a five year
old Damian would be totally fine with me. just
like kicking ass, it would be hilarious. I could
see it. Great answer, Scotty. Dishonorable
mention to you, Gillie. Which also counts as
an honorable mention coming from a DC guy,
so good job. We wanna give a special thanks
to Cyrus Moore, Abner O'Tary, and Kat Stevenson
for taking the time to visit our website and
record an answer. And Gil Camacho and Nate
Wagner. No, no, they're dead to me. The winner
of this week's snow prize, however, is Mickey
Math and Gian, who said... Hey, what's up guys?
This is Miggi and no surprise the DC Studios
film I'm looking forward to the most is Superman.
I'm a huge Superman fan and everything I've
seen from GunsPost about his inspirations and
set photos and the casting, the costume design,
it just looks like it's going to be the perfect
Superman film. And a great start to the DC
Studios reboot. So yeah, Superman. I'm super
excited. Thanks guys. Yeah, the initial photo
they released of David Corn sweat as Superman
in the costume did not get my hopes up, but
the set photos absolutely did. From seeing the
costume on set to all of the actors portraying
their different roles, I am so unbelievably
pumped for James Gunn's Superman movie, which
as Biggie said is really going to kick off James
Gunn's DC universe in the live action sense.
I mean yeah, if you like that sort of thing.
Uh, yeah, bro. DC fans do, and that's why this
is the best answer, cause it's effing Superman.
And if you don't like Superman, then you don't
like superheroes, cause they wouldn't exist
without him. So then. I mean, surely there
was Zorro before Superman, you know, he was
kind of a superhero. I'm sorry, could he leap
tall buildings in a single bound? No, fuck Zorro.
John Carter of Mars? Was he faster than a speeding
bullet? No, fuck John Carter. The Phantom? Oh,
was he bullet powerful than a locomotive? I
have no idea. Oh, it's Phantom! What is happening?
Superman, that's what's happening. Next year
he's happening. It's gonna be awesome. Can't
wait for it. Great answer, Miggie. You win
this week's No Prize. If you the listener want
a shot at winning your own No Prize, stay tuned
to later on in this episode when we'll be asking
another Question of the Week. And now that
that's done, on to the news!
Alright, this past week we learned from the
Hollywood Reporter that the actor James Spader
would be returning as the voice of the villain
Ultron in the upcoming Vision series. Now,
previously we heard that the series was going
to be called Vision Quest, but the Hollywood
Reporter said that that's not the official title,
which thank God, because really the series
should just be called Vision. I don't know,
I kind of liked the title Vision Quest. Shut
up! So the Hollywood Reporter also called...
Vision series as like the third in a sort of
Trilogy of television shows starting with WandaVision
followed up by Agatha all along and then ending
with this upcoming Vision series Which is a
pretty cool concept Rumors are that Elizabeth
Olsen will be returning in her role as the Scarlet
Witch in the upcoming Vision series as well
Although that's not been confirmed. Spoiler
maybe? I don't think so. I think it's pretty
expected, right? If she was gonna show up anywhere,
it would be here Well, maybe it's like a flashback
or something. I guess it could be. Or maybe
she's just coming back from the dead in Agatha,
La Lange. Who knows? But this is exciting news.
If you remember from the end of the Avengers
Age of Ultron movie, Ultron allegedly died off
screen during a conversation with Vision, where
they kind of had this philosophical discussion
about the nature of humanity. And then Ultron
lunges at Vision, and then there's a bright
flash of light. And then we never really see
what happens. We're just left to assume that
Ultron is dead. But as we know from the comics,
Ultron has implanted failsafe coding within
the Vision android, compelling him to rebuild
the evil robot. Now that may not be exactly
what's happening here, especially since the
original Vision body was recreated by the Sword
Organization and he's white in color now and
kind of devoid of his previous personality,
also similar to what happened in the comics.
So. There's a lot of cool stuff going on here.
I really like the character of Vision, especially
how he's portrayed by actor Paul Bettany. So
I'm really excited for this series, especially
now that we know that Ultron's gonna be the
bad guy. I feel like series like these should
have come years ago. Like I'm so ready for Marvel
to pick up all these loose threads that they've
been dangling everywhere. Ultron being a big
one. Yeah, and Vision too. We've been waiting
to see what happened with the white Vision ever
since 2021. I can't remember, did we like James
Spader as Ultron or was it lame? My impression
was that he did a great dark sinister voice.
It wasn't necessarily what I thought the character
sounded like based on how I read it in the
comics. I would set up him as a little bit more
snivelly and whiny I guess. But yeah, I like
James Spader as an actor and he does a good
take on Ultron I would say. thinking behind
Spader's casting in Avengers Age of Ultron was
that Joss Whedon was kind of counter casting
against Robert Downey Jr. because both Downey
and Spader were teen heartthrobs in the 80s.
And considering how Ultron here was kind of
portrayed as the brain child of Tony Stark,
I thought that all fit pretty well. Yeah, I
think if anyone could go toe to toe with Robert
Downey Jr., it's definitely... James Spader.
He's a solid actor. And definitely a formidable
one for Paul Bettany to go up against. For sure.
For sure. It's gonna be a great show. I can't
wait for Marvel to announce a release date for
Vision. But as soon as we know it, we'll let
you guys know. But speaking of great casting
for a Marvel villain, that brings us to our
Question of the Week.
Who do you think was the best cast, Marvel or
DC villain of all time? A lot of great options
to choose from, from both Marvel and DC, so
we can't wait to hear your guys' answers. Record
them at dynamicduel.com by clicking on the red
microphone button in the bottom right hand
corner of the screen, which will prompt you
to leave us a voicemail. Your message could
be up to 30 seconds long, and don't forget to
leave your name in case we include you on the
podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer, and
award that person a Dynamic Duel No Prize that
we'll post to Instagram. Be sure to answer before
August 31st.
But I think that does it for all the news for
this episode, so let's go ahead and get into
our main event where we find out who'd win in
a fight between the Green Arrow protégé, Arsenal,
and the Black Widow protégé, White Widow.
All right, Arsenal versus White Widow. We are
doing this duel episode now because it's a
lead up to our team duel that we have going
on in a few weeks where we find out who'd win
in a fight between the Outsiders team versus
X-Force. And that was selected by our executive
producers. That's going to be a fun episode.
But Arsenal is a quintessential outsider. Yes.
He was the leader of an incarnation of the Outsiders
for a time. Yes. And he has the ability of
a marksman. just like Green Arrow, correct?
Uh, yeah, except he uses more than a bow and
arrow. Like, Green Arrow pretty much sticks
to only that, but Arsenal has a literal arsenal
of weapons that he is a perfect marksman with.
Does he have a boxing glove arrow? I'm sure
he does. As Arsenal, he's a little probably
too cool and hip for something like that. But
as Speedy, you know, in his younger years, he
definitely used that. You know who doesn't
have a boxing glove arrow? White Widow. And
that's probably because she doesn't have a
bow, but it automatically makes her the better
character. I just said Arsenal doesn't use
that. Well, in my headcanon, he does. He fires
nothing but boxing glove arrows and he's a
big dumb dumb. Well that will be your downfall.
To be fair, I don't really know much about
the character, so I guess I'm going to find
out now as we go into the characters backstories,
input their stats, run simulations, and find
out who to win in a fight. But to explain the
methodology behind our duels, let's go to our
sentient duel simulator. Alfred Jarvis 9000.
AJ9K, tell our listeners how you go about determining
a winner in our duel matchups. Yes, of course,
sir. The way I determine a winner between the
contestants is by running 1000 Monte Carlo
simulations using the characters statistics.
A Monte Carlo simulation is a probabilistic
model used to determine outcomes through random
sampling. In this case, I randomize the statistics
along a normal distribution as a way to simulate
the many variables that can occur during battle.
The stat parameters are based on the official
Marvel power grid from which the DC characters'
statistics are extrapolated. Additional stat
categories are included such as range, damage
potential, versatility and perception in order
to create a more detailed and accurate simulation.
The results of the 1000 simulations provide
a percentage of wins for each character. The
contestant with the higher percentage is declared
the victor. as they have a higher probability
to win any given battle. In an equitable pairing,
neither character should win 100% of the matches.
The comic book stories have shown that there's
even a way for Batman to defeat Superman, so
the confidence rate of my method falls in line
with the precedents that have been established
in the source material. My mathematical simulations
are without subjectivity or bias. Feats are
not the sole consideration, nor are fan votes
tabulated for determination of the winner.
Thanks, Adrian 9K. Before we run the simulations
though, we like to break down each character's
histories and abilities before improvising a
scenario on how we imagine one of the 1000
simulations would play out beat for beat. And
I believe, Jonathan, it is your turn to go
first with the DC character, so tell us all
about Arsenal. Alright. Roy Harper Jr. was
raised by a single father, Roy Sr., who was
a forest ranger in the southwestern United
States. At age two, Roy Jr. was orphaned when
his father helped evacuate and rescue members
of a Navajo reservation because of a wildfire,
and Roy was adopted by Brave Bow, the tribe's
shaman who trained Roy in archery. When Green
Arrow emerged as a superhero, Roy became fascinated
that someone could become a hero with only a
bow and arrow. When Brave Bow learned that
he was dying from an illness, He invited Green
Arrow to visit the reservation and judge an
archery tournament, during which Roy impressed
Green Arrow with his bow skills. Though Roy
was sabotaged in the final round of the competition,
Green Arrow recognized how fast Roy was with
his bow, even speedier than him, and he agreed
to take Roy on as his ward to continue his
archery training as well as foster skills in
crime fighting. When Green Arrow felt Roy was
ready, He presented him with his own costume
and trick arrows so that he could become his
sidekick, known as Speedy. You can learn more
about Green Arrow in our Green Arrow vs Hawkeye
Duel episode. After aiding Green Arrow in numerous
adventures against villains such as Count Murdigo
and Clock King, Roy eventually helped found
a team of teen sidekicks known as the Teen
Titans, which you can learn more about in our
Titans vs X-Men Duel episode. After breaking
up with his teenage sweetheart Donna Troy, the
eventual disbandment of the The loss of Green
Arrow's fortune and its subsequent abandonment
of Roy to travel the country with Green Lantern
and Black Canary, Roy, depressed, turned to
drugs and became addicted to heroin. When Green
Arrow uncovered Roy's drug use, he kicked him
to the curb, forcing Roy into homelessness.
It took some time, but eventually Roy overcame
his addiction after promising to Black Canary
that he would, though it took a lot longer for
him to overcome his resentment toward Green
Arrow. Having grown into an adult, Roy became
a counselor to teams with drug problems, and
he attempted to become a crime fighter once
again, even joining a reformed Team Titans,
though the team later disbanded. Eventually,
Roy was recognized by the Central Bureau of
Investigations, or CBI, as a potential clandestine
agent to stop drug trafficking and terrorism.
The CBI trained him in the use of firearms and
turned him into an official drug enforcement
agent. tasked on one assignment to gain the
trust of a foreign assassin named Cheshire.
Though Roy was eventually supposed to turn Cheshire
into the authorities, the two ended up falling
in love and having an affair. Worried that their
relationship would endanger her, Roy abandoned
Cheshire, unaware that she was pregnant and
would give birth to his daughter, Leanne. When
Roy learned of Leanne's existence, he and Nightwing,
who you can learn more about in our Nightwing
vs. Daredevil episode, tracked Cheshire down.
though she captured and poisoned Roy, leaving
him for dead along with their daughter. Though
Nightwing was able to save Roy, and Roy accepted
the responsibility of being a single father,
just as his father was. After the CBI was moved
under the larger clandestine organization Checkmate,
Nightwing came to an agreement with the US
government that the Titans should be a gove
team, at which point Nightwing stepped down
as team leader, and Roy, now going by the new
superhero codename Arsenal. took his place.
The Titans team eventually dissolved, and Arsenal
used the opportunity to reconcile with Green
Arrow, shortly before his Mator dive in an airplane
explosion. After a new incarnation of the Titans
disbanded following the death of several team
members at the hands of Brainiac, Arsenal received
corporate sponsorship to form a new superteam,
which he named the Outsiders. That included
Nightwing, the Green Lantern-powered Jade,
and a rehabilitated brainiac robot named Indigo,
among others. During one mission, the team
encountered a child slaver named Tanner from
Roy's past as an undercover CBI agent. Tanner
recognized Roy and decided to torture him by
kidnapping his daughter, Leon, even branding
her with his mark. But Roy and the outsiders
were able to track him down and safely rescue
all of the children he had captured, including
Leon. After being shot in the chest and having
his throat slit- During the team's many adventures,
Roy decided that the outsider's aggressive
approach to crime fighting wasn't suitable for
a single father, and he left the team with
Nightwing in charge. Eventually, Roy was recruited
to the Justice League, during which time he
was dubbed Red Arrow by Green Lantern, an identity
he fully embraced by taking up the bow as his
primary weapon once again. During his time on
the League, the team was attacked by the villain
Prometheus, who infiltrated their satellite
headquarters, ambushed Roy, and sliced off
his arm with a sword. You can learn more about
Prometheus in our Prometheus vs Taskmaster
duel episode. As Roy was undergoing emergency
medical treatment for his arm, Prometheus successfully
destroyed most of Star City, where Roy resided
with his daughter. Leon was home when it was
destroyed, and she died as a result. Green Arrow,
who had long since returned to life by this
point, killed Prometheus in response, and Roy
was given a cybernetic arm. though it was of
little solace as he initially had trouble aiming
with his new arm, and in his despair he turned
to painkillers. He was eventually ambushed one
night in his new home by Cheshire, who blamed
him for Leon's death, though in their dispute
the two ended up grieving together rather than
fighting. Returning to heroin, Roy took to the
streets, viciously beating up criminals while
high. He was eventually discovered by Nightwing,
who put Roy in rehab, though Roy escaped and
later killed the imprisoned villain. known as
the Electrocutioner, who was Prometheus' accomplice
in the destruction of Star City. After which,
Roy burned down his home and all of his possessions
while reclaiming the mantle of Arsenal. Roy
joined Deathstroke's villainous version of
the Titans, helping to build a healing machine
called the Methuselah that Deathstroke was
able to use to heal his son, Jericho. You can
learn more about Deathstroke in his duel episode
against Deadpool. When Deathstroke claimed the
machine could also bring back Leon, Cheshire
jumped at the opportunity, but Roy came to the
sobering conclusion that his daughter was in
a better place, and he took on Deathstroke and
the rest of the team to successfully destroy
the machine. Though Cheshire vowed revenge against
him, Roy and the newly-healed Jericho decided
to reform the Titans' team. In post-Flashpoint
continuity, Roy's backstory remained about
80% intact, though his arm was replaced with
an organic replica, and Leon never died. After
forming a team called Iron Rule to overthrow
the Korraki dictatorship, Roy was forced to
kill his teammates when they turned against
him and began killing civilians. For his crimes
against Korraki, Roy was sentenced to death,
though he was rescued by the Red Hood and Starfire,
both of whom you can learn more about in their
respective duels against the Punisher and Sunspot.
Together, the three formed a team known as the
Outlaws, taking on the likes of the Joker in
Gotham City and the League of Assassins around
the world. world. When Wally West returned
to continuity, Roy and the original Titans reformed
the team, though Wally would accidentally cause
Roy's death later during a speed force explosion
incident at a therapeutic resource center for
superheroes known as the Sanctuary, where Roy
was getting treatment for his addictive nature.
He was eventually resurrected via a black lantern
ring, but he was able to overcome its influence
through his love for his daughter, Leon, and
help from his former teammate, Jade. Roy eventually
reunited with Leon, learning that she had become
a young vigilante on her own, known as Cheshire
Cat. Well, he, Black Canary, and Green Arrow's
son, searched for a Green Arrow who had become
lost in the timestream along with the rest of
the Justice League. That's pretty much his
backstory so far. Powers-wise, Arsenal has no
superhuman ability outside of his uncanny speed
and precision with ranged weaponry. He's an
accomplished technician, having developed many
of Green Arrow's trick arrows including ones
that are explosive, electrified, cryogenic,
contain knockout gas, smoke, adhesive resin,
and neural scrambling waves, just to name a
few. And though he's among the best archers
in the world, unlike his mentor Green Arrow,
Arsenal employs other weapons such as handguns,
rifles, grenades, crossbows, darts, daggers,
and other throwing blades. He is literally a
walking arsenal, on top of being an expert
in close quarters combat and strategy. His only
weakness is, well, heroin. But he's working
on that. Well, I hear that White Widow has some
contacts in the underground drug trade, so
you might be screwed. I'm sorry, is she regularly
carrying heroin on her? Why do you think they
call her the White Widow? Oh, shit. It's one
of those slang words that Deadpool knows about.
I doubt that. I think you just made that up.
But let me go ahead and tell you the real backstory
of White Widow. Now little is known about the
early life of Yelena Belova, who was born to
unknown parents in Russia. At age 15, she attracted
the attention of the Soviet Red Room, who recruited
her into their Black Widow program, training
her to be an elite spy for 10 years. While
in the program, she constantly held herself
to the standard of the Red Room's most infamous
Black Widow, a spy by the name of Natasha Romanoff,
who had defected from Russia to join the American
group of heroes known as the Avengers. You can
learn more about Natasha in our Black Canary
vs Black Widow duel episode. Yelena's marks
exceeded Natasha's while in the program, and
after succeeding in a test to avenge the death
of her mentor, Yelena graduated from the Red
Room. Sent out as Russia's new elite spy, Yelena
shadowed her rival Natasha during a mission
to retrieve a biological weapon. Planning to
kill Natasha and retrieve the weapon for Russia,
she learned that Natasha was onto her all along.
and the two were forced to fight together against
one Colonel Khan. In order to teach the ambitious
young Yelena a lesson in what makes a spy,
Natasha brought her into S.H.I.E.L.D. custody.
They swapped faces, just like in the movie
Face Off, and Natasha went undercover as Yelena
to stop Yelena's handler, a rogue Russian general,
from restarting the Cold War. Disguised as Natasha,
Yelena learned that the general viewed her
as a disposable and naive tool. Feeling betrayed,
Yelena defected from Russia and had her and
Natasha's faces restored, abandoning their rivalry.
She retired from being a spy to Havana, Cuba,
where she became a model and ran a safe house
that she used to help shelter Natasha while
she was on the run. Yelena teamed up with Daredevil
to rescue Natasha when she was captured by
a cosmetics agency known as Gainacon who was
using pheromone triggers acquired from the
Russian Red Room and its products to manipulate
women around the world. Returning to life as
a spy, Yelena joined SHIELD where she became
part of a rogue faction that was illegally
mining Antarctic vibranium down near the South
Pole in an area called the Savage Land. There
she was attacked by a villain named Soron who
burned and disfigured her body. While in intensive
care, Yelena was approached by Hydra who offered
to restore her appearance by outfitting her
with cybernetics, giving her the powers of the
superadaptoid. villainous robot with the ability
to alter its appearance and take on the powers
of others. In turn, Yelena was tasked with
destroying the Avengers. She nearly succeeded,
taking on the power of the Sentry, but was
defeated by subsequently taking on the Sentry's
villainous alter ego, The Void, which drove
her insane. Seeing that she had failed her mission,
Hydra killed her. You can learn more about
the Sentry in this duel episode against General
Zod. The evil science organization AIM was
able to use Yelena's Adaptoid components to
revive her body, and they manipulated her into
joining AIM. After stealing the Iron Patriot
armor on behalf of the evil scientists she
worked for, Yelena became an enemy of SHIELD,
who sent Natasha after her former protege.
This time, Yelena was able to overcome her fellow
Black Widow using her super Adaptoid powers.
But Natasha was rescued by the Avenger Hawkeye.
When AIM captured Hawkeye's ex-wife, a spy
named Mockingbird, she and Yelena fought. When
it appeared that Mockingbird was victorious,
AIM had her shot. However, it was later revealed
that during the fight, Mockingbird used a holographic
image inducer to alter Yelena's appearance,
and Yelena was the one that AIM had killed.
The Russian Red Room then enacted a program
to revive their best agents via genetic cloning.
This included Natasha, who at the time was also
dead. Regaining her original memories from
Epsilon The Natasha clones sought to shut down
the program by using three amnesiac clones
of Yelena to help destroy the facility and the
genetic samples. Only one of Yelena's clones
survived, who was given the original's memories
from the Red Room psychic as well. Back in
control of her life, Yelena became a mercenary
spy known as the White Widow, and went on a
mission to break the Russian hero Red Guardian
out of captivity. Together, They rescued Natasha
and broke her out of her brainwashing from her
enemies that made her forget her life as a
spy. Both Yelena and the Red Guardian later
joined the new Thunderbolts team led by the
Winter Soldier, a former Captain America sidekick
turned Russian assassin turned hero whom you
can learn more about in our Red Robin vs. Winter
Soldier duel episode. Together, the Thunderbolts
took on and defeated the Red Skull, a villain
you can learn more about in his duel against
Rosal Gull. And that's Yelena's backstory. Abilities-wise,
White Widow has been vigorously trained in
the Soviet Red Room to be one of Marvel's premier
operatives. She is a master in multiple styles
of fighting, and she has biological enhancements
that grant her peak human physicality in terms
of strength, speed, agility, endurance, and
durability. She is an experienced spy, tactician,
hacker, and markswoman. Her costume provides
resilience to small arms fire, and her specialized
bracelets contain a variety of weapons and gadgets
from which she can shoot grapple lines, gas
pellets, and a blast of 30,000 volts of electricity
called a widow's bite. On her person, she also
carries combat knives, handguns, and lock picks.
And that's White Widow. So basically, she's
like a less armed version of Arsenal. Sweet.
A less armed but better in every other way
version of Arsenal, yes. What? That's correct.
We'll find out, I guess. All I'll say is that
she's never done heroin. Wow. How judgmental,
you judgmental piece of shit. Remember kids,
don't do drugs.
Where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
Dynomic Podcast Network presents... Console
Combat, where video game legends brawl every
Monday. Dynamic Duel, where comic book titans
smash every Tuesday. Max Destruction, where...
TV and action heroes battle every Wednesday,
and Sendro World, where anime champions clash
every Thursday. Join us as we speculate on the
matches and armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge victorious.
Visit dynamicpodcast.com where we settle the
debate and settle the score.
Now that we got their histories and abilities
out of the way, let's speculate on how one
of the 1000 simulated matches will go. The winner
is determined by simulations, not the speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how the fight could
play out. AJ and IK, what are the rules of
our speculation? Well, I should say there are
no rules, other than the characters have no
prior knowledge of the other going into the
fight. All they are aware of starting out is
that the other character is a threat that needs
to be eliminated. contestants will begin approximately
50 meters apart in a nondescript environment
that will have no bearing on the match itself
as no environmental statistics are considered
in my simulations the contestants must earn
victory on their own merit. Alright then let's
get into it. Arsenal and White Widow meet on
the battlefield who goes first? Wait let me
answer that. Arsenal goes first. Like they
don't call him speedy for nothing. Alright.
So Arsenal has already drawn duel handguns
and shot her twice in the chest. All right.
Except White Widow's spy suit is made entirely
out of Kevlar. So the bullets are going to hit
her. They're going to knock her down, but she's
not dead. She's still alive and she's going
to go into like agility mode, you know, just
sliding across the floor and handspringing up
to her feet. And while she's in mid handspring,
she's going to fire a gas pellet, a cyanide
gas pellet at Arsenal. and the gas pellet breaks
on him and Arsenal breathes in the cyanide gas
and his lungs just burn up. Actually, Arsenal's
going to shoot that capsule before it even gets
close to him. So now there's this like small
cyanide cloud between them and as White Widow,
you know, is doing hand springs across the
environment, he's going to holster his guns
and he's going to draw his bow and he's going
to fire a glue arrow at her hand just as it
touches the ground. And so her hand is just
stuck there. How does he even know where to
shoot if there's this cyanide cloud in between
them blocking their line of sight? I said it
was a small cloud, you know, plus she's moving
around. So, you know, it's not blocking him
for very long. OK. All right. Well, if he can
see her, then White Widow can see Arsenal firing
this arrow and like a fucking badass, White
Widow is going to catch the arrow midair because
she's an elite spy. OK, she's not going to
get shot with some goo like a chump. And as
she catches the arrow, she's going to immediately
hurl the arrow back at Arsenal. And the glue
arrow is going to hit his holster so that he's
not able to draw one of his guns anymore. She's
that good. Like, she could hurl an arrow that
accurately and that fast. She's that good. OK,
let's say that happens. Let's say Arsenal doesn't
somehow manage to shoot a thrown arrow out of
the air, just like he did with the capsule.
That's fine. You know, because that's just one
gun out of an entire arsenal that he still
has. So he's tired of her flipping and diving
around. So he's going to knock a bola arrow
that's tied to a line. And she gets wrapped
up in it, falling to the ground. At which point
he's just going to reel her toward him like
a fish on a hook. Except White Widow is a master
escape artist. She can slip out of anything.
So she slips out of being wrapped up by this
bola. And at this point, she's within ass kicking
distance of Arsenal. So she's just going to
proceed to kick his ass. She's going to grab
his arm. and she's gonna twist it, flipping
him onto the ground. And then she's gonna step
on his back and just break his arm in like
four different places. Well, I'm sorry to inform
you that she in fact grabbed his prosthetic
arm. Fuck! So, she's holding his arm and Arsenal,
he's just gonna lay down his own ass kicking
on her, but with a knife in his good hand. And
that's gonna allow him to like sever tendons
in her arms and legs. That's going to slow down
her movement. No, I mean, he might get one
good slash in there on her arm, but Arsenal
is now literally fighting one handed. So White
Widow is going to use her other arm that didn't
just get stabbed to put Arsenal in a wrist
lock, forcing him to drop the knife, which she's
going to catch midair before it hits the ground.
And like in one smooth motion, she's going to
stab that knife right into his thigh. OK, like
Aria from Game of Thrones style. Yeah, yes,
exactly. Okay, but I mean, she's going to have
to drop his prosthetic arm while doing that.
And, you know, since Arsenal, you know, he
needs to reattach the arm and he'll need some
distance and some time to do that. This is
where he's going to snatch a cryo arrow from
his quiver. He's going to slam that into White
Widow's back, freezing her torso. So she's going
to be in shock. And that's when Arsenal is
going to reattach his arm and pull the knife
out of his thigh. Okay, so White Widow is in
shock from having her torso frozen, but she's
trained for this. You know, she's from Russia.
I'm sure she's been out in those Siberian winters.
She probably knows what it's like to be frozen.
So she's going to assess the situation quickly.
It's not going to affect her too much. And
yeah, she's not going to be able to move around
as much, but she can still move her arm. And
while Arsenal is attaching his prosthetic, Zap!
He gets shot with 30,000 volts of electricity
to his forehead with White Widow's, Widow's
and it's going to fry his brain and end this
match because he's not faster than fucking electricity.
Damn. Uh, the thing is, though, Arsenal saw
her aiming at him, so he just moved slightly,
like just in time, just enough so that the
widow's bite just knocks off the ball cap that,
you know, he usually wears. And with the knife
in his hand that he pulled from his thigh, he's
just going to flick that into her neck. and
that's gonna sever her spinal column like a
damn surgeon. So unfortunately for you, she
is the one that is dead. You mean unfortunately
for you, Arsenal was already electrocuted before
he could even do that. Why? What do you mean
why? Why not? Because he saw her aiming her
arm at him because she fires those from her
wrist bracelets, right? Yeah, so? He doesn't
know what they do. No, she knows that she's
gonna shoot something from them. He doesn't
know that she has widow bites. He doesn't know
shit. Agree to disagree, but I guess we can
leave the match there. Either Arsenal gets his
brain fried by her widow's bite, or she gets
a knife thrown through her neck. Damn. Let's
go ahead and input the character stats, run
the simulations, and come back with a winner.
Adrian 9K, hit it. Inputting data, running
calculations, processing results, simulations
complete. All right, this was a really good
matchup. I didn't realize the characters had
as many background similarities in being both
hero and villain and being both spies and stuff
like that. But they also were pretty similar
when it came to their stats as well. Yeah, I
knew right off the bat that Arsenal was going
to have an advantage over White Widow when it
came to damage level. And I knew that he would
probably have her when it came to range as well,
just because, you know, being a marksman is
all that he has. And he has a vast arsenal as
well. But White Widow did have a few stats
over Arsenal, including fighting skill and intelligence.
Yeah, they went a little bit tit for tat in
the stats, but any time one of them came out
on top, it was just barely so. Like when it
came to a lot of the physical stats like speed,
evasiveness, durability, strength, they were
even. Surprisingly, because I thought speedy
would be speedier. So taking all of this into
consideration. Joseph, who do you think came
out on top in this match? I think it's going
to be White Widow, because I think they're pretty
evenly matched, and I think Luck is just on
White Widow's side. Oh, I'm sorry, we do not
have a Luck stat, so that is completely moot.
Will our Instagram followers agree with me?
In our poll, 53% said that White Widow would
be Arsenal. Now, to be fair, though, I put up
that poll super late. So there's still a chance
that Arsenal could come out on top. If people
thought Arsenal would win, they would vote
for him. I don't want to hear your excuses.
All right, well, AJ 9K, the results, please.
Here you are, sir. The winner of the matchup
between Arsenal and White Widow is... Arsenal!
He won 54.6% of the 1000 matches compared to
White Widow, who only won 45.4% or 454 total
wins compared to Arsenal's 546%. But where does
the drug dependency stat come into play? Cause
I feel like at any given moment, it's most likely
that Arsenal is just smacked up on heroin and
White Widow barely has to do anything to even
try. He's kicked the habit often enough where
I don't think that would be the case. Uh, what
you didn't account for, and I think why this
is an appropriate win is that even during our
speculation, like I didn't unleash Arsenal's
full Arsenal, like I didn't use anything explosive.
I didn't pull out any crossbows or rifles.
Well, White Widow has explosives too. Yeah,
but they can't go as far as Arsenaals can.
You don't know that? Yeah, I do. Okay. I like
100% know that. All right. So yeah, Arsenaal
wins. Go team DC. After that long break of duel
episodes as we were doing reviews, it's nice
to come back to a duel episode and get the win.
And it will be nice for me to come back in
our next duel episode after this one and teach
you a lesson. What is the next duel episode?
Our next duel episode is going to be the team
duel, Outsiders vs X-Force. That's right. But
that's not going to be next week, that's going
to be in a couple weeks. Right, our next episode
is actually going to be a review of Suicide
Squad Isekai, the television series, and we're
going to bring on a special guest for that.
So look forward to that next week, but that
does it for this duel. AJ9K, help close us out.
Thanks for listening to Dynamic duel. Visit
the show's website at dynamicduel.com and follow
us on Instagram at dynamicduelpodcast. You
can support the show on Patreon at patreon.com
slash dynamicduel and joining a tier that works
for you, or by rating and reviewing Dynamic
duel on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser
or on our website. Don't forget to listen to
the other shows in the DynaMic Podcast Network,
including Max Destruction, Senjou World and
Console Combat. That's all for this episode.
We want to give a big thanks to our executive
producers, Ken Johnson, John Strosky, Zachary
Hepburn, Dustin Balcom, Miggy Mathen-Geehan,
Brandon Estregard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yeaton,
Austin Wazilowski, AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho,
Gil Camacho, Adam Spies, Andrew Shunk, Dean
Molesky, Devin Davis, Joseph Kershting, and
Josh Leiner for helping make this podcast possible.
And we'll talk to you guys next week. Up up
and away, true believers. My ward is a junkie.
He eats too much junk food.