This is a DynaMic Network podcast. Hey guys,
Marvelous Joe at the top of the episode to
let you know that the day this episode drops,
December 31st, 2024, is the very last day to
make a purchase on our Dynamic Duel merchandise
store and have 10% of the proceeds go to the
Stand Up to Cancer Charity Foundation. So visit
dynamicduel.com, click on the store link in
the top navigation, support our show, and support
a great cause. And do it right now. because
again, this is your last chance to help support
a good cause. Thanks guys, and on with the
show.
Hi and welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast,
a weekly show where we review superhero films
and debate the superiority between Marvel and
DC by comparing their characters in stat-based
battle simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe. And I'm
his twin brother, Johnny DC. And in this episode,
we are going to count down the best that Marvel
and DC put out in the year 2024 with our 9th
annual Brothers Awards episode. Yeah, this is
a super fun episode every year. Although Prior
years have probably been more fun because this
wasn't a great year for Marvel and DC films
I would say. Whoa, speak for yourself. You can
talk shit about DC all you want to, but leave
Marvel alone. No no no. You did not have a bad
year whatsoever. Marvel put out shit in the
theaters this year. No, they didn't. And also,
they put out great content on Disney+. Oh that's
weird. Apparently Joseph loves Sony's Spider-Verse
everyone. He just admitted it.
We'll talk all about what shows and movies are
getting our awards later on this episode. Before
that we're going to break down the latest comic
book movie news to come out this past week,
of which there was just one news item and that
was the official trailer for the Your Friendly
Neighborhood Spider-Man television series. As
always we list our segment times in our episode
description so feel free to check out the show
notes if you want to skip ahead to a particular
topic. Our artificially intelligent Duel simulator
AJ9K has a quick message for our listeners.
So listen up. Why hello there, do you want even
more from this podcast? Then become a part
of the dynamic Duel community on Patreon, where
you can choose from three tiers. The dynamic
two-oh tier gives you access to our Discord
chat server. The fantastic four tier gives
you two bonus episodes each month, and the X-Force
tier makes you an executive producer of this
show. Lastly, the Diner Mike podcast network
tier lets you create your own podcast using
this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe will
help you develop your show, provide graphic
support and consultation, and get you simulation
results. Pitch the twins your ideas via email
at dynamicduelpodcast at gmail.com. Check it
out at patreon.com slash dynamicduel. Pip pip
cheerio. Thanks, AJ9K, and thanks to everyone
who supports the podcast. Guys be sure to tune
into the other shows on the DynaMic Podcast
Network this week including Max Destruction,
which pits your favorite action heroes from
film and television against each other. This
week, hosts Scotty and Gilly are finding out
who would win in a fight between Godzilla and
Gamera. On the Sendrow World Podcast, host Zachary
Heppern speculates on fights between fan favorite
anime and manga characters. Last week, Zach
wasn't able to put out his Shinra from Fire
Force vs. Najima from a Dick in a Box episode.
So he will be doing that this week. And on
the console, Combat Podcasts hosts John and
Dean simulate battles between popular video
game characters. In yesterday's episode, they
found out who would win between Shadow the
Hedgehog and Black Zero from Mega Man. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our
show notes to listen to all of the shows in
the DynaMic Podcast Network. But with that
out of the way, quick to the new prize. A no
prize is an award Marvel used to give out to
fans. Our version, the dynamic Duel no prize,
is a digital award that we post on Instagram
for the person that we feel gave the best answer
to our question of the week. Last week we asked,
on a scale of 1 to 10, how excited has the official
teaser trailer for Superman made you for James
Gunn's DCU? And why? And we got a whole lot
of answers this week, 8 in total, so let's
go ahead and count down our 3 honorable mentions.
as well as the no prize winner. Our first honorable
mention goes to Daniel Alonso, who said, From
one to 10, one, I guess, because I can't pick
zero. I mean, Superman is one of the most boring
characters of all time. I don't care, I've
never cared. And then adding crypto, like, why?
The animals in DC are so boring, no one cares.
The only version of Superman I've ever. And
it pains me to say liked is Henry Cavill's,
but God, I do not care at all about this movie.
Did I say this was an honorable mention? Because
I meant it was a dishonorable mention. It's
so ironic that you are saying Superman is the
most boring character because I thought that
was your mom. What? Why are you getting personal?
He didn't get personal. He just said he doesn't
like Superman as a character because he's boring,
which is a valid criticism. Well, I feel personally
attacked because I loved this trailer and I
don't see how anyone could say it was boring
because like I mentioned, when we were discussing
the trailer in our last episode, we see a side
of Superman, a more human side that we really
haven't seen on screen before. For people who
think that the character of Superman is boring,
do you think James Gunn's Superman movie will
be the one to turn them around? If it doesn't,
I don't know what can. And what do you have
to say to the people who think that Superman
is boring? You are on the wrong side of history,
my friends. Wrong side. I know that a lot of
people thought that characters like Captain
America were boring prior to those MCU films
coming out. So I really hope that the Superman
movie does for the character of Superman that
Captain America was able to do for Steve Rogers.
And then some, because Steve Rogers is still
pretty boring. You know what, Daniel Alonso,
you're right. Good job. Our next honorable
mention goes to. Travis Herndon who said, What's
up Dun and Medoos, Travis here, shout out to
my Evil Twins. So my scale would have to be
a seven and a half out of ten. I think it looks
really good, looks promising. The costumes and
stuff, still gotta get used to those, but everything
else looks pretty good. The music is just amazing.
I mean, I'm a sucker for rock ballads. So honestly,
yeah, looks promising to me, but I'm not putting
my hopes up until I see the movie myself. And
that's fair. It's fair to delay judgment until
you see the final film in terms of how you're
going to feel about James Gunn taking over the
DCU. The trailer may be great, but that does
automatically mean that his DCU will be great,
although I hope it will be. So was the teaser
trailer great? I thought so. Yeah, I thought
it was fantastic. I think I'm more along the
lines of Travis Herndon here. I'm at a steady
like maybe seven, six and a half. kind of in
terms of excitement level. Like the teaser trailer
wasn't mind-blowingly awesome. It didn't blow
me away. I thought it was pretty good. It was
a great Superman movie trailer. As I mentioned,
again, last episode, I didn't really have too
many expectations and maybe that's why this
trailer exceeded mine. I will totally admit
that, but I can't help but love what I saw.
I remember back in like 2012 when we got the
first teaser trailer for Man of Steel, and
I remember being blown away by that. I thought
that was a fantastic teaser. I don't know if
the trailer for this most recent iteration of
Superman quite lived up to that. I think it
was hard to really gauge that the first Man
of Steel teaser trailer was a Superman movie
because we got shots of like a butterfly on
a porch swing and a guy walking down the road
with a beard. It wasn't as much of a Superman
movie as it was just like a fairly decent looking
movie in general. I liked the music for that
one, though I do have to say, as Travis Herndon
mentioned, the rock ballad that they use here
of John Williams' original score hit me way
harder than I thought it would. Like when he's
saving that young girl and the music is just
swelling, I was like, holy crap, tears in my
eyes. Tears in my eyes. Oh my god, get over
yourself. Tears coming out of my eyes, bro.
Thanks Travis Herndon for your answer. Our
next honorable mention goes to Mason Thompson,
who said, What's giddy? Plain and simple, 10
out of 10. I love it, because I like how much
it pops. I think James Gunn does that very
well. And I think he represents more hope than
Henry Cavill did. I don't know what it is about
it, it just does. And then Guy Gardner's bowl
cut, mwah. I like the actor for Lex Luthor,
and I like Mr. Terrific, so 10 out of 10. Yeah,
one of the major criticisms of the DCEU was
how dark it was, not only in terms of themes,
but also in terms of the cinematography. The
colors in this new Superman movie looks like
they really are going to pop and really jump
at you on the screen. I was actually pretty
amazed by how striking the visuals were in
this trailer. And that's partly why I think
people are getting a much more hopeful vibe
from this universe. If you're a DC fan who reads
DC comics, seeing things like Guy Garner's
bowl cut, that's all really exciting because
it feels like for the first time we're getting
a pretty close translation of the comics characters
to the screen in a more faithful way than perhaps
we've had in the past. Well, it means that you're
getting a shared universe like right out of
the gate. Right. Yes, exactly. It's a risky
move to jump in the deep end like that, but
we'll see if it pays off. My body is ready.
Great answer, Mason. We want to give a quick
shout out to Jarell, who called in for the first
time. Thanks for calling in. John Storosky,
Josh Hayward, and Michael Williams for taking
the time to visit our website and record an
answer. But the winner for this week's No Prize
is Miggy Mathengian, who said, hey, what's
up, guys? This is Miggy. And on a scale from
1 to 10, it would be a million. The Superman
teaser trailer got me super hyped. It's everything
I wanted and more. We got to see. the hope
that Superman really embodies. We got to see
him saving people and being who he is. We got
to see crypto and the terrifics and the Daily
Planet staff like Lois and his classic enemies
like Lex. And a lot of people agree with me
because it is the fifth most viewed trailer
of all time. The fact that Warner Brothers Studios
has been around as long as it has and Superman
has become its most viewed trailer. bodes really,
really well for this movie. It's the number
five most viewed trailer of all time. And if
you look at the four above it, they're all
Marvel films. Deadpool and Wolverine actually
just set the number one record earlier this
year, but also all four of them went on to gross
over a billion dollars. I'm not saying that
means Superman is going to gross over a billion
dollars, but man, what a precedent. Does high
trailer views on YouTube correlate to enjoyment
of the trailer? Or do you think a lot of them
were hate views? No, no one hate watches stuff
that many times. It's it's hype factor. It
officially has like the biggest hype factor
of a Warner Brothers or DC movie ever, apparently
right at the gate. It's awesome. I hate watched
it a few times. I'm just going to say that.
You know what? That's fine. Keep adding to it.
The numbers. Anyone who didn't like the trailer
should definitely hate watch it at least five
or six more times. And the movie in theaters
as well. Right. Go hate watch that. At least
three times. Well congrats to Miggy for winning
this week's No Prize. If you the listener want
a shot at winning your own No Prize, stay tuned
to later on this episode when we'll be asking
another Question of the Week. And now that
that's done, onto the news!
Alright, this past week we got our first official
trailer for the Your Friendly Neighborhood
Spider-Man series, which is going to debut in
January of 2025, so just in a few weeks here.
It's pretty late to be getting a trailer, but
maybe that's because when I watched it I didn't
like too much of anything that I saw. I'm just
gonna say it right off the bat. I didn't love
this trailer. What didn't you like about it?
Okay, so for a bit of context, this show was
originally going to be Spider-Man Freshman and
it was going to be a look at the MCU version
of Peter Parker, you know, the Tom Holland version.
It was basically going to be his origin story.
But the show was later retooled to be an alternate
universe version of Peter Parker. You know,
this is definitely not the MCU version of Peter
Parker. But you know, there's supposed to be
a lot of parallels here. One of the parallels
we see here is that instead of Tony Stark mentoring
Peter Parker, it's going to be Norman Osborn,
which is an interesting take. Yeah, and instead
of getting the Iron Spider suit, he gets like
the Future Foundation suit. Yeah, that's one
of the things I don't like. That's at the end
of the trailer. But yeah, it is weird that
Spider-Man's initial Spider-Man costume outside
of his homemade one is going to be the Future
Foundation, which, of course, in the comic books
is a white and black Spider-Man outfit that
was given to Peter Parker. By Reed Richards,
Mr. Fantastic, when he formed the Future Foundation
in honor of Johnny Storm, who at the time had
died in the Negative Zone in the comic books.
And it was a science organization and it was
a cool looking outfit. But it is weird for
that to be his first, like, official outfit
within this particular universe. So that was
like one of the things I didn't like. I also
don't really like his initial homemade outfit.
Like, it doesn't have the goggles from the MCU
version of Spider-Man that we saw. Like it
comes with his curved eye lenses, like right
off the bat, which I thought was a little bit
weird. But also the suit doesn't look very appealing,
despite the fact that it's supposed to be,
you know, homemade. Yeah, it's almost more like
Scarlett Spider's costume. Well, yeah, I mean,
that's what inspired Tom Holland's version of
his homemade outfit. But I really liked the
way they took that one, where it was like a
hoodie, you know, with the goggles. Here we
have more like a sports jersey with the curved
lenses and everything like that. He's wearing
a backpack which holds his web fluid which is
connected to his wrists via these hose cables.
It's all just very different. I didn't like
some of the scenes that we got here where Spider-Man
is beating up a bunch of high school bullies.
He straight up web slings a brick into one
of the kid's head. I'm pretty sure he commits
murder in the course of this trailer. It just
seems a little bit violent for the character.
I'm not anti-cartoon violence, but I'm pretty
sure... that in the next shot where we see the
kid who got hit in the head with a brick, he's
totally comatose. And I don't know, it's just,
it's weird. This feels a little bit nitpicky,
but everything just falls in line with my prior
biases that I had developed against the show.
We see Peter Parker say deuce is out. I thought
that was fucking weird. It is cool to see Liz
Allen and Nico Minoru within the trailer. I'm
really interested in seeing what they do with
Nico if she's gonna get her staff of one. and
maybe there's gonna be like a runaways tie
in with this particular series. That would be
really cool. But that would be one of the few
things that I would be looking forward to. I
understand your criticisms, though I guess
I am surprised that you didn't like this. I
didn't care for it too much. I definitely thought
you were going to like it more than I did. I
actually did like the animation style. It reminded
me very much of like a Silver Age kind of Steve
Ditko approach. But that said, I could also
criticize that because I would much rather see.
then continue the what-if animation style for
MCU projects, just to keep that branding, essentially.
No, I mean, I don't need that at all. I mean,
look at X-Men 97. Well, that's not in the MCU.
Neither is this, you know? And actually, now
that I mentioned that, the ideal version of
this project, considering how good X-Men 97
was, would have been for them to make Spider-Man
98, which is the year that the 90's Spider-Man
cartoon ended. And that cartoon was fantastic.
You know, it was a quintessential Spider-Man
cartoon. which came out concurrently with the
X-Men 90s cartoon. So I think I would have
preferred that a million times more than what
we're getting here with this strange quasi
MCU take on Spider-Man. Yeah, that seemingly
has one foot in the MCU and one foot out. Yeah.
I get it. I would have loved to have seen like
year one of the MCU Peter Parker. Yeah, I either
wanted freshman year or Spider-Man 98. This
whole criticism of the trailer just feels like
me bitching and moaning. But I think a lot of
people would at least agree that what could
have been for this show would have been better.
So when we review this, are you going to count
that against this show? No, I'm going to try
to go in as objective as possible. You know,
for everything that I'm saying about the show,
it could have really tremendously well-written
stories. And in that case, I'm going to rate
it accordingly. But I just want to on the record
basically that this show probably could have
been something better. Well, who knows? Maybe
we'll end up seeing this version of Spider-Man
in the Beyond the Spider-Verse movie. or in
Secret Wars or something, who knows. I guess
we'll find out how good the show is when it
starts streaming on Disney Plus on January 29th.
But speaking of people's anticipation and excitement
levels, for this series that brings us to our
question of the week.
On a scale of 1-10, how excited has the Friendly
Neighborhood Spider-Man trailer made you for
the series, and why? This question is kind of
similar to last week's question about the Superman
trailer, but it's going to be about this animated
series. Record your answer at dynamicduel.com
by clicking on the red microphone button in
the bottom right hand corner of the screen,
which will prompt you to leave us a voicemail.
Your message could be up to 30 seconds long,
and don't forget to leave your name in case
we include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a dynamic
duel no prize that we'll post to Instagram.
Be sure to answer before January 4th.
That does it for all the news for this episode.
So let's go ahead and move on to our main event,
which will be the 2024 Brothers Awards instead
of like going with a purple carpet or a red
and blue striped carpet. Jonathan, let's go
with the carpet whose fibers are like red on
one side and blue on the other. So like the
carpet changes color as people walk on it.
No, no, no. Two separate carpets. All right.
Yeah, let's segregate the Marvel fans from
the DC fans. You're right. Red carpet goes to
the back door. Blue carpet goes to the front.
The red carpet goes to the glass elevator. Anyway,
we're getting too caught up on this carpet
thing, but let's go ahead and get seated for
the 9th Annual Brothers Awards.
All right, everybody, welcome to the 2024 Brothers
Awards. It is the premiere event that we hold
every year on this show where we award the best
onscreen content to come out from Marvel and
DC. Yeah, it's an award show that we've done
every year since the podcast started back in
2016. If you've listened to one of our award
shows before, you'll know that the Brothers
Awards are actually named after the Marvel and
DC Red and Blue Brothers that represented their
respective universes. in the DC vs Marvel comic
mini series that came out in the 90s. Yeah,
we award these statuettes to Marvel and DC Media
in 10 different categories, including Best
Trailer, Best Original Music, Best New On-Screen
Character, Best Villain, Best Hero, Best Moment,
Best Actress, Best Actor, Best Series Slash
Special, and finally Best Picture. Ten different
categories, each with four nominees from which
we pick the winner. Yeah, anything that came
out in theaters or on a streaming platform is
eligible to win. For Marvel, in 2024 that included
the theatrical films Madame Web, Deadpool and
Wolverine, Venom the Last Dance, and Kraven
the Hunter. And on streaming, there was Echo
Season 1, X-Men 97 Season 1, Hitmonkey Season
2, Agatha All Along Season 1, and What If Season
3. So 9 different Marvel projects eligible
for a Brothers Award in 2024. Whereas DC had
13, that included the feature films Justice
League Crisis on Infinite Earths Part 1, Part
2, and Part 3, Watchmen Chapters 1 and 2, and
Joker Folie a Deux. For streaming services we had
Dead Boy Detective Season 1, My Adventures
with Superman Season 2, Suicide Squad Isekai
Season 1, Batman Caped Crusader Season 1, Kite
Man Hell Yeah! Season one and the Penguin season
one. A lot of season ones here. A lot of content
for sure. Although not as much as previous years.
I think largely due to the writer's strike,
but enough to work with. That's what you say.
No, this was a tough year. I feel like for
DC and Marvel too for both of us. Not really,
no. Yes, don't lie. Don't lie to yourself.
Let's go ahead and get started with our first
category, which is best trailer. The way I
picked the nominees and the winner for best
trailer are the trailers that not only got
me very excited for the upcoming project, but
also I think gave us something new and exciting.
Yeah, it should be noted that the content eligible
for this award was not necessarily on our list
of projects that came out in 2024. Right. They
could be trailers for projects that come out
in 2025. Let me run down the Marvel nominees.
The nominees are Captain America Brave New
World Official Trailer. Your inner circle's
been compromised. Let me fix it. Watch yourself.
You're not Steve Rogers. You're right. I'm not.
Deadpool and Wolverine. Official teaser. You
don't just stand there, you ape. Give me a hand
up. Nope, I'm actually okay. Thank you very
much. Thunderbolts. D23 Brazil special look.
You are all so adorable. Eat shit, Valentina.
Venom The Last Dance Final Trailer What's his
name then?
We have something in me.
That's a solid lineup. If I had to guess which
one of those gets the win this year, that's
tough. It might be the Thunderbolts because
I know you like the TOTY's Possum Kingdom that
song was used in the Thunderbolts trailer. But
I also really liked the style of the Brave
New World trailer. So I think I'm going to go
with that. That's my guess. And the winner
is. Captain America, Brave New World official
trailer. Alright, you guessed correctly right
out of the gate. Yeah, Captain America Brave
New World was a different kind of trailer for
Marvel. You know, they've never really put out
something that stylistic ever really. You know,
the trailer didn't have the typical Marvel Studios
title card. It was heavily stylized with like
split screenshots and kind of creepy sound effects
and everything like that just really evoked
the best political thrillers ever made. Yeah,
there was no music. There were no jokes. It
felt very off brand for Marvel. but also it
was really intriguing. Yeah, the trailer was
a big swing for Marvel, I feel like, and it
gets me excited for the future of Marvel trailers
and how stylistic they're willing to go with
them from here on out. And also excited for
Captain America Brave New World. I am really
pumped to see that now. Regarding the other
nominees, I nominated Venom, The Last Dance
final trailer, because that was when we got
word that Null was gonna be in the movie. We
didn't know that before, so that got me super
pumped. Of course, the D23 Brazil special look
for Thunderbolts was fantastic. It was an extended
preview for the film and Deadpool and Wolverine.
The teaser for that film came out around the
Super Bowl, and it just got me all sorts of
hyped. Like we didn't even see Wolverine in
that preview until we see his shadow walk over
Deadpool laying on the ground and his claws
pop. And then we get the official title of the
movie, which was Deadpool and Wolverine. So
that was all just very exciting. But yeah, Captain
America Brave New World gets the win. for its
stylistic choices. Great year for Marvel trailers,
absolutely. Also a great year for DC trailers.
And let me get into my nominations. The nominees
for best DC trailer are Joker, Folie a Deux, official
teaser trailer. Whoa.
The Penguin Season 1 Official Teaser 2 Suicide
Squad Isekai Season 1 Official Trailer 3
Superman official teaser trailer
crypto Home david home
I think this one's pretty clear cut. I think
you're going to give it to Superman because
even though it's a mid trailer, you just seem
to really be gung-ho for it. So that's my guess.
And the winner is... Superman Official Teaser
Trailer. Yeah, you're absolutely right. I gave
this one the award, not only because it was
the most recent one and very top of mind, but
also because of, again, how hyped it gets me
for James Gunn's universe as a whole. It's
really awesome to be a DC fan right now and
have something like an entirely new universe
to look forward to, especially after a trailer
like this that makes you fairly confident in
the quality and tone that universe will have.
I think prior to the release of the Superman
trailer, you were most excited by the Joker
Folly-A-Do trailer. I almost gave that one
the win because that teaser trailer was incredible.
What the World Needs Now, a song by Tom Jones,
just fit perfectly with the tone and the footage
that they were showing. It looked like it was
going to be another masterpiece from Todd Phillips,
and it really set my expectations unbelievably
high. dashed on the rocks below once the movie
finally came out and we all saw it. Yeah, that
was definitely an instance of the trailer being
better than the movie. Yeah. Regarding the
other two nominees, the Penguin Season 1, Official
Teaser 2, and Suicide Squad Isekai Season 1,
Official Trailer 3, I chose those largely because
they also got me really excited and pumped
for the upcoming projects. I was actually really
happy with just about every trailer that came
out for DC this year. Well, let's go ahead and
move on to our next category, which is best
original music. Music in movies and television
have a way of moving and affecting audiences
in a way they may not even realize. A good score
can go a long way in setting the tone for a
film and our emotional response to it. Yeah,
the way I usually judge a film's music is by
how evocative it is of the material you're seeing
on the screen. If it's iconic. That's a big
bonus. And of course, I try to pick out what's
unique as well. This category encompasses both
the score and original songs that were made
for the movie. DC had some great music this
year, and let me go over my nominees. The nominees
for best DC original music are Dead Boy Detectives,
season one.
Joker, follow ya'll do.
I'll follow you. Take my hand. Stay here, my
friend. The Penguin, season one.
may be trouble ahead. Suicide Squad Isekai,
Season 1.
These are good options. The music for The Penguin
was fantastic, but I think ultimately you're
gonna give it to Suicide Squad Isekai, because
the music for that show was just next level.
And the winner is Joker, Ballyadoo. What? No!
Are you joking me? You think I wouldn't give
it to a musical that had good music? The songs
for that movie sucked. No, you are wrong, my
friend. If you listen to the soundtrack, of
Joker Folly I do, it's actually a really damn
good soundtrack. And it actually had multiple
soundtracks. Not only did it have the score
from Hilda Gunnedadder, which crushed it, it
also had an original soundtrack featuring songs
from Lady Gaga and Joaquin Phoenix. And on top
of that, Lady Gaga released a side album called
Harley Quinn, featuring a lot of the same music
from the movie, as well as some original songs
that she composed, which just blew my mind how
classic they sound. The movie was terrible,
but amidst the garbage that was on the screen
was not the music. You know, you usually have
a controversial choice every year. And I think
this is your controversial choice for this
year. I think you're going to get a lot of flack
from fans when they see this award being posted
to Instagram, but I think you at least you have
a good reasoning behind this one, better reasoning
than you have had in past years with your controversial
choices. I'm going to share the albums with
you and I hope you listen to them. And I think
you'll agree with me at the end of the day.
I won't listen to it. OK. Dead Boy Detectives,
the Penguin, both had really solid scoring
throughout the series. Suicide Squad was interesting
also in that it had original music from artists
like Maury Kaliope, which was used in the end
credits for each episode. Yeah, those songs
were bangers. And that was, I think, the clear
winner. here.
Echo, season one.
Hit Monkey Season 2
Kraven the Hunter.
have to say that the music choices they made
for Hit Monkey season two were phenomenal but
I don't know how many of those were original
to the show. Agatha all along was the closest
thing that Marvel had to a musical this year
so I think that's gonna get the win. And the
winner is Agatha all along season one. Alright
you're just nailing the guesses so far. Two
for two! Yeah, Agatha all along season one did
things with music that we haven't seen since
Wandavision in that we had a lot of original
music and the score for the show itself was
top notch. It was incredible to listen to. Echo
had a lot of great original songs, including
some really awesome Native American music, as
well as a very heavy desert rock sounding riffs.
Hit Monkey, as always, is just a fantastic show
that not only includes a lot of great pulls
in their soundtrack, but the score itself is
a great mix of rock and EDM and hip-hop and
R&B. It's just fantastic to listen to. Kraven
the Hunter I included on here largely because
I thought it was more unique than the other
options that Marvel had released this year
in that Kraven had a lot of music with strong
African influences and traditional Russian
music. I don't think I even really noticed the
score from Kraven. Well, I'll send you the
link to the album and you can check it out.
I will listen to it if you listen to all three
Joker albums. I won't. Then fuck off. Let's
go ahead and move on to our next category,
which is best new on screen character. Now we
like to give this award to the characters that
are new and surprising and hopefully exciting
on the big and small screen. You know, a lot
of the reason why fans enjoy watching these
movies and shows is to see who's going to be
adapted next and what they're going to look
like and what their powers are going to be
portrayed as. So this is always an exciting
award. Yeah, specifically the nominees eligible
for this award are characters that appear for
the first time within a specific universe.
Right, yeah, when you talk about the multiverse,
things get a little bit tricky because you
may see new iterations of characters that you've
seen previously, but we consider a new adaptation
essentially to be a new version of the character.
Let's get into the Marvel Award. The nominees
for best Marvel new on-screen character are
Gambit from Deadpool and Wolverine.
Null from Venom the Last Dance.
Kraven the Hunter from Kraven the Hunter.
Wiccan from Agatha All Along, Season 1.
Oh, interesting. Does Wiccan technically count?
Because we've seen the character in the MCU
earlier. Yeah, but that wasn't even the same
kid. And I'm not talking just about actor wise.
And if you've seen Agatha all along, you'll
know what I'm talking about. OK. Either way,
I don't think he got the win. I think the winner,
hands down, is Gambit from Deadpool and Wolverine.
And the winner is Wiccan from Agatha All Along,
season one. Wow. Controversial choice. All
right. This is yours. Is it? Here you go. So
we've seen Wiccan in the WandaVision television
series that came out back in 2021, but that
wasn't really the official version of the character.
He was just wearing a Halloween costume and
it was more of an Easter egg than anything.
In Agatha all along, we got to see the fully
realized version of Wiccan from the comic books
who had the full costume and all of his magic
powers. And I thought it was a great adaptation,
especially in the way that they chose to adapt
the character of Billy Kaplan. How he was once
Billy Maximoff. I don't want to give away too
many spoilers because there are more to be
had there. But it was just a beautiful story.
And I thought Joe Locke did a fantastic job
playing the character and out of all the new
characters that were debuted this year, I think
I'm most interested in seeing more of the story
of Wiccan. Nah, not Gambit. I want that Gambit
movie. I will be surprised if we see Channing
Tatum back in the role again. Like maybe he'll
have another cameo in the Secret Wars movie
or something like that. But I don't think he's
the MCU's long term gambit. I don't think he's
the MCU's gambit, but I think we'll definitely
see him again. For sure in Secret Wars. I will
bet money on that. Yeah, I wouldn't take that
bet. Now, Wickham, he did a good job. Actually,
all of your nominees were pretty awesome on
this list. Noel wasn't seen too much. Kraven
was, you know, Aaron Taylor Johnson did a good
job acting, even though it was Kraven in name
only. But I still would have chosen Gambit
if it was my award. You thought he was going
to make a name for himself here? Hoo yeah,
boy. Well, let's move on to the DC award. The
nominees for best DC new onscreen character
are Charles Rowland from Dead Boy Detectives
Season 1.
Edwin Payne from Dead Boy Detectives Season
1.
Harleen Quinzel from Joker Folie a Deux.
Victor Aguilar from The Penguin, season one.
Oh, this is a lackluster list. I have no idea
what direction you're going to go with this,
but I think my own personal choice would probably
be Charles Rowland from Dead Boy Detectives.
And the winner is Victor Aguilar from The Penguin
season one. OK, yeah, I can totally see why
you went this route for me, I think just due
to the fact that the character was original
to the series. And so it was an exciting as
an adaptation from the source material. It
would have been the reason why I didn't choose
him. I had a tough time choosing the winner
for this award this year. I really wanted to
give it to Charles Rowland. He was my runner
up because I thought the actors who were in
the Dead Boy Detectives did a fantastic job
with their performances and the show is just
really cool. Ultimately though, I gave the
win to the character that I think had the biggest
impact on me and that had to be Victor Aguilar
from The Penguin. I grew to really love that
character as the season progressed and I don't
want to give away any spoilers. But what happens
to him in the end of that show is devastating.
And I feel like I'm still devastated by that.
It was a fantastic show, largely in part because
of a character like Victor. For sure. That final
episode of The Penguin had a lasting impression.
And Renzi Feliz gave a great performance as
well. Absolutely. Give the guy an Emmy. Let's
go ahead and move on to the next category, which
is best villain. Of course, a hero is only
as good as his villain. I found that. What really
makes a good Marvel and DC television show
or movie is the quality of the villain. You
know, a project that has a weak villain usually
isn't that impressive. So we like to give accolades
to the best villains from this year. Yeah,
villains, you love to hate them, but they really
set the stakes for the projects that they're
in. And story wise, stakes are huge. It's the
whole reason for why the hero fights the good
fight. Let's start with DC. The nominees for
best DC villain are Esther Finch from Dead
Boy Detectives Season 1.
Harleen Quinzel from Joker Folie a Deux.
Joker from Suicide Squad Isekai Season 1.
Sophia Falcone from The Penguin, season one.
Oh, man, I was about to say that this was a
lackluster list until you got to that final
nominee. I think you're definitely going to
give it to Sophia Falcone. And the winner is.
Sophia Falcone from the Penguin season one.
All right, I finally got one. Yeah, we got
Superman the trailer, too. But you're getting
two for four. So if you felt Cohn was a no
brainer on this list, although I did love the
Joker twist at the end of Suicide Squad, Isakai.
but for a majority of the Penguin series, Sophia
Falcone was just remarkable as a villain and
antagonist for Oswald Cobb. I guess I'm most
surprised by your nominees that you included
Harley Quinn in Joker Follyado. Did you consider
her the villain of that movie? Cause I would
have figured it was probably like Harvey Dent.
No, I thought Lee Quinzel was a much bigger
antagonist for Arthur Fleck. than Harvey Dent
was, even though Arthur Fleck probably would
not admit that. Or maybe like the security guard.
He'd definitely be a villain as well. I guess
it's arguable as to who the main antagonist
was. But for my money, that was Lee Quinzel.
She was awful. I hated her. Was Esther Finch
the witch in Dead Boy Detectives? Yes. OK,
yeah, she was great. She was fantastic, but
not as great as Kirsten Melody as Sophia Falcone.
She knocked it out of the park. episode to episode.
She was essentially the second star of the
show. And I wasn't thrilled initially that she
was going to be the lead villain of the series,
but I thought she was put to use expertly in
having Azkab rise to the role of the Penguin.
And performance wise, Kristen Milioti scared
the shit out of me. So yeah, she was very effective
as a villain. Yes, hands down. Give her the
Emmy. Let's move on to the Marvel Award. The
nominees for best Marvel villain are Bastion
from X-Men 97 Season 1
Cassandra Nova from Deadpool and Wolverine.
Death from Agatha All Along, season 1.
Kingpin from Echo Season 1.
Oh damn, this is a really good list. That's
a hard choice to make. I guess I'm gonna go
with Bastion from X-Men 97 because I think he
was the most complex villain. And the winner
is Bastion from X-Men 97 Season 1. Woohoo! Am
I that predictable? Yes. Yeah, Bastion was
an incredible villain for X-Men 97. Not only
did he continue the themes of the X-Men animated
series into this new season, but he also posed
like a great, like modern threat to the team
in this day and age that felt very in keeping
with who the X-Men are. And he did a lot of
damage in that show. You think about what happened
on Genosha. He was a very effective villain.
Absolutely. And the wrap up they did with him
at the end. was so powerful in terms of like
the story arc for Cyclops. It was such a great
season of television, which is why we gave
it five out of five stars when we reviewed the
show. Right. He played a large part of that.
Yeah, I forget the actor who did his voice,
Theo James. Oh, yeah. He did a fantastic job
as well. I loved that. That was great. Yeah,
I hope he plays the character in live action
if they ever bring Bastion into the live action
MCU. The live action actors on your list weren't
bad, terrible, like Aubrey Plaza as Death. That
was a great twist. Yeah, and Kingpin was the
best thing about Echo season one. And Cassandra
Nova, of course, was just really interesting
and pretty damn cool in Deadpool and Wolverine.
Yeah, very spunky. Well, let's move on to our
next award, which is best hero of 2024. Of course,
this is the opposite of the villain award,
whereas the villains set the stakes. The heroes
are there to overcome them in the story. Yeah,
we like to give recognition to the heroes that
inspire us. and provide the whole reasoning
that we watch these tales of morality play out.
Starting off with the Marvel Award, the nominees
for best Marvel hero are Cyclops from X-Men
97 Season 1.
Deadpool from Deadpool and Wolverine.
Venom from Venom the Last Dance.
Wolverine from Deadpool and Wolverine.
Holy crap. Wow. I think Cyclops had a really,
really good arc, but so did Wolverine and Deadpool
and Wolverine. So I'm gonna go with Wolverine.
And the winner is Deadpool from Deadpool and
Wolverine. Oh, controversial choice. Is it?
No, I don't think so. I think if you remember
the arc from Deadpool and Wolverine that Deadpool
had, I think it was the most depth we got of
the character in all of his film trilogy. You
know, he started out with a really touching
moment talking about how he wants to matter
and, you know, getting rejected from the Avengers
affected his entire life. He really grew as
a character through the course of the film
and was really pleased with his journey, as
goofy as it sometimes may be. I think he really
grew as a character and as a hero. I guess I
kind of thought his arc was just an upgraded
version of what we got in Deadpool 2, which
you know is still a solid arc for the character.
I would have given it maybe to Wolverine because
of what that version of the character went
through and what he learned from X-23 and everything
like that. But I could totally see giving it
to Deadpool as well. Honestly, all of the character
arcs from all four of your nominees were solid.
Yeah, yeah. He was a standout hero from that
series. Venom, you know, the way that movie
ended was very much in keeping with the heroic
theme of sacrifice. So yeah, all these guys
were great. Yeah. Great choices this year. Moving
on to the DC award. The nominees for best DC
hero are Batman from Batman caped Crusader season
one.
Harley Quinn from Suicide Squad Isekai Season
1.
Kite Man, from Kite Man, Hell Yeah, Season 1.
Superman from My Adventures with Superman Season
2.
I have to say your lists are not up to scratch.
You can go fuck yourself. The Marvel lists
have been much more solid than these lists.
I find it hard to pick from your list of nominees
primarily because I don't see a good standout
option. I'm gonna go with Batman from the Caped
Crusader season one. And the winner is Superman
from My Adventures with Superman season two.
Sure, yeah, why not? I think on that way too.
So I love my adventures with Superman as a
show. I think they do a fantastic job reinventing
the character for modern times. In season one,
Superman's arc really revolved around who he
was. And in the second season, it was more
about where he comes from and what that means
in regards to the relationships that he's developed
on the show. I thought they did a fantastic
job introducing characters like Supergirl and
Brainiac. for Superman to interact with. And
again, I just really like how heroic the character
of Superman is in the show compared to some
of the other heroes on my list, such as Batman,
Harley Quinn, and Kite Man. Well, Superman is
the quintessential hero, right? Portrayed correctly,
he would always win this award. And I think
My Adventures with Superman does just that.
It's a fantastic show for sure. Yeah, this is
actually the second year in a row that he's
won this award. I was thinking of giving it
to Batman, the caped crusader, because that
was just as good of a show, I think, as my adventures
with Superman season two. But Batman kind of
played a second fiddle in that show to the city
of Gotham itself. I would agree. Yeah. Like
you want to keep Batman mysterious too, you
know? Right. Exactly. That really helped with
that show, actually.
Where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
Dynomic Podcast Network presents Console Combat,
where video game legends brawl every Monday.
Dynamic Duel, where comic- Smash every Tuesday,
Max Destruction, where TV and action heroes
battle every Wednesday, and Sendro World, where
anime champions clash every Thursday. Join
us as we speculate on the matches and, armed
with the power of mathematical simulations,
discover who will emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
Let's go ahead and move on to the next category,
which is Best Moment. Now, this is one of my
favorite awards to hand out because I like going
back and thinking about the moments that really
stood out to me from Marvel and DC projects.
These are the occurrences on film and television
that really got you up on your feet cheering
or like just despondent emotionally. But these
are the moments that you remember for years
to come. Yeah, the nominees for this award
consist of the most impactful moments. from
the past year. Let's start with the DC Award.
The nominees for best DC moment are Escape from
Hell, Dead Boy Detectives, season one.
Joker questions Gary Puddles from Joker Folly-a-doo.
Was I the same old Joker that I always been?
Oh, it's the Tugtelist yourself. Magical Armor
Op from Suicide Squad, Isekai, season one.
Get out of here! Oz and Victor's farewell from
The Penguin, Season 1.
I can't bring you with me this time. Alright
now this list is impressive. For as much shit
I'm giving you about your other lists, I actually
think that these are all standout moments.
I don't think anything will stick with me as
much as Oz and Victor's farewell though. So
that's my guess for the win. The winner is...
Oz and Victor's farewell from the Penguin season
one. It has to be. Yeah. To me, this was hands
down the most impactful moment from, I think,
any DC show in recent memory. It was heartbreaking.
You know, DC has had some pretty heartbreaking
season finales. I think back to the Doom Patrol
moment from that show's series finale. And
that was pretty heartbreaking, too. Yeah, that
Doom Patrol moment won a Brothers Award earlier.
And I would have to say that This packed just
the same amount of punch, which is surprising
because with the Doom Patrol characters, we
had been with them for several seasons. But
when it comes to The Penguin, only having one
season to establish its characters, it was
just a better produced show overall, I would
say, as much as I like The Doom Patrol. And
it's something that'll stick with me for some
time, particularly this moment, which is one
of the reasons we gave the show 5 out of 5 stars.
Yeah, I liked your other moments too, like
the scene in Suicide Squad Isekai where they
get their power up armor in the final episode.
That was so much fun. That was a blast. Yeah,
totally. Honestly, if this was like an award
for the happiest moment out of all of the shows,
that would get the win. The escape from Hell
scene was also pretty powerful from Dead Boy
Detectives. Right, yeah. And of course, Joker
questioning Gary Puddles may have been the best
part of Joker Folie a Deux. Great list, great
list. Now I kind of feel like my list is a little
bit shallow, but these are all stand-up moments
too. Let's get into the Marvel Award. The nominees
for Best Marvel Moment are... Deadpool Core
from Deadpool and Wolverine.
I am Uwatu from What If Season 3.
Let's go, boy. Take her down!
To me, my X-Men from X-Men 97 Season 1. To me,
my X-Men.
Oh, is that in reference to the Sentinel fight
in episode one of the X-Men 97 show? Yes. OK,
that's interesting to me. Honestly, I think
the most impactful moment from X-Men 97 would
have been what happened in Genosha. So already
your list is flawed. I was looking for like
quintessential moments, I guess. Gotcha. Well,
it was nice just to see the X-Men come back,
I suppose, after all these years. But of those
options that you gave me of the nominees. I
would say the Deadpool core is your choice.
And the winner is Deadpool core from Deadpool
and Wolverine. Of course, you know, it was such
a fantastic moment. There were so many great
climaxes in the third act of the Deadpool and
Wolverine movie, which is I think why it got
over a billion dollars. People just love this
movie because you had the fight with, you know,
blade electric gambit against Cassandra Nova's
forces. followed up by the Deadpool fight,
followed up by the sacrifice by Deadpool and
Wolverine at the end. But the fight against
the Deadpool core was not just musically powerful
and heavy on the action and a visual effects
tree. It was everything rolled into one. It
was so much fun to watch. And I think that
moment will stay with me for years to come as
well. I know it will. Yeah, it was incredibly
fun. It was two of four climaxes that happened
while I was watching this movie. I don't know
what the fourth one was, but I don't want to
know. I don't know if you've seen What If Season
3 yet, Jonathan, but I will... I haven't finished
it. So I had no idea what the Watu reference
was. The season ends on a bang. We'll get into
it in our next episode when we review What
If Season 3. The season's not fantastic, but
the finale is pretty much everything you could
hope for in a finale. Nice. That's good to hear.
And of course, release of Symbiotes was another
big action scene. It was really cool to see.
the varying symbiotes that the movie introduced.
That was just a whole lot of fun, too, in the
same way that Deadpool core fight was. Yeah,
it was all right. It was definitely not as good
as Deadpool. So I think you had a solid choice
there. Well, moving on to the next award. This
is for the best actress of twenty four. Yeah,
we love our actresses. Love me some actresses.
It's always fun to give out acting awards,
because in that sense, it feels like we're the
Oscars, right? But. Yeah, the basis of this
award is who we think gave the best performance
in a Marvel or DC project this year. We're
way better than the Oscars. Like those are not
even relevant anymore. Yeah, if you win a Brothers
Award, it means something. Like put it on your
resume, right? 100%. Well, let's see what actress
gets to do that. The nominees for best Marvel
actress are Emma Corrin as Cassandra Nova from
Deadpool and Wolverine.
Catherine Hawn as Agatha Harkness from Agatha
All Along Season 1
Patti LuPone as Lilia Calderou from Agatha All
Along Season 1.
Sashir Zamata as Jennifer Cale from Agatha All
Along, Season 1.
Like all of your nominees basically came from
Agatha. Interesting. Emma Corrin was from Deadpool
and Wolverine. I said almost all. No, you didn't.
I said basically all. I said something like
that. Anyway, of the nominees, I'd probably
say that you went with the star of Agatha all
along, who was Catherine Hahn. And the winner
is. Catherine Hawn as Agatha Harkness from
Agatha All Along Season 1. I am killing it.
You are crushing it, man. You are crushing
it. Yeah, Agatha All Along had a stellar cast
and really these nominees were just a testament
to the fantastic actresses that they got for
that show. You know, Patti LuPone and Sashir
Zamata were playing minor characters but had
major roles within the show and I was really
impressed with the caliber of performances that
we got in that series. But, you know, Catherine
Hahn led the whole thing and I thought she stood
up to the task. As a leading lady, she really
impressed me and definitely went up a tier from,
you know, just a supporting role in WandaVision.
Yeah, she was fantastic. She had a lot of different
roles to play, I guess you could say. Everything
from, you know, dramatic to comedic to doing
a musical number. It was probably an actress's
dream role. Oh, for sure. And she crushed it.
Yeah. Of course, Emma Corrin was also good
in Deadpool and Wolverine. Jonathan, I guess
I'm a little bit surprised that you're surprised
by my list. I'm wondering who you would have
added like Dakota Johnson from Madden Web.
What would you have done? Probably not Dakota
Johnson, but probably Sydney Sweeney. OK, OK.
No, honestly, I'm actually surprised you went
with Emma Corrin over Aubrey Plaza for death.
Aubrey Plaza was in consideration. but I'm still
convinced that the character of Death was Aubrey
Plaza just stumbling onto the set one day, acting
like her normal self. Hahaha. She just is Death.
Yeah. Gotcha. Well, great choice. I think Catherine
Hahn definitely deserves this award. Moving
on to DC, the nominees for best DC actress are
Kristen Milioti as Sofia Falcone from The Penguin
Season 1.
Lady Gaga as Harleen Quinzel from Joker, Folly
I Do.
Jen Lyon as Esther Finch from Dead Boy Detectives
Season 1.
Cassius Nelson as Crystal Palace from Dead Boy
Detectives, season one.
Oh, that's a solid list. It's going to be in
between, obviously, Sophia Falcone and Crystal
Palace. But I think it's going to go to Kristen
Milioti as Sophia Falcone. That's my guess.
The winner is Kristen Milioti as Sophia Falcone
from The Penguin season one. Yeah, honestly,
to me, the choice was between Kristen Milioti
and Lady Gaga. I thought Lady Gaga gave a great
performance in the Joker Folly I do, even though.
I hated her character and I hated the movie
overall. Her performance was not one of the
reasons why, but one of the reasons why I absolutely
loved The Penguin was because of Kristen Milioti's
performance as Sofia Falcone. You know, I gave
her the best villain award in part because Kristen
Milioti's performance was so impeccable. It
really was. I hope that The Penguin Season 1
really does incredible things for her career
because she deserves it. I've seen her in a
few other projects and she's... just an incredibly
capable actor, just so transformative. I don't
know if I ever would have believed her as a
villain until I saw it done and she was just
so intimidating that it blew my mind. Yeah,
the episode specifically where it goes into
her origin, as it were, in Arkham, that hit
really hard and I really hope she wins an Emmy
just for the episode. Give her the Emmy! You're
saying that for every award. Hey, the Penguin
deserves it. Let's go ahead and move on to
our next category, which is best actor. You
know, this award is just like our actresses
award, except the actors are hanging dong instead
of the alternative. I don't know how else to
put it. I've never actually heard that expression
before, but it is accurate. Their actors recommending
their performances. Let's do it up. The nominees
for best DC actor are Colin Farrell as Oswald
Cobb in The Penguin Season One.
George Rexdrew as Edwin Payne in Dead Boy Detectives
Season 1.
Jaden Reverie as Charles Rowland in Dead Boy
Detectives Season 1.
Joaquin Phoenix as Arthur Fleck in Joker Folie a Deux.
Great list, but it's gotta be Colin Farrell,
final answer. The winner is Colin Farrell as
Oswald Cobb in The Penguin, season one. So like
my best actress list, it really came down to
The Penguin and The Joker movies for who I thought
were in contention for this win. I mean, as
great as the Dead Boy Detective guys were, I
mean, it's Colin Farrell and Joaquin Phoenix
giving master class performances. In the end
though, I ended up giving it to Colin Farrell
because I'm still unbelievably shocked that
it's Colin Farrell! It does not look like him.
And as I mentioned in our review, he gives a
technical performance that plays like another
actor giving a method performance. And to me
that's just incredible. I don't even know how
you would classify that, but you're absolutely
right. Colin Farrell deserves all the Emmys
and every single award for his performance as
Oswald Cobb. and I hope he gets it. Give him
the Emmy. Of course, Joaquin Phoenix returning
as Arthur Fleck in a role that won him an Oscar
the last go-around should not be overlooked.
I just felt like we've seen it before. And
though we've also seen Colin Farrell as the
Penguin before, not like this and not to this
depth. Yeah, that's true. Yeah, we previously
saw the character in the Batman movie, but
the Penguin series was much more substantial.
Let's go ahead and move on to the Marvel Award.
The nominees for best Marvel actor are Hugh
Jackman as Wolverine in Deadpool and Wolverine.
Joe Locke as Wiccan in Agatha All Along Season
Ryan Reynolds as Deadpool in Deadpool and Wolverine.
Tom Hardy as Eddie Brock slash Venom in Venom
the Last Dance.
Wow, this is a solid list. Who to choose? I
want to go with Hugh Jackman, but last time
I did that, you gave it to Deadpool. So you
might choose Ryan Reynolds, but I'm going to
stick with my gut and go with Hugh Jackman as
Wolverine as my guess. And the winner is Hugh
Jackman as Wolverine in Deadpool and Wolverine.
You son of a bitch. Woohoo! It's like you could
read my mind or something. It's not cool. Stop
doing that. It's weird. Yeah, Hugh Jackman
as Wolverine just when he thought that the guy
couldn't bring anything more to a character
that he had already spent over two decades playing
He did and yeah his performance in the movie
I wouldn't say is quite at the level as What
he did in the Logan film, but you know he wasn't
the main star of this movie, and he had less
screen time I still thought his performance
was incredible going from a down-and-out Wolverine
you know, severely depressed, giving a really
emotional performance when he admits as to the
reason why he's depressed. He conveyed anger
in a way that we haven't quite seen from the
character before, and he was a great straight
man to Deadpool's Wisecracking Idiot as well.
Yeah, he did the humor great, he did the drama
fantastically. The scene between him and X-23
at the campfire alone gives him this award,
I feel. Give him the Emmy. There's no way he's
winning an Oscar for this role. Does Hugh Jackman
even have an Oscar yet? No, he was nominated
for Les Mis, but did not win. That is a travesty.
The guy deserves an Oscar. He's definitely not
gonna get it for this movie, but someday, hopefully.
He should have got it for Logan. Yeah, he should
have been nominated for Logan. That's why I
say the Oscars are irrelevant. Yeah, Brothers
Awards, way better. Well, let's move into our
penultimate category. the best series or special
of 2024. Yeah, we live in times now where a
lot more media is being consumed at home as
opposed to on the big screen in theaters. So
this award, I think, gets more and more important
every year since we started this podcast. Yeah,
this includes television series as well as one
of specials. We actually didn't have any specials
this year. So this is really just the series
category in 2024. Yeah. And Marvel had some
doozies, man. Let me break down those nominees.
The nominees for best Marvel series or special
are Agatha All Along, season 1.
Hit Monkey Season 2.
What if season 3?
X-Men 97 Season 1
Oh, this is hands down X-Men 97 season one.
And the winner is. X-Men 97 season one. Of
course. Yeah, that's right. I mean, we reviewed
the show and gave it five stars. I mentioned
at the time that it was the quintessential X-Men
experience watching this season, and I still
feel the same way. The MCU has a very difficult
time ahead of itself in adapting the X-Men
as well as the X-Men 97 season one was. Yeah,
not only did it have that nostalgic edge to
it, but also improved animation wise upon what
we remember seeing on Saturday mornings and
brought an even more mature slant to it than
I thought it was even capable of. Yeah, I don't
even think you need the nostalgia factor to
enjoy X-Men 97. It certainly helps, but I think
it stands alone even for fans who are new to
the show. I am super pumped for whatever they
decide to do with that franchise next. I know
we're going to and hopefully it holds up to
season one. If it does, it'll probably go down
in history as the greatest animated superhero
series of all time. Just the way it portrayed
the action, the way the characters were written
so true to their comic book counterparts, the
themes that it addressed, it was all done flawlessly.
It was executed so perfectly. Give that show
an Emmy. For real, it was terrific. We gave
both Hit Monkey season two and Agatha all along
four and a half stars. It was a great year.
great year for Marvel Television and also for
DC Television. So let me get into the DC Award.
The nominees for best DC series or special are
Batman Caped Crusader season one.
Dead Boy Detectives, season one.
My Adventures with Superman, Season 2.
Penguin, season one.
Oh geez, I wonder what it's gonna be. That was
a joke. Obviously Penguin season one, final
answer. The winner is Batman, Caped Crusader.
Fuck off. It was absolutely The Penguin Season
1. A fantastic show and a year of incredible
DC shows. I also wanted to include Suicide
Squad Isekai on my list. Did I have room for
it? Oh, for sure. Yeah, yeah, that was fantastic.
I'm really sad that Dead Boy Detectives got
cancelled. I would have loved to have seen
what they could have done in another season
of that show. But overall, I think the show
that gets me most excited for what's coming
up next is The Penguin Season 1. Not only was
the show incredible, but I also think it was
a tremendous setup for what's ever coming next
in Matt Reeves, the Batman universe. Rumors
are that we are going to get a Penguin Season
2, I really hope we do. We'll see if that becomes
official down the road. I mean, as we said
in the review, the Penguin Season 1 was not
just S-tier DC television, it was S-tier television
in general. Oh yeah, it's classic HBO Sunday
night television. It was fantastic. I know
a lot of people who watch the show. who really
aren't into the whole superhero genre, and
they loved it. I loved it, how could you not?
I think this is the first year we've done this
show that we awarded two television projects,
five stars, from both Marvel and DC. Yeah,
you might be right. And as I mentioned earlier,
this category has gotten bigger and bigger
every year since we started doing this podcast.
Oh yeah, and this year specifically for DC,
the shows vastly outperformed the feature films.
But speaking of feature films, Let's move on
to our final award, best motion picture of 2024.
Yeah, for as big as the television category
is getting, there's still nothing quite like
seeing a film in the big screen in the theater.
It's movie magic. You know, I will say that
for both Marvel and DC, the theatrical offerings
were kind of slim pickings. DC only released
one theatrical film in Joker, Fallia, Do and
Marvel had three Sony Spider-Man movies come
out this year. So. Um, not our best showing
in 2024, but DC also had a lot of direct to
video films that came out this year. And so
yeah, we're going to find out which one wins.
I think we all know what the Marvel winner
is going to be, but I'm really interested in
seeing who the DC nominees are. Well let's
find out. The nominees for best DC motion picture
are Justice League Crisis on Infinite Earths,
part one.
Justice League, Crisis on Infinite Earths, part
two.
Watchmen, chapter one.
Watchmen, chapter two.
Shut up, I hate you!
I'm not surprised that JokerFollyIdo did not
make your list of nominees. Oh, absolutely
not. That is not a great list at all. Geez,
Watchmen Chapter 2, I guess. And the winner
is... Justice League Crisis on Infinite Earths
Part 1 Oh yeah that's okay yeah the obvious
answer there that was better than Watchmen Chapter
2 yeah Yeah so Watchmen Chapters 1 and 2 if
you listen to our reviews you know I didn't
love them I thought they were largely redundant
and inferior to the adaptation that we received
from Zack Snyder they're not bad they're actually
really faithful adaptations but of all of the
films that came out this year The one that
I thought was absolutely the best, far and away,
was Crisis on Infinite Earth's part one. It
was actually the first film to come out this
year. Yeah, part two was weaker than part one,
and then of course part three dropped the ball
on that trilogy of films completely. But part
one showed a lot of promise, especially with
its non-linear narrative structure. You know,
it was really fascinating to see how that movie
played out. Oh, absolutely. Yeah, the story
of The Flash and his involvement with the Mezzo
and the whole crisis event that was going on
was intermixed with a larger story that was
being told that involved many characters from
across DC's multiverse, particularly the crime
syndicate. It was told in a very interesting
way that was reminiscent of some other projects,
particularly the time traveler's wife. It was
a really strong setup for what I thought the
subsequent two films were going to try and
recapture the magic of, but that didn't quite
happen. Yeah, it was a shame considering how
big of a swing DC animation took with part one
and just couldn't follow through with. Right.
When the first movie came out, we were under
the impression that this was going to be a
heartbreaking finale to the tomorrowverse that
didn't end up being the case, but the movie
is still good. I think you're gonna get flack
for this award, but you shouldn't because,
yeah, it's the most deserving out of all of
DC's films this year. I do feel bad for you.
Yeah, me too. Thank you. Let's get on to the
Marvel Award. The nominees for best Marvel
picture are Deadpool and Wolverine.
Kraven the Hunter.
Madam Webb.
Venom The Last Dance
Let me guess. Madame Web. Nope, just kidding.
And the winner is Deadpool and Wolverine. Obviously.
I mean, you have an MCU film going up against
three Sony films. I am totally shocked that
Sony released three Spider-Man Universe films
this year. It was a major faux pas on their
part and they're gonna be paying for that big
time. Hopefully it results in the best case
scenario of Marvel getting the rights back to
Spider-Man because... The only decent film
out of the three Sony offerings this year was
Venom The Last Dance, and that even paled in
comparison to the awesomeness that was Deadpool
and Wolverine. The three Sony Spider-Man movies
this year were a joke. Deadpool and Wolverine
was, in my opinion, the best Deadpool movie
that came out. So yeah, I see how this easily
gets the win. 2024 was just... Ugh! I'm so
glad it's over. Yeah, it'll be good to put this
year behind us. And there's a lot of great
projects to look forward to in 2025. At least
the MCU will be releasing more than one movie
in 2025. That's right. You guys are getting
Captain America, Brave New World and Thunderbolts.
And the Fantastic Four in July. Ah, geez. That's
right. I totally forgot about that. We're also
getting a lot of great Disney Plus television
content, too. We were supposed to be getting
a Constantine 2 film next year, but that got
scrapped, I believe. So we're only getting
Superman. It's another year where DC only gets
one theatrical release. But you guys will also
be getting a few direct to video animated films
like Batman Ninja versus the Yakuza League.
Aztec Batman. All the Batman movies, I guess.
Basically, actually, just those three movies
have been announced so far. If there are other
animated projects in the works, we have yet
to hear about them. Well, just another reason
to hope that the Superman movie is good. It
has to be. I think it will be. But that does
it for the awards show this evening guys. Be
sure to reach out to us and let us know who
you think the winners in these categories could
have been. AG9K, help close us out. Thanks for
listening to Dynamic Duel. Visit the show's
website at dynamicDuel.com and follow us on
Instagram at dynamicDuelpodcast. You can support
the show on Patreon at patreon.com slash dynamicDuel
and joining a tier that works for you or by
rating and reviewing Dynamic Duel on Apple podcasts,
Spotify, Podchaser, or on our website. Don't
forget to listen to the other shows in the DynaMic
podcast network, including Max Destruction,
Senjo World, and Console Combat. In our next
episode, the first episode of 2025, we are
going to be reviewing What If Season 3. I think
I'm only on episode 3 of that series. Need
to catch up. But you saying that it ends with
a bang has me kind of excited because I'm not
too thrilled with what I'm seeing so far. Thank
you guys so much for listening to us in 2024,
and we hope you continue this journey with us
in 2025. Big thanks to our executive producers.
Ken Johnson, John Sturawski, Zachary Hepburn,
Dustin Belcombe, Mickey Mathanghian, Brandon
Estergard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yaiten, Austin
Wiselowski, A.J. Dunkerley, Scott Camacho,
Gil Camacho, Adam Spies, Andrew Shunk, Dean
Molesky, Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, Josh
Leiner, Mike Williams, and Oscar Galvez for
helping make this podcast possible. We'll talk
to you guys next week. Up, up, and away, true
believers. My 2025 New Year's Resolution. World
domination.