This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
Hi and welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast,
a weekly show where we review superhero films
and debate the superiority between Marvel and
DC by comparing their characters in stat-based
battle simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe. And I'm
his twin brother Johnny DC. And in this episode,
we are going to find out who would win in a
fight between the artificial intelligence robot
characters, Amazo and Bastion. Now if you guys
have recently watched X-Men 97, the cartoon
on Disney+, you will know who Bastion is, and
if you're not a DC fan, you probably have no
idea who Amazo is. Everyone knows who Amazo
is. Uh huh. Like, everyone. Okay. Both of these
guys are highly adaptable. It's going to be
a really great matchup. We're going to input
the character's statistics, run a thousand simulations,
and find out who would actually win, but not
before speculating on the match itself. Before
that, we're going to break down the latest
comic book movie news to come out this past
week, of which we have two news items, the
first one being that Nicolas Cage is going to
star in a Spider-Man War live action series
for Amazon, and we got a release date for the
movie Supergirl, Woman of Tomorrow. As always,
we list our segment times in our episode description,
so feel free to check out the show notes if
you want to skip ahead to a particular topic.
Our artificially intelligent duel simulator
AJ-9K has a quick message for our listeners.
So listen up. Why hello there. Do you love
listening and chatting about Marvel and DC?
Then become a part of the dynamic duel community
on Patreon, where you can choose from three
tiers. The dynamic 2-0 tier lets you listen
to this podcast without ads and gives you access
to its Discord chat group, where you can chat
with Johnny DC and Marvelous Joe. The fantastic
four tier gives you that and more with two
bonus episodes each month, including bloopers
and top 10 shows, where Johnny and Joe count
down your favorite Marvel and DC subjects. The
X-Force tier makes you an executive producer
of Dynamic duel. where every month you help
the hosts choose what to review and who to
fight against each other. And finally, the Dynamite
Podcast Network tier allows aspiring podcasters
to create their own battle-focused show using
this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe
will help you develop your show, provide graphic
support and consultation, and get you simulation
results to announce on your show. Pitch the
twins your show via email at dyna or by reaching
out to them on social media. your pip cheerio.
Yeah, I know we said that was going to be last
week. For real this time, it's tomorrow. Yeah,
last week they reviewed Conan the Destroyer.
On the Syndra World podcast, host Zachary Hepburn
speculates on fights between fan favorite anime
and manga characters. This Thursday, we'll
find out who would win between Laxus from Fairy
Tale and Lambo from Hitman Reborn. And on the
Console Combat podcast, host John and Dean find
out who would win in fights between popular
video game characters. In yesterday's episode,
they found out who'd win in a battle between
Jimmy Hopkins from Bully against Naughty Bear.
Fascinating stuff. Go check it out. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com
or click the link in our show notes to listen
to all of the shows in the DynaMic Podcast
Network. But with that out of the way, quick
to the no prize. A no prize is an award Marvel
used to give out to fans. Our version, the dynamic
duel no prize. is a digital award we post on
Instagram for the person that we feel gave the
best answer to our question of the week. Last
week we asked, which actor wore your favorite
Superman suit and why was it your favorite?
And this was coming off of the first look that
we got at David Cornswett's Superman suit in
the upcoming Superman movie directed by James
Gunn. We got only three answers and two of
them were the same. So really we got two answers,
but let's go ahead and break down those honorable
mentions as well as the no prize winner. Our
first honorable mention goes to Christopher
Minotti, who said, Hi guys Christopher Minotti.
My favorite Superman suit has to be the one
that was worn by Brandon Ruth in the CW's Crisis
on Infinite Earths. I really like that one.
It's like a combination between the one that
he wore in Superman Returns and the super suit
in Kingdom Come. I love the emblem from that
one and I like how this one looks. It's...
designed very well and I like him as well. Yeah,
it was not a bad costume. I'm a big fan of
Kingdom Come, so it was really great to see
that suit in live action. I don't remember
seeing too many elements from the Superman Returns
costume. Actually, I'm not a big fan of that
costume, but I thought it was a really good
adaptation of the Kingdom Come comic, and it
was just really cool to see Brandon Routh as
Superman again. Yeah, with the graying temples
and everything in homage to Kingdom Come. That
was pretty cool. Of course, David Cornsweat's
Superman costume has a similar looking S emblem
shield on his chest where it's just like the
diagonal line going across. Right. Except it's
not against a black field. Right, it's yellow
for Cornsweat's suit. Great answer, Christopher.
Our next honorable mention goes to Colby Hentges,
who said... Hey boys, Colby Hentges. My favorite
Superman suit would have been the Brandon Roth
CW Crisis Kingdom Come Superman suit. It looks
like he just pulled that thing out of an Alex
Ross painting and put it on. Yeah, Alex Ross
is just a really good costume designer. I mean,
Superman suit was cool, but so was like Batman's
and Wonder Woman's and just everybody. And
not just in Kingdom Come, but like across the
board. He has really good like reinterpretations
for characters like the Riddler or even like
Clayface. Yeah, he's very much a fan of the
Silver Age, but I like his modern adaptations
of the costumes from that time for sure. I'm
interested in all the different ways Brandon
Routh's last name can be pronounced. I think
we got Ruth, we got Roth. It's Routh. Honestly,
I'm surprised that these two honorable mentions
were the same answer. I actually thought there
would be a lot more answer submissions for
this particular question. But let's go ahead
and announce the winner of this week's Snow
Prize, who is Miggy Matangian, who said, Hey,
what's up guys, this is Miggy and I'm here
to voice the popular opinion on the server in
case somebody else does. And that is Tyler
Hawklund's Superman suit and Superman and Lois,
and I guess the rest of the Arrowverse. It's
just very classic looking, great symbol, good
textures, kind of like rebirth suit inspired,
but also just very classic. I don't know, like
Silver Age. Yeah, it's a good one. So all TV
answers for this question, I expected at least
one answer from one of the movies. But, you
know, Tyler Hawklund Superman suit is not. terrible.
There's actually a lot of fans of it. I'm not
particularly a fan of Tyler Houghlin as Superman.
In my opinion, he kind of looks like a younger
version of Ty Burrell. But I also can't deny
the fact that his suit is really good. And
I love seeing the different iterations of it
that we've had from across, you know, the various
crisis and else world storylines that we've
seen him in and like his golden age costume.
They were all really cool. Actually, this is
my favorite Superman costume as well, Tyler
Hocklands, because not only is it a great, like
modern adaptation of the Superman costume,
I think it's better than Henry Cavill's Superman
suit. And I definitely think it's better than
the upcoming David Cornsweat suit. So yeah,
I think Tyler Hockland's Superman suit is the
one to be at least in this day and age. I'm
trying to think of what my favorite Superman
suit is. Honestly, it's probably Christopher
Reeves. I know it's kind of dated, but it's
also iconic in my opinion. Maybe if it had a
little bit of texture it would be absolute
perfection, but yeah I think so far that's as
close as we've gotten. What an old man answer.
This is an old man answer, Jonathan. What are
you, an old man? Kids these days can't tell
the difference between just plain old and classic.
Well congrats to Mickey for winning this week's
No Prize. If you the listener want a shot at
winning your own No Prize, stay tuned to later
on this episode when we will be asking another
question of the week. And now that that's done,
on to the news!
Alright, in a bit of news that was definitely
not on my bingo card for this year, we learned
this past week that Nicolas Cage is set to star
in a Spider-Man Noir live action series for
Amazon produced by Sony. The series is just
going to be titled Noir, which seems like a
strange omission of the name of Spider-Man,
but basically it looks like Nicolas Cage is
going to play Peter Parker, the Noir version
of the character that he voiced in the Spider-Man
Into the Spider-Verse movie. The character basically
is Spider-Man set in the 1930s Great Depression
era. Of course he wears all black, you know,
he shoots guns, he still has organic webs and
everything like that, but the stories are much
more grounded and down to earth and very gritty.
So it should be interesting to get this as a
live action series. This is really bizarre
to me. Like the character wasn't even in Across
the Spider-Verse. So I'm not sure why they're
circling back to him. I don't know if it's just
because of Nicolas Cage's name combined with
Spider-Man or what? Yeah, it's strange because
like they could have also developed series
around any other number of Spider-Man characters
that were in those films, such as like Spider-Punk
or Silk, which actually, you know, she was going
to have a show on Amazon that just got scrapped.
I think it is a little bit strange to have someone
like Nicolas Cage, who's, you know. Not a spring
chicken. He's kind of up there in age, but he'll
be playing a superhero here. I'm guessing they're
gonna kind of tone down the super aspect and
really up the nor aspect where he's gonna be
more of like an investigative reporter who just
happens to have some spider related superpowers.
Right, yeah. I'm wondering stylistically how
this is gonna go. Like, is it gonna be more
like the Penguin or is it gonna be more like
Sin City? I hope it's like the latter. Well,
uh. I would hope it's like the latter too, like
just make it in black and white, kind of like
how the Spider-Man war universe was depicted
in, into the Spider-Verse. Yeah. I think that'd
be pretty cool. It's just gonna be really weird
to see a 60 year old Peter Parker. Yeah, that's
very strange. Who knows, maybe they'll like
not even make him Peter Parker. It's bizarre
in that Sony has the film and live action television
rights to the character of Spider-Man. But
of course, due to their deal with Marvel, they
can't really make a movie starring Spider-Man
set in their Sony Spider-Man universe. That's
why we're getting movies like Venom and Madame
Web and Morbius and stuff like that. This Noir
television series seems kind of like a workaround
to include the Spider-Man character without
still actually including him. Yeah, I have
a feeling that if Nicolas Cage is playing Peter
Parker, Kevin Feige probably has something
to say about that. I wouldn't be surprised if
they renamed him. Yeah, I wouldn't be surprised
either, but that would be unfortunate because
then, you know, they're going against the comics.
And then at that point, why even make the show?
But we'll see what happens. We'll see what
they end up going with. The show is actually
being showrun by Oren Uzziel and Steve Lightfoot.
Apparently, it's going to be executive produced
by Phil Lord and Christopher Miller, the directors
of the Into the Spider-Verse film, which is
good news. We don't know when exactly the show
is going to come out. It's currently in development,
so it's probably still a year or two out. You
have to imagine that Spider-Man Noir is probably
going to make an appearance in Beyond the Spider-Verse
then, just so that they have that synergy between,
you know, what's in theaters and what's on
your television screen. Yeah, I wouldn't be
surprised. Like, I think Noir will actually
be a sequel to the character that we see in
the Into the Spider-Verse films, where he's
like older and down and out. It has the potential
to be good, but also it's just strange. If
Kraven bombs, I'll be surprised if this even
still happens, honestly. I just think... Sony's
not quite knowing what to do. I don't know,
I think there's a big difference between their
live action villain stuff and they're into the
Spider-Verse stuff. I think this can move forward
despite what happens with Kraven. And who knows,
if this is a success, maybe we'll get like
a Spider-Man India TV show and like a Spider-Punk
TV show. Yeah, that would definitely be cool.
Maybe like an anthology Spider-Man series where
season to season we focus on a different Spider-Verse
character, live action. Sold, and I don't really
care for Spider-Verse. You lost me on the last
part of that sentence. But that brings us to
our question of the week.
What celebrity voice actor for a Marvel or DC
animated film would you like to see play the
character in live action? So similar to how
Nick Cage voiced Spider-Man or in the Into
the Spider-Verse movie, he's now playing him
in live action. What other voice actor do you
want to see that happen with? Record your answer
at dynamicduel.com by clicking on the red microphone
button in the bottom right hand corner of the
screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long and don't forget to leave your name in
case we include you on the podcast. We'll pick
our favorite answer and award that person a
dynamic duel mill prize that we'll post to Instagram.
Be sure to answer before May 23rd. We're recording
the next episode a little bit early because
of Memorial Day. In DC news, we learned this
past week that DC Studios' second live-action
film, Supergirl, Woman of Tomorrow, has landed
a 2026 release date on June 26th. So it's going
to be 6-2-6-2-6. That's cool. news. Hell yeah
it is. Hell yeah. What else is there to say
about this? Well I'll tell you. It turns out
that they were really interested in locking
down a release date now that they have a director
in Craig Gillespie. Now he was rumored or in
final talks to be the director of Supergirl
Woman of Tomorrow for a few weeks now but apparently
the trades are reporting on the
That's exciting news. Of course, Craig Gillespie
is the director of prior films such as Cruella
and I, Tanya. Both of those, I think, were great
films. So it's pretty exciting to see that
he will be directing Supergirl Woman of Tomorrow.
Holy shit, that's a great get for a director.
Hell yeah. That's actually really fascinating.
His stuff tends to be a little bit dark, but
from what I hear about the Supergirl Woman of
Tomorrow storyline, it is a little dark. It
is a little bit mature. It's a departure from,
I think, what we typically think of, you know,
the lighthearted Supergirl Fair is. Yeah, that
project suddenly got a whole lot more interesting
to me. I wasn't even sure what to think about
it. I know that the Tom King series is highly
praised and with that kind of directing talent
behind the camera in Craig Gillespie, this
movie has a lot going for it. It seems like
all of a sudden like Oscar worthy or something.
It's weird. Well, there's been a lot of praise
not only about the graphic novel, but also
the script adaptation. written by Anna Noguera.
Apparently it's phenomenal and it seems like
they've really fast tracked this storyline based
off of her really great script. Initially this
film wasn't pitched as being the second film
in the DC Studios universe, but now it is.
You know, we got a director for Batman and Robin
and Swamp Thing before we got the director
for Super Girl, so I would have imagined that
those projects would have gotten up and running
prior to this, but apparently not. They just
are in love with it. The film of course is
going to star Millie Alcock in the lead role.
Still not 100% sure about that casting, but
everything else seems to be going off fairly
well for this production. So it gets me excited.
I'm not sure when they're gonna start shooting
this, but we'll see if the Millie Alcock Supergirl
suit is anything like David Cornswett's Superman
suit. It should be. You would think that it
would be. God, I hope not. Don't hate!
But I think that does it for all the news for
this episode, so let's go ahead and get into
our main event, where we find out who'd win
in a fight between the Android characters of
Amazo and Bastion.
Alright, Amazo versus Bastion. We have two highly
adaptable androids here. They're basically
just going to keep adapting to each other until
one of them can no longer adapt. And then they
just both explode. I have no idea how it's gonna
go. It's gonna be a very strange, but interesting
battle, pitting these two characters against
each other. Yeah, this specific battle was
suggested, I believe, by our executive producer,
Devin Davis, although he initially suggested
Bastion versus Omak, which I loved. but we've
also been trying to get a mezzo into a duel
for a while. Yeah, and we also thought that
omak might actually be a good matchup for deathlock.
So that'll be a duel likely in the future. Bastion
is really cool though, because to me Bastion
is the ultimate sentinel robot. In fact, in
my history write up of the character that I'm
going to get into in a short while here, I basically
go over the entire history of the sentinels.
He is kind of the culmination of everything
the sentinels had been built for. Yeah, he's
like the ultimate X-Men villain, and he's going
up against the ultimate Justice League villain.
Is Amazo the ultimate Justice League villain?
I mean, when it comes to androids, I'll say
yes. But like how a Sentinel can analyze and
adapt against the mutant that they're fighting,
Amazo can absorb the abilities of the people
that he's fighting. That's right. And Joseph's
not letting me start the match off with all
the powers of the Justice League because he's
a big fat cheater. Right, I'm the cheater, because
I won't let you start off with all the powers
of the Justice League. Right, okay. Yeah! Alright.
Yeah! To explain the methodology behind our
duels, let's go to our sentient duel simulator,
Alfred Jarvis9000. AJ9K, tell our listeners
how you go about determining a winner in our
duel matchups. Yes, of course, sir. The way
I determine a winner between the contestants
is by running 1000 Monte Carlo simulations
using the characters' statistics. The Monte
Carlo simulation is a probabilistic model used
to determine outcomes through random sampling.
In this case, I randomised the statistics along
a normal distribution as a way to simulate the
many variables that can occur during battle.
The stat parameters are based on the official
Marvel power grid from which the DC characters'
statistics are extrapolated. Additional stat
categories are included such as range, damage
potential, versatility and perception in order
to create a more detailed and accurate simulation.
The results of the 1,000 simulations provide
a percentage of wins for each character. The
contestant with the higher percentage is declared
the victor, as they have a higher probability
to win any given battle. In an equitable pairing,
neither character should win 100% of the matches.
The comic book stories have shown that there's
even a way for Batman to defeat Superman, so
the confidence rate of my method falls in line
with the precedents that have been established
in the source material. My mathematical simulations
are without subjectivity or bias. Feats are
not the sole consideration, nor are fan votes
tabulated for determination of the winner.
Thanks AJ9K! Before we run the simulations though,
we like to break down each character's histories
and abilities before improvising a scenario
on how we imagine one of the 1000 simulations
would play out beat for beat. And I believe
it's my turn to go first with the DC characters
backstory, so let me tell you all about Amazo
and his inventor. Now, Professor Anthony Ivo,
the eventual creator of the Android Amazo, grew
up with severe Thanatophobia, or the fear of
death. Obsessed with avoiding death and achieving
immortality, Ivo studied both cybernetics and
genetics, eventually turning to criminal activities
to fund his experiments. While working for
a criminal organization known as Locus, Ivo
was granted access to advanced alien technology
and the cadavers of biologically adaptable aliens
from the planet Appalachs. Over time, Ivo developed
the theory that by studying and experimenting
on other species with long lifespans, he could
create an immortality elixir and use it to achieve
eternal life. To help with his plans, Ivo created
Amazo, an android equipped with an absorption
cell that Ivo reverse engineered from alien
technology, which allowed Imezo to mimic the
abilities of any superhuman it's encountered.
Imezo targeted the founding members of the Justice
League and used their powers to steal animals
required for Ivo's immortality elixir, which
the scientist successfully created and consumed.
The Justice League, however, realized that Imezo
absorbed their weaknesses as well as their
powers, allowing them to defeat both Imezo and
his now immortal maker. Ivo, the latter of
whom was punished with a 500-year prison sentence
in case his immortality elixir actually worked.
You can learn more about the Justice League
in their team duel against the Avengers. Amazo,
meanwhile, was kept in the Justice League headquarters
trophy room, where it reawakened several times
and battled the League before being shut down
and put in storage once again. When the original
Justice League team disbanded, a new, smaller
team composed mostly of new setting up their
new headquarters in Detroit. Ivo escaped prison
shortly before this and realized that his elixir
did in fact work, though it also transformed
his appearance, progressively disfiguring him
over time. Driven insane by his predicament,
Ivo created android duplicates of himself in
his human form to care for him, though they
ended up locking him up to protect him from
his own increasing mental illness. Since Ivo
blamed the Justice League for his appearance,
the Androids decided that they would destroy
the newer, weaker League to please him. Though
they managed to kill the hero Vibe, who you
can learn more about in our Vibe versus Miss
America duel episode, the Androids were later
defeated, but not before they awoke Amazo,
who also attacked the new League members, but
was destroyed by the original members of Martian
Manhunter and Aquaman. As Ivo's body continued
to break down, he eventually wished for death,
and built an army of robots called Amazoids
to kill him, though they were unable to do
so. The Amazoids caught the attention of a new
version of the Justice League, who managed
to cure Ivo and return him back to his normal
human state. Over time, however, Ivo succumbed
to his fear of death and took his elixir once
again, determined it was better to live forever
as a monster than to die. Eventually, Ivo recreated
an upgraded version of Amazo, who battled with
Justice League on several occasions, before
being destroyed by Resurrection Man. Moments
prior to his destruction, however, Amazo was
summoned to the future by a time-controlling
android from the 853rd century named Our Man,
as he considered Amazo something of an ancestor,
since part of the technology within Our Man
was based on Ivo's design. You can learn more
about Ourman in our Ourman vs Bishop episode.
Imezo copied Ourman's time traveling powers
becoming Timezo and wrecked havoc across the
timeline, though he was eventually captured
and defeated by Ourman, who returned him back
to his original time just before Imezo was
destroyed. Initially, Imezo was only capable
of mimicking one power at a time, but Ivo eventually
created a version that contained all the powers
of all Justice League members. This version
of Amazo was nearly successful in destroying
the League until, upon the Atom's suggestion,
Superman disbanded the Justice League and rendered
Amazo powerless, allowing the League to dismantle
him. Batman and Nightwing later found a partially
built Amazo in a weapon shipment and managed
to destroy him. Ivo, meanwhile, in one of his
experiments, had managed to combine his absorption
cell with human ova and DNA to create an android
slash human hybrid version of Amazo, who was
adopted and grew into a young man named Frank
Halloran. Frank's powers awoke as a college
student while he was with his girlfriend Sarah,
and though he sought to become a hero named
Kid Amazo, he eventually became mentally unstable
after learning Sarah was actually Ivo's daughter,
and he was later destroyed by Batman. When Ivo
secretly installed the Amazo programming in
the Android Justice League member Red Tornado,
who you can learn more about in our Red Tornado
vs. Sandman episode, Amazo was able to take
over his body and ambush the League, leading
to an entire army of Red Tornado robots. The
League was forced to destroy Red Tornado's
body, and when they built a new one, Amazo took
control of that one as well, forcing the League
to teleport him into the gravity well of a distant
star. In post-Flashpoint continuity, Professor
Anthony Ivo was the head of Star Labs' Red Room
project, which collected and studied the most
dangerous technology encountered by the government.
As a result of the project, Ivo was able to
develop organic pattern processing technology
that mimicked organic life down to the cellular
level. This eventually led to the artificially
intelligent Amaze computer operating system.
which eventually became corrupted and inhabited
the body of an android from the Red Room becoming
Amazo, which learned from and adopted the Justice
League's powers when it was attacked. Though
Amazo was defeated, the Amazo system eventually
infiltrated the League's satellite computer
system, allowing it to build itself a new body
on board the satellite where it attacked and
was defeated by Batman. After Amazo was defeated,
Lex Luthor used the operating system programming
to develop an organic Amazo virus that infected
people and gave them superpowers. The first
person treated for the virus, a Lex Corp scientist
named Armin Icarus, went insane and became
the new Amazo. However, for this speculation,
I will be going with the OS Android version
of the character as the organic AI learning
aspect makes more sense to me than the absorption
cell. Powers-wise, by default, Amazo is built
with an extremely durable and strong robotic
body and shell that houses an artificial intelligence
capable of learning and mimicking the abilities,
including Superhuman, of those it encounters.
And that's Amazo. These two characters are
actually vastly similar, not just in their power
sets, but also in their histories. And I think
you'll find a lot of weird parallels in the
Bastion backstory, even through the Sentinels
and everything like that. Wait, was there a
Tyne Bastion as well? Haha, kinda. But let
me get into it. Now to know the history of the
X-Men villain Bastion is to first know the
history of the sentinel robots. Decades ago,
a robotics expert named Bolobar Trask worked
with the US government to address the growing
mutant population. Driven by a desire to protect
humanity from mutants with dangerous abilities,
Trask created a prototype robot called Mastermold.
the very first sentinel robot which was designed
to create other sentinels. The sentinel robots
were programmed to capture and exterminate mutant
threats, which they did with frightening efficiency.
However, Trask underestimated Master Mold's
artificial intelligence, which deduced that
in order to protect mankind, the sentinels must
also protect humanity from itself, and therefore
destroy it. Trask then helped the X-Men blow
up Master Mold and the sentinel base, losing
his life in the process. You can learn more
about the X-Men in their team duel against
the Titans. However, Trask's death did not stop
Master Mold and the Sentinel program from resurrecting
time and again, manifesting various kinds of
Sentinels, including the 20-foot tall Mark
II Sentinels, the X-Sentinels, which were robotic
replicas of the X-Men Mutant Heroes, and Wild
Sentinels, which were as big as cities. No matter
their form, Sentinels always posed one of the
greatest threats to the X-Men and throughout
their history. This threat also extended decades
into the future, where in the days of future
past timeline, Sentinels took control over
North America, killing most of the mutant population
and turning the continent into a dystopian
nightmare where only humans were permitted to
breed. During this time, the most highly advanced
Sentinel prototype yet was created, which was
named Nimrod. He was a scourge to the surviving
mutants of the future, being highly adaptable,
infinitely immensely powerful and utterly unstoppable.
At one point, he was pulled from the time stream
and traveled from the future into the present
time. While he initially posed a threat to the
X-Men, over time, his advanced artificial mind
began to develop emotions, and he discovered
empathy, choosing to become a robot vigilante
of sorts, protecting all life instead of eradicating
mutants. This was short lived, however, as
Nimrod soon came into contact with the remnants
of a circuit board. belonging to Mastermold,
which corrupted Nimrod's systems and set him
on a mission of eliminating both mutants and
humans. The Mastermold and Nimrod fusion proved
to be unstoppable by the X-Men team, however
Nimrod was able to assert dominance over the
Mastermold intelligence, convincing it that
in their synthesis they had become a mutant
of sorts, and therefore must also be destroyed.
Concurring, Mastermold self-destructed, knowing
that the fragments could recombine, The X-Men
pushed the Nimrod Mastermold body into a transformative,
mystic gateway known as the Siege Perilous.
The portal merged the two into a tech hybrid
being, with no memory of who or what he previously
was. He was found by a woman who adopted him
as her surrogate son, giving him the new name
Sebastian. He joined the Friends of Humanity
anti-mutant group and used its political connections
to gain influence and lead a new Pentagon-backed
group. initiative known as Operation Zero Tolerance,
which resurrected the Sentinel program. Sebastian,
now just going by Bastion, developed nanotechnology
which would infect humans with cybernetic implants,
making them sleeper agents that, when activated,
would be driven to detect and capture mutants.
Calling these human cyborgs Prime Sentinels,
Bastion used them to capture several X-Men and
take over the Xavier Institute. Eventually,
the X-Men defeated Bastion, revealing him as
a cybernetic being, and Operation Zero Tolerance
was shut down. Bastion was remanded into S.H.I.E.L.D.
custody, where he escaped and tried to transform
the android hero Machine Man into the Sentinel
Supreme, though he was stopped by Cable, whom
you can learn more about in our Booster Gold
vs Cable duel episode. Later, Bastion was decapitated
by Wolverine, and his head was recovered by
the US government to retrieve the information
he had stolen from the Xavier Institute. Bastion
Head was then stolen by the mutant-hating William
Stryker, who attached it to the body of a Nimrod
series sentinel, as Stryker had access to Nimrod's
technology due to time travel. Back online,
Bastion used his nanotech to control and resurrect
some of the X-Men's greatest villains, including
Donald Pierce of the Reavers, Grayden Creed,
and Bolivar Trask himself, calling themselves
the Human Council. Together, they tried to
kill the mutant, Hope Summers. who was the first
mutant born after the Scarlet Witch had for
a time erased the abilities of most of Earth's
mutant population. Bastion erected a large
dome force field over the X-Men's base and had
his team target their teleporters like Nightcrawler
so they couldn't escape the attack. Bastion
then opened a portal to his home dimension,
Days of Future Past, from where he summoned
a fleet of Nimrod series sentinels to kill
the X-Men. The human council was only defeated.
when the X-Men sent Cable and Cipher to the
future to reprogram the Nimrod series sentinels
and destroy the Nimrod master mold. Defeated,
Bastion still tried to kill Hope Summers himself,
though she destroyed him with a massive energy
blast. Bastion managed to survive by escaping
into the future, however, during the time of
the war between the X-Men and the Inhumans.
There he started creating new sentinels, however
he was later apparently destroyed by the mutant
who swallowed him with a black hole inside
his head. Powers-wise, Bastion is a techno-organic,
cybernetic hybrid being with enhanced physicals
such as strength, able to lift up to 25 tons,
speed, and durability basically indestructible.
Using nanotechnology, he can transmute humans
into techno-mechanical beings that he can control
and he has technopathy in the same manner. Bastion
can techno-morph both himself and any being
he controls, including altering or giving himself
wings or new appendages. This makes him self-repairable
and highly adaptable considering he can also
detect and analyze the abilities of other beings
and modify himself accordingly.
Bastion can fire energy blasts and emit energy
shields, and can open portals for teleportation
or time travel. Finally, he has a genius level
intellect having a highly advanced calculating
cybernetic mind. Cybernetic mind. OK, cool.
I have all of that down. Amazer has all of that,
too. Including the techno warping? Well, I
mean, if Bastion has it, yes. Oh, that's right.
That's right. OK. Shoot. Well, we're going
to see how this goes.
fantasies collide and heroes clash, one podcast
network rises above the rest. Prepare yourself
for the ultimate showdowns in comic books, video
games, movies, and anime. The Dynomic Podcast
Network presents Console Combat, where video
game legends brawl every Monday. Comic Book
Titans smash every Tuesday. Max Destruction,
where TV and action heroes battle every Wednesday.
And Sendro World, where anime champions clash
every Thursday. Join us as we speculate on
the matches and armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge victorious.
Visit dynamicpodcast.com where we settle the
debate and settle the score.
Because now that we got their histories and
abilities out of the way, let's speculate on
how one of the 1000 simulated matches will go.
The winner is determined by simulations, not
the speculation, but it's fun to imagine how
this fight could play out. AG9K, what are the
rules of our speculation? Well, I should say
there are no rules, other than the characters
have no prior knowledge of the other going into
the fight. All they are aware of starting out
is that the other character is a threat that
needs to be eliminated. For the speculation...
contestants will begin approximately 50 meters
apart in a nondescript environment that will
have no bearing on the match itself as no environmental
statistics are considered in my simulations
the contestants must earn victory on their own
merit. Alright then let's get into it. Amazo
and Bastion meet on the battlefield who goes
first? I'm gonna say Bastion goes first because
like it just seems like he has more personality
than Amazo. That's not true. He's gonna analyze
and scan Amazo. like a sentinel would and determine
his power set and the best course of action.
Okay, I mean, of course, Amazo's own system
is going to sense that it's being scanned and
it's going to mimic that action scanning Bastion
as well. Okay, well Bastion is going to generate
these missile pods from his shoulders and he's
going to fire a pair of missiles at Amazo that
just blow him up. Okay, except that, you know,
once Amazo scans Bastion, he instantly learns...
everything Bastion could do, including shooting
energy, which a mezzo he's going to do from
his eyes like Superman to shoot down the missiles.
And then he's just going to turn that laser
vision toward Bastion himself and blast his
head off. OK. Energy shield. Bastion's going
to throw up like a pink glowing energy shield
that blocks the lasers. And then he's going
to techno morph from his back a pair of these
razor sharp techno dragon wings kind of thing.
He's going to fly at a mezzo with super speed
and he's going to plow his fist right into
a mezzo's face just spinning his head 180 degrees.
I mean, like, that's fine. I mean, that doesn't
bother him. His head is now backwards. It's
just going to make him angry. And with his
sights still on Bastion who, you know, flew
past him, a mezzo is going to techno morph
a ring onto his hand that's going to glow with
that. pink energy and having learned to create
energy shields from Bastion, Amazo is going
to create a like a crude pink energy construct
of a giant hand that slams Bastion down into
the ground and just flattening him. I see what
you're doing here now. You're doing Justice
League powers. Yeah. OK. Well, Bastion, he's
going to grow in size to lift this hand off
of him. He's going to lose the wings, but he's
going to become like this 20 foot tall. kind
of disproportionate distorted figure. And he's
gonna manifest all of these like hoses from
his back that kind of like snake around and
point at Imezo and just like they all blast
him with energy from like 10 different angles,
just pew, pew. Okay, so Imezo, he gets tagged
by like one or two of the lasers we'll say
before he's just gonna start moving, just like
zipping around quickly by generating. energy
boosters on his heels and his back that just
propel him forward like really fast. So, Amazo,
he's running zigzags around the environment
before he runs behind Bastion and generates
his own like hose cable thing that he's going
to lasso around Bastion's neck and he's going
to use his strength to yank him down to the
ground real hard. Okay, well, Bastion is going
to shrink back down to normal size now. He's
going to immediately get up off the ground.
And you done fucked up because Bastion is gonna
grab Amazo's lasso and he's gonna transmit
his technovirus through it and that's gonna
infect Amazo and turn him into Bastion's puppet
matchover. I mean jokes on you because like
as soon as Bastion starts to do that suddenly
this wing shaped blade severs the lasso cord
in half before the technovirus could even reach
Amazo and Amazo's by throwing several more of
those wing shaped blades that embed themselves
into Bastion's torso and upload their own Amazos
techno virus into him, taking over Bastion's
mind. You can't do, Amazos so stupid, anything
that Bastion does, Amazos just do it back.
That's right. I'm gonna say though that the
exact opposite happens. I'm gonna say that
Bastion converts these Amazo batterings or whatever
into small sentinel drones that look like...
Sentinels from the Matrix movie like with small
wild sentinels, okay Okay, and they're fully
under Bastion's control Bastion is gonna send
them out to surround a mezzo and These sentinels
are gonna like wrap them up in their tentacles
and they're gonna overload them with energy
that just blow them up to pieces We're just
like nuts and bolts flying everywhere We had
the heck did a few batterings turn into like
a swarm of flying sentinel drones Technomorphing
man, and it's not like a swarm. It's only like
three or four or whatever. In fact, where did
Omizo even get the batarangs from? If we're
asking questions like that. Uh, I don't even
know. Like, where did Bastion get his wings
from? Again, techno-morphing. You know, he
just used some of the mass from his back. He's
a dense dude. You know, he can make wings out
of his back. So is that how he grew in size
earlier? He just like expanded his dense volume?
Uh. Like I pictured it as more of like a disproportionate
growth. He was only using the mass he had available
to grow to 20 feet tall. So I kind of pictured
him as like this robot slenderman with like
cables coming out of his back firing glazers.
Ah, that's creepy. Yeah, he get pretty creepy
looking sometimes. OK, OK. So Amazo is getting
overloaded by these drones, but he's also working
at assimilating these drones back onto his side,
which he does, and they're going to like drill
into the ground. and form the frame of this
crazy looking wild sentinel made of metal cables
and earth that looks like a giant lobster squid.
And it just erupts from the ground and falls
on Bastion and devours him, destroying his technology
and bringing an end to this match. He summoned
the Kraken. Okay. Except that as the techno
squid creature or whatever is about to land
on Bastion, he's portal above him into the Days
of Future Past timeline. And the creature and
Amazo, they're both gonna get pulled into this
time portal and they just get their asses handed
to them by a legion of Nimrod series sentinels.
Dang, okay. Well, I mean, if time play is an
issue now, Amazo is just gonna generate his
own time portal while he's in the Days of Future
Past. And he's gonna go all the way to the 853rd
century where he's gonna once again become
Timeazo. And he's just gonna travel all throughout
time acquiring all the powers of every DC character
ever And he's gonna return back to the Days
of Future Past and just beat the shit out of
those Nimrods After which he's gonna go back
to where Bastion is and just beat the shit
out of him Ending this match for real this time
Okay Um, I'm gonna say though that Bastion
was quicker with his time travel and he already
went and turned all the DC heroes into his
personal sentinel army. So Time-Mazo becomes
Die-Mazo. I don't know. Dead-Mazo? Whatever.
Match is over. How are you going to be faster
with time travel though? Easy. Time travel.
There's your answer. All right, I guess we'll
leave it there. Either a Meizo acquires all
of the powers of every DC hero ever using time
travel and uses it to destroy Bastion or Bastion
uses time travel to assimilate every DC hero
into a prime sentinel. Why has it got to be
the DC heroes? Why can't you go to your own
universe? Sure, you do it to Marvel, too. The
human ones, at least. But yeah, we'll leave
it there. We'll input the character stats.
We'll run the simulations and find out which
of these ending scenarios happens when we come
back with a winner. AG9K, hit it! Inputting
data, running calculations, processing results,
simulations complete. Okay, so it was a huge
challenge coming up with a mezzo stats considering
the fact that there's so many different versions
of this character like you have one guy who
could take on the entire Justice League and
you have another version that can be defeated
by Batman. Yes, so what we decided in the end
was to kind of average the Justice League powered
version of a mezzo with what we call the base
model a mezzo, which is pretty still damn powerful.
But at that level, we got a character who was
pretty on par with Bastion because like the
Justice League Amazo is going to be way too
powerful for Bastion, but the base model is
not nearly powerful enough. Right. Yeah. We
said that Amazo came out on top in terms of
speed and strength and fighting, surprisingly.
Amazo is much more of a brawler than Bastion.
Yeah. Bastion, however, came out ahead in terms
of durability, considering like, He could get
his head blown off and reconstitute himself.
He's like infinitely repairable. Bastion also
got the edge in intellect because Amazo's a
big dum-dum for a robot, which is kind of surprising.
And then Bastion also came out ahead on versatility,
which that seems weird, right? Yeah, and that
was a result simply of the averaging that we
did between Amazo's most powerful form and
his base form. Interestingly enough, Bastion
came out a little bit ahead on that. Yeah,
because base level Amazo doesn't really do a
whole lot. Like he can fly and punch things
and shoot lasers from his eyes, but not too
much else. Right. Yeah. So taking all of this
into consideration, who do you think came out
on top? I'm going to give it to my boy Bastion
for sure. Well, Instagram disagrees with you
because 70 percent of them said that Amazo
is going to win. And I feel like I'm on this
like DC hot streak when it comes to Instagram,
like the past like five or six polls. have all
gone in DC's favor, which I feel like had been
really rare in the past. Yeah, I think consistently
Marvel characters usually get the win in those
polls. So, yeah, I don't know what's happening.
It feels like the tide of public opinion is
kind of turning against Marvel, which I don't
like Marvel fans. Let's represent ourselves
in these polls, but also be honest, you know,
with who you think will win, obviously Marvel
characters. Well, let's see if that's true.
A.G. 9K, the results, please. Hey, you are,
sir. The winner of the matchup between Imezo
and Bastion is Bastion! He won 552 of the 1000
matches or 55.2% compared to Imezo's 44.8% win
rate. I feel like that makes sense. Really,
Bastion would just turn Imezo into a sentinel.
For as powerful as Imezo is and his whole adapting
ability... At the end of the day, he's made
out of technology that Bastion can just manipulate.
But that doesn't make sense to me as reasoning
why he would win, because Amazo could just
do the same thing to Bastion if they're, you
know, going toe to toe against each other.
Ultimately, I think it really comes down to
intelligence because what Amazo think to do
that before Bastion would, and I'm not quite
sure he would. Overall, though, this was pretty
close. So, I mean, who's to say? I'm really
glad we went with Bastion. for this matchup.
I think initially I wanted to do Nimrod the
sentinel from Days of Future Past who is my
favorite sentinel. But Devin Davis, one of the
executive producers, was like, now I should
be Bastion. Not only because he's a major villain
in the X-Men 97 animated series, but also,
you know, Nimrod becomes Bastion. So Bastion
is kind of like the final form of the sentinel
robot. And everybody loves the sentinels. I
thought this was a great match. Well, I thought
it sucked. You wanted to go with the Mark 2
Sentinel robots, right? I wanted to go with
the Justice League of Mezzo. Dude is hella powerful,
way more powerful than Bastion could ever be.
And I don't know, this loss just makes me feel
dirty. It makes me feel like Bastion could
defeat the Justice League, which I know he can't.
I mean, if the Justice League were all robots,
he'd have a pretty damn good chance of taking
over. So he has no chance then, because none
of them are robots. Well, maybe Cyborg. I don't
know. I mean, Cyborg has technopathy too. So
that's true. That's true. But that does it for
this duel guys. Let us know what you thought
about the results by writing to us at dyna or
by visiting us on Instagram, which you can
find a link to on our show notes or by going
to our website at dynamicduel.com. And on our
site, you could also find a link to our Patreon
page where you could join our dynamic duo tier
and chat with us and fellow listeners, our fantastic
four tier, which gets you bonus content each
month. our X-Force tier that makes you an executive
producer of this podcast, or our newest tier
that lets you join our DynaMic podcast network.
Hey guys, please don't forget to rate our show
either on Apple podcasts or on Spotify or Podchaser
or even on our website. In our next episode,
we are going to be reviewing X-Men 97, the Disney
Plus animated series, 10 episodes. If you haven't
checked it out yet, definitely go watch it,
especially if you're a fan of the 90s x-men
animated cartoon Even if you weren't it's fantastic.
I haven't even started it yet. So I'm gonna
be doing some baby. You better get on that shit.
I know But that is over this episode guys.
We want to give a big thanks to our executive
producers Ken Johnson, John Storosky, Zachary
Hepburn, Dustin Belcombe, Miggy Mathangian,
Brandon Essergard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yeaton,
Austin Wiselowski, AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho,
Gil Camacho, Adam Spies, Andrew Schunk, Dean
Maleski, and Devin Davis for helping make this
podcast possible. And we'll talk to you guys
next week. Up up and away, true believers.