This is a Dynamike Network podcast.
Welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin brother Marvelous
Joe. And in our fourth week of Spooktober,
we are going to be reviewing the spooky film
Ghost Rider Spirit of Vengeance. Spooky good,
right? or spooky in the kind of way where it's
like, oh no, I don't want to watch this. It's
because it's kind of spooky and bad. Yeah, you
know, there's things I like about the movie,
things I don't. But we are going to be joined
in our review by special guest John Storosky
from the Mad Trivia podcast. So look forward
to that later this episode. Of course, before
that, we're going to break down the comic book
movie news from the past week, which actually,
no, we're not because. There was no comic book
movie news from the past week. It's super dead
right now in terms of Hollywood coverage. But
we are coming to you with the news of how awesome
the podcast Senjou World is hosted by executive
producer of this show, Zachary Hepburn. We're
going to be talking to him later on this episode.
As always, we list our segment times in our
episode description, so feel free to check out
the show notes if you want to skip ahead to
a particular topic. As our listeners may know,
our dual simulator is so advanced that it's
gained sentience and has named itself the Artificial
Lifeform for running extensive duels, just
a rather very intelligent Simulator 9000 or
Alfred Jarvis 9000. Here's a quick message
for our listeners, so listen up! Why hello there.
Do you love listening and chatting about Marvel
and DC? Then become a part of the dynamic dual
community on Patreon, where you can choose
from three tiers. The dynamic 2-0 tier lets
you listen to this podcast without ads and
gives you access to its Discord chat group,
where you can chat with Johnny DC and Marvelous
Joe. The Fantastic Four tier gives you that
and more with two bonus episodes each month,
including bloopers and top ten shows where Johnny
and Joe count down your favourite Marvel and
DC subjects. The X-Force tier makes you an executive
producer of Dynamic Duel, where every month
you help the host choose what to review and
who to fight against each other. And finally,
the Dynamite Podcast Network tier allows aspiring
podcasters to create their own battle-focused
show using this Monte Carlo simulator.
Thanks ag9k and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast. Be sure to tune in to the Max
Destruction Podcast, part of the Dynamike Podcast
Network. this Wednesday, where this month host
Ken is going to pit some of the spookiest film
characters against each other, including Candyman
and Leatherface and Predator vs. the Alien Queen.
Yeah, also tune in to Sendrow World this week
to find out who'd win in a fight between the
anime characters of Muzaka and Alucard. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click on the link in
our show notes to listen to all the shows in
the Dynamike Podcast Network. But with that
out of the way... Quick! to the no prize. A
no prize is an award Marvel used to give out
to fans. Our version, the Dynamic Dual No Prize,
is a digital award we post on Instagram and
in our email newsletter for the person that
we feel gave the best answer to our question
of the week. Last week, we asked, what upcoming
television series from Marvel or DC are you
most looking forward to and why? Yeah, we got
a few answers, not very many. Actually a little
bit disappointed in the quality of the answers.
because none of them were Marvel. They were
all DC. Actually, we did get one Marvel answer,
except it was for a non-existent show that's
not actually coming out. Someone said that
they were excited for Nova to come out, but
that's not really a thing. That was just something
that someone said one time on the internet.
So wishful thinking, yeah. Yeah, wishful thinking.
But our first honorable mention goes to Miki
Matengian, who said. Hey, what's up guys, this
is Miki. And the first thought that came to
my mind was My Adventures with Superman season
two. But I think you guys said series and not
season, so I'm gonna go with the Green Lanterns
show. That's gonna be part of the James Gunn
DC Comics universe. I think it'll just be really
fun to see like a buddy cop movie and see like
redemption for the Green Lantern franchises
and live action. Yeah, so we've been waiting
for a live action Green Lantern series for
what seems like forever. Of course, with James
Gunn and Peter Safran taking the helm of DC
studios, The planned HBO Max Green Lantern series
has been scrapped, and I guess it's being retooled
under the direction of the new heads of the
studio. Of course, our first Green Lantern
in the universe has already been cast. Nathan
Fillion is playing Guy Gardner, but we're not
sure if he's going to be a star in the upcoming
Green Lantern's television series. Yeah, Finn
Wintrock was attached to the character of Guy
Gardner in the previous iteration of this series,
but this new show set in the DC universe has
been described as being akin to True Detective,
which sounds awesome. So, yeah, I can see why
Miggie's looking forward to it. Yeah, no words
on our release date yet for that show. Great
answer, Miggie. Our next honorable mention
goes to Andrew Shunk, who said, Andrew Shunk
here. The show I'm looking forward to most
is Lanterns. With it being a true detective
style, it can bring in so much. And having
a group like the Durlins play the main antagonist
also then opens up the world of DC and can
bring in Brainiac or the Dominators and really
makes it an epic show. Plus, interested to
see who they're going to cast. So Andrew also
gave the answer of Lanterns, saying that it's
really going to open up DC's universe. specifically
the cosmic universe where we get to meet different
alien characters. And I think that's a great
justification for why the show is going to
be awesome, because not many DC movies have
taken place in outer space on other planets.
Yeah, Andrew also mentioned that he's excited
to see who they're going to cast for the characters
of Held Jordan and Jon Stewart. Jonathan, off
the top of your head, who are you going with?
Oh, shit. Well, Channing Tatum has been rumored
for Held Jordan, and I don't hate that. Like,
I would totally accept that. I kinda hate that.
I don't know. What? No, get out of here. And
then to pair with Channing Tatum, I'd go with,
I don't know, John David Washington. There
you go. That wouldn't be bad. Great answer,
Andrew Schunk. Thanks to Nate Mantineo for
taking the time to visit our website and leave
an answer. But the winner of this week's No
Prize is Christopher Manotti, who said. Hi guys,
Christopher Manotti. I'm really looking forward
to the Penguin TV show. I really like. Colin
Farrell's The Penguin in the Batman, and I
really wanna see more of that character. I think
it would be cool to see more of his empire
and see how much control he actually has over
Gotham. Plus, this could be a good way to introduce
more of Batman's rogues gallery, like Black
Mask or even Deadshot. Absolutely, I cannot
wait for this series to come out. Of course,
the series is a sequel to the Batman film that
came out last year. Colin Farrell totally killed
it as The Penguin, Totally unrecognizable,
did a fantastic job, and I can't wait to see
more of that character in his own series where,
yeah, you're right, we may be introduced to
more of Gotham's criminal underworld with characters
like maybe Harvey Dent, Black Mask, maybe even
Harley Quinn. That would be cool. Yeah, those
characters would all certainly be interesting
set within the very realistic grounded world
that Matt Reeves set up in the Batman movie.
So great answer, Christopher Manotti, you win
this week's No Prize. If you the listener want
a shot at winning your own No Prize... Stay
tuned to later on this episode when we'll be
asking another question of the week. But with
that out of the way, onto the news!
Alright, so there's no news this week, but we
are going to in a moment here get Zachary Hepburn
on the line Who is the host of the Send Your
World? Anime action podcast which is part of
the dynamite podcast network, but leading into
the interview We want to hit you guys with
a question of the week
Which Marvel or DC character do you think would
make for the most awesome anime series, and
why? Yeah, since we're gonna be talking to Zack
about his show, which is about anime, we thought
this was an appropriate question. Of course,
there already have been some Marvel and DC
characters that have had animes, such as, uh,
I guess Superman, with the recent My Adventures
with Superman show. Also Wolverine, the X-Men,
Blade. So none of those guys that have already
had animes. We're talking about, like, new characters
that have not had animes, movie, or series
yet. Right. Recording your answer at dynamic
duel dot com by clicking on the red microphone
button in the bottom right hand corner of the
screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long. And don't forget to leave your name in
case we include you on the podcast. We'll pick
our favorite answer and award that person a
dynamic duel no prize that will post to Instagram
and our email newsletter. Be sure to answer
before October 28th. Alright, let's get executive
producer Zachary Hepburn on the line to talk
about his podcast, Senjo World. Hey Zach, glad
to have you on the show since you were last
on for our amazing Spider-Man review. It's good
to be back. I'm excited. It's been a while.
It has been a while. For those who don't know,
Zach is an executive producer of Dynamic Duel
and as we launched our Dynamike podcast network,
Zach came to us right away pitching a show
where he would use the Monte Carlo simulator
to see who would win in fights between anime
characters. And without hesitating, Jonathan
and I were like, absolutely. You know, he has
podcasting experience. He's extremely knowledgeable
about not just anime, but literally everything.
Pop culture, really. I think out of anyone,
Zach, you probably could have created a show
about anything like because you game more than
anybody I know. Like, you know, everything
about video games. You have an insane movie
collection. You know, everything about movies.
You read tons of comics. You know, you're a
big fan of superheroes. And of course, you
watch a lot of shows. both animated and live
action. So I guess starting off, out of everything
you could have made a show about, what made
you decide on anime? To be honest, it was one
of those phases I was going through. I kind
of go through phases of what I really get into.
And at that point it was anime, but at the same
time I was like, anime would be perfect for
this, right? And I was actually talking with
one of my guests and he also listens to Dynamic
Duel. And... When he first heard you guys talk
about the new level for the Patreon where you
make your own podcast, he was like, oh, I want
to do an anime one. And then like the next
episode, like my podcast got announced. So lead
him to the punch. Yeah. Right. So but yeah,
no, it's it just fits. Right. And the internet
is just full of people just fighting and arguing.
You know what I mean? So it's like, let's do
the math. Let's get the actual results. You
know, it was perfect. I feel like I see more
people arguing about anime characters than
I do like Marvel versus DC or comic book characters
in general. Like I feel like everyone's always
talking about who would be Goku or someone like
that, you know? Pretty much. Yes, definitely
a passionate fan base for sure. Oh yeah, like
I've shown you guys like how they talk to each
other. It's very toxic if you guys, if people
don't agree. So I try and stay on the, you
know, on the edge, but like it is what it is,
but it's fun. It's very fun. And of course,
there's nothing more objective to determining
who would win these fights than math, right?
You can't really argue with math. So I kind
of feel like you're the last word on this subject,
whether people want to admit that or not. Pretty
much, right? So Senjou World is releasing its
15th episode this week. It's going to be Alucard
versus Muzaka for Spooktober. And plus, you've
broken down some amazing matches in the past,
like Yusuke from Yu Hakusho. versus Tangiro
from Demon Slayer, you've done Alan Walker from
D. Greyman versus Edward Elric from Fullmetal
Alchemist, and most recently, you did Denji
the Chainsaw Man versus D. O'Brando from Jojo's
Bizarre Adventure. Out of all the episodes you've
done, what episode so far without spoiling
anything would you say has been your most surprising?
Most surprising would probably be the Devilman
episode. I had a guest on for that one as well
and... We were just amazed how great the matchup
actually was. So, yeah, I would have to say
probably the Devilman versus Kaguya episode.
Nice. I am highly fascinated by the character
of Chainsaw Man. I remember seeing him a while
back when the anime first started coming out
and I was like, what the heck is this? I got
to check this out because it's just, I don't
know, the imagery of a guy with a chainsaw
for a head is quite alarming. But I think one
of the best qualities of Centro World for people
like myself who aren't necessarily that well
versed in anime is that Senjou World is almost
like a gateway drug I think for those who are
curious about what anime is out there. My favorite
episode of Senjou World so far has been Alan
Walker vs Edward Elric, largely because I've
seen Fullmetal Alchemist, but the story of D.
Greyman sounded just fascinating. My favorite
episode was probably Gaara vs Akutagawa. I know
I totally butchered that. I always butcher
the names. Akutagawa. Yeah. The guest you head
on for that. Just listening to you guys geek
out. over anime. It was just fun to listen to.
It's fun to listen to people who are passionate
about the genre talk about it. Yeah, no, that
is definitely one of the awesome parts about
getting some of these guests, right? And it's
putting me a little bit further into the anime
community where I can, you know, branch out
a little bit more, even just expand my own
knowledge base. It's really dope. Like I'm loving
it. It's clear that you are really knowledgeable
about the characters because when you go into
your battle speculation, It seems like you
have a solid grasp of not only what the characters
can do, but also what they would do. And that
can be a fine line because knowing what they
would do requires a greater understanding of
the characters and the characterization that
they have. So kudos on that. I'm always really
impressed by your battle speculations. Oh, I
appreciate that. As an anime fan, what type
of anime shows or movies are you most drawn
to? And what would you say are some of your
all-time favorites? It's kind of cliche, but...
I'm definitely a shonen guy. Shonen is more
action based. A lot of shonen follows the same
kind of tropes and that's why a lot of people
kind of hate on them. But I don't know, I find
a lot of the best fights come from shonen.
But don't get me wrong, there's a whole bunch
of other ones that are just as good. But if
I would have to say anything, it would probably
be shonen, action, martial arts. That's usually
like my wheelhouse. Anything that has that definitely
draws me in right off the bat. which is totally
fitting for a fight podcast. Exactly. I'm still
waiting for you to do like Neon Genesis, Evangelion
versus Gundam, because you and I have had debates
about that. And I will totally fight you on
that one. Yeah. As a guest on that one. For
sure. 100 percent. I just don't want to like
break your heart when it when it really comes
down to it. You know, so we'll see. Jonathan
gets his heart broken all the time on our show,
so don't worry about it. About half the time.
That's true. I just have to find the right Gundam
to go up against it. But to be honest, I would
probably bring the guy from DerLogin, that big
robot. I think that would be a better matchup.
That's a deep cut. I've never heard of that.
I'm never going to take your word for that
one. I'm going to have to look that up now.
For sure. That one's so good. Can you tell
us the origin of the name for your show, Senjou
World? How did you come up with that? Well,
to be honest, I just... kind of went on Google
and I'm like, hmm, what would be some cool
names, right? And then I was like, Battle World.
So I looked up like, okay, how do I say battle
in Japanese? And then it was just like, Batool.
And I was like, okay, well, that's kind of
stupid. So I was searching around and everything
and then I was like, okay, let's try two words
together because in Japanese, they'll have a
completely separate word for that, right? battle
arena and that's where Senjou came up and it
was one of the first things that actually popped
up because I know we talked about it we had
a couple different spellings for it at the
beginning right? That's right. So Senjou also
has multiple meanings depending on how you
spell it. Right yeah I think if you spell it
with just the O didn't it mean like fairy or
something? Fairy? Yeah. But every time I hear
the name Senjou World I always want to pronounce
it in a that heavy anime style where I'm like
Senjou! but Jonathan won't let me. Um. Senjou.
You have to say like deep. You have to say deep.
Well, it depends on what anime archetype you
are, I think. I consider myself like the burly,
like excitable big guy, you know? Really. Okay.
I do not see that. Well, I'm definitely not
like the skinny, like long-haired pretty boy
type. I feel like that's just not how I see
myself. So. No, you're like the like the short
punk ass kid with glasses and like the messy
hair.
Well, Senjo World is an awesome show. You should
be super proud of it, Zach. We're super proud
to have it as part of our Dynamike network.
Listeners, if you love anime and want to see
who mathematically would win in Zach's matchups,
and if you're interested in hearing the stories
of your favorite characters and perhaps discovering
new favorites, be sure to listen to Senjo World.
That's S-E-N-J-O-H World. Anywhere you listen
to podcasts or by visiting dynamicpodcast.com.
Zach, thanks for joining us. It was great to
have you. And yeah, look forward to listening
to more Sinjo World in the future, especially
this upcoming episode. Sounds awesome. Yeah,
thanks a lot guys. And tell John I said what
up. Oh yeah, for sure. This episode is almost
like a media night with the boys reunion. That's
the cool thing too, like, cause I just had
John on my show and it's pretty cool that, you
know, we're on the same episode. We might not
be together, but we're still on the same episode.
Yeah, yeah, I think John's taken over.
With that being said, let's go ahead and say
goodbye to Zach and get on to our main event
where we review the 2012 movie by Sony Pictures,
Ghost Rider Spirit of Vengeance.
Ghost Rider Spirit of Vengeance came out in
2012, directed by Mark Neveldeen and Brian
Taylor and starring Nicolas Cage, Idris Elba,
Johnny Whitworth, and Kieran Hines. The movie
is a quasi-sequel to the 2007 film directed
by Mark Steven Johnson and also starring Nicolas
Cage as Johnny Blaze, but it doesn't really
keep anything else in regards to continuity.
I used to struggle with these reboot sequels,
or requels as it were. But now that the concept
of the Marvel multiverse exists, it's easy to
see this film and the 2007 Ghost Rider as parallel
timelines where some things change, but some
things, like Johnny Blaze, remain the same.
But speaking of badasses named Johnny, and I
sure as hell do not mean Johnny DC, I'm talking
about MadTrivia John, aka executive producer
of this show, John Staroski, from the MadTrivia
Podcast. Say hi, John. Hi, John.
I had to, I had to, I'm sorry, take that one.
Thanks for having me on, guys. It is a pleasure
to be back after so very long. Yeah, you last
joined us for the amazing Spider-Man review
that you did with Zack, who was on this episode
earlier when you guys were doing the Media
Night with the Boys podcast. Since that time,
you've put out the Mad Trivia podcast, which
marries the concepts of movie discussions and
trivia. So tell us a little bit about that
show. Yeah, so as you well know, because I've
actually had you on as a guest already, it
is essentially a trivia game for my guests and
a little bit of a mad lib as well at the end.
My guests provide me their five favorite movies
of which I pick one without their knowledge.
I then do a good amount of research to find
as many good questions as I can, narrow it
down to 10 with 11 possible answers. Of course,
one of those being a two answer question. And
then I pretty much always something because
I go really hard in the paint when it comes
to research You found out the hard way with
fight clubbing. Yeah, I think I only got about
half the questions, right? Something like that.
Yeah, five or six. Yeah, it's a fantastic concept
for a podcast I never would have thought to
marry mad libs with trivia and movies. It's
it's phenomenal. I love it. Yeah, thank you
and then as the mad libs go I actually I love
doing that more than the trivia because I love
taking those scenes that people love from those
movies and making them unknowingly ruin it and
the result is usually just hilarious. Those
mad live surprises are some of the best parts
of the show. I think also it's great just to
hear people talk passionately about their favorite
films. Absolutely. So, I remember you enjoying
The Amazing Spider-Man back when we reviewed
it on the show and I believe you really enjoyed
Ghost Rider Spirit of Vengeance which is why
we wanted to bring you on board for this review.
Tell us, I guess, your history with this movie.
Like, when did you first see it, and what do
you think about it overall? OK, so I am a Marvel
fan, very long term. I've been following Marvel
since the early days. Blade, obviously, as everyone
knows, Blade kind of paved the way for everything,
so to speak. And I just started falling in love
with the characters that they had. And then
Ghost Rider came out in, I suppose, 2007. And
Nicolas Cage is so cheesy, but you just have
to love him. And the way he delivered the performance
in the first one, I kind of like it was new
to me because I'd never seen that kind of character.
And he was so unique that I just kind of always
had like this love for Ghost Rider in a way
that is, you know, it's always there and hoping
that something good comes along. And I remember
seeing it in theaters. I remember loving it.
But I remember loving that one specific line
in the middle of the movie while around the
middle of the movie about eaten souls. We'll
get there when we come to the review. I know
you know what I'm talking about. Yeah. I'm going
to leave the rest of my thoughts for during
the review because I haven't seen it in a long
time. Okay. And things have changed. Oh, interesting.
This was actually my first time watching the
movie and it was so unbelievably different
from what I was expecting. I don't know why
because I had heard that it was, you know,
kind of out there from other people who have
seen it, but it kind of defied my expectations,
which I didn't think was going to happen. Defied
them in a good way or a bad way? in a just
fucking weird way, just like Nick Cage's performance,
how completely different it was from the first
movie and just like the one liners from Ghost
Rider that he delivered. And just like even
like the animation that they would incorporate
to the movie and stuff like that. It was interesting.
And I don't know if that's interesting in a
good way. I think it's in a good way. You know,
the directors Mark Neville Dean and Brian Taylor
are very different types of filmmakers than.
Mark Steven Johnson who directed the 2007 film.
I remember being fascinated that Mark Neville
Dean and Brian Taylor were announced to direct
this movie back when they announced that even
though I've never seen the crank franchise or
the movie gamer or any of their other films,
but I knew of the reputation of creating movies
that had gritty adrenaline packed action. And
I was like, yes, that would be perfect for Ghost
Rider because I also remember reading that
even though they're the directors, they do most
of the camera work on their films themselves,
using handhelds while riding on rollerblades,
which was this insane concept. It's like almost
like they're stunt guys themselves. So I thought
it was fitting that they were put on a film
about a former stunt writer. Yeah, absolutely.
I remember in lead up to this film, just seeing
sort of behind the scenes promotional material
showing them like riding behind trucks on their
rollerblades. That's dangerous stuff. And that's
very admirable that you have these guys who
are so ballsy and willing to take risks to get
the shot that they really are envisioning in
their head. I remember seeing this and not having
any association to the directors whatsoever.
I think that's a really interesting perspective
to have given this movie. For sure. Yeah. And
not only the camera work, but also like the
gritty visual tone that they chose. They set
the movie in Eastern Europe. I think they were
trying to go for some kind of like... I think
David Escort described it as Da Vinci Code-esque
setting where you have the main protagonist
of that movie and this movie over in Europe
kind of going on this adventure involving these
monks and stuff like that. I know this movie
is kind of like a far cry from the Da Vinci
Code, but it is interesting that they have those
kind of parallels. I think Eastern Europe was
a fantastic setting for this film, not just
because of the tone that it brought, but also
the grittiness. It's cool because we don't typically
see Eastern Europe and a lot of superhero films.
I sort of feel like that was another motivation
for them to do this film there, because not
only was it probably cheaper than filming in
a lot of major cities where typical superhero
films take place, but I totally get the Da Vinci
Code connection because this film definitely
looked very different from other films in the
genre. Yeah, the story was written by David
S. Goyer. who is yes, the very same David S.
Goyer who wrote and directed the last film
we reviewed, Blade Trinity. And while I don't
think the story here was bad, like overall
I actually think that Ghost Rider Spirit of
Vengeance has a decent Ghost Rider story, I
will admit that it does feel a little bit cliché
and the dialogue was pretty terrible, I'll
say that. But I think that the schlocky tone
was maybe what the directors and the writer
were going for. Grindhouse appeal when you combine
the dialogue with the gritty visuals. But I
will say that if that was what they were going
for, I don't think they took it far enough.
I think a true Grindhouse ghostwriter film would
be epic. But you know, straddling the line
between a schlocky gritty monster movie and
a modern superhero action film just leads to
something that can feel kind of almost half-hearted
and occasionally silly. Yeah, I agree with
that. And now that you mentioned Grindhouse,
I'm wondering how this would have looked if
it's a... Is it Robert Rodriguez, the greenhouse
director? Yes. I would love to see his version
of a Ghost Rider film. Now that I'm thinking
about that. Oh, man. Oh, he and Guillermo del
Toro would be at the top of my list in regards
to the most ideal directors for a Ghost Rider
film. I think I would place Robert Rodriguez
over Guillermo del Toro just because he's a
little bit more gritty and a little bit more
like rubber meets the road, leather jacket
kind of style with machine guns blazing and
stuff like that, explosions in the background.
He would be so perfect for that. That's true.
I do sort of feel like, you know, if the writer
and directors were trying to make something
that was a little bit grindhouse, I feel like
they definitely got direction from the producers
to, hey, make the cheapest possible film you
can, you know, because the story is so simple.
And I agree, it's not a terrible story for
Ghost Rider. You know, it feels very much like
a comic book story to me. Like this is a comic
book arc in the Ghost Rider comic. But you're
right, it's very cliche, it's very simple.
And I love David S. Goyer as a writer. So I
was actually very surprised to see that he
wrote this film, because I didn't know that
previously. That kind of made me be like, oh
yeah, this is gonna be awesome, only to be severely
disappointed. I actually think this is probably
my least favorite film that I've seen of his,
next to Blade Trinity, of course. I would say
this is better than that. I can't say that I
agree or disagree on that one. I liked Blade
Trinity. When I initially saw it, I haven't
rewatched it recently enough to know if I dislike
it now. Yeah, I don't know if I would put this
above or below Trinity. Alright, Joseph, you've
got to break the tie. What's worse, Ghost Rider
Spirit of Vengeance or Blade Trinity? Well,
definitely Blade Trinity. So if you compare
each movie to the previous installments in
their respective franchises, comparing Blade
Trinity to the first two Blade films is like
comparing a cheap beer to a fine wine, you know,
and comparing Ghost Rider Spirit of Vengeance...
to the first 2007 Ghost Rider is not that drastic
of a comparison, but I do like the darker gritty
tone that this sequel decided to go with. I
think it's the best thing it has over the original.
There are a few things about the original I
like a little bit more. I do think it set up
the origin story for the character in a kind
of groundbreaking way for the comic book character
of Ghost Rider, but Spirit of Vengeance is more
in line with what I would hope to see from
a Ghost Rider film, I think. It shouldn't be
your standard superhero action adventure story.
It should have a little bit more of a darker
tone and feel. And I appreciate that. That's
fair. That's true. I didn't even think about
how I would compare this film to the first
Ghost Rider film. And I guess I would agree
with you in that I do think that I liked this
one more just because it felt, like I mentioned
earlier, almost like a comic book. And I really
liked that. I do wish it had a harder edge.
It was only PG-13. could totally go rated R
with this character and I think they should
have. Like to me Ghost Rider should be a horror
character. A horror Ghost Rider film without
any comedy whatsoever to me is how a Ghost
Rider film should be. I could be wrong, but
I would love to see that. Well, I would definitely
say that the ideal Ghost Rider film would keep
the jokes to a minimum. I mean, in an ideal
world, a Ghost Rider film would be very much
in the horror genre, I think. Horror action
for sure. But let's go ahead and get into the
character breakdown. Starting with Ghost Rider,
AKA Johnny Blaze, who's played by the one and
only Nicholas Cage. And talking about the guy's
acting skill and performance ability is no small
task, I'll say that. On one hand, you have
people who consider him one of the greatest
actors of his generation, with films like Adaptation
and Matchstick Men proving their point. On the
other hand, you have people who consider him
one of the worst actors ever, with films like
Wicker Man and Vampire's Kiss proving their
point. I think fittingly, his performance in
Ghost Rider Spirit of Vengeance straddles both
viewpoints where at times I think he delivers
a vulnerable real performance, such as when
he confesses his selfishness being behind his
deal with the devil, and other times when he
goes incredibly over the top, such as when the
writer is trying to break through while interrogating
one of Kerrigan's contacts. I think either way,
whether you love him or hate him, at the very
least you have to admit that his performances
are interesting at worst and fun at best, or
at least you can tell he has fun. while performing.
Yeah, I can say with the utmost confidence
that Nicolas Cage is the actor of all time.
That's true, for sure. No, I did not love his
performance in this movie. I wanted it to feel
like it was interesting, but there were just
so many unbelievably weird moments that I feel
like he's kind of the worst aspect of this film.
Like I feel like this might have been a good
Ghost Rider film. if someone besides Nicolas
Cage played him. OK, OK. John, what do you
think? I don't think he was great, but I don't
think it was his fault. I think the lines that
he was he was given were just it was like they
weren't written for anyone to read. They were
just there to throw out on the page. Like it
just it didn't feel like he was given the right
script. Who can deliver a line like I will eat
your stinking soul? No one can do that. I almost
wonder, though, if like he intentionally wanted
those lines added. Something about his performance
just makes me think that he wanted this character
to be so much more weird than the first movie.
You know, I feel like the line delivery was
something like roadkill. You know, it's just
so cheesy, sort of in the same way that his
performance was cheesy. So I don't know if
it's the writing. I wouldn't be surprised if,
you know, he just delivered those lines ad-libbed
while they were performing. It almost felt that
way to me. That wouldn't surprise me because
he does make a lot of strange choices. You know,
in the first Ghost Rider movie, he was the
one who wanted to be drinking jelly beans out
of martini glasses and things like that. Just
these little weird idiosyncrasies that he thought
would help inform his portrayal of Johnny Blaze.
What's kind of funny is that Nicolas Cage in
this movie, Spirit of Vengeance, he allegedly
invented a new acting technique when playing
the character of Ghost Rider called Nuvo Shamanism.
where he painted his face black with a white
skull, kind of like Baron Semity, and he sewed
some ancient Egyptian trinkets into his leather
jacket to try to invoke some kind of supernatural
energy into his performance. You could definitely
see it, I think, in the character of Ghost
Rider because there's a lot of times during
the film where I'm like, what is Ghost Rider
doing? Like, why is he acting that way? Like,
he's swaying back and forth. just standing
there and acting creepy. You know, it's not
a traditional approach that Nicolas Cage took
to this for sure, but I do think his version
of Ghost Rider was more creepy here than the
first film, which I think means it's better.
He definitely came off as a bit more creepy,
albeit very stale at times. It was like he went
from not moving at all, and then he was swaying,
and then he was just fast and in your face.
Like it did kind of catch me off guard. I think
they were intending for jump scares in those
scenes and... It didn't scare so much as it
just kind of shocked that it went from nothing
to burst of speed. Yeah, I feel exactly the
same way. And I know exactly what you're talking
about. And it makes me think that the film
also suffered from poor editing, because I think
if they would have cut down those weird slow
moments and just kept him as this, like, frightening
in your face creature, he would have been a
lot more effective. I agree. Yeah, totally.
Now, the character of Johnny Blaze. has always
been a tragic one in the comics, where his superpower
is really a curse and a burden, similar to
the Hulk, where his powered form is a separate
being of wanton destruction. At the start of
the film, Johnny Blaze is essentially in self-exile,
but when given the opportunity to remove the
demon, he takes it, which is understandable.
But Johnny Blaze lives with this guilt of his
selfishness, and he claimed to Meroe that it
led him to make the deal with the devil in
the first place. And despite this weight that
he feels, what he learns after the fact of
removing the curse is that maybe he's not as
selfish as he once thought because he chooses
to potentially sacrifice his mortal self to
save the boy, Danny. He chooses to take back
the curse and he revives the boy from death.
In the end, he discovers he's actually quite
a selfless, heroic person despite what he may
have thought earlier. And like the ghost rider
itself, perhaps... he finds himself as an angel
in disguise. I like that description. I do.
I think that kind of validates a lot of how
it played out. Yeah. His arc, I think, was
actually really well done in this movie. I love
at the beginning when Moreau and Johnny blaze
our first meeting. And, you know, Moreau is
like, you have to save this boy. And Johnny
is like, I don't save people. But by the end,
you see that, like you mentioned, he actually
does the whole reveal, the whole secret that
he chose to save his father even though his
father had accepted the fact that he was cancer
stricken was an element to Johnny Blaze's story
that was surprising to me and I thought very
heartfelt and very interesting for the character.
What did you think of the revelation in this
movie at least that Xerathos was once an angel
who was tortured in hell and transformed from
an angel of justice to a spirit of vengeance?
Honestly, I don't know how it compares to the
comic book origin of Xerathos, I do like that
he's kind of like this fallen angel character.
It gives him a little bit more depth that you
otherwise wouldn't have, especially considering
in the first movie, there was no delving into
Zerathos' history or background or anything.
There was no nothing really to him. He was
just the entity inside of Johnny Glaze. So that
little bit more perspective that we got, even
if it is only just a small amount, it does give
the character more depth that you didn't get
to experience. gives more of an understanding
as to where the hatred's coming from. And I
think that makes him more relatable. Yeah, definitely
adds interest to the character for sure. I
thought it was badass that they went the angel
route with the Zerathos. Like you mentioned,
John, they didn't mention Zerathos in the first
movie. I'm really glad that they did this route
because it does add a little bit more dimension
to not just Johnny Blaze, but the character
of Ghost Rider. At the very end when he goes
blue. I thought that was a really cool way
of showing that he's sort of like become this
redeemed figure in a way. He's fighting for
justice now, you know, not just vengeance. Yeah,
the blue fire aspect is an interesting one
that comes from the comics. This film was heavily
inspired by the Road to Damnation storyline
from the comics, which was written by Garth
Ennis, which was a fantastic run. Yeah, really,
I highly recommend that one. The art was incredible
alone. So the second person to be Ghost Rider
was Johnny Blaze's brother, Danny Ketch. who
in the comics at one point lost his powers
and he was offered to take them up again by
an angel named Zadkiel. And when Zadkiel bestowed
upon him the powers, he had blue flame. So it
was like he was the angel writer. But in the
end, it turned out that Zadkiel was actually
an evil angel who was looking to overthrow
heaven. But it was interesting how they kind
of took that blue fire aspect. which is the
angels fire, you know, and then applied that
to Johnny Blaze at the end of this movie. When
he was able to, you know, like tap into Zerathos'
former angel powers. Yeah, that was really
cool, I thought. I do think that the character
of Ghost Rider is so much better looking, or
at least more believable, I should say, in this
movie than in the first film, largely because
of that black skull. For some reason, even though
in the comics, Ghost Rider's flaming skull
is depicted as white. It just doesn't look as
real in live action like how it did in the
first movie. And you could see the difference
when comparing the two ghostwriters from the
two films. Ghostwriter Spirit of Vengeance just
looks more realistic. The same can be said
about the leather. I mean, it's got that bubble
boiling, you know, firstly burned look to it.
And it definitely seems like they invested more
of their budget into the look of Ghostwriter
in this movie. I completely agree with that.
Yeah, I'm really glad they updated his look
for this film, and I didn't even know it needed
updating, but apparently it did because this
was way more hella cool than the first movie.
I'll say, however, that the design of the hell
cycle in the first movie was leaps and bounds
better than this motorcycle in spirit of vengeance.
Like Ghost Rider needs to be writing, you know,
like some kind of demonic chopper, like in
the first film or some kind of souped up Danny
Catch style techno crotch rocket or something
interesting like that. But not just some standard.
You know, Yamaha Cruiser like he had in this
movie. I thought that was really disappointing.
I do think you need something a little bit
more stylistic or cool. Got to be a chopper.
It's got to be a chopper. I don't know. I don't
know much about motorcycles. I actually liked
this more than the chopper, and I feel like
I'm about to be jumped by like a biker gang
of guys who are like, fuck you, choppers are
the best. I don't know. That's I guess it's
just my aesthetic. I lean more crotch rocket
than chopper. Personally, I think they're cooler.
And not that this was a crotch rocket, but
I hate it. Let's go to move on to Moreau, who
is played by Idris Elba. Now, Idris Elba is
actually better in this movie than he had any
right to be. You know, the first time I saw
the film where, you know, from the very opening
scene, he's portrayed as this badass character,
French and drunk, leaping down staircases, ripping
turns on his motorcycle and slow motion shooting
tires off cars while falling to his apparent
death. I just remember being like, who the
F is this guy? You know, perhaps the story gave
too much agency to him and maybe gave him too
big of a role to a guy who isn't even from the
comics. But part of me doesn't even care because
Idris Elba crushed it. He crushed this role.
The French accent kept throwing me because
Idris Elba has such a distinct like British
accent, you know. I thought he was great in
the role, don't get me wrong. I could have sworn
he was from the comics, but as big of a role
as he had. Like I was ready to hear all about
him during this review. Yeah, you think he
would be from the comics, but no, he's a completely
original character that they made for this
film, who just happened to be kind of a superhero
in his own right. You know, a superhero monk,
as it were. Yeah, yeah. I also think, by the
way, that I agree that he was badass in this
movie. There was no question about that whatsoever.
Yeah, and every bit the hero that Ghost Rider
was, you know, he ended up sacrificing himself
at the end just to buy Johnny a chance at saving
the kid. So maybe one day he will make an appearance
in the comics. But speaking of the comics,
let's go ahead and move into our villain, Blackout,
aka Ray Carrigan, played by Johnny Whitworth.
This movie, I think, is the first and only time
I've ever seen Johnny Whitworth in anything.
My first impression was that just like Idris
Elba, Carrigan was more character than was
necessary for the film. I don't want to be misconstrued
as advocating that actors should be generic
in their roles, but when a movie presents somebody
that is clearly like someone but doesn't really
delve into who that someone is beyond a surface
level, it does leave viewers with a lot of
questions and I think that could be a little
bit frustrating. Beyond the very surface level
exploration of Kerrigan, I did think that he
was cool and a convincing enough mercenary
asshole type character. Although I'll say I
didn't find the actor quite as convincing as
Blackout when he's in a super villain form.
I think just because of how like not menacing
and goofy the character looks. Yeah, that hair
was rough. The way his skin was kind of like
peeling around the edges. I mean, I know that
the intent was there because of his ability
to decay, but I don't get decay from Bleach
Blonde. So I was really pulled away from that.
Yeah, what's interesting is that in the comics,
he doesn't have the power of decay. So the
fact that they gave him that power in this movie
and then kind of based his makeup look around
this decaying figure was a strange choice for
sure. What does he do in the comics? So in
the comics, Blackout is a half demon character.
He's the grandson of Lilith, who is the mother
of demons, and he has enhanced strength and
durability and speed like a half demon would.
But he also has razor sharp fangs and claws.
He's kind of like vampiric. in that regard,
but his main power is to extinguish light and
generate this type of darkness that deprives
victims of all their senses. So of course that
type of power would be really hard to replicate
on film where audiences need to actually, you
know, see and hear what's going on. But I do
think the movie did an okay job of portraying
it as more of like this psychic darkness of
sorts, where his victims, like minds kind of
go into this shroud of darkness and they only
see him. but you know, it allows the audience
to still see what's going on. I do think that
this was an interesting concept for like a henchman
type secondary bad guy. But I'm also with you,
Joseph, like I didn't quite think the performance
was menacing enough at the end. It was it was
more silly than anything I felt. Yeah, for sure.
Speaking of silly, let's go to move on to Mephisto,
a.k.a. Rourke for some reason, played by Kieran
Hines. I'll come out and say it right away.
The first movie did it better when it comes
to the devil because Peter Fonda was so cool
in the first Ghost Rider movie and seeing Kieran
Hines take over the role was just so disappointing.
I don't think he brought anything to the role
other than being a man in his later years with
a deepish voice. You know, almost anyone could
have done this role, I feel, but it should
have been Peter Fonda and that way you could
have had that greater sense of continuity between
films. Yeah, I agree. I don't know this actor.
I just kind of thought he was like Stephen
Fry's stunt double. Well, you know this guy,
he played Steppenwolf in Justice League. Well,
he did the voice for Steppenwolf. Oh, and the
mocap, I believe. I doubt that. But Rourke
towards the end, when his face is melting, it
just looked really bad. And they should have
went a different route, I think, with that effect.
They probably could have showed his like skin
cracking or something like that. But instead,
they decided to make him look like he had the
mumps. which was a bad call for sure. Yeah.
How do you guys think you would have gone about
portraying visually the idea that his body is
succumbing to its own power? I don't know.
I think you could have gone a route similar
to Ghost Rider and that like he sort of has
this fire emanating from him, at least turn
his skin red. So he looks a tad bit like Mephisto
from the comics, you know. I didn't mind that
Kieran Hines played this role, though, because
they did kind of establish the fact that Mephisto
the devil. has taken on many forms through
the ages. To me, this was just sort of like
his next form after Peter Fonda. I do agree
that Peter Fonda did it better, but I didn't
really mind the actor swap. Thinking about
it for me, I think I would have much rather
seen him not cracking, but like almost losing
like structure. Like his bones started showing,
his skin started getting tight around his bones
on certain spots of him. I think that would
have been a better representation, like almost
like rapid aging in certain areas. That would
have been a cool effect too, for sure. Both
of those ideas are better than what they did.
Let's go ahead and move on to Nadia Kecs, who
was played by Violante Placido, I think is how
you pronounce that. She's an Italian actress,
I've never seen her before. And she hasn't been
in too much. The only other notable thing I
saw that she was in was Transporter, the series.
But I thought she was good for what the script
called for. I do think she was a believable
badass. I do find myself kind of wishing that
there was... more romantic tension, I guess,
between her and Johnny Blaze, because I think
that could have brought more of an overt father-son-like
dynamic to the story. Wait, because I just
caught on to something that I didn't catch when
I was watching the movie. Her last name is
Ketch? So this is Danny Ketch? This is his mom?
Yeah. Yeah, this is in fact Danny Ketch. The
boy is Danny Ketch from the comics. I guess
we could just jump right into him. He's played
by Fergus Riordan, who, you know, he's a kid
actor. He's fine. He did fine. It is weird
how they made him Danny Ketch though, because
fans of the character will know that Danny
Ketch is Johnny Blaze's brother, who in the
comics, as I mentioned, became the second version
of Ghost Rider. Here, there's no relation between
Danny and Johnny, but I do think that maybe
they were going for like a brotherly type dynamic
between the two characters when Johnny is trying
to kind of relate to the kid and tell him that
the power they have comes from a dark place,
but it doesn't make them bad. It was almost
like he was a mentor. Which is kind of cool.
Like you never see Ghost Rider really as a mentor.
But as cool as it is, I do kind of wish now
knowing that this is fucking Danny Ketch that
they would have cast the role older. Yes. Yeah,
it would have been great if he was in his teens
or something. Yeah. If he was just like five
years older, you could have had like a cool
like Terminator 2 dynamic kind of mentorship
going on. I think that would have been cooler
than what we got here. I think that that's
a good call. Have him older. more capable even
because as a, what do they say, as like nine,
10, 11 years old, something like that. Yeah.
To give that kind of an aged child, that kind
of power seems extraordinarily irresponsible.
Yeah, like if Rorke's plan was successful,
then he would have been like this little twerp
kid now with the power of the devil. You would
think that Mephisto would at least wanna transfer
his power into a young adult man at the very
least, you know. Yeah, like early 20s, at least
someone who's gone through fucking puberty.
Come on. Right. That's a great point.
Alright, let's go ahead and move into our story
highlights. In Eastern Europe, probably Romania,
I'm guessing, an alcoholic monk named Mereu
tries to warn a monastery that a boy they're
harboring, Dani Kec, is not safe there and he's
wanted by the devil. A group of mercenaries
led by Kerrigan arrive to take the child, causing
Dani and his mother Nadia to flee. I actually
kind of thought this was a really cool setup
for the movie. I was very intrigued by it.
I expected to see Ghost Rider. like right off
the bat, but to see this Muro character, I
thought it was really cool. It was just a pretty
bad scene, I thought. Yeah, the whole like
getting knocked off of his motorcycle and shooting
his gun in slow motion, shooting out the tire
while falling to his death was quite the opening
action scene. Yeah, I thought he was dead.
I thought they were going to kill him off. Yeah,
I was like, well, what was the point of that?
Right. So after a brief animated reintroduction
to Johnny Blaze, Muro seeks him out for help.
promising that if he escorts the boy to his
order, he will help remove the Ghost Rider
curse. Nadia and Danny are captured by Kerrigan
and his men, prompting Ghost Rider to find
them and kill several of the mercenaries, using
the pendant stare on one of them. He's knocked
out with several grenade launchers, however,
and Kerrigan escapes with Danny. I remember
being so pumped for this scene in theaters when
we see Ghost Rider launch his motorcycle over
everybody's heads and land and do a donut. I
thought he was immediately going to So when
he just started standing there and rocking I
was like what the fuck is happening kill somebody
I Also thought the pennant stare in this movie
if you didn't know what the pennant stare was
you'd have no fucking idea What was going on
for one it took way too long to implement and
two there were no visual cues exactly as to
what was going Gone, he was just holding their
head and they started screaming and then they
had burst into flames, but It seems so unnecessary
because Ghost Rider clearly demonstrated the
ability to make anyone burst into flames upon
contact with either him or his chains. So why
would he leave himself vulnerable for so long
taking such a long time to consume this guy's
soul? It just seemed weird. They should have
had at least some kind of visual cue with the
eyes like they did in the first movie, where
you could actually see the people living out
their crimes and stuff like that. There was
nothing like that here. Or at least do something
with like the eyes glowing like they did in
the opening animation for this movie. Yeah.
I agree. The going back to the first movie
that was much, much better than this movie with
Penn and Stair. And I mean, he even said stuff
in the first one when he was doing the Penn
and Stair. This may just kind of looked creepily
with his head tilting left and right like he
was a dog hearing a funny sound. Right. That's
a great way to describe it. I just want someone
to like make a supercut of like him moving
and like swaying back and forth to like some
music. That would be hilarious. That would
be hilarious. Waking up in the hospital, Johnny
confronts Nadia who took him there and she
wants to know if he can use Ghost Rider to find
Danny. However, the devil aka Rourke places
a spell on Danny through Kerrigan's phone that
prevents Ghost Rider from tracking him. Johnny
learns that Nadia sold her soul to the devil
to keep from dying in exchange, burying the
devil's son Danny. This is where we saw the
second animatic of the movie where we got an
explanation on how the devil uses the power
of his deal. to conduct business on earth or
to get things done. There was a really strange
moment during this scene where they seem to
imply that Jerry Springer was the devil. Yes.
Now this movie came out in 2007 and I think
Jerry Springer lost relevancy somewhere like
in 2001, the year 2000. Definitely his peak
was in the 90s, you know. So it was such a dated
reference. I don't understand why they went
with Jerry Springer given that joke was probably
made about a decade too late. This movie came
out in 2012, you said 2007. Oh shit, yeah, this
movie came out in 2012. I meant 2012. So even
later, the first movie came out in 2007. So
by 2012, the Jerry Springer joke was way too
late. Nadia takes Johnny to one of Kerrigan's
contacts at a gambling gring where, as Johnny
tries to constrain Ghost Rider, They learn that
Kerrigan is meeting with an arms dealer at
a quarry. They go there and Ghost Rider destroys
everyone using a big ass mining machine while
Nadia rescues and escapes with Danny. Ghost
Rider catches up with them and turns on Nadia,
about to use the pendant stare on her, but reverts
to Johnny when Danny commands him to stop.
So this is where we get the infamous Nicholas
Cage beating down the door performance. A lot
of times when I watch this movie, I just love
it. I laugh my ass off. But I remember the
first time I watched it, I was like, what the
fuck is he doing? As over the top as it was,
I loved it. You can tell he at least has fun.
Like he's really trying to go for something.
Pretending that Ghost Rider is attempting to
crawl out from him. Essentially, I will say
that I did really like the effect that when
he was about to turn into Ghost Rider, like
his eye sockets would suck in, like his face
is turning into a skull. Thought that was a
pretty cool, horrific idea. I mean, as fake
as it looked, I guess it was cool. You say
that Nicolas Cage had fun, but part of me feels
like he was taking this super seriously as
an actor. Like this is his art form, you know?
I don't know if he had fun with it. I don't
think he did. I think part of me just feels
like sometimes he's oblivious to what the hell
he's doing and thinks he's doing something brilliant.
And maybe he is. I have no idea. I don't think
this is one of those times. Well, it's one of
two things, right? Either he's super not self-aware.
Or he's very self-aware and he has this kind
of like weird sense of humor where he doesn't
really care about what people think about him
and just does whatever he wants to on the day
because he thinks it's fun. I think either option
is plausible, but for the sake of the actor
himself and kind of the respect that I have
for the good performances he has given in the
past, I like to think he just has a weird sense
of humor. An auteur, okay. That's fair. That's
absolutely fair. What did you guys think about
the big ass mining machine? I thought that
was really cool. It's rare that you see Ghost
Rider take over other types of vehicles. We
learned, you know, in the comics later on that
he could do it because, you know, Robbie Reyes
vehicle of choice is his car. But the idea of
the character of Ghost Rider being able to
take over any vehicle and turn it into a hell
vehicle is so cool when that vehicle is, you
know, five stories high and weighing thousands
of tons. I mean, we kind of saw in the first
movie that anything that the rider rides is
going to be a hell vehicle with Carter Slade's
horse. Right. But I do got to say the badass
mining machine, I thought that him turning
into basically a quasi chainsaw was pretty cool.
Yeah, that was so badass. That was really cool.
Yeah. If you guys could put Ghost Rider on any
vehicle besides a motorcycle or a car, what
do you think would be cool to see? I'm going
to go with the funny one first, and I'll come
back to a serious one. The funny one is going
to be him on a horse and carriage. Yeah, that
would actually look pretty cool, I think. Yeah,
I think the horse and buggy with him on the
buggy would be pretty fantastic. What's the
not funny one? A Tesla. It's got to be a Tesla.
An electric self-driving hell vehicle, for sure.
I want to see him ride a helicopter, just having
like a flaming freaking fan on top. That'd be
cool. That would be cool. You broke me when
you said helicopter and the first thing that
came into my head is hell a copter. Yeah, that's
how it would have to be spelled, right? Yeah,
well then I'll have two hells instead of the
one. I go two ways with this question. Like
part of me would love to see him write something
ridiculous, like a kid's tricycle and turn it
into like a hell tricycle. But the other part
of me goes the completely opposite direction
and like I would like to see him in like the
space shuttle or something like that. just this
massive like rocket. That would be badass.
That would be awesome. He would just like ride
around like slim pickings from Dr. Strangelove.
That'd be great. Yeah. Back to the story, Johnny,
Nadia and Danny meet up with Muro on their
way to his monastery. Meanwhile, Rourke resurrects
Kerrigan as Blackout who steals an ambulance
to track down Danny. Johnny and the group arrive
at Muro's order led by Methodius. Who freaking
knew that Christopher Lambert was going to be
in this movie? Because I did not the first
time I watched it. I was like, holy crap, it's
freaking Highlander Raiden guy. I was very
surprised when I saw him. But then I was like,
should I have been? Because like I just held
by Nicolas Cage. It seems like the kind of film
that Christopher Lambert would love to be in.
My favorite gag in the whole movie is during
this part where we see Blackout riding in the
ambulance and he's looking for something to
eat. But everything he touches decays in his
grasp. until he grabs the Twinkie, which just
stays static. And he's like, oh, okay, pops
it in his mouth. I thought that was hilarious.
Yeah. That was funny, but it left me with questions.
He was pulling things out of the lunchbox. They
were decaying. How was he driving the ambulance?
That's a great question. You would think that
like how the sword started rusting that he
touched later on, that anything metal that he
was touching like the car would also rust or
fall apart. It's a great question. Back to the
story, Muro tells Johnny about the history
of the demon Zerathos, how it was an angel of
justice before being tortured in hell and corrupted
into the spirit of vengeance and then bonded
to Johnny as the ghostwriter. After confessing
that his deal with the devil was made out of
selfishness, Johnny goes into a chamber and
exorcises the demon. It was an interesting scene
when Ghostwriter was getting exorcised, like
it was a weird acting moment I think when Nicolas
Cage was like, Merry Christmas assholes or
something like that. It's so bizarre. Right?
Such a Nick Cage moment, for sure. Meanwhile,
Methodius attempts to kill Dany, believing that
the boy is a threat as long as he exists. He
and the monks are killed by Blackout, however,
who kidnaps Dany and delivers him to Rourke,
who plans to transfer his mind and power into
the child in a ritual. Johnny, Mereau, and
Nadia infiltrate the ritual location to rescue
Dany. Kerrigan kills Mereau, but Dany returns
the demon, Zerathos, to Johnny. giving him back
the power of the Ghost Rider. Ghost Rider kills
the Devil Worshippers in attendance, then pursues
Rourke, who had escaped the ritual with Dany.
Between when Johnny didn't have the demon and
when he did, he was being held down by Garragon,
who was rubbing his hands all over Johnny and
touching him, and you'd see the decay, but
then it would instantly heal. Yeah. Why? That
has no logical sense to it. No, it's definitely
an error in special effects continuity where
we clearly see Johnny Blaze's forehead start
to decay and then in the very next shot, it's
entirely gone. I do think that this is an editing
issue. I think they took too long with Blackout
holding Johnny Blaze and didn't get to the
whole getting the power back quick enough. My
favorite shot in the whole movie though is
that above shot down on Ghost Rider as he's
surrounded by the devil worshipers and then
he turns into and he spins his chain around,
just freaking annihilating all of them. I love
that shot. That was a cool shot. Legend of Zelda
style. Mm hmm. I kind of liked it and how like
you weren't quite sure in that moment if he
was going to fully be Ghost Rider until he
whips out that chain. It's like surprise, bitches.
Then they're all dead. Yeah. In a really cool
chase scene, Ghost Rider destroys Rourke's convoy
and fights Blackout, who eventually succumbs
to Ghost Rider's penance there after causing
Rourke's vehicle to crash. Ghost Rider sends
him back to hell by slamming him through the
ground. Though Danny is believed to be dead,
Johnny is able to summon the power of Zerathos'
former angel powers to revive him. The film
ends with Ghost Rider wielding blue fire. Riding
into the sunset. I thought it was a great chase
scene towards the interior. It was cool to see
him take over one of the military vehicles
and turn it into like a hell jeep. Yeah. Again,
I think that the penistare took too long to
work on Blackout. At that point, it almost felt
like a kind of a not a Deus Ex Machina. but
kind of like this cheap move where you always
knew that Ghost Rider had it in his back pocket,
the ability to do the pendant stare. So you
wonder why he didn't like do it sooner or why
doesn't he do it more often, I guess, against
these guys. It's almost like Ghost Rider knew
he was saving the pendant stare for the climax
in his fight against Blackout, which is, feels
a little, yeah, cheap. I agree. I thought this
chase scene was really cool at the end. I loved
just being able to see everything because it
took place during the day. As cool as Ghost
Rider looks at night, I thought he looked equally
as cool during the day with like all the black
smoke and stuff like that. That was it was awesome
to see. You showed me the trailer for this
movie before I watched it, Joseph. I was surprised
at how much of like the final chase scene sequence
in battle ended up in the trailer. Yeah, definitely
the final ripping out of the axle and causing
Rourke's vehicle to crash. That was kind of
like his coup de grace, you know, other than
slamming work through the ground. And actually,
you know what? Slamming Gork through the ground
was also in the trailer. So it was, yeah, the
whole final blow was entirely in the marketing
for this film. Although I guess you wouldn't
know that unless you had seen the movie. So
was the flame therapy in this, by the way, that
was also one of the trailers. That's right.
That's so awesome. I was going to say stupid,
but then I switched it to awesome because I
think that's a better description. I do kind
of love how the last line, you know, like at
the end of Punisher Warzone, the last line was
like, oh, great. Now I got. brain splattered
all over me, which is just like, it's so ridiculous,
but it's amusing in how devil may care. It
is to use a pun. The last line for this movie
was just as good where they're like, did we
win? And he's like, I'm gonna say yes. Hell
yes. And like the camera zooms in on his face
and everything like that. So good. His eyes
like bulged out of his head. Yeah. Jonathan,
I take it you didn't like that. I fucking rolled
my eyes so fucking hard. No one cares about
your opinion. That was awesome. Apparently.
But that's the end of the film. Overall, you
know, the film is such a mixed bag. There are
aspects to Ghost Rider Spirit of Vengeance
that I have a lot of fun with that I think are
really well done for the character of Ghost
Rider. There are also some pretty objectively
bad parts about the film. Nicolas Cage's performance
being one of them. Even though I do think he
had fun, I do think he could have made some
better choices for a better film. So. The film
revs and stalls, swerving between gritty and
silly, with scorching action, but a cliched
story, with fiery performances, but burned
out dialogue. I'm giving the film 3 stars out
of 5, which is a 60%, but I'm classifying it
as a rotten rating for Rotten Tomatoes. Because
at the end of the day, I don't think I would
actually recommend it to a whole lot of people
unless they were big time Ghost Rider fans.
Yeah, I think a rotten rating makes sense because
it's right on the cusp of 60%. So you could
go either way. And I do agree that there was
a lot to like about it. There was also a lot
to dislike about it. The biggest thing I disliked,
as I mentioned earlier, was Nicolas Cage's
performance. I think he kind of hurt the film
in a way, which is hard to say because I know
how cherished Nicolas Cage is as an actor. But
sometimes it just came off as almost borderline
cartoony. and just bizarre as I mentioned earlier.
Ultimately, my thoughts on the film come down
to how much I respect David Goyer as a writer
versus Nicolas Cage as an actor. And I really
find it hard to believe that David Goyer, as
often as he can sometimes drop the ball, would
write lines like, hell yes. You know? So I put
a lot of that on Nicolas Cage. Earlier on,
I did say that I loved this movie and then going
back to it, I hadn't watched it in a long time
and a lot of it doesn't feel like it. did when
I watched it 11 years ago. And I mean, that's
easy to say. Anybody can forget how something
feels after 11 years. You can totally lose
track of things and how they felt or how they
were. And just in your memory, you know, things
change over time. Seeing Nicolas Cage deliver
lines that felt like he didn't write them.
And then in the next scene, there was a bunch
of lines that felt like he wrote them and then
back and then forth. That took me out of it
a lot. The animation sequences also kind of
took me out of it. I had never realized until
you mentioned it actually that this was a requel.
I understand, but I also see no purpose to it.
It could have been a much better movie if they
just continued the continuity and had more of
the same actors or more of that original story
being followed through with. I can't justifiably
even give this better than a 2.5 because of
how much it was let down compared to what I
remembered. So I'm going to go 2.5. Yeah, sometimes
nostalgia could get the better of you. I can
totally see. how the film could be two and
a half stars as well as three. But John, thank
you so much for joining us for this review.
We're really glad to have you as a guest and
hopefully I can return as a guest on your show,
Mad Trivia Podcast. I know that Jonathan will
be recording here shortly doing a guest spot
for your show talking about his favorite movies.
So that'll be a lot of fun to listen to. Listeners,
if you wanna hear what my five favorite movies
are and then see me get pretty embarrassing
with the mad libs, definitely go check out John's
show. It's a blast. So thanks again, John.
and talk to you later. Later. But that does
it for this review. Let us know what you guys
thought about the movie by writing to us at
dynamicduelpodcast.gmail.com or by visiting
us on Instagram or X. You can find links to
all of our accounts by checking out our show
notes or visiting our website at dynamicduel.com.
And on our site, you can also find a link to
our Patreon page where you can join our dynamic
duo tier and chat with us and fellow listeners,
our fantastic four tier, which gets you bonus
content each month. our ex force tier that
makes you an executive producer of this podcast,
or our newest tier that lets you join our dynamike
podcast network. If you can't join Patreon,
you can still support the show by signing up
for our e-newsletter also at dynamicduel.com
so you never miss an episode. You can also
rate the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser,
or on our website. Our next episode is a big
one, guys. It comes out Halloween Day. And it's
going to close out Spooktober with one of the
biggest surprises that this show has ever provided
to our listeners. Should we give them a hint,
Jonathan, as to what the next episode is going
to be? Fuck no! All right. He said it. I guess
we're saving the surprise for when you guys
see the next episode drop. So look forward
to that. But that does it for this episode.
We want to give a big thanks to our executive
producers, Ken Johnson, John Sturowski, Zachary
Hepburn, Dustin Belcombe. Miggi Matangian,
Brandon Estergaard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yeaton,
Nick Abonto, Austin Wazilowski, AJ Dunkerley,
Scott Camacho, Adam Spies, and Andrew Schunk
for helping make this podcast possible and
we'll talk to you guys next week. Up up and
away, true believers. You will tell me or I
will eat your stinking soul.