This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
Welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, the weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin brother Marvelous
Joe. And for this episode, we will be reviewing
the latest direct-to-video DC animated film,
Watchmen Chapter 1. Who watches The Watchmen?
This guy. And this guy, and he also regrets
it. But we'll talk about that later. Before
that, we're going to break down the comic book
movie news from the past week, of which there
was just one major news item, and that was the
official trailer number two for Craven the
Hunter. A movie I also will regret watching,
I'm pretty sure. Same here. As always guys,
we list our segment times in our episode description,
so feel free to check out the show notes if
you want to skip ahead to a particular topic.
Guys our artificially intelligent duel simulator
AJ9K has a quick message for our listeners,
so listen up. Why hello there, do you want
even more from this podcast? Then become a part
of the dynamic duel community on Patreon, where
you can choose from three tiers. The dynamic
2-0 tier gives you access to our Discord chat
server. The fantastic 4 tier gives you two bonus
episodes each month. And the X-Force tier makes
you an executive producer of this show. Lastly,
The Diner Mike podcast network tier lets you
create your own podcast using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and consultation,
and get you simulation results. Pitch the twins
your ideas via email at dynamicduelpodcast at
gmail.com. Check it out at patreon.com slash
dynamicduel. Pip pip cheerio. Thanks AJ9K, and
thanks to everyone who supports the podcast.
Be sure to tune into the other shows on the
DynaMic Podcast Network this week, including
Max Destruction, which pits your favorite action
heroes from film and television against each
other. This week, hosts Scotty and Gilly are
reviewing Double Dragon. And on the Send Your
World podcast, host Zachary Hepburn speculates
on fights between fan favorite anime and manga
characters. This Thursday, Zach's finding out
who would win between Tatsumi Oga and Baby
Beel from and Kiyotaka Mine. On the Console
Combat Podcast, hosts John and Dean find out
who would win in fights between popular video
game characters, and in yesterday's episode,
they determined who would win between Virgil
from Devil May Cry and Raiden from Metal Gear.
Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link
in our show notes to listen to all of the shows
in the DynaMic Podcast Network. We want to
give a quick shout out to Zachary Hepburn,
who is the host of Senjou World. It was his
birthday this past week. So happy birthday
man. If I could get you any gift from Marvel,
it would be silver samurai's armor. Cause I
think I got you the Muramasa blade last year
for your birthday. So I'm gonna go silver samurai's
armor this year. The adamantium suit from the
Wolverine movie. That was pretty bad ass. Well,
I'm gonna have to get you the soul taker sword
to go with that. I think you already gave him
that. Fuck. Ha ha ha. But also happy birthday
to Josh, another one of our patrons. If I were
to give you a gift from Marvel, it would be
Wolverine's adamantium claws, because I know
you like Wolverine. Like, I probably wouldn't
give you the whole skeleton, because that just
seems like it'd be a pain in the ass. So we'll
just go with the claws. Okay, but you're not
going to give him the healing factor as well.
So he's just going to stab his hands all the
time. You know what? I'm going to give you Deathstroke's
healing factor. You're welcome. Deathstroke
barely has a healing factor. So that's a horrible
gift. He's from Marvel. It's fine. And we have
one more birthday wish to give to John Storosky,
the host of the console combat podcast, which
we forgot to do last month when it was his birthday.
So happy birthday, man. If I could get you
anything from Marvel, it would be the war machine
armor, because that's one of the new weapons
being unveiled in the Fortnite season. And being
a gamer like yourself, it's just cool. I think
you'd like it. And I would get you a red lantern
ring, because while you claim to be on the
fence between Marvel and DC, we all know your
team red, bro. So happy birthday to all you
guys, Zach, Josh, and John, but with that out
of the way, quick to the No Prize! A No Prize
is an award Marvel used to give out to fans.
Our version, the Dynamic Duel No Prize, is
a digital award we post on Instagram for the
person that we feel gave the best answer to
our question of the week. Last week we asked
you guys, which upcoming Marvel Studios film
or show are you most looking forward to and
why? And this is coming off of all of the leaked
trailers that were presented during the D23
event for Disney investors a couple of weeks
ago. We got two whole answers, so let's go ahead
and run down the honorable mention and the
no prize winner. Our honorable mention goes
to Kat Stevenson, who said, Hi guys, it's Kat
Stevenson again, and the one that I am most
excited for is Ironheart. Ironheart, I feel,
is going to be a lot about taking over from
Tony Stark's legacy. especially leading up
to Secret Wars and Doomsday with Robert Downey
Jr. coming back. I can't wait to see what they
do with Ironheart to help build her and build
herself off of the Iron Man legacy. Thank you
guys. Have a good day. Yeah, I wasn't too excited
for Ironheart myself. Just coming off of my
reception to Dominique Thorne's performance
as Reeve Williams in Wakanda Forever, I wasn't
a fan of it. But when I saw the leaked trailer
for Ironheart and the app- approach that they
were taking to the story where it was almost
like a set it off type plot where she starts
stealing money to help fund her research and
development of the new armor. I thought it
was a pretty interesting angle and the hood
looks really cool as well. So I can see why
people are looking forward to this now because
I am. Yeah, I'm not quite sure it's going to
delve into her kind of taking up Tony Stark's
legacy. I didn't get that from the trailer.
That's what I thought the show was going to
be about. But like you, the trailer did definitely
get me intrigued for the project. Great answer,
Kat, but the winner of this week's no prize
is Lizzie Dyer Arnie, who said, Hey, it's Lizzie.
So it's been six years since season three of
Daredevil. No question. That's the one I'm most
looking forward to. Six years. That's a really
long time ago. I think we're way overdue and
I cannot wait for season four. Season 3 of
the Daredevil Netflix series is among the best
projects that Marvel television has ever produced.
And now that the show is under the Marvel Studios
umbrella, and it's apparently not a reboot,
more like a Season 4 of that show, it just looks
incredible. The leaked trailer for Daredevil
Born Again was probably my favorite trailer
to come out of this year's D23. And with all
the returning characters and all the new characters
that they'll be introducing, like White Tiger
and Muse, it looks like it's going to be phenomenal.
especially as the Daredevil franchise begins
folding itself into the greater Marvel Cinematic
Universe. Yeah, we gave season 3 of Daredevil
a perfect rating because how could you not?
That season was incredible. I'm really looking
forward to see where they take that story. The
leaked footage was awesome. So yeah, it's really
easy to get pumped for Daredevil. So congrats
again to Lizzie Dyer Arnie for winning this
week's No Prize. If you the listener want a
shot at winning your own No Prize, stay tuned
to later on this episode when we'll be asking
another question of the week. And now that
that's done, on to the news!
Alright, this past week we got the official
trailer number two, although it's not being
called official trailer number two, for Craven
the Hunter. We got our first official trailer
almost a year ago for this movie, but it's been
delayed so many times now. It's coming out
this December, and so the time came for another
new trailer, and this one was pretty action-packed.
Of course, this is part of the Sony Spider-Man
universe, along with Madame Web and the upcoming
Venom The Last Dance movie. It's crazy that
Sony's releasing three Spider-Man related movies
this year because the whole point of making
and releasing these films for that company
is to retain the rights to the Spider-Man character.
And to that end, you would probably want to
stagger these out over the years so that you
retain the rights that much longer. But I feel
like Sony is going to lose a lot of money this
year on the Spider-Man franchise and hopefully
that's a good thing. Like, hopefully, the rights
end up reverting back to Marvel due to the
epic disaster that this film will probably be.
Because I wasn't impressed with this trailer
too much. Despite the action, there was very
little inclination of what the movie is actually
going to be about. Yeah, it feels like they're
really trying to oversell me on the violence.
It's like, OK, like you do some pretty crazy
stuff, like trap a guy's head in a bear trap
and like split a guy in half with a tree trunk
and some ropes and stuff like that, which is
pretty wild. But I don't know, like violence
isn't going to sell me on a movie. I want to
know what the story is. I want to know what
the stakes are. Things like that to me. This
is like Aaron Taylor Johnson just doing a bunch
of violence and then posing like a GQ model.
You know, this is GQ Craven. And I'm like, why?
I mean, the last trailer that we got kind of
gave us a hint at the background of the character,
right? We know that he comes from a family
of hunters, that he was bitten by a radioactive
lion or some shit. And so he got super strength
and speed and stuff like that. But we don't
know exactly who the bad guy is, what their
aims are. and we didn't get any more information
about that for this trailer. We know that one
of the bad guys is going to be the Rhino. And
I will say that the Rhino looks pretty cool.
It looks like the actor who plays Alexei Sistovich
is going to be injecting himself with some
kind of like Rhino serum, I guess. And it transforms
him into this Rhino looking dude. And the character
design is pretty good, but it's strange because
the Rhino is not typically a Kraven villain,
you know? Though I think it makes sense for
him. For sure. Yeah, I'll give you that. We
know that Craven's brother, Dmitri Smirdyakov,
is also in this movie, who is known as the
chameleon in the comic books. And while they
typically work together in the books, I'm wondering
if maybe his brother is the main antagonist
in this film, especially the lines that he
has in this trailer where he's like, you're
just after another trophy or something like
that, you know? Oh yeah, setting up like a sibling
rivalry. That would make sense. Yeah. Maybe
they'll give him like radioactive chameleon
blood, you know, sort of like how the rhino
guy shooting radioactive rhino blood into him.
Yeah, he'll shoot himself with chameleon blood
and then be able to take on the appearance of
anyone. So stupid. I hope they don't do that,
but I also kind of hope they do because this
movie, I don't think deserves to do well just
by virtue of the fact that one, it doesn't look
good and two, it's made by Sony. And I think
the sooner that Marvel gets the rights back,
the sooner that will stop getting crappy movies
like Madame Web and most likely this movie.
Now, to be fair, a lot of the reason you're
trashing this is because of Sony's reputation
but what if the movie is good? If the movie
is good I'll eat my words. If I enjoy it, sure.
I mean I did that with the first Venom movie
which I enjoyed. I hated Let There Be Carnage.
Did not enjoy that one at all. But you know
if this ends up being more like the first Venom
movie and actually brings something new to
the table in the way that film did, then yeah.
But as of right now, judging off of this trailer
and everything else I've seen for the movie,
I'm ambivalent about it. And since I'm not
too excited for this, I don't think that the
question of the week this episode will tie
into the Craven trailer. And instead, we're
gonna kind of riff on our previous question
of the week with this new question.
Which upcoming DC Studios film or show are you
most looking forward to and why? Record your
answer at dynamicduel.com by clicking on the
red microphone button in the bottom right hand
corner of the screen, which will prompt you
to leave us a voicemail. Your message could
be up to 30 seconds long, and don't forget to
leave your name in case we include you on the
podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer, and
award that person a Dynamic Duel No Prize that
we'll post to Instagram. Be sure to answer before
August 24th.
That's all of the news this week, so now let's
move on to the main event of this episode,
in which we review DC's latest direct-to-video
animated film, Watchmen Chapter 1.
Alright, Watchmen Chapter 1 is the first of
a two-part computer-animated adaptation of
the seminal 1986 comic series by writer Alan
Moore and artist Dave Gibbons. It cannot be
overstated how much of an impact Watchmen had
on the comic book medium and superhero genre.
Recent works like The Boys, Kick-Ass, Invincible,
and even to an extent DC's Snyderverse, with
their attempts at deconstructing flawed, morally
ambiguous, and psychologically complex superheroes
owe a considerable amount to The Watchmen Story,
which was the first mainstream superhero comic
intended for mature audiences and to successfully
achieve literary success with accolades such
as the Hugo Award, the Kirby Award, the Eisner
Award, and was the only comic work listed on
Time Magazine's list of the 100 best novels
of all time. It is in arguably the most celebrated
comic book ever made and it continues to be
one of the best selling graphic novels year
after year, which is probably why Warner Bros
continues to adapt it to other mediums. It
is a fool's errand because Watchmen is the best
example I could think of a story tailor-made
for the comic medium in the way it was expertly
paced and creatively laid out on the pages.
Though I will also admit that I've enjoyed basically
every adaptation of the story, most notably
Zack Snyder's 2009 live-action film, which we've
reviewed on this podcast. Snyder's film was
mostly faithful to the source material, even
recreating some comic panels in the framing
of certain scenes, but it also took some liberties
with the story, which I honestly didn't mind.
The mediums of comics and film are very similar
in that they're both comprised of pictures,
And it's not like I wanted the live action film
to replace anyone's need to read the graphic
novel, which I will say everyone does need to
do. Now while I was excited for this animated
film adaptation, my biggest fear was that it
would be too faithful to the source material,
to the degree that people would not need to
read the book. And as I watched Watchmen Chapter
1, I admittedly found it really hard. to enjoy
because it is indeed the most faithful adaptation
of the source material outside of the motion
comic which essentially was just an audiobook.
Now, reviewing Watchmen Chapter 1 is in essence
like reviewing an abridged version of the first
issues of the comic series. So if you haven't
read the comic and haven't seen this animated
film, just know that doing one will spoil the
other and will essentially be spoiling both
in this spoiler review. Yeah, Watchmen Chapter
One is faithful to a fault. And I think a lot
of people would come at me for saying that because,
you know, it's every fanboy's dream to essentially
see direct translations from the source material
to the movie medium. And that's valid. I think
if Zack Snyder's 2009 live action film didn't
exist, this review would be an entirely different
thing, right? Because it would be cool to actually
see these characters move in three dimensional
space and hear their voices and stuff like that.
But... because it's coming off of the back
of Zack Snyder's movie, which arguably did a
superior version of adapting the story to the
screen. This feels uber redundant, as I mentioned
in our discussion of the trailers for this
movie. Yeah, absolutely. It's like Marvel doing
an animated version of the first Avengers film.
It's like, why? The first Avengers film is already
a thing. Right, exactly. I will absolutely
give credit where credit is due. You from the
first trailer said that this looked like it
would be redundant and I didn't want to hear
it You told me that I was butt hurt and that
you were gonna get me a hemorrhoid pillow and
cream for when I watched this movie And yeah
got butt hurt about it And you know what? I
wish I had that pillow and that cream because
I was butt hurt when I was watching this movie
because it just felt So fucking pointless.
I was like, why am I doing this? I know this
story. I've read it so many times I mean, yeah,
sign me up for that pillow and cream because,
you know, same, right? At the time, I didn't
want to hear it because I argued that this animated
adaptation and the graphic novel could coexist
in much the same way that the book and live
action version do. But I'm not going to say
that they should have never made this animated
adaptation because the story is still really
good and still really relevant. And while I'll
always recommend the book because it has several
more layers of depth and artistry, What I don't
want to do is be a book snob to someone who
only has time to watch the film because it's
one way to appreciate the story, a slightly
inferior one. That's going to be the case for
99.9% of book to screen adaptations anyway.
Now, I reread Watchmen like every other year.
I own several copies of the book and when I
hand them out to someone to read, I often find
myself reading it alongside with them. And
just about every time I do... I notice something
that I overlooked before or I find a new appreciation
for how consistently relevant the book remains
across the decades. I enjoy rereading the book
so I thought I would enjoy watching this film
but like you mentioned watching this film I
couldn't help but think man I already know the
story this is a waste of time. Watchmen as
an entire story does have this sixth sense-esque
killer twist that I won't spoil here. And while
it's fun to spot all of the foreshadowing upon
revisiting the story, that really didn't save
the somewhat disappointing experience I had
in watching this film. Because Watchmen Chapter
1 was so faithful, there's nothing really to
scrutinize other than the animation and voice
performances, which I mean, neither were bad
enough for scolding criticisms or profound
enough to warrant too much commentary. The animation
was fine. I've seen people compare it to Marvel
Television's animated What If series, and it's
not as good, I will admit, but barely. The
characters are a little bit more robotic in
their movements, and the textures are a little
bit more cheap, but the line work they incorporated
made it more reminiscent of artist Dave Gibbon's
comic artwork, and there are brief scenes where
the lighting almost makes the animation look
live action. It doesn't look as good as Zack
Snyder's film. but I can see how some Watchmen
fans would actually prefer the colorful, cartoony
look for the story, since Watchmen itself is
something of a satire of the superhero genre.
And one of the criticisms of Snyder's adaptation
is that its dark and grim aesthetic resulted
in a film that took itself too seriously. Though
personally, I would argue that's a good thing.
Yeah, I was one of the people that compared
the look of this movie to the What If Disney
Plus animated series, and you're right, it's
not as good. The What If show is very fluid
in its characters' motions and facial expressions
and stuff like that. Here, everything was very
robotic and stiff to the point that it almost
felt like a video game cutscene extended over
a feature length runtime. I could see that.
You know, I'm not surprised, though, because
you're going up against Disney animators who
are literally at the top of their game in the
industry. It's so you admit that Marvel is
better than DC. I do not recall saying any such
words. It's essentially what you just said.
I just said Disney animators are better than
basically any other animation, except for maybe
like Studio Ghibli. OK, all right. Yeah. So
Marvel's better than DC. Oh, my gosh. OK. But
animation aside, I do want to talk more about
the voice cast in our character breakdown.
Just overall though, it wasn't bad and it was
a lot closer to how I read the lines than what
the actors did in the live-action adaptation.
Though that doesn't necessarily mean the voice
actors for the animated film did a better job
than the actors. Actually if I had a choice
between recommending Snyder's live-action film
or this animated version. right now I'd say
go with Snyder's version, though that may change
after seeing Chapter 2. And if I thought they
also planned on watching the HBO sequel series,
because that ignores creative liberties Snyder's
film took with the story. If they're watching
the HBO series, definitely go with this animated
version. Now regarding the story, this film,
like Snyder's version, took some liberties,
but they impacted the story fairly minimally.
Like most of the changes involved rearranging
flashback scenes throughout the film that normally
happened during the comedian's funeral, you
know, soon after various characters learned
of his death. And I didn't mind that, you know,
I didn't mind them cutting certain lines. Like
I said, it's an abridged version of the novel.
And despite that, the filmmakers, namely the
screenwriter J. Michael Straczynski, who's
a comic book writer, managed to successfully
translate the genius that is writer Alan Moore,
who uses this technique in his writing where
dialogue or narration from one scene is overlaid
onto a different concurrent scene, creating
this cross-contextual resonance. The text is
not only relevant to the scene it originates
from, but also adds layers of meaning to the
scene. overlays and this interplay between dialogue
and visuals deepens the story's thematic impact
and draws these connections between scenes that
otherwise would not exist. You know, for example,
a government agent could be debriefing Dr. Manhattan
about what can and can't be mentioned during
an interview, warning him not to get into any
tight corners. But that voiceover is played
over Dan and Laurie walking into a narrow alley
as they're being pursued by a gang of not tops.
It adds this complexity to the narrative in
that it encourages readers or viewers to engage
with the words on multiple levels simultaneously.
There's a few, very few comic writers who can
do that technique effectively, but Alan Moore
is the absolute master of it. Now, the biggest
problem I had with Watchmen Chapter One's story
is that it's only half of a story. And what
could be considered the climax of the film,
the standoff between Rorschach and the police,
wasn't expanded upon or drawn out in any kind
of climactic way. So the film ends on this
anticlimactic cliffhanger that's pretty unsatisfying
and completely unnecessary, considering the
film is about five minutes shy of a standard
90 minute runtime. Like, you couldn't give
me five more minutes of action. Everyone knows
who listens to this podcast that I don't mind
long runtimes. Zack Snyder's Justice League
is four hours. The Batman is about three hours.
Our past two episodes have been reviews of five
hour long television series that I binged and
I've come to the realization that if you really
wanted to do an animated Watchmen adaptation
justice at the bare minimum, you should just
make each comic issue a 20 minute long episode
of a 12 episode television series. That would
be perfect. And you know, the things that the
film and television mediums have over comic
books is action and movement. Right. And if
they could have drawn out some of those fight
sequences, some of those climactic battles
where we have Ozzy Medeus going up against the
assassin and you have Rorschach going up against
the police and stuff like that, they could have
drawn those out longer. And they had the opportunity
to do that, not just to extend the runtime,
but provide a more cinematic experience for
the viewer. Exactly. Yeah. Cinematic. I could
not have said that better myself. Now, anyone
who's listened to this podcast for a while has
also heard me say a thousand times that one
of the reasons DC Comics is better than Marvel
is because DC's characters are pure archetypes
and symbols of virtue, these true heroes unburdened
by character flaws. Now when I say that, I'm
100% not talking about Watchmen. Watchmen was
Alan Moore's way of criticizing DC superheroes
by showing us a world of unconventional superheroes
that are these insecure or immoral or nihilistic
humans. whose motivations for vigilantism would
not and should not be trusted or accepted by
the public. In that case, you can kind of say
that the Watchmen story is DC's most Marvel
tale. Yeah, but only if Marvel was like good,
you know, it's like DC could do Marvel better
than Marvel could do Marvel. No, they can't
shut up. But let's get more into these flawed
characters in our character breakdown, starting
with Rorschach. Now Rorschach was voiced by
Titus Welliver, the star of the Amazon series
Bosh, and who you may also recognize from shows
like The Good Wife or Deadwood or films like
Argo. I know the guy's face, but I didn't know
his name or his voice, apparently. I felt like
he was doing an impression of the Rorschach
actor from the live action film Jackie Earl
Haley. And though Haley did it better, I wouldn't
say Titus Welliver did a bad job by any means.
There was nothing like new or unique or superior.
to his performance over what we got in the Zack
Snyder film. If you had told me that Jackie
Earl Haley actually did the voice for the character
again, I totally would have believed you. I
wish that they would have tried a different
approach. Like maybe go for like a very monotone
serial killer spooky type voice, you know. But
yeah, what does that sound like? Kind of like
your voice, but fuck you.
I guess a good reference for that would be Michael
C. Hall's performance in the Dexter television
show. He did a lot of narration across all of
those episodes and just his cold voice, I thought,
could have provided a good template for this
version of Rorschach. Interesting. I think
you're going to go more along the lines of something
like Buffalo Bill and be like, put the lotion
in the basket. Never compromise. Never in the
face of a barbeque. That's weird. No, I just,
I mean, to me, he kind of sounded like. Gravely,
Batman, and I think they could have done something
unique just to help separate this from Zack
Snyder's film and draw fewer comparisons. Yeah,
that would have been great if they would have
tried something new. Again, though, I didn't
mind this. Now the first half of The Watchman's
story, Rorschach is the only active street
vigilante driven by his uncompromising black
and white moral philosophy to punish those
who have done wrong and evil. When investigating
the murder of Edward Blake. Rorschach learns
that he was the comedian, a former vigilante
turned government agent in middle age. His
arc involves a descent into obsession and conspiracy
as he arrives at the possibility that someone
is killing former costumed heroes, and his obsession
shows just how much he's willing to alienate
his remaining relationships and hurt anyone
in pursuit of justice. Yeah, it's really hard
to add commentary to the character of Rorschach
as a character in this film that hasn't already
been said about. The comic book character. I
liked the movement of Rorschach's mask in this
movie, though. You mean more than the live action
version? No, no, of course not. No. OK. No,
no, no. Yeah, the whole concept of Rorschach's
mask, how it is constantly shifting. I always
thought has been a really cool one. Like, there's
no other costumed mask character in the comics
that's like that. Moving on to Dan Dreiberg,
aka Night Owl 2. He was voiced by Matthew Riz.
He's not a big name. I'm not too familiar with
his other work, but I also kind of felt like
his performance was somewhat inspired by Patrick
Wilson's take on the character in live action.
Yeah, if I was the director of this animated
film, I would have told the actors to not watch
at all the Zack Snyder film if they haven't
already, but it looks like what these guys
did is went and watched Zack Snyder's film and
then just tried to do that exactly. I mean,
everyone's seen Zack Snyder's film. It's a great
movie! Well, they should have tried to erase
it from their brains and come up with a new
approach. Do you think Matthew Riz did a better
job than Patrick Wilson? Because I actually
do. Really? What? No, I don't at all. I loved
Patrick Wilson's take on Night Owl. Well, I
mean, who doesn't? Everyone does. But regarding
his arc, you know, Dan starts out as a retired
superhero struggling with a sense of purposelessness
in a world that no longer values masked vigilantes,
you know, living a quiet, lonely life. that
changes when Rorschach warns him of his conspiracy
that someone is targeting former masked heroes.
Dan's interactions with Laurie Uspechek betray
his insecurity, which seemingly contrasts with
his former superhero persona. As Dan reconnects
with Laurie, he begins to reconnect with his
old identity, grappling with the harsh realities
of the world around him. Now his arc is one
of... tentative reawakening as he slowly reclaims
his role as Night Owl and grows closer with
Laurie. It's essentially the story of how Night
Owl got his groove back. It's a good way to
put it. But speaking of Laurie, aka Silk Spectre
II, she was voiced by Katie Sackoff from Battlestar
Galactica fame, who I thought did a much better
job with the character than Malon Ackerman
did. Yeah Malon Ackerman was the weak link of
the live action version, but she looked the
part. the movie. I agree. I really liked Katie
Sikoff's performance here. It felt different
from Mal and Ackerman's in a way that the previous
two characters did not. Right, yeah, I agree.
Now, Laurie is a retired superhero and initially
the romantic partner of Dr. Manhattan, who
grapples with her identity and the legacy of
her mother, the original Silk Spectre. Living
with Dr. Manhattan, Laurie feels increasingly
isolated and disillusioned with her life as
a former superhero and current pacifying companion
you could say to Dr. Manhattan. As Dr. Manhattan
grows more and more detached from humanity,
however, Laurie rekindles a friendship with
Dent Dryberg, whose loneliness and diminished
glory as a superhero allow her to easily relate
to him. When she eventually leaves Dr. Manhattan,
she starts to reclaim her own identity, one
independent from the roles her mother and the
government imposed on her. and one that she
knowingly or unknowingly uses to manipulate
Dan. Laurie's character was always a bit of
a mystery to me in the original story because
it really didn't make sense for her, I think,
to redawn the Silk Spectre identity considering
her stance on it and her mother and superheroism
in general. It's like she largely did it just
to bring Ny'al out of his shell. Yeah, but
I guess I don't see why she did it herself.
I was under the impression that was largely
it. Like they were off to go rescue Rorschach
and she was going to do it as a superhero.
She kind of found her own way to that lifestyle
without, you know, badgering from her mom or
anything like that. But is that a lifestyle
that as a character she would even want to
go to? That I don't think rung true from the
original story. I think she found excitement
in it. And I think the alleyway scene where
she's beating up the gangsters was proof of
that for both her and Dan. They both kind of
got hot and bothered by that. So her angle
into Super Hero X was merely just thrill seeking.
100%, yes. So then why wasn't she satisfied
as a hero prior to that? Because she felt like
she was only doing it because her mom wanted
her to. What effect did that have on the thrill
seeking aspect? Well, who knows how much thrill
seeking she actually got from it considering
she was going to be on the same team as Dr.
Manhattan. I always kind of saw her more as
like a model than a superhero and the same
goes for the first Silk Spectre. I don't know
how much crime fighting they actually got involved
with because it didn't show that in the original
comic. Now, May in the expanded Watchmen universe,
I haven't read all of those comics, but maybe
the answer is found in there. Maybe. Moving
on to Jonathan Osterman, aka Dr. Manhattan.
He was voiced by Michael Cerveris. I'll be
honest, I'm not familiar with his work. Apparently
he played Professor Pig in the Gotham television
series though. Interesting. I did not like his
performance at all. His was the one performance
where I could say was not as good or better
than what we got in live action. Well, not
even as a comparison to Billy Crudup's because
obviously Crudup's performance in Zack Snyder's
film was exceptional. It was so brilliant. But
here, Dr. Manhattan sounded like... literally
an AI voice. Yeah. I guess I can understand
the approach, but I did not like the execution
at all. No, it was 100% inferior. Dr. Manhattan
is very detached from humanity, yes, but he's
not a robot, right? He's somewhere in between
is what I'm guessing. And really, I think Crudup
nailed it, that sort of human yet detached quality
to his voice. Absolutely. Not just his voice,
his whole performance in general, like his facial
expressions. The Dr. Manhattan in the comic
had way more emotive facial expressions than
they gave him in this animated film. I was
actually looking at the comic as I was watching
this film the first time I watched it. And
yeah, they stripped a lot of the emotion out
of Dr. Manhattan, which was really surprising
to me. Now from the get-go, Dr. Manhattan is
portrayed as this detached god-like figure
that struggles to relate to humanity. His transformation
into a being of nearly unlimited power made
him distant, viewing human life and emotions
with a cold, almost clinical perspective. As
he becomes more involved in geopolitical and
international matters, his growing disconnection
from humanity is made evident by his deteriorating
relationship with Laurie, who leaves him due
to his emotional absence. When he's accused
of causing cancer to people close to him throughout
his life, Dr. Manhattan retreats to Mars, distancing
himself from Earth. His arc is one of profound
alienation as he grapples with his loss of humanity
and the existential weight of his powers which
will ultimately set the stage for his change
of heart and renewed interest in human beings
later on in the story. Why do you think Dr.
Manhattan became detached with humanity? Why
does just the ability to perceive time in the
fourth dimension and an abundance of superpowers
make you act like a robot? Right? Like Superman
has a lot of powers. He doesn't act like a
robot. No, but I mean, Superman also experiences
time the same way we do. When you can see so
many things in the way that he sees them, things
become more trivial to you for the most part,
I would say. I don't necessarily think so. I
think if I could perceive my entire life nonlinearly,
I don't think that would strip me of my personality.
No, but when you get to see like the individuel
atomic makeup of people and you find that interesting
It's like he said there's no difference in
the number of atoms between a dead human and
a live human He doesn't really see them as
humans anymore He just sees them as these ghosts
shifting through time as he's able to see all
of time They don't really matter and things
don't really matter because it's all just atoms
moving I think even if I were able to see atoms,
I would still see people. I guess I never understood
the evolution of John Osterman as a character
into Dr. Manhattan. It was just something that
happened, and you had to kind of accept that's
who he was, but how he got from point A to
point B just by rebuilding himself, I'll never
quite understand. Okay, well think of it this
way. Do you care about the lives of ants? No,
not really. Do you care about what they care
about? But human beings would not be ants to
me because human beings act different than
ants to me. And yet if you were Dr. Manhattan,
they would all be ants to you. No, no, because
he's still carrying on conversations with us
and stuff like that. If we were really ants
to Dr. Manhattan, why would he bother communicating
with us? Why would he bother interacting with
us? Why would he bother having a girlfriend
and having these emotional attachments and
stuff? But it's not like the conversations he's
having are interesting to him. In fact, they
become less and less interesting as time goes
on. You were Ant-Man and you could talk with
ants. Who the fuck cares what an ant has to
say? It's a fucking ant. What? Fuck Ant Bro.
How would you know? You've never talked to one.
Oh, I know. Don't worry. All right. OK. There
you go. This conversation has gotten really
weird. I think we should move on. Oh, we've
already moved on. It's the future. That's how
you perceive time. We're already there. It's
all right. Moving on to Adrian Veit, AKA Ozymandias.
He was voiced by Troy Baker. who's a very versatile
and prolific voice actor for a lot of animated
work in video games as well. I thought he did
a great job for as little as he was in the movie.
I thought he did a better job with the character
than Matthew Goode did in the movie. I didn't
really love Matthew Goode's performance in
the live-action version. Well, yeah, Matthew
Goode kind of approached it with a German accent,
if I remember correctly, like slightly German
or something. Yes. I'm not sure if that was
the right call there, but I would say that in
this animated movie, Troy Baker approach the
character in a way that was more consistent
with how I read it in the original books. Yeah,
same for me. Although I do have to hand it to
the people who wrote Zack Snyder's Watchmen
movie. In many ways, I think they improved upon
Alan Moore's original dialogue with lines like
statistically, what murder doesn't constitute
a trend or something like that, which Ozymandias
told Rorschach the first time they met. Just
lines like that I thought were well done. Or
even lines where he was telling other businessmen
like I could buy and sell you 10 times over.
something like that, you know, just to like
actually show that this guy really is the richest
guy in the world. Now next to Dr. Manhattan,
Adrian is presented as the most capable man
in existence. He's the world's smartest man
and a former superhero who successfully transitioned
into a wealthy businessman. Outwardly, Adrian
appears to have left his vigilante days behind,
you know, focusing on his global enterprises
and philanthropic efforts. But there are hints
that he actually hasn't lost any of his touch
as a superhero, as evidenced by the foiled
assassination attempt. His public persona as
a benevolent billionaire genius is only a half-truth,
and his arc is one of subtle manipulation and
control, though we don't really comprehend
that until later in the story, since in this
first half, his true motivations and plans
are nonexistent. Yeah, I kind of forgot just
how few appearances the character of Ozymandias
actually makes within the first half of the
story, which kind of seems like a misdirection
on behalf of Alan Moore's part considering his
role in the second half of the story. You know,
we don't think too much about Ozymandias in
this first half. Yes, absolutely. And you know,
that was the case when I first read the comic
as well. I thought he was kind of the most
boring character. I didn't really quite understand
why he was even in the story or what purpose
he served. But yeah, he's very heavily involved
in the story as we find out in the second half.
You know who gave the best Azumandias performance
of all time? Who? Jeremy Irons. Oh yeah! Yeah,
that guy was great. That whole show was just
so good, I need to rewatch it. I think I will
actually after watching Watchmen Chapter 2 when
that comes out next year.
Our fantasies collide and heroes clash. One
Podcast Network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
DynaMic Podcast Network presents Console Combat,
where video game legends brawl every Monday.
Dynamic Duel, where comic- Smash every Tuesday,
Max Destruction, where TV and action heroes
battle every Wednesday, and Sendro World, where
anime champions clash every Thursday. Join
us as we speculate on the matches and, armed
with the power of mathematical simulations,
discover who will emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
Let's move on to the story highlights. A man
named Edward Blake is murdered by being thrown
out of the window of a high-rise apartment.
The superhero vigilante Rorschach illegally
investigates Blake's murder and discovers Blake
was the comedian, a former masked adventurer.
Concerned that Blake's murder could mean that
someone is targeting former superheroes, Rorschach
warns his old associates, beginning with Dan
Dreiberg, a former superhero known as Night
Owl. When Dan returns home from visiting his
mentor Hollis Mason, the original Night Owl,
he finds Rorschach, who broke in, and the two
discuss Rorschach's theory regarding a mask
killer, after which Dan remembers an incident
from the past when he and the comedian violently
confronted protesters against an ongoing police
strike at the time and the hero's vigilantism.
I gotta say, we didn't discuss the comedian
in the character breakdown, but I hated this
version of the comedian. Now... I know I've
been saying that I wish these voice actors
took a different approach from what was done
in Zack Snyder's film. And that's definitely
what the comedian actor did here. But it was
just so bad that I wish Jeffrey Dean Morgan
had come back to voice the character. Dude,
you are so inconsistent. You want to be the
same? Come on. I wanted Rorschach to be different,
but I wanted the comedian to be a little bit
more wry in his delivery, a little bit more
ironic. because that's kind of who the character
is, I think. Here he was just angry and one
note and frankly, boring. That's fair. Actually,
I mean, the comedian is a character who kind
of sees the tragic humor in everything. Right,
he's the ultimate cynic. Yeah. That's his whole
thing. That's very fair. Jeffrey Dean Morgan
is such a charming actor. He makes so many like
bad guys likable, you know, whether it's here,
whether it's in The Walking Dead, The Boys,
a lot of different places. So yeah, if you're
gonna play a character like the comedian who
should be played, you know, very human, I guess,
for lack of a better term. I don't want to say
sympathetic, but almost. He's not a caricature
like he was portrayed here. He's a piece of
shit, but he's not one note, you know? Yeah,
he's very, very complex as a character. Probably
the most complex character in Watchmen. So
many lives were affected by him in so many different
ways. Now after roughing up patrons at a bar
looking for answers, Rorschach visits Adrian
Veit, the former hero known as Ozymandias,
now the current head of Veit Industries as well
as the smartest and richest man in the world.
Upon learning what happened to Blake, Adrian
remembers a time when the comedian interrupted
a meeting held by Captain Metropolis and the
potential formation of a new super team because
he pointed out that nothing they did would be
able to stop the world's inevitable apocalyptic
descent into nuclear war. And Adrian's recollection
of the comedian is really the one that brings
out the nihilism of the Watchmen story and particularly
that of the comedian. I actually liked the
animated performance that Azumandias gave in
this scene. The way he would eyeball everyone
who talked to him, kind of like sizing them
up and just being very calculating. You really
got that vibe. Yeah, you know, in the comic,
the artist who did it, Dave Gibbons, he's a
master of like body language. So it's impressive
that they could expand upon that. in something
that moves. I thought they took really great
cues from what was going on in the story to
do things and add things like that. I kind of
wish Matthew Good would have done that in the
live action movie. Oh yeah, I agree. But instead
he kind of acted more like a diva when the
comedian was pissing him off during that meeting.
Yeah, again, there's a number of ways in which
this adaptation is better than the live action
version. And it's kind of interesting to compare
and contrast the two. Like I said, maybe by
the time the second chapter comes out, I'll
end up liking this adaptation more. We'll see.
After sneaking his way onto a military base,
Rorschach approaches Dr. Manhattan and Lori
Yospechik, the latter being the former hero
and model known as Silk Spectre II, who became
agitated upon hearing about the comedian since
he tried to rape her mother, the original Silk
Spectre, decades ago. After teleporting Rorschach
away to comfort Lori, she decides to arrange
dinner with Dan Dreiberg for old time's sake.
and the two bond over their glory days as heroes.
Alone with his scientific work, Dr. Manhattan
recalls his time with the comedian during the
Vietnam War, in which they helped America win
the war, and when upon their victory, Dr. Manhattan
failed to stop the comedian from killing a
young Vietnamese woman he had impregnated. And
it's interesting to see how time goes on from
when Dr. Manhattan first became superpowered
to the point where the story takes place. he
becomes more and more detached from humanity
over time. And that's evidenced by the fewer
clothes that he wears. Like when he's in Vietnam,
he's wearing more clothes than he does in the
present day. And he was wearing more clothes
than that when he first began his superhero
career and was even meeting with the Minutemen
to form potentially a new team. It's at Vietnam
where I think Dr. Manhattan begins to realize
how disconnected he's becoming from humanity
because the comedian was 100% right. He totally
let the comedian kill that woman. He could
have stopped him, but he didn't because he's
just kind of become this watcher type character
who's just watching time progress as opposed
to being physically a part of it. And that's
a huge red flag for the comedian. You know what
I miss in this movie though, were the music
choices from the Zack Snyder film. Nah, the
music choices and the soundtrack for Zack Snyder's
Watchmen are top notch. I freaking love that
soundtrack. It bothered a lot of people and
it bothered a lot of critics. because they thought
it was a little bit too on the nose. But I
actually really liked the way it invoked specific
time periods and themes, stuff like that. It
was really well done, in my opinion. Like, I
wanted to hear Simon Garfunkel's song during
the funeral scene, and I wanted to hear Flight
of the Valkyries during the Vietnam War scene
and stuff like that. It was just missed. Yeah,
same here. Now, during Blake's funeral, Lori
visits her elderly mother, Sally, who lives
retired in California. Upon discussing Blake's
death, Sally remembers when she and Blake, as
Silk Spectre and the Comedian, were both members
of the Minutemen superteam, along with other
heroes such as the First Night Owl and Hooded
Justice, the latter of whom we see halt Blake's
attempted rape of Sally. Dr. Manhattan, Dan
Dreiberg, and Adrian Veidt all attend Blake's
funeral, along with an old retired supervillain
known as Molech. Rorschach attacks Molech in
his home later that night, believing he may
be the mask killer. only to learn that not only
is Malik innocent and dying of cancer, but
that he was visited by a somber and drunken
comedian not long before his death, during
which time he gave an ominous yet incoherent
warning about a massive plot that somehow involved
Malik and Dr. Manhattan's old girlfriend, Janie
Slater. Now how cool is it seeing Hooded Justice
and perceiving him as a black cop wearing white
makeup around his eyes with the noose around
his neck that was once used to try to lynch
him. Now, I'm not sure how in continuity the
Watchmen HBO television series is. It's totally
my head cannon. It should be. It should be
because that was a fantastic origin for Hooded
Justice. And yeah, I 100% thought about that
during this scene with him. It kind of adds
another layer as to why Hooded Justice didn't
get more involved in punishing the comedian,
because the comedian kind of alluded to the
fact that he knew something about Hooded Justice,
a seeker of his, that he didn't want to get
out. So he was blackmailed, essentially. I think
the comedian knew that Hooded Justice was gay.
Well, yeah, maybe multiple things. Well, a young
boy at a newspaper stand reads a comic book
about a stranded pirate that's interwoven into
the main plot. Laurie becomes distressed upon
learning that Dr. Manhattan is working on his
scientific research simultaneously while they
make love, and she departs for Dan's home to
lament her relationship, and the two later
defend themselves from a gang attack. Meanwhile,
Dr. Manhattan goes on a talk show to discuss
international tensions and potential war, only
to be publicly confronted about a pattern of
cancer diagnoses among those from his past,
including Malik and Janie Slater, among others.
Agitated by the accusation that he's the cause,
Dr. Manhattan teleports the entire talk show
audience and crew away before grabbing an old
photo of himself and Janie at an abandoned
military base and teleporting to Mars to live
in seclusion. Now one thing that was missing
from Zack Snyder's adaptation was of course
the tales from the Black Freighter storyline
that was interwoven in the comic book. I completely
understand why that was omitted because it's
not really pivotal to the plot of Watchmen,
but it is fascinating to see how, like I mentioned
earlier, Alan Moore will use text from the comic
to relate to the scene that we're currently
viewing. Yeah, I don't think the incorporation
of the Tales of the Black Crater comic was
done successfully here. I appreciate how they
actually tried to interweave the tale within
this story. but it just goes to show how unique
of a medium comic books is and that it felt
very successful in the Watchmen comic. Even
though it was an abrupt shift in the pacing
of the overall story, I think for film and television,
you need to keep that momentum going. And every
time you go to the Black Friday, it was just
really confusing, I think, to any new coming
audiences. Yeah, I can agree with that 100%.
I don't think it was unsuccessful entirely
because there were those scenes where it added
layers, but you know, if they... dropped it
from the film, I also would not have complained.
I think it was just really hard to catch the
relevance of it all the way it was executed
here. You know, I'm not 100% you could even
call it relevant. It's not. It's just this literary
framing device that, yeah, 100% works in the
comics, but like you mentioned, maybe not anywhere
else. With Dr. Manhattan gone, Lori is kicked
out of her shared home on the military base,
and worldwide tensions escalate dramatically
now that America is without its protector. Meanwhile,
on Mars, Dr. Manhattan relives his past as
the young man Jonathan Osterman, the son of
a watchmaker who encouraged him to become a
scientist. He also recalls when he met and fell
in love with his scientist co-worker, Janie
Slater, along with the accident that destroyed
his body and gave him his superpowers. His
subsequent life with Janie and later Laurie
is briefly explored before he creates a massive
clockwork structure made from glass back on
Mars. This whole sequence infuriated me, actually,
because it was so inferior to what we got in
the live action movie. It just didn't work
here. It was so boring the way the voice actor
narrated the jumps through time, giving the
years and everything like that, and the lack
of music, you know? It just, it didn't work
as well. nearly as well. It was like a magical
sequence within the live action version. And
here I was almost born to death and I couldn't
wait for them to just move on with the story.
This sequence is probably one of my most favorite
in the movie and the comic. And I would agree
I liked it the least here. There was at one
point something they did that was really interesting
where he says, I dropped the photo to the floor
and 30 seconds of the future it's already there.
And you actually see that. So it's like looking
through his eyes. but they only attempted to
do that one more time where he says, you know,
I'm standing looking at the stars and then
you see his body shift into a transparent ghost
version of him. I don't know if I'm explaining
it well. Ultimately, it was not done as well
as it could have been, though there was a hint
at something possibly genius that they just
did not follow through with. With Malak being
mentioned during the talk show, Rorschach revisits
and tortures Malak for information, which proves
fruitless. After Dan offers to let Lori live
with him for the time, Adrian Veidt is attacked
by an assassin only to disable the killer, though
he dies via a cyanide capsule before he can
give Adrian any information. With Dr. Manhattan
gone, the comedian dead, and the assassination
attempt on Ozymandias, Rorschach becomes more
convinced of his mask killer conspiracy and
revisits Malek, only to find him in his home
alone, dead, with a gunshot wound to the head,
along with the gun. just as a swarm of police
arrive on the scene. Rorschach attempts to
flee, attacking police officers in the process,
but he is soon apprehended and unmasked, revealing
him to be a homeless doomsayer that had been
seen walking the streets throughout the film.
I always loved that reveal. I remember being
shocked by that in the comics when it's like,
oh, it's that guy, it's the redhead guy with,
you know, the sign. There's a lot of things
that happen in these scenes that I can't really
touch on until some reveals are made in the
second half of this story. Because I don't want
to spoil that for anyone who's just coming
into this fresh. But revisiting these scenes
with that in mind just kind of showed the masterwork
of the plan that's going on behind the scenes.
And that's something that I always like to
see anytime I re-experience the story. During
the end credits, we hear on a radio snippets
from Janie Slater talking about Dr. Manhattan
and Hollis Mason talking about his early superhero
career while we see blood slowly drip halfway
down the screen and a clock ticking closer
to midnight. And actually really liked that
they included that in these end credits. Because
you know, a lot of movies, especially superhero
movies will do things with their end credits.
But like, Watchmen is known for the supplemental
elements that they included at the end of each
comic. And for them to include portions of that
here, I thought was really cool. Like the ticking
clock, like the blood going down the screen,
like the different excerpts from books and
radio interviews. That was cool. It was brilliant.
I mean, I think you're right. If this was a
12 part television series where each issue was
an episode, it would be really fucking cool
to get the supplemental material in the form
of like a radio broadcast during the end credits
scene. Dude, 100 percent. I would have loved
this as a 12 episode series. I would not put
up past Warner Brothers to do that with like
in the next 10 years, just as another adaptation
to give to us. I wouldn't be surprised either.
You'd think with the success of the Watchmen
live action television series, maybe they've
even thought of doing that, but you know, animation
is cheaper. So they should have just done that
here instead of doing what they did. Right.
I don't hate this movie. I feel like a lot of
my review may have come across that way because
it is well made, it is a good story. Not everything
is as successful as other adaptations, but
it is still a good adaptation, a very faithful
one as well. Though despite filmmakers best
intentions, the film is faithful to a fault.
In essence, it's an abridged and superfluous
version of the celebrated graphic novel. It
was a really hard film to give a star rating
to. But at the end, I decided to go with three
out of five stars, just barely recommendable
as an adaptation. It's still a fresh rating,
but I'm still always going to recommend the
book over this adaptation 100% of the time.
I feel like I would not recommend this movie.
Actually, I would give this a rotten score because
at the end of the day, if you're going to read
the book, I'd recommend reading the book. And
if you're going to watch a movie, I'd recommend
Zack Snyder's live action film. I would never
in any circumstances, I think, recommend this
animated adaptation. Well, you haven't seen
the full adaptation yet. That's the problem.
And you're always going to have instances. I
come across this all the time where I'm like,
read the book and people are like, I don't have
time to read comic books. Okay, well then watch
this movie maybe. Yeah, watch the live action
movie because it's better. There's literally
no instance in which I would ever recommend
this ever. You have two great options to choose
from the original novel or the 2009 film. I
would just pick one of those. I think this
is the most unnecessary thing that DC has ever
put out. It's hard. It's so hard because I
really like Watchmen. And I feel like by giving
this a Rotten Tomato is the equivalent of saying
I don't like Watchmen or that it's bad. You
know, 3 out of 5 stars is right on the cusp
of fresh and rotten. It's 60%. You may have
just convinced me. I may give this a rotten
rating. Look within your heart. That's all I'll
say. I'm not here to steer you one way or the
other. Well, too bad, because he did. You happy?
Yeah, guys, don't be surprised if you see a
rotten rating on this from me on Rotten Tomatoes.
Save your death threats. I'm already dead inside
for having to do this as much as it pains me.
So yeah, I guess that does it for this review.
Let's wrap this shit up. Agent NK, wrap this
shit up. Thanks for listening to Dynamic Duel.
Visit the show's website at dynamicduel.com.
and follow us on Instagram at Dynamic Duel
Podcast. You can support the show on Patreon
at Patreon.com slash Dynamic Duel and joining
a tier that works for you or by rating and reviewing
Dynamic Duel on Apple podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser,
or on our website. Don't forget to listen to
the other shows in the DynaMic Podcast Network,
including Max Destruction, Senjo World, and
Console Combat. In our next episode. We would
normally be doing yet another review of Suicide
Squad Isekai, but I need a freaking break from
these reviews. So we're going to delay that
week and we are going to instead be doing a
duel between Arsenal or Red Arrow and White
Widow. Right. White Widow is Yelena Belova.
She's played by Florence Pugh in the MCU. And
I think it'll be fun to see her beat the shit
out of Arsenal. So looking forward to it. and
I'm looking forward to you ending your words
once again when DC wins. So there. But that
does it for this episode, we want to give a
big thanks to our executive producers Ken Johnson,
John Sierowski, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Balcom,
Miggy Mathen-Geehan, Brandon Nestergaard, Nathaniel
Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Austin Wazilowski, AJ
Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam
Spies, Andrew Schunk, Dean Molesky, Devin Davis,
Joseph Kirsting, and Josh Leiner for helping
make this podcast possible. And we'll talk
to you guys next week. Up up and away, true
believers. The accumulated filth of all their
sex and murder will foam up about their waists,
and all the whores and politicians will look
up and shout, Save us! And I'll look down and
whisper, Taste the rainbow.