This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
Hi and welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast,
a weekly show where we review superhero films
and debate the superiority between Marvel and
DC by comparing their characters in stat-based
battle simulations. I'm Marvelist Joe. And I'm
his twin brother Johnny DC. And this is the
episode where we review the latest Marvel Studios
cinematic release, Deadpool and Wolverine.
Was it awesome? I'm not going to say right now.
I'll let you know my thoughts later on this
episode. Yeah, it was awesome. It was awesome.
Of course it was. It was pretty damn awesome.
But yeah, I can't wait to talk about it. Before
we get into that, there was a shit ton of San
Diego Comic-Con news to come out this past week
for Marvel and DC. Not all of it great news.
In fact, most of it was really disappointing
news. So I'm like really glad that Deadpool
and Wolverine was a good movie. Otherwise I'd
be pretty damn depressed right now. But we're
gonna be talking about how the Russo brothers
are attached to direct Avengers Doomsday and
Avengers Secret Wars. We learned that Robert
Downey Jr. has been cast as Dr. Doom. I'm still
not over it. Joker Folly I do got an official
trailer. DC Studios unveiled their new logo.
Fantastic Four announced their subtitle for
the film, First Steps. We got the Penguin official
trailer and we got an official teaser for Creature
Commando. So a lot to get through. As always,
we list our segment times in our episode description.
So feel free to check out the show notes if
you wanna skip ahead to a particular topic.
Our artificially intelligent duel simulator
AJ 9K has a quick message for our listeners.
So listen up. Why hello there, do you want
even more from this podcast? Then become a part
of the dynamic duel community on Patreon, where
you can choose from three tiers. The dynamic
two-oh tier gives you access to our Discord
chat server. The fantastic four tier gives you
two bonus episodes each month, and the X-Force
tier makes you an executive producer of this
show. Lastly, The Diner Mike podcast network
tier lets you create your own podcast using
this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe
will help you develop your show, provide graphic
support and consultation, and get you simulation
results. Pitch the twins your ideas via email
at dynamicduelpodcast at gmail.com. Check it
out at patreon.com slash dynamicduel. Pip pip
cheerio. Thanks, AJ9K, and thanks to everyone
who supports the podcast. Guys, be sure to tune
into the other shows in the DynaMic podcast
network this week, including Max Destruction,
which pits your favorite action heroes from
film and television against each other. This
week, hosts Ken and Scotty are reviewing the
Deadpool and Wolverine movie, just like us.
On the Send Your World podcast, host Zachary
Hepburn speculates on fights between fan favorite
anime and manga characters. The show is currently
on a season hiatus, but it's coming back real
soon, guys, and Zach's kicking things off with
a matchup between Hiyai of Yu Hakusho and Yuta
Okatsu of Jujutsu Kaisen. And on the console
combat podcast, hosts John and Dean find out
who'd win in fights between popular video game
characters. In yesterday's episode, they reviewed
the 1993 Super Mario Brothers movie. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our
show notes to listen to all of the shows in
the DynaMic Podcast Network. But with that
out of the way, quick to the no prize. A no
prize is an award Marvel used to give out to
fans. Our version, the Dynamic duel No Prize,
is a digital award that we post on Instagram
for the person that we feel gave the best answer
to our question of the week. Two weeks ago,
we asked you guys what has been your favorite
Disney Plus original series from Marvel Studios
so far. And we got a lot of answers, let's
go ahead and run down our honorable mentions
as well as the no prize winner. Our first honorable
mention goes to Daniel Alonso, who said... Alright,
so best show on Disney+. Man, I don't know
how you guys don't like Moon Knight. That show
is amazing. I didn't grow up with the comics
or anything, so that was my first introduction.
And you can't beat that suit. I actually really
love that story. The fighting was amazing. Man,
that's the best show on Disney+. That's a Disney
original. Hands down, Moon Knight, dude. So
good. Now imagine if they had actually adapted
the story from the comics. how much better it
would have been then. Yeah, I mean, if you
guys are familiar with the Moon Knight character
from the comics, I definitely recommend going
all the way back to what was episode two in
our Batman versus Moon Knight duel episode.
The show was not bad. Like acting-wise, special
effects-wise, action-wise, it was pretty cool.
I just thought it was pretty inconsistent with
the rest of the MCU. And inconsistent with
the source material. I didn't dislike it. Even
though a lot of the story was original. to
the series, they weren't bad elements, you know?
It was still fairly interesting. Not as interesting
as the comic books, but interesting enough to
kind of develop a following for the show. Great
answer, Daniel. Our next honorable mention goes
to Cat Stevenson, who said, Hi guys, it's Cat
again, and I really want to say that the best
Disney Plus show is Hawkeye. I know a lot of
people are gonna say like Loki, Falcon and the
Winter Soldier, but Hawkeye was so good. with
multiple really good character introductions
slash reintroductions with Kingpin, Echo, Kate
Bishop, really, really well done. I loved the
Christmas undertones. Everything about this
show was amazing. I loved the action. I loved
the acting. Everything was really good. Yeah,
Hawkeye was pretty good. I really liked the
Christmas setting. I think it really made the
show stand apart and introduced a lot of fun
elements with Hawkeye, such as the whole I'll
be home for Christmas theme. workshopping his
own trick arrows in the vein of like Home Alone
or something like that. Yeah, Hawkeye was a
lot of fun. And definitely deserved for a character
that never received his own film. A lot of the
story revolved around Kate Bishop, but I thought
it was a great passing of the torch or bow as
it were. Yeah. So great answer, Kat. Our next
honorable mention goes to Travis Herndon, who
said, What's up dudes? Travis here. Shout out
to my other twins. So my answer had to be Werewolf
by Night. I was very surprised when they announced
that, to finally see Werewolf by Night, Madding,
and Elsa Bloodstone within the MCU was just
sick. It was awesome. This just opens the door
to the supernatural part of the MCU, which
was more my favorite sort of element within
Marvel. So yeah, Werewolf by Night was my favorite.
Great. Yeah, I loved Werewolf by Night as a
Halloween time special presentation by Marvel.
It's to this date. probably the most unique
thing that Marvel Studios has done with its
short runtime, its black and white cinematography,
the clear homages to past horror films. I thought
it was just incredibly fascinating. Yeah, there's
been a number of projects that Marvel has done
post-Endgame, like War Wolf by Night, like Eternals,
like Moon Knight, that they really haven't
picked up on. But I think of all of those things,
I would love to see them run with War Wolf
by Night and the world that sets up. Yeah, like
the dark underworld of monsters and demons
and stuff like that. Yeah, yeah. And monster
hunting. It was awesome. Want to give a quick
shout out to Abner O'Terry, who gave the answer
of what if, and the kingpin. Someone did a
really solid impression of Vincent D'Onafrio's
kingpin who gave the answer of Echo. But the
winner of this week's no prize is Scott Camacho,
who said, Odo Loki is my favorite. I'm going
to have to give it to WandaVision. only because
they did a great job of the different universes
within episodes and then finally ending it with
the good movie to follow. So I think out of
all of them, that's pretty much the one that
nails it for me. So I'm gonna go with Wandavision.
Yeah, Wandavision was the first Marvel Studios
Disney Plus original series to come out. And
in some ways, to me, it still feels like one
of the most special because not only did it
have the unique element of riffing on classic
television series throughout the decades, but
towards the end, it also felt really cinematic
in that you're like watching a movie on the
small screen. And yeah, it was hugely influential
on the greater MCU, you know, spawning movies
like Multiverse of Madness and the upcoming
Agatha all along. It was just really well made.
And that's likely why Matt Shackman was hired
to direct the Fantastic Four first steps movie
coming up. Yeah, I don't think I was the biggest
fan of WandaVision when we reviewed it, but
I do have to admire it for its artistry. Like
my favorite Disney Plus series is Loki, and
I'm kind of surprised no one gave that as their
like definitive answer. But WandaVision, I
would say is more unique and very ambitious.
Absolutely. So great answer, Scotty. You win
this week's No Prize. If you the listener want
a shot at winning your own No Prize, stay tuned
to later on this episode when we'll be asking
another question of the week. And now that
that's done, on to the news!
Alright, this past week we had the San Diego
Comic Con event in which we get a ton of news
from Marvel and DC regarding their upcoming
film, comic book, and television movie Slates.
There wasn't a whole lot of news, I feel like,
this year that came out of San Diego Comic
Con, and the news that did come out kind of
pissed me off. I'm not gonna lie. But let's
go ahead and get started going through the rundown
of everything that happened. I think one of
the biggest major news items we received was
that the fifth Avengers movie, has been renamed
to Avengers Doomsday. When I saw that, I actually
got really excited because I think a lot of
us were expecting that Kang was gonna get replaced
due to the offscreen drama regarding the actor
Jonathan Majors who plays the character of Kang.
Now, you know, if it were me, I wish they would
have just recast Kang. I don't think anybody
would have minded that. But it seems like they're
going in a completely different direction by
going with Dr. Doom instead of Kang the Conqueror.
And that normally would really thrill me until
I heard about the casting. But before I talk
about that, we got release dates for the next
two Avengers movies. So Avengers Doomsday is
going to come out in two years, May 2026, which
seems really damn soon. It's likely going to
be filmed back to back with Avengers Secret
Wars, which comes out May 2027, just due to
the proximity of those two release dates. Yeah,
and of course, that's what the Russos did with
Infinity War and Endgame. Those two films came
out almost a year apart, and I believe they
were filmed simultaneously. Yeah, we haven't
had an Avengers film for about six years now,
and we won't have another one for two years.
You know, the Avengers are the crown jewel
of the MCU, those movies. So it'll be nice to
see them come back and get those epic team
stories where we have a lot of characters involved.
They're always a lot of fun. So I'm really
excited for these upcoming two movies, even
though I have no idea now what Doomsday is
going to be about. But let's talk about Doctor
Doom. Doctor Doom, as I think most people know,
especially Marvel fans, is probably Marvel's
biggest villain. And I'm talking about bigger
than Thanos in terms of popularity and threat
level to Earth's heroes on a consistent basis.
Thanos is very threatening, but he's a cosmic
villain that makes fewer appearances than Doctor
Doom. Doctor Doom is huge. He's primarily a
Fantastic Four villain, posed a threat to almost
every single Marvel hero throughout his span
in the Marvel comics. He was the inspiration
for Darth Vader. Right. Was he? Yeah. I heard
that was a rumor. I don't know if that's actually
true. I believe it. But it wouldn't surprise
me. Yeah. Yeah, I believe it. For sure. The
mask that he wears, very intimidating. You know,
he has his own country. He's the monarch of
Latveria. He's a master of occult magic, similar
to Doctor Strange, but he's also a technological
genius much like Reed Richards or Tony Stark.
So he's very formidable. A lot of people have
been looking forward to an accurate depiction
of the comic book character ever since, you
know, before the 2005 Fantastic Four movie because
the Doom we got in that one sucked. You know,
they gave him bioelectricity powers. The Dr.
Doom that was in the 2015 Phantaforstick movie
also sucked. You know, he was like some kind
of weird telekinetic mutant birthed out of
the negative zone. They never got him right.
And so with the advent of the Fantastic Four
movie coming out, a lot of people were really
anticipating who they were going to cast as
Dr. Doom, whether he show up in Fantastic Four
or in Secret Wars or whatever. And what's really
sad is that all of these Dr. Doom fans are still
going to have to wait for an accurate depiction
of the comic book character because fucking
Robert Downey Jr. is gonna play Victor Von
Doom? I don't know. What? What is happening?
Such a dumbass idea. So basically you have
one of the most beloved and most popular actors
to portray a Marvel Studios character coming
back, but not as that character, as a completely
different, perhaps, variant of Doctor Doom,
or perhaps, you know, they're taking a cue from
one of the comic book storylines where Doctor
Doom became Iron Man. And note that I said Doctor
Doom became Iron Man in the comics. It was
never really the other way around outside of
like a couple issues where an alternate universe,
Tony Stark, became Doctor Doom. And maybe that's
what they're doing here. I think the only way
this could possibly work is if Robert Downey
Jr. is Victor Von Doom in the alternate universe
that the Fantastic Four come from. Because we
know that the Fantastic Four movie is taking
place in an alternate universe. And that's why
we're getting like a female silver surfer and
everything like that. That's the only way I
see this working. But there's no way in hell
I will accept Robert Downey Jr. being Victor
Von Doom in the primary 616 cinematic universe.
It just doesn't work. No, it boggles the mind,
honestly. I remember when we were talking about
Silver Surfer and how she was going to be a
female, and it was like, OK, does Norenrad
not exist in the 616? And in the same way, does
that mean Victor Von Doom does not exist in
the 616? It's just weird to me. I feel like
what they're trying to do is make it weird
for the 616 heroes when they see Victor Von
Doom and they're like, oh, what, Tony? Oh,
I'm so conflicted. But it's stupid, I feel like.
I just think he's really miscast. When I think
of Doctor Doom, I think of someone very sinister
and very cunning. And not that RDJ can't play
that, but he's known for playing these fast
talking, wisecracking characters. And I really
don't want to see that in Doctor Doom. No, absolutely
not. No, he's not Doctor Doom. Maybe they'll
alter his voice. You know, maybe they'll cover
up his face. I mean, they should cover up his
face. You never really see Doom's face. And
if you do, it's allegedly scarred to hell.
from when he burned his face when he put the
mask on for the first time, as the legend goes.
But even if we don't see his face, I still don't
want Robert Downey Jr. to play Dr. Doom. I
mean, that's even more of a reason to not cast
him, because you could literally cast anybody.
You could literally cast anyone with a great
voice who could act behind a mask, and there
you go. It does not have to be someone who was
notorious for making an insane amount of money
on these Marvel films. It feels like creative
bankruptcy, right? You know... The MCU is kind
of in shambles right now because over the past
couple years, they haven't been getting as
much of a return on their films. So it's like
a big marketing move in that they're getting
their biggest star back in an effort to entice
viewers back to the theater. But it's not the
right call. There are so many great actors out
there that could have played Doctor Doom that
would have gotten me so excited. I did not watch
Marvel movies to see Robert Downey Jr. I watched
Marvel movies to see Tony Stark. And that's
all I'm gonna see when I'm watching Avengers
Doomsday, which can I just mention is a horrible
fucking title? Doomsday, really the Superman
villain? I know it's not based off of that,
but it's like a movie coming out That's called
Justice League Dr. Doom Exactly. Well, they
should have just called it Avengers Doom. I
think that would have been better Doomsday Yeah,
of course is a DC villain one of the most popular
DC villains, you know, the guy that fucking
killed Superman I just don't know what they're
doing over at the MCU, especially with this
Robert Downey Jr. casting choice. And that
brings us to our question of the week.
What the fuck? Record your answer at dynamicduel.com
by clicking on the red microphone button in
the bottom right-hand corner of the screen,
which will prompt you to leave us a voicemail.
Your message could be up to 30 seconds long,
and don't forget to leave your name in case
we include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a Dynamic
Duel No Prize that we'll post to Instagram.
Be sure to answer before August 3rd. Can't
wait to hear you guys' answers.
In DC news, in good news, we got to the official
trailer for Joker Folly I Do, the sequel to
the Joker film, which was fantastic. A lot of
people aren't looking forward to this Joker
sequel because they don't like the idea of a
musical, but the more I see from the movie,
the more I'm falling in love with the concept,
the more I just am in awe of the cinematography
and the acting performances that it looks like
we're going to get for this movie. It looks
like it's going to be a masterpiece. Oh my God.
I'm sorry, what? Calm down, OK? It looks mid
at best. Oh, my gosh. If this doesn't look like
a masterpiece, I don't know what a masterpiece
looks like. And clearly, you don't either. Sure,
I do. Then it's OK. So then you recognize this
looks like one. No, it doesn't. Well, then you
don't know. You don't know what you're talking
about. You could just sit this one out. The
the trailer starts off with. Arthur Fleck being
escorted, I think, to a courtroom. And on the
radio, you hear different voices talking about
him. The first time I watched this trailer,
I watched it without subtitles, which I like
to do because sometimes subtitles can give away
different lines before you hear them. So I
had no idea that one of those voices was Harvey
Dent. I had no idea Harvey Dent was going to
be in this movie. That gets me so much more
pumped up to see it, because you have to imagine
if he's involved in the courtroom scenes. Something's
gonna happen to him. And that's gonna be wild
to see how that happens in this Joker universe,
because it's just so surprising and violent.
Do you think Joker's gonna throw acid in his
face or something like that? I don't know,
him or Harley Quinn, maybe he gets shot in the
face. I have no idea. I just imagine it's gonna
be very intense. We get to hear Joaquin Phoenix
singing for the first time in this movie, along
with Lady Gaga as well. They're not coming across
as like very polished singers. Which is interesting
because I thought the musical numbers were going
to be much bigger. We haven't really seen anything
like that yet in these trailers, though I do
imagine they will be in the film in Arthur's
sort of imagined sequences in his mind. We see
a number of those sequences in this trailer,
like when him and Harley are on stage or when
they're dancing in the courtroom or on the
rooftops and stuff like that. But in this trailer,
you also get a sense of the origin of how Harley
Quinn became enamored with Arthur Fleck. You
know, she saw him on TV for the first time
and he spoke to her in the same way that the
Joker has spoken to a number of people, particularly
in Gotham City. But also you see that spilling
out into the real world, where in like political
protests, you'll see people wearing Joker masks
or clown makeup in the same way that people
used to wear the Guy Fawkes mask from V for
Vendetta. But it's believable, you know, that
someone like Harley Quinn would be influenced
by him. It does look like she is a patient
in Arkham Asylum. Though my theory is still
that she's manipulating the Joker. We'll see
if that's a valid theory or not. She definitely
influences the Joker and makes him feel like
he's a star if he didn't feel like that already.
And one of the guards played by Brendan Gleeson
mentions that. And I think that totally makes
sense that the Joker would think that he was
a star based on the ending of the first Joker
movie, how he just stood up on that police
car and felt like seen for the very first time.
He's conflating fame with infamy. Sort of.
Like people are influenced by him in this weird
way. And yeah, it could be infamous, the guy
is a violent killer. But like, people were praising
him around that cop car. So he probably feels
like he's doing the world a favor in some weird
way. I don't know, maybe drawing attention
to people who feel unseen. I don't know. The
first movie of course was a sympathetic look
at the Joker. So I imagine they'll continue
to run with this. And that's kind of horrifying,
I agree. But it makes for damn good cinema.
The music in this trailer. so damn good using
Frank Sinatra and Judy Garland. It really gives
you the vibe of what kind of musical numbers
they'll be doing in the movie, like these classic
mid-century tunes. They're just nailing the
tone. They're crushing the tone. All it is tone.
That's all it is. But damn, that tone, though.
Yeah, there's not much substance to these trailers.
You know, it's like you get a line here or
there and then you get a crescendo swelling
of music. Yeah, and you see the Joker and makeup
and stuff like that and then you see the title
and then it's over like You really have no
idea Too much of what the overall story is going
to be or how they're going to make it interesting
like is it a trial movie? Uh, is it a romance?
All of the above who knows yes all of the above
I imagine honestly I'm sold on tone like I don't
want to know too much of the story Like if
you can get me with the performances if you
could get me with the music if you could get
me with a hint of a story If you could get me
with the revelation that Harvey Dent is going
to be in this movie, you got me. Check your
expectations, man. Fuck you. It's too late.
I'm too far gone. There's no hope. I just need
to see the movie. Well, it comes out in just
a little over two months and I will be there
day one. I honestly hope to get like an early
screening for this. I want to see as many times
as I can in theaters before we have to review
it. And I'm really looking forward to it. Mind
you, you did not like the first Joker movie
the first time you saw it. That's very true.
That's very true. You better watch yourself.
This time I'm not going to take all my coworkers
so I can feel like uneasy and almost like embarrassed.
It's just me going in. And I love how these
trailers are letting me know what to expect.
Now, the Joker trailer came out before Comic-Con
so that it could play in front of the Deadpool
movies at Comic-Con. There wasn't too much of
a presence from DC Studios. James Gunn wasn't
there, but he did record a video to unveil the
new logo for DC Studios and DC in general.
I say new, but it's really not. It's just a
return to the classic DC Bullet logo that was
designed by the renowned graphic designer Milton
Glazer. Now let's be real, it's a step down
from what came previously. The existing DC Comics
logo. I thought was a great modern interpretation
of the bullet logo. You know, it simplified
it and made it really clean and bold. Returning
to the logo that they used in the 80s and 90s
seems dumb. Which was my initial reaction because
I was under the impression that it was only
DC studios that was going to be using this
logo and not the comics, not the merch, not
the video games or anything else. Which I thought
was really bad for brand synergy. Like you don't
want one division using one logo for DC and
other divisions not using that same logo. I
do really like DC's most recent logo. I agree
with you. I thought it was a great interpretation
of not only the DC bullet, but a lot of other
logos from DC's past. It was perfection in my
opinion. That said, my second favorite DC logo
is absolutely the bullet. It's the one that
was around when I first started reading comics.
So I don't know if nostalgia plays a factor,
but yeah, the design is not bad. Well, I mean,
it's inferior, but I understand why they needed
to do this because they needed to make it clear
to the general public that DC is moving in a
new direction, that they're like establishing
a new cinematic universe and whatnot. But the
issue is that DC has rebranded like 50 fucking
times in the last couple of decades. Yeah. You
had the swoosh logo. You had the stupid like
fold over logo. That was a really bad logo.
But then you also had the most recent modern
DC logo, which was fantastic. Because of all
these changes, I think DC knew that they couldn't
really afford to go in another new direction
and still maintain that solid brand awareness.
In that regard, they had to go back to something
that had come previously, and so they went
with their classic logo. Something that is arguably
more iconic. When I talk to people about DC
comics, I talk about Watchmen, I talk about
Dark Knight Returns. All of these things came
out during the DC Bullet logo era, so it's not
surprising that they would want to remind people
of that and be like, hey, remember when you
loved DC Comics? Well, get ready to love it
again, because here we are. I do agree that
they probably wanted something new. I don't
know if they needed it. But yeah, you're right.
It would have signaled to everyone that, hey,
this is a brand new era. And there's a lot of
different companies who are going back to their
old retro logos. Like fast food chains like
Pizza Hut and Burger King. You know, they're
all going back to the 70s and 80s. So, you know,
I guess it's just DC's turn. I don't love it.
I wish it never happened. But if it had to happen,
you could have done worse logos than the bullet.
All I know is that Marvel better not do this
shit because I'll be pissed. What? You don't
like the classic Marvel logo with the lettering
on top of the giant and with yellow? comics
written across it? It's fine. You know, that's
the logo that they had when I grew up reading
the comics and everything like that, but it's
been improved upon and I don't want to see
them doing a DC. Oh, you mean being badass?
No, I mean fucking up. You guys are fucking
up plenty. Don't. Exactly. Don't act like you're
not. Speaking of fucking up, back to Marvel
news, we got the first subtitle announced for
the Fantastic Four movie. A lot of us just
thought that. This upcoming MCU Fantastic Four
film would just be called Fantastic Four or
The Fantastic Four. But no, it's going to be
called Fantastic Four First Steps. And the
title treatment kind of makes it seem like a
kid's cartoon. And I understand that's probably
due in part to the 60s sitcom vibe that they're
kind of going with. But I don't know why they
needed a subtitle for this movie. It makes it
sound like. Fantastic Four are learning how
to walk. Now, the only way that this subtitle
works, I think, and really it could work on
multiple levels. First Steps could allude to
the Fantastic Four taking their first steps
on the moon or something like that. If in fact,
you know, this is the 60s and part of their
space exploration where they run into their
cosmic ray accident is part of the space race
or something like that. I can see that working.
But I think more than that, in order for this
subtitle to work... A big part of the storyline
needs to revolve around Reed and Sue becoming
parents for the first time. Because then you
have first steps alluding to Franklin and maybe
Valeria as well, as their children taking their
first steps. I feel like Valeria is a bit of
a stretch, maybe all you need is Franklin, but
even then that seems really soon. I guess it
is a way to differentiate this Fantastic Four
film from other Fantastic Four films in that
Reed and Sue would become parents and maybe
make this film feel more family oriented. So
it's not a terrible idea. I just don't think
it needed the subtitle. It didn't. I'm not.
I'm not a fan of the subtitle. Fantastic for
first steps. I don't ever want to call it that.
OK, can I just say that Marvel has really been
sucking lately when it comes to subtitles?
I think it started with homecoming. I was like,
what? Homecoming? No, just stop with the sucky
ass subtitles. Give us like real subtitles that
we actually want. You know, Brave New World
is not a bad one, but Asterisk? I guess that's
not really a subtitle. It's just it's just
weird. Are you talking about the Asterisk that
comes at the end of the Thunderbolts title?
Yeah, yeah. Yeah, who knows what's going on
there? That's weird. I feel like I'm complaining
a lot for a subtitle, but it just confuses me
and I hate being confused. And people really
shouldn't be confused at this stage in Marvel
because they need wins. Like they can't really
afford bad news. I mean, maybe they can because
Deadpool and Wolverine totally killed, but
that could be forgotten so easily with one more
bad Marvel movie. Yeah, Goodwill only lasts
as long as your most recent announcement or
decision or movie. You know, I've been online
a lot and it seems like the majority opinions
regarding the first step subtitle and Robert
Downey Jr.'s return as Dr. Doom are mostly negative,
and deservedly so. I hope Marvel listens to
the fans because making them happy is how they
make money. You know what makes me happy? The
new Penguin trailer. Everyone who's been listening
to the podcast knows that I love the Batman,
that I've really been looking forward to this
show and how it expands the world of Matt Reeves
the Batman. I think Colin Farrell totally nailed
the performance of the Penguin. I still can't
believe it's him in this role. And it looks
like this show is going to be one epic. crime
drama of how the Penguin rises to power. We
see him being heavily influenced by his mother
in this trailer who makes him feel like he should
be the one in charge of Gotham's underworld.
And the trailer does a really good job of making
the Penguin appear like a threat. You see him
freaking stab someone, you see him shoot people
with machine guns, you see him plow into people
with his car. It's freaking crazy. Yeah it looks
a lot more violent and action heavy than most
other crime shows and films. Like something
like the Sopranos. Sure it's but I wouldn't
say there's a lot of action. The Penguin seems
to have a lot of action. Yeah, I think we mentioned
that in our review of the last trailer that
they put out and how the explosions and stuff
sets a step above, action-wise, other crime
dramas that you see on networks like HBO. This
is grounded, but it's still very much oriented
in that comic book world. Yeah, it looks more
like Heat as opposed to something like The Wire.
Yeah, yeah, I could see that. This trailer
also gives us a really good idea of who is going
to be Oswald's main antagonist in the show,
and that's going to be Sophia Falcone, the daughter
of Carline Falcone, who we saw get shot and
killed in the Batman movie. It looks like both
of those characters are going to be fighting
to see who comes out on top and rule Gotham's
criminal underworld, but the wrench thrown
into the mix is that Sophia Falcone was apparently
an inmate at Arkham, which definitely makes
things interesting. It looks like we're going
to get to see the inside of Arkham. and I'm
wondering who else we're gonna see there. Maybe
we'll see the Riddler, maybe we'll see the
Joker again. Maybe, that would be incredible,
it's probably unlikely, that feels like a pipe
dream, but who knows. We got to a release date
with this trailer, finally. It's going to be
debuting on HBO, they're really branding it
with HBO instead of Just Max, on September
19th. Do you know how many episodes it's gonna
be? Eight episodes. So we'll be reviewing this
like in mid-November. Also coming out this year
in December, is Creature Commandos, which we
got the first teaser trailer for during Comic-Con.
Of course, this is the first official project
in James Gunn's DCU Cinematic Universe, but
it really looks like it's stemming off of the
events that happened in Peacemaker Season 1,
with the outing of Amanda Waller as the head
of Task Force X, and it looks like here she's
kind of doing more of the same, except instead
of creating a Suicide Squad, she's creating
the Task Force M, which is somewhat in keeping
with the comics. They didn't call it Task Force
M there, but they called it Project M. Interesting.
The show looks really good, actually. I was
kind of blown away by how quirky everything
feels, how great the animation was, and how
cool the character designs are. And the voice
cast is awesome. And the great thing is that
the cast will also be playing live action versions
of these characters in the films. So you have
David Harbour as Frankenstein. You have Sean
Gunn as Weasel, who of course played the character
in The Suicide Squad, directed by James Gunn
a few years ago. Alan Tudyk is Dr. Phosphorus.
Indira Varma is The Bride. But of course, you
also have Viola Davis as Amanda Waller, Frank
Girlo as Rick Flagg Sr. and Steve Agge, who's
returning as John Economus. The teaser trailer
we got was not very long. It was only a minute
and 30 seconds. We didn't get a great idea of
what the story is, but it looks to be in keeping
pretty much with The Suicide Squad just a little
bit more monstrous as it were. Well, it sounds
like they're fighting Nazis according to GI
Robots line. Right, yeah. I love the fact that
these characters are getting their own show.
The Creature Commandos have always been a really
cool team to me and I love the fact that James
Gunn is kind of continuing his Suicide Squad
kind of zany character team group dynamic because
he did a phenomenal job with the Suicide Squad
film. Again, the show is coming out in December.
I'm not sure how many episodes there are for
it, but we're definitely going to review it.
Well, if it starts in December, it's probably
going to lead into January, which means that
the show probably won't qualify for a Brothers
Award. It'll probably go into the 2025 awards.
Oh yeah, it's definitely going into January.
Absolutely.
But I think that does it for all the news for
this episode, so let's go ahead and get into
our main event where we review the latest Marvel
Studios movie release, Deadpool and Wolverine.
All right, Deadpool and Wolverine was directed
by Sean Levy and stars Ryan Reynolds, Hugh
Jackman, Emma Corrin and Matthew McFadden. It's
one of the most anticipated movies of the year,
the only film that Marvel Studios is releasing
this year. But did it deliver on the hype and
expectations? Well, John, Adam, what do you
guys think? I would say it did. Not just did
it, it massively lived up to the hype, my man.
Welcome back to the show, guys. Longtime listeners
will know John and Adam Spies. They were the
hosts of the blast from our past podcast. They
are the hosts of the throwback trivia take down
podcast. And longtime listeners know them from
our reviews of X-Men Origins Wolverine, Batman
Forever and Batman the Movie. Both of them
have been or are executive producers of Dynamic
Duel. They are the self professed biggest Deadpool
fans in the world. And I believe it. And they
are also the most requested guests. from our
fans. To this day, people still ask when we're
going to do another review with Adam and John.
And I couldn't think of a better movie than
the one that probably ends the journey that
was started with X-Men Origins Wolverine. John,
Adam, glad to have you guys. How you guys been
doing? Been doing great. We just both had to
body slide over from the BeFop Network podcast
verse, if you will. We've been doing great.
We actually got to hang out with y'all just
a couple of weeks ago, which was wonderful in
person. I was very excited for you all to invite
us for this amazing movie, which I have no doubt
will be the first six of all time on your ratings.
Six out of five. That's obvious. So I want to
jump in real quick and give a quick spoiler
warning to the listeners. This is a spoiler
review. So don't like ruin the surprises for
yourself. If you haven't seen the movie yet,
definitely go see the movie. It's absolutely
worth the ticket price. Like regardless of end
quality. The movie itself is a big deal in
that it brought Hugh Jackman out of retirement,
who had hung up his claws about seven years
ago after the Logan movie. John Adam, I want
to get real quick your reactions to the Deadpool
3 announcement teaser that Ryan Reynolds did
that announced that Wolverine would be in the
movie. I mean, I was as pleasantly surprised
as everyone else. I didn't think it was something
that was beyond the realm of possibility because,
you know, money talks. and never say never.
Patrick Stewart also said that he would never
play Professor X again and then we saw him
a few years later in Multiverse of Madness.
So the truth is, is any story that's worth
their weight is gonna entice an actor to any
role regardless. I mean, even I heard James
McAvoy was asked, you know, would you ever return?
He said, listen, if the story is there, if
it's a story worth telling, I'm in. And I think
especially, actors who have been around for
a while where maybe money isn't necessarily
the biggest draw, it's creativity. If you come
to them with something really good, they're
probably in. I came in with a whole heart of
optimism. I mean obviously with Deadpool in
the comics, him and Wolverine have a very interesting
relationship. It's not that buddy-buddy relationship
that he had with Cable, which honestly I think
they botched in Deadpool 2 a little bit. I did
not like Cable being as... kill hungry as he
as he was in that movie. But time and time again
in Deadpool one and two, Hugh Jackman and Wolverine
was brought up by Deadpool like, you know, that
first movie you take the mask off, you see
the Hugh Jackman mask on top. He was obviously
a driving factor for creativity for Ryan Reynolds.
And so seeing them sitting together, him walking
behind, you know, oh, hey, Hugh, you in for
it? And he's like, yeah, sure. Chills, man.
It got me super excited. That's not without
hesitation because we all saw Logan and Logan
is a phenomenal film. Could they make it work?
It's all about the story. Yeah, for sure. That
totally makes sense. I remember seeing that
announcement trailer a couple of years ago and
just being pumped, like bouncing off the walls.
Just I think I'm still writing the energy from
that announcement. And it's definitely taking
me through all the disappointing comic news,
the fact that this movie was good. And I definitely
think lived up to the expectations because.
My big takeaway from the movie was that it
110% delivered on the dynamic between the main
characters and gave us scenes that we've always
wanted to see as fans and even some scenes that
we never knew we always wanted to see. It's
so weird because Ryan Reynolds, he definitely
has his finger on the pulse marketing-wise
in terms of like what fans want. Like this is
the movie that Doctor Strange and the Multiverse
of Madness should have been. This is the multiverse
movie that all of the fans have been asking
for. They delivered in such a big way with all
the different cameos and stuff like that. Yeah,
it was ironic that at the end of the film, Deadpool
was like, can we cool it with the multiverse
thing? When, you know, in reality, he's probably
done it better than any other film has thus
far. It's one of those kind of things where
because they did so well in this film, it kind
of adds validation to some of the older ones.
Go like, OK, I kind of had to sift through
the shit to get to where it actually makes sense.
For sure. Yeah, like 20 years of shit. Right.
I mean, like they went back to the Electra movie.
They went back to the Fantastic Four movie.
They gave us the Channing Tatum Gambit movie
that we never actually got to see that was
canceled. And their writing and the allusions
to that, you know, the meta side of that was
so perfectly done. And something you could only
have done in a Deadpool movie. Any other movie,
it doesn't make sense. It seems cheesy. This
movie, it works. Right. Yeah. All those like
meta in jokes where you not only have to know.
The films themselves were probably some of
the behind the scenes stuff as well, like how
Wesley Snipes was not a fan of Ryan Reynolds.
And he was like, I don't like you. And then
this movie is like, he never did. That was
so good. Like in a way, this movie almost makes
Blade Trinity better because it gives you some
closure to that whole shit storm. And like it
never felt good watching Blade Trinity, not
only because it wasn't a good movie, but because
you knew all the behind the scenes drama and
stuff like that. So it was nice to get a lot
of closure. And I think that's one of the best
things that this movie has going for it. In
addition. to all the fan service. But speaking
of the fan service, how did you guys feel about
the movie leaving the theater? I had a shit
eating grin from beginning to end. First time
I saw it, I saw it with my wife and we walked
out. And she, who knows very little, she knows
basically just from marrying me, you know,
some tiny things about Deadpool. And she enjoyed
the film. And I just turned her I said, I fucking
loved that. And then the second time I went
with a buddy from work, who is a huge Batman
fan. And we've had some fun little Deadpool
versus Batman things. And I talked to him and
I was like, so what do you think? He was like,
yeah, that's better than any Batman recent
Batman movie. And I'm like, fuck yeah, it is.
No lie. No, it's better. It's better than anything
you've had recently. I mean, because it's just
a fun film and you're getting more for like
the extra nerds like us who have read comics
and know enough about extra things. But because
it just brings the fun. I couldn't help but
be in a state of euphoria at the end of this
film both times. I mean, I really don't have
too much to add. That's basically how I was.
I saw it Friday morning, I saw it Saturday morning.
Friday morning I left it and all I could do
the rest of the day was think about it. And
I finally told my wife, I said, I got to go
back. I got to go back and watch it again. So
my son and I went back the second time. And
I told my son as soon as we walked out, I said,
I think I liked that even more the second time
I went in, even already knowing what was going
to happen. I would agree. I think actually
seeing the second time, I felt like I was able
to absorb maybe even more of a wider picture
because I'm not trying to take in so much detail.
Yeah, there was a lot in this movie. I remember
my first reaction coming out of the theater
was texting Joseph, letting him know, hey dude,
you need to see this movie more than once. I
think my biggest takeaway coming out too was
just how much of a fan service movie this was
and how rewarding it was to see as a fan. because
you got so much more out of it. My wife went
to go see it with me as well and she enjoyed
it. But I just know that I got so much more
out of it because I understood all of the different
references and meta jokes and stuff like that.
And it's probably the most rewarding film in
terms of fan service than anything else that
has ever existed. It's like even more than
Endgame. Definitely more than The Flash, for
sure. Hey, hey. OK. My big takeaway walking
out of the movie was, I mean, I was entirely
pleased with what they had done here. I did
feel like there was a story structural problem
that Deadpool 2 had as well where there were
almost four acts or more of like a prequel as
it were. Everything kind of felt more episodic
or like a series of comic issues than it did
like a typical narrative structure. Why is
that a problem? It does make the film feel a
little bit long and I think that moment at
the end when Deadpool's like hang tight folks
were almost there, at that moment I was like
okay, yeah, I am kind of feeling that. Because
you had what felt like a big third act fight.
with the resistance against Kuzantronova's army.
And then you had almost an epilogue going back
to Deadpool's universe. You had the Deadpool
core fight. And then even after that, you had
the big sacrifice to destroy the time ripper
machine. So it felt episodic. There was a lot
of sequences strung together as opposed to watching
a singular movie narrative. I will say this,
the first time I watched it, I felt that, I
felt the length. The second time I watched
it, went by like that. Absolutely. I completely
agree. And I think that has to do with you
already having the right expectations for what
the story is going to be. Yeah. So, yeah, I
definitely didn't mind that as much the second
time I watched the movie. And each of those
beats gave you something exciting, gave you
something fun. Because, yeah, you had that
climactic, you know, oh my God, Blade and Electra
and Gambit are all kind of getting their hero
moment. And that's cathartic. And then you're
like, okay, oh shit, I'm still going on a journey
here. But then you're getting that. bus fight
in that Deadpool core fight, which is incredible.
And then you're like, OK, shit, we are still
going here. But then you have the emotional
tie of their kind of sacrifice, which wasn't
a sacrifice, but I'm that didn't bother me,
honestly, because it works for Deadpool. But
that emotional moment, it hits you in a lot
of different fields. Like this film did a great
job, even though I agree. I'm actually with
you guys 100 percent, where it kind of felt
like, OK, we got another thing to conclude
and then another thing to conclude. But I got
satisfied conclusions from each of them. Yeah,
the good thing about the sort of episodic nature
of the story is that you got a lot of great
moments at the end of each like little beat,
right? There are so many moments in this movie
that will be contenders for the Brothers Awards
that we do at the end of the year. You know,
there was the scene where they're sacrificing
themselves listening to Madonna. Like I got
chills. I got teary like watching those moments
of them thinking of like their entire arcs
culminating in that moment thinking they're
about to die. I got chills during the Deadpool
core fight scene. What was your favorite moment
from? the movie, would you say, if you had
to pick one? I want to say the one that got
the biggest reaction from me in the theater
was the bait and switch of Chris Evans. Yep.
Was the Captain America to flame when he said
flame on. I about shit myself because that's
I mean, they did such a great job of peppering
in Captain America multiple times before. And
Deadpool's love of him, which is pretty comic
accurate. And then, oh, my God, yes, it's Cap.
And then, oh, it's not. And I just I was floored.
I fucking died in the theater and I can't believe
I didn't see it coming. Yeah. But right when
you get that reveal, that's when you figure
out, oh, I know exactly what this movie is
going to be here, at least in the void setting.
Yes. It's just going to be a ton of cameos
and all this just so much fun, just so much
fanboy excitement. Like I definitely had to
grab my special sock. Yeah. It was so good.
I didn't think in a million years that Chris
Evans would be playing Johnny Storm again. It
was so good. I... I wouldn't say that it was
spoiled for me, but I'd heard numerous people
say, hey, he could come back as Johnny Storm
because they're doing this here. So that was
kind of in the back of my mind. It was still
a surprise, but I was like, oh, of course they
did this because it's the funny thing to do.
The thing that got the biggest reaction out
of me, other than the initial very first trailer,
I didn't watch anything. I didn't watch anything
else. I did have a couple of things spoiled
for me just because social media sucks. Big
time. X23 was spoiled for me, and that was
without having seen the trailer. I really was
disappointed that they spoiled that. The thing
that got the biggest reaction out of me was
Wesley Snipes. Oh, yeah, that shocked the hell
out of me. I literally shouted, holy shit, in
the theater right next to my 14 year old son,
who surprisingly didn't hear me because everyone
else in the theater was also yelling, holy
shit. It was one collective holy shit. Uh-huh.
So Wesley Snipes was actually spoiled for me.
And I messaged you guys on Facebook Messenger.
I said, stay off the goddamn internet because
there are spoilers out there. I had opened up
Instagram and I saw the clip of Wesley Snipes
and it was unforgivable. At that point, I just
completely like did not get on Instagram or
anything until I saw the movie. It was a great
feeling. It was another kind of like chills
down the back. Like, oh, my God, he's back.
Oh, my God. Where's my white pants? It was
exactly because we're never fucking getting
Mahershala Ali. I know, it's like 10 years
in the making now already almost. But I'm excited
for Mahershala Ali's. I thought it was a great
meta joke when Wesley Snipes was like, it's
only one blade and there's only gonna be one
blade. It was so good. I was like, I hope that's
not actually true because we gotta get that
Mahershala Ali movie. I already knew that Elektra
was gonna be in the film because that was revealed
by the trades back when she was actually cast.
But I did not know that Channing Tatum was
gonna be in the movie. What was your reaction
to Channing Tatum's look, accent, all I would
say pleasantly surprised. I felt like his headpiece
was a little thick. That part took a little
way for it. Also, I don't think his hair was
big enough. I feel like his hair needed to
be bigger, taller. There needed to be more.
His accent I thought was fine. It's not an
easy accent to do unless you're a native speaker.
So the shock of him being in it was fun. It
was the fun surprise. It wasn't the holy shit
surprise that Blade was, but it was the fun
surprise of like, oh, we get to do this. This
is cool. I thought what they did with the visual
effects with his cards was cool. I thought his
fighting was fine. I thought the lines he had
to say was fine. Like I said, I thought his
accent was fine. It wasn't perfect. But the
thing that took me, not out of it, but the thing
that bothered me the most was I thought the
headpiece was too thick. For some reason, that
kind of bothered me. Yeah. I always think of
Gambit as just having a very gaunt facial structure.
And when you combine Chyney Tatum's rounder
face, especially as he gets older... with that
headpiece. I just wish they got rid of the
headpiece. I think it would have been fine just
with the jacket. I agree. Or make it may have
a cloth. It didn't have to be out of leather.
Yeah. Or a rubber or whatever it was. I thought
that moment of Channing Tatum in there was another
perfect moment for us, the extra nerds, the
people who really have given in the time to
not just watch all the movies and shows because
we've all done that. And so many people have
done that. But the people who know, oh, this
is the extra stuff that we know this is going
to happen or that, you know, all this stuff
is rumored, etc, etc. This was for the real
deep cut people. And when he was talking, I
loved his bad accent. I mean, it wasn't even
that bad. But I know because even when you
watch X-Men 97 and you know that stuff, it's
a real hard accent and even rogues is that
Louisiana accent's real fucking tough to do.
And so them just making fun of it. And also
the meta jokes of your fourth wall breaks of
who's your dialect coach, like all that stuff.
I thought it played off exactly the way a Deadpool
movie can do it in a very interesting and funny
and met away. But like my wife, who was sitting
next to me, had no idea. Like, well, why the
hell is Channing Tatum in this? And I was like,
well, you see, you see, because he was cast
and he was supposed to be in it. And like all
the jokes of him, like, yeah. And I some people
feel like they were born in the void. And I'm
like, because he never got the movie, honey.
Do you get it? Like that was great for us. It
was for that extra level of deep nerd that
even just the casual fan wouldn't get. They
would be fine with it. But like us, we got
a little a little extra boner from that. Just
an extra inch there. The Channing Tatum reveal
was actually probably my favorite moment in
the entire film, because when I saw the card,
I was like, oh, shit, they brought Taylor Kitsch
back. And then sure enough, it's fucking Channing
Tatum. I was like, what? It was amazing. Hands
down, my favorite cameo. I got to say my least
favorite cameo, though, was fucking Henry Cavill
as Wolverine. I did not appreciate that shit.
That was perfect. The Cavalry was so good. They
broke my heart. Well, I think DC and the executives
broke your heart when they fired him. Yeah.
I'm going to insist everyone on the Discord
that's part of Team Marvel now refer to Team
DC as the shit fucks down the street. Yes.
It was such a good moment. I remember people
talking about Henry Cavill being cast as the
new Wolverine in the MCU. I was like, you guys
don't know what you're talking about. That's
just wishful fanboy thinking. But apparently
the rumor got enough traction to actually warrant
a cameo in this movie. And I was, I'm totally
here for it. And he seems like such a nerd
guy that he'd be down for that kind of stuff.
Cause you know, you know, he loves all this
kind of nerd stuff. I do have to say that they
did drop the ball on one major cameo that they
could have and totally should have done. And
that was Joe Manganiello as Deathstroke. You
could have played off of that with like, oh,
like I came first, you're a variance of me
kind of thing. Now we only need so many DC cameos
in a Marvel movie, okay? All right, whatever
I will tell you one cameo. I was expecting and
highly disappointed I didn't get I didn't get
Taylor Swift as dazzler and I was very disappointed.
I didn't get that I was totally expecting that
I was too actually well I mean like there was
so much buzz around that Taylor Swift being
in the movie and she even sent out like an Instagram
post congratulating Ryan Reynolds and Blake
Lively and Hugh Jackman and everybody on their
movie and stuff like that So yeah, I felt very
strange that she wasn't in there. I wasn't actually
expecting her to be in the film per se I was
expecting to see her in like an end credit scene
like and it's just a throwaway thing that didn't
really matter I was not disappointed with the
end credit scene. We got yeah It was exactly
like my high school senior class video that
they put on at the end of the year Oh, yeah,
the mid credits, you know with Green Day. It
was the exact same video. Yeah but a perfect
cathartic moment for the end of an era, if you
will. Right. Made me feel sad. Yeah. Well,
like the movie turned out to be a love letter
to the superhero films of the early 2000s and
late 90s. You know, the Fox universe, the New
Line stuff with Blade. So it was like bittersweet
in that way. We're saying goodbye to all that
nostalgia. And now we're in this new consolidated
MCU universe. Sony notwithstanding. Fucking
Sony. The end to end credit scene with Johnny
Storm, though. I don't know if it was quite
worth staying for, but it did make me laugh
my ass off. I love that this was like a Boston
version of a Chinese storm and Chris Evans
brought out like his natural Boston accent.
That was that was good stuff. Yeah, I didn't
need it to set up anything new. I was happy
to just kind of add an extra laugh. That was
right for me.
fantasies collide and heroes clash, one podcast
network rises above the rest. Prepare yourself
for the ultimate showdowns in comic books, video
games, movies, and anime. The Dynomic Podcast
Network presents Console Combat, where video
game legends brawl every Monday. Comic Book
Titans smash every Tuesday. Max Destruction,
where TV and action heroes battle every Wednesday.
And Sendro World, where anime champions clash
every Thursday. Join us as we speculate on
the matches and armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge victorious.
Visit dynamicpodcast.com where we settle the
debate and settle the score.
Let's go ahead and get into our character breakdown,
starting with Deadpool, aka Wade Wilson, played
by, of course, Ryan Reynolds, who is Marvel
Jesus as far as I'm concerned. He is, I think,
Marvel Studios' biggest A-list talent now that
Robert Downey Jr. and Chris Evans have left,
although, you know, RDJ is coming back, but
I'm trying not to think about that too much.
Lame. So lame. Super lame. Yeah, this, I mean,
this is the largest R-rated opening weekend
of all time. Yeah, I think it's projected to
make around 205 million. And it's like the
eighth biggest opening worldwide of all time.
It's just it's going to make a billion dollars,
which is really good for, you know, people who
are talking about super hero fatigue. Yeah,
Ryan Reynolds is a gem. You know, he's just
as in command of the Deadpool role as a like
Robert Downey Jr. was for Iron Man or, you know,
Christopher Reeve for Superman back in the
70s or something like that. He just very much
personifies the role and not even just Deadpool,
even like the other variants that he played
like. Nice Pool and stuff like that. I thought
that was hilarious. I forgot about Nice Pool.
Van Milder. He was like regeneration. What?
The first time through I wasn't all that big
on Nice Pool, but the second time through I
think it worked better for me Sure. I think
one of my biggest laughs in the movie was when
Deadpool killed him on purpose. Oh, yeah You
know like early in the movie they had set that
up because he was like, you know You don't want
me as an owner in case anything happens to
you and he's like what could happen to me and
he's like all kinds of things. So you knew
it was kind of lurking there in the background.
I think this is the most sinister we've ever
seen Deadpool was in this movie. Like when he
got Johnny Storm killed and then he got nice
pull killed. It's kind of funny, especially
the part where he's like, you're going to live.
God damn it. Shout it. And he's like, I was
laughing my ass off at that point. The thing
that made me laugh the most and it happens very
quickly after Wolverine walks past the Deadpool
core with the dog and they're not shooting him.
When they cut back, they He's performing CPR
in a headless body. It only happens for a few
seconds. But I was giggling for so long to
the point where my son was like, what is so
funny? And I was like, I'll tell you later.
And then following that up with him brandishing
the gold plated guns, that was just so good.
Again, which was set up earlier, you knew he
was gonna end up with those. Right. My favorite
part with NicePool was so when he looked at
the camera, it was like, the proposal. And
Deadpool was like, is that what you think I
do? So Deadpool's arc here, I think, was about
coming out of depression. He got rejected from
the Avengers, which was just the final straw
for him in that moment that put him into a downward
spiral, leading to his retirement. It cost
him his relationship with Vanessa, but he comes
out of his funk, getting abducted by the TVA,
finding new purpose. He saves his friends and
his timeline from destruction in the process,
bonding with a larger team of heroes like Wolverine
and the Resistance. culminating in his attempt
to sacrifice himself for those he loves. But
here's the thing, in Deadpool 2, he saved Cable's
timeline from Firefist in the process bonding
with a larger team of heroes, Cable and X-Force,
which culminated in his self-sacrifice. Like
he died in that movie and Cable brought him
back. So the character growth that he went through
in Deadpool and Wolverine was pretty damn similar
to the character growth he already had in Deadpool
2. Like if you substitute Wade's sadness over
Vanessa's death, with Wade's depression over
his lack of meaning, you have almost nearly
identical arcs. I don't disagree. I found it's
more about sacrifice for others, not sacrifice
for himself. I felt like this one was a little
bit more about him himself, finding his personal
growth. They had that specific moment where
Happy talks about the Avengers, like, you know,
they're Avengers because people need them. And
at the end, when he is doing the time-ripper
thing, he says, I'm doing it for others, finally.
It's his growth for trying to put others above
him. I think that's valid fucking. I don't care.
We're still good I noticed that as I was watching
that thought that was really similar to the
second film You just kind of replace the foil
that was cable with the foil that is Wolverine
though I have to say I think Deadpool and Wolverine
played off each other a lot better than Deadpool
and cable So even if it was the same one we
can agree they did it better in this movie.
Yes, absolutely Absolutely. Can I add to that
real quick, though? Sure. That's Deadpool. Deadpool
constantly wants to be the hero and then gets
in his own way. And he tries to be the hero,
then gets in his own way. Wants to be a part
of team, gets in his own way. That's his whole
fucking arc over and over and over again. So
it doesn't bother me that it's the same thing
we're getting, but it's done better. Well,
Deadpool is a type of character that you don't
necessarily need to take seriously in that
way. So in some regards, he's above this type
of criticism. And that could either be to the
character's detriment or you guys are big Deadpool
fans, there's a reason that he's such a popular
character is because he's so charismatic and
endearing no matter what he goes through. And
you don't want him to change that much. Right.
You kind of want him to keep getting in his
own way. Yeah, valid, valid. But to get to Hugh
Jackman and Wolverine, I totally see him as
the heart of this film. He actually had a fantastic
character arc because he is also battling depression
here, which manifested with alcoholism and self-loathing.
His aim was to seek redemption for his past
when he abandoned his X-Men team who died. And
though he wasn't able to fix what happened
in his timeline, he was able to help save Wade's
and it was enough to help him get through his
depression and find a new life in that timeline
with his new surrogate daughter, X-23. I was
really glad that they brought her back into
Wade's timeline as well, because then he could
kind of go through the same arc that Logan did
in the movie. Logan. Yeah. The arc for Wolverine
is really the one that matters here as we've,
as I've kind of already set up Deadpool. doesn't
do these arcs all that well, you know, he just
kind of is going to revert to his, oh, I'm
the funny mouth and I kill people and all that
kind of stuff. Like say for the end of Deadpool
one, where he kills Ajax at the end, even though
Colossus is giving him that speech of, you
know, we don't kill them for five moments and
then he shoots Ajax in the head in this movie.
It parallels that, you know, but Wolverine is
the one who says, no, we're not going to kill
Cassandra Nova. He's the real hero. He is the
one who goes through this arc. And because
he is the important one, he is the hero guy.
He is that hero type and he is the anchor being.
I think it totally makes sense why he is the
one who goes through more of the character
arc than Deadpool. Yeah, absolutely. I do have
to say, though, that I thought the reason for
why he was so depressed and how he failed everybody
was going to be much more interesting. And
I was at first initially. disappointed that
was basically, oh, he went to a bar and while
he was away, everyone died. I thought it was
going to be something more like in Logan where,
you know, Professor X started to get seizures
and those seizures kind of killed everyone.
So for it to be something so simple, again,
initially I found kind of disappointing, but
later on I kind of appreciated how simple it
was, I guess, because that really wasn't what
the story was about. All he needed to do was
kind of feel that survivor's guilt, which Logan
is bound to do because he has such a high longevity.
He was going to outlive everyone anyway, and
they could have gone with that even. But that
ultimately wasn't as important to a story arc
as the fact that he did grow. We don't need
to make things more convoluted than they are.
I thought it was pretty well done. Well, it
wasn't just that he got drunk and kind of ran
away. He talked about how he basically went
to a berserker rage and he killed fucking everybody.
And then. All humans turned on mutants afterwards
because of that. That's true. So he started
that because of his rage. He was the downfall
of all mutants. And to add on to what Adam
said, the first time he tells you what happens,
he says he was away when they revisit it. At
the end, he actually says, it wasn't just that
I was away. I walked away. I heard them basically
being killed and I walked away. Then when I
saw the bodies, I went into my rage. So. It
was not just that he happened to be away. It
was his active choice to walk away from it.
Yeah. And then his guilt with that. And that's
why he was wearing the suit. The pajamas, as
Deadpool called them, because he felt guilty
about rejecting that earlier. What did you
guys think of the suit? God damn, that suit
looks good. Yeah, I loved the suit. I have
thoughts on the cowl. Yeah. I mean, the cowl,
you when I saw it, I was like, oh, I mean,
of course, you know, extra another extra inch.
just came on me. But after a while you kind
of realize, okay, that's why they didn't do
this. Right. It's the eyes. Also, it's hard
to make that mask a perfect size because I feel
like the wings needed to be slightly bigger
to make them look more comic accurate, but at
the same time, they would look ridiculous.
The blow job handles? Yes, if they were actually
that big. So it was a hard thing to do in live
action. I think they did the absolute best they
could. They stuck to the white eyes because
they're already doing it with Deadpool. Although
I feel like they didn't make them as expressive
as Deadpool's are because I know that the way
they do that is he actually takes the eyepieces
out when they're filming and they track his
eyebrow movements so that Deadpool's eyes are
expressive. I don't feel like they did that
with Wolverines and I wish they had. Yeah,
I think the issue was his eye line was always
off. It was like he was blind when he should
have been looking at Wade. you have that kind
of line that really shows you where his head
is pointing. And it's kind of an issue in live
action. Kind of like Batman. Yeah. I thought
his Wolverine suit was great. It did look a
little football patty at times. I actually
think I slightly preferred the brown and yellow,
the mustard and brown one that they use for
that short little moment for the Hulk thing.
I was like, that looks a little bit more simpler.
I think I liked it just a slightly bit better,
but still super exciting to see him in a more
Accurate costume for sure. That was great I
kind of feel like the whole reason they did
the Deadpool core scene at the end and I could
be wrong Was just so that they could show the
mask I kind of like that whole scene didn't
really need to be in the movie I think that's
when the movie started to feel long for me.
I don't really care about the Deadpool core
personally Well, that's because you're wrong
I think if they just put the mask on earlier
when they were going up against Cassandra Nova's
team I think that would have been perfectly
fine. I would have been happy with that. It
all kind of felt a little bit extra I can see
where you're coming from because the Deadpool
core was shoehorned in they could have immediately
just gone to destroy the time Ripper because
they already had really their third act fight
back in the void But here's the thing how can
you have a multiversal Deadpool movie and not
have the Deadpool core you have to I was just
gonna Say they had to have them because this
is the only place you can do it anywhere else
It doesn't make any sense. Yeah secret oars
Well, because that would take over too much.
Yeah, there's going to be too much in too much
Deadpool. But I mean, they tied it in well enough.
They set it up, you know, multiple times. We
you know, we when we first met Nice Pool, he
kind of alluded to it. And then Cassandra Nova
said Deadpool's are a diamond dozen here, but
we do, you know, this is like our first Wolverine.
So we got little glimpses. And then when they
came out for the Deadpool nerds like us, I
was in there looking at like, oh my God, which
ones do I recognize? Which ones have I seen
in the comics? There's only one I'm gonna mention
that disappointed me that wasn't in there because
I imagine John was as well If he thought of
it is agent X was I would have loved to see
him It's somewhere in the background as well,
but that's it. I see I don't see him as a Deadpool
variant I know he is but I kind of see him.
I see him as his own thing. Sure. So fair Let's
go ahead and move on to the villains of the
piece. I Think the Deadpool films their main
weakness has always been the villains sure especially
Deadpool 2 I didn't love either Cassandra Nova
or Mr. Paradox. Dude, I loved Cassandra Nova.
What are you talking about? I'm with Jonathan.
Cassandra Nova I really liked. I guess I've
never really been a fan of Cassandra Nova from
the comics. Now she was a Grant Morrison creation.
She's the twin of professor Charles Xavier.
In the comics, I always saw her as more bitter
and nasty and stuff like that. But here she
was like deceptively sweet. And I guess that
kind of threw off my preconceived notions of
what the character. should and would be like
in the movie. I don't know, it sounded like
maybe she was still a little bitter, but I mean,
it's not gonna be the exact same thing. I mean,
she was evil. I will say, that shit sounds like
something Grant Morrison would do, so I totally
understand that. I'm actually with them, I actually
really liked her. I liked her better even the
second time than the first time, because there's
a lot of things that I noticed about her the
second time. Some of the mannerisms in her facial
expressions were really good. The fact that
they actually elongated her fingers. which made
her seem more creepy. She was fairly creepy.
I thought the actress did a good job. Yes, I
agree. And I'll be honest, I'm kind of glad
we didn't get like an all out fight at the end
with her, because by the time we got to that,
I was already fought out. Also, realistically,
they weren't gonna win a fight with her. They
had to do something out of the ordinary in order
to, well, say finish her off sounds weird.
But, I'd finish her off. It's a Deadpool review,
you're fine. Especially when she talked about
flicking her bean. Yeah, to end you- oh man.
Yeah, I was happy there. Now I got a new box
set, I gotta go find- Yeah, I'm gonna listen
to White Flag tonight. There's a box set? White
Flag is Dido, isn't it? Oh yeah, you're right,
that's Dido, my bad. I always confuse him.
Come on, man. It's the same person. Fine. I
thought the way they portrayed Kassandra Nova's
powers was really fascinating here because,
you know, she has all the powers of Professor
X in addition to his potential latent powers
according to his DNA. So- She has telekinesis.
She has the ability to phase. And I thought
the way that they combined those aspects here
by giving her more tactile telepathy and she
has to like phase into their minds in order
to read their minds. That was creepy as hell.
Oh, yeah. It was incredible. Very cinematic.
Great decision to do that. Absolutely horrifying.
It's just a new great way to visualize telepathy
without. doing the same old boring thing of,
you know, two people standing across from each
other. One of them raises their fingers to their
forehead and then, you know, they read their
thoughts. I guess to move over to Paradox, the
other villain, I actually really like the actor.
I thought he was wonderful. I liked, you know,
the very Britishness about him. And he's the
white collar villain in this one. I do think
he had some motivational issues. I thought
it was kind of strange that they're going off
grid and they're going to build this time ripper
and prune stuff themselves. But yet he also
decided to pull Deadpool out because his bosses
told him to. Like, why are you listening to
your bosses on this when you're just gonna
like turn around and not listen to them for
other stuff? Right. I will say this, the one
thing they say is that basically that timeline
was going to get pruned, it was just gonna
take 2,000 years for it to happen. But I just
think he just wasn't patient. Also, my first
thought was why would he have so many of these
people with him? Because he had like a whole
section of people. However... If we're taking
this to kind of happen not long after Loki
season two, their decision to change the way
they do things is a very stark change in a
very fast time. And I could see that being iffy
for people who are used to doing the same thing
for probably thousands of years at that point
and not wanting to change and say, oh, this
guy wants to go back to the way we did do it.
I'm more comfortable there. Let's go with him.
It's not a good motivation though. It's my biggest
issue with the film. was to destroy Wade's
timeline because it was more efficient to do
so and it would impress him to his higher-ups
so that he would become leader of the TVA. But
since Loki took over the timelines and they're
allowing these branches to grow and a multiverse
to exist, the TVA's function is no longer to
prune timelines. You're assuming that he knows
about Loki. Even if he doesn't, his directive
would be to let the multiverse thrive. TVA has
reset charges that they used to use to prune
timelines all the time. I don't understand why
he had to use this time ripper device. It was
very strange and definitely not in accordance
with a lot of what we saw in the Loki television
series. Also considering that, you know, they're
in the TVA, time doesn't exist, there was no
reason why they were like, oh, we have to rush
this 2000 year thing. Exactly. That doesn't
make sense. And it was clear that even if he
did prune this timeline with the time ripper,
he's not going to impress anybody with it. They
would have actually admonished him and they
did. for what he tried to do. So it just made
no sense and because his whole motivation doesn't
make sense, the story almost falls apart because
of that. Also I have an issue with anchor beings.
The idea of anchor beings, it makes me wonder
how any timeline branch survives more than
a couple thousand years because humans only
have so long of a lifespan. The idea of anchor
beings means that eventually any timeline branch
is going to die and that the multiverse is
then essentially self-containing. and the TVA
beforehand would seem irrelevant prior to Loki
taking on his throne. I don't know, that's reading
a lot into it, I think. The issue of anchor
beings didn't really bother me. I actually liked
the idea that they exist and that Wolverine
would be one of them. I'm sure there is some
kind of, you know, paradoxical nature to it,
but then it bothered me so much as we never
learned who Paradox was like answering to or
working for, because it seemed like... He really
wasn't answering to the TVA. He was answering
to some kind of like shadow organization, perhaps
within it or even outside of it. And we never
got that closure. Well, he was working for himself.
He was selfish. He wanted to be in charge of
the TVA. It was all bullshit. So then why pull
out Deadpool? Why pull out Deadpool at all?
Because his higher ups wanted Deadpool to be
part of the Sacred Timeline because it's part
of his destiny. He has some kind of big role
to play in the Sacred Timeline's future. Oh,
yeah. He has to die in Thor's arms. Yeah, exactly.
So he could die. The motivational problems
were there. But at the same time, it didn't
anger me like it seems to have angered you,
Joseph, because at the end of it, it's a fucking
Deadpool movie, and I was able to kind of cut
that cord from my head and be like, alright,
fine, fuck it. Also, I'm gonna say this is
why I think you're wrong. First of all, you're
assuming that all the anchor beings are happening
now. Instead of maybe one timeline, anchor being
doesn't happen for another 5000 years. In which
case, that timeline doesn't get trimmed. Also,
everything up until this point, up until Loki,
was one timeline, yes? Correct. Yeah, it was
the secret timeline. Everything else was being
pruned. So in this case, anchor beings is probably
a new thing because they have all these different
timelines. Some people say like if it doesn't
happen on screen, it shouldn't happen, but
to me, I don't need to hear about them discovering
anchor beings. They just say, hey, we discovered
it. Each of these timelines has an anchor being.
So all of these little variant timelines are
not all going to be the same length. I think
it just brings it back to even if that were
the case, the TVA never needed to exist because
the multiverse was self-sustaining in that
sense errant timelines would eventually die.
But Kang started the pruning because he didn't
want the multiverse wars. And so even with like
over these thousands of years, that war still
might have happened. And so it got pruned because
he, you know, knew that the even the sacred
timeline would get exploded. And so that was
kind of why he started the prune stuff and
the TVA. So, I mean, yes, it could be self-sustaining,
but it wasn't about it being self-sustaining.
It was about Kang stopping the war. The other
Kang's. Yeah. And now that is the TVA's new
primary function, is stopping the multiversal
war. It's all convoluted. Super! As John says.
So convoluted. Multiverses suck.
I think that does it for the character breakdown,
so let's go ahead and get into our story highlights.
Deadpool visits Logan's grave where he's attacked
by a group of time variance authority hunters.
In a flashback to when Deadpool used Cable's
time travel device, he ends up on the Sacred
Timeline in 2018, where he tries to join the
Avengers in an interview with Happy Hogan,
but is rejected. I thought it was really interesting
that typically the Deadpool films don't take
the credit scenes seriously. And like this one
didn't, but like it actually had actual credits
for the people that were involved in the production.
And I kind of missed those gags. But it was
really funny to see Deadpool dancing to N-Sync.
Oh, yeah. I mean, it was a ton of fun. They
set up what you're getting. You're getting a
lot of dumb fun. And I agree, like as the first
two movies, they had like the fake title cards.
And this one, they use extra real ones. But
I do specifically want to mention because of
that scene, all of us were worried about how
the fuck are we going to respectfully bring
and deal with Logan and then we don't. And
that's so perfectly fucking done that way. And
only a way a Deadpool could do it is, yeah,
we're not going to be respectful. We're going
to literally play with his fucking bones, desecrate
his body. And we'd love it. And I love every
second of that. It was so good. I was horrified.
I never understood the confusion because it
always said that Logan takes place in the future,
like 2029 or some shit. There is nothing to
say that Deadpool and Wolverine had to take
place after that. So I was never confused about
how they were going to include him in the story
because it's fucking time. Logan was set in
the future. Jesus H Christ people, it is not
that difficult. I have the same issue with people
who couldn't figure out why in Endgame affecting
the past does not affect the future. And I've
talked to so many people who are like, I just
understand. It is not fucking hard. It's not
hard to understand that when you move to the
past that past is not your past It is now your
future and it is a completely different Timeline
essentially in this case, but it's funny cuz
Deadpool 2 they use the dead they use back
to the future style because the bear that cable
was carrying was burned and then when he Sacrificed
himself at the end the bear turned to bright
and it's showing that his kid didn't die. So
they Fucking, well granted at that time, there
wasn't part of the MCU, but it's- I mean, you
could also say that it was not cyclical. He
went back and changed it, and what he went
forward to was a completely new timeline. And
look at Days of Future Past as well, you know,
the way they handled time there. I guess time
works differently depending on which branch
of the Marvel multiverse you're in. Yeah, I
was one of the people who was not thrilled
when I found out that Hugh Jackman was returning
to the role of Logan, not because I was wondering
how they were going to do it story-wise. but
because we already had that cathartic goodbye
for the character. But I will admit that I am
happy that he decided to make the return back
and that they brought him back in such a fantastic
way. I liked the heartfelt scene of when Deadpool
was trying to join the Avengers because he really
felt like he wanted it. And I thought that
was a great bit of acting. That confused me.
That really confused me. Okay. So I get he
breaks the fourth wall, right? And so he would
know about the Avengers. But the fact that
they established him as being on Earth 1005,
whatever it was. So he traveled through the
multiverse to Earth 616. He's wearing a cable's
thing. So that's how he moved across. But so
he was willing to leave his friends and everything
that he had saved to be a part of the Avengers.
And yet when he was offered that opportunity
later on, that's when he got upset. Six years
changes a man. OK, that's a great question.
I didn't think of that. I guess my assumption
is that he probably would have wanted to bring
his friends and family over to the Sacred Timeline
with him if he got the job. I don't know. In
2024, in his native timeline, Wade works as
a used car salesman with his friend Peter, who
throws Wade a surprise birthday party with
all their friends, including his ex-girlfriend
Vanessa. A group of TVA hunters show up and
take Wade to meet Mr. Paradox, an agent who
offers him a place on the Sacred Timeline.
Paradox informs Wade that due to the death of
Logan, who was his timeline's anchor being,
his universe is slowly dying. He goes on to
tell Wade that he intends to speed up the process
using a time ripper device to prune Wade's universe
in order to improve the TVA's efficiency so
he can get promoted to the head of the organization.
Unwilling to see his friends die, Wade steals
the TVA Tempad to visit Logan's grave. I love
this scene when the TVA hunters show up at
the party and he's like, this isn't like Pretty
Women. We're going to be kissing. Oh, yeah.
This is the one where he talked about pegging
is not new for me, but new for Disney. Right.
That's the and then the wink to the camera.
I mean, that's perfect. Absolutely perfect.
Hilarious. Deadpool travels the multiverse looking
for a Wolverine variant substitute to save
his timeline. He visits short Wolverine, Brown
Suit Wolverine, Age of Apocalypse Wolverine
Patch Crucifixion Wolverine. Old Man Logan and
Cavalryne before coming upon an alcoholic Wolverine
whom he brings back to the TVA. Mr. Paradox
calls this variant the worst Wolverine who
abandoned his X-Men during their tragic deaths.
He then uses a time stick to send Deadpool
and Wolverine to the void at the end of time.
And just wanted to reiterate, Cavalryne is
awesome. He's a better Wolverine than he ever
was a Superman.
The crucifixion Wolverine. was dark as hell.
I mean, that's like a classic iconic cover
from the comics. I remember the cover. When
the X-Men went up against the Reavers. But
like seeing it in real life, I was like, holy
shit, you don't want to be that Wolverine for
sure. It also made me realize that I don't want
them to actually cast a five foot three actor
to play the character. No. Seeing short Wolverine.
That's hilarious. I was cracking up the whole
time just because of that. And then I stopped
laughing when I saw Cavalereen. Sucker.
In the Void, Deadpool and Wolverine fight before
Deadpool promises that if they escape the Void
they can not only save his timeline, but also
have the TVA save the X-Men from Wolverine's
timeline. They're discovered by a Human Torch
variant who tells Deadpool and Wolverine about
Cassandra Nova, Professor X's twin sister who
rules over the Void, and about the resistance
force in the Borderlands formed against her.
The three are attacked by Cassandra Nova's
gang who brings them before her. And I do think-
You know, obviously we mentioned already the
importance of the cameos, getting some of these
moments. But fan service was that was this
movie. And we're getting things like, you know,
Wolverine and Deadpool fighting. We're getting
Wolverine and Sabretooth going up against each
other. And it didn't bother me. I know a lot
of people might have wanted like an actual bigger
battle with them. Now we got a lot of other
battles down the line, so I didn't care. You
know, he just kind of sliced his head off pretty
quickly. And, you know, in the comics, he beheaded
him. And that's how Sabretooth died. It didn't
bother me one bit, but, you know, I enjoyed
seeing all those characters come in kind of
one by one and be like, oh, shit, there's pyro.
Oh, shit. There's this person. There's that
bro. Tyler mains back. Those were wonderful
moments. I mean, John and I have talked about
nostalgia ad nauseam. I love nostalgia. I live
on nostalgia. I mean, I can just feed off of
it and I sustain myself. You had a whole podcast
about it. Exactly. And so it makes me happy.
I have to say next to a cavalry. Tyler Maine
as Sabretooth was the cameo that I was most
disappointed in because I expected a bigger
match between the two. I would have taken a
bigger match between those two and maybe skipped
the whole brawl and the Honda Odyssey fight.
Oh, you're fucking wrong. The Odyssey was amazing.
What? That was so good. That was such a good
fight. The Honda Odyssey fucks, man. Yeah, the
Honda Odyssey fucks. I don't know. So good.
The first fight between Wolverine and Deadpool
where you see Wolverine running on all fours
and stuff, very animalistic. Holy shit. Love
it. Oh, that was so good. See, there were too
many fights between the two and it just felt
redundant to me because no, they're not hurting
each other anyway. They have fucking healing
factor. So why do I need to see this five fucking
times in the movie? You saw it twice in the
movie. Yeah, and that's what they would do
with the twice what they would fucking do. Yes,
exactly. If you look behind Adam over his right
shoulder, there is a cover of Deadpool holding
up Wolverine's body because that is all they
fucking did in the comics was fighting each
other. Wolverine 88 this is one of my favorite
comic covers of all time. Yep, same so fucking
good same nice color That's a great one. That
is really good. They can't hurt each other though.
It's wasted film doesn't matter It doesn't
matter if you ever if you ever just wanted to
get out aggression Have you never punched a
wall or something you know the wall is not gonna
win or you're not gonna win against the wall
I don't think I have I did that just a few hours
ago When I lost my microphone cable They're
just they just got to get out aggression. They
don't care. They're they're definitely trying
to kill each other But they just know it's not
gonna happen And I think the two fights were
so drastically different in style because you
get a wide Brawl right out in the open for
the first one and then this really nice contained
almost defensive fight Inside of the car. I
loved it. I could have gone with another one.
Yeah for sure Oh, we kind of got it with the
Deadpool core fight It was will ring going up
against a whole legion of Deadpools Cassandra
Nova kills the human torch and buries Wolverine
underground with her telekinesis before using
her tactile telepathy to read Deadpool's mind.
Wolverine stabs Cassandra Nova, who heals and
leaves the pair to be devoured by Eliath, a
temporal entity that feeds on reality in the
void at the end of time. Now you guys all saw
Loki, right? Absolutely. Yeah, I'm sorry. I'm
reminded of, my son and I were discussing it
after the second time and he goes, you know,
the thing I don't understand is I didn't identify
with like, Eliath? What was his name? And I
go, bitch, you saw Loki season one. He goes,
yeah, but I didn't really remember. I'm like,
well, that's on you. Why is that my problem?
Deadpool and Wolverine escape Aliyah on a jet
powered Sentinel leg and decide to find the
resistance force in the Borderlands. They come
across Dogpool and his owner, Nicepool, who
lends them his Honda Odyssey. This is so ridiculous
to read out loud. Can we talk to Dogpool for
a little bit? I think the casting choice for
Dogpool was perfect. The most ugly dog of all
time. They've actually won the 2023 Britain's
Ugliest Dog Award. Oh, really? They cast that
thing. Yes. And it was perfect. Definitely
didn't look like the comics version of Deadpool.
But yeah, I super appreciated this version.
I didn't care. Yeah, I didn't care. Yeah. Wolverine
learns that Deadpool lied about the possibility
of the TVA fixing the tragedy of his timeline
and the two fight, knocking each other unconscious.
They're discovered by an X 23 variant who takes
them to the borderlands where they meet the
resistance consisting of Electra, Blade and
Gambit. Together, they decide to attack Cassandra
Nobra's brotherhood to steal Juggernaut's helmet
which offers protection from her psychic powers.
Speaking of Juggernaut, I'm really disappointed
that Vinnie Jones didn't come back for his
role. A little bit. This random dude did nothing
for me. Like Vinnie Jones, Olivia Munn, I don't
know if they didn't cast them because they really
didn't need to. They didn't have speaking lines
or anything like that or if it was a budget
concern. Maybe both. Vinnie Jones was quoted
in an interview saying they called him for the
role. But he didn't want to do it because he
didn't like wearing the juggernaut suit, but
he fucked up Why is he being a little bitch?
He is. One day at work. Come on, Vinny. I tell
you what it would have been funny. That whole
thing was a Mad Max sort of pseudoism If they'd
gotten the giant guy from Fury Road to be Juggernaut
Yeah, was it Nathan Jones? Yeah, that would
have been a funny twist That would have been
great. At least then it would have kind of made
sense with the Mad Max name Honestly, Vinny
Jones probably just grew a beard, got lost the
abs after all these years. That's what CGI
is for. Yeah, fair. The Resistance fights the
Brotherhood, and X-23 is able to decapitate
Juggernaut and throw Deadpool the helmet, while
Cassandra Nova uses her telepathy to try and
convince Wolverine to join her crew. Her psychic
powers are subdued, then Pyro shoots her, revealed
to be working with Mr. Paradox in exchange for
a way out of the void. Knowing that she is
their only way back home, Wolverine chooses
to save her life. In exchange, she uses a Doctor
Strange variant sling ring. to open a portal
out of the void. I don't think it's a Doctor
Strange sling rings. I heard a theory on this
and I'm choosing to believe it. She said like
a half-rate magician. I think it is a variant
of the shitty magician that they had in She-Hulk
that they went to court over. Johnny Blades
or Donny Blades. I think it was him. Yeah.
Could have been, yeah. I do feel like Strange
would have put up a better fight. I agree.
Kind of thing. Now, can the sling rings go through
time? Cause I feel like then why do you need
the time stone? Oh. Did they go through time?
Well, it went through time because like all
time ends at that point. It's like the end point
in time. Right. Then you know what? Yes, they
can. OK. All right. Sure, Jonathan. Damn it.
It's a good point. Who cares? It does seem
like it would be really risky to send any sort
of magician back to the void because they could
just escape pretty easily. Yeah. Back in Deadpool's
timeline, he and Wolverine learned that Mr.
Paradox's time ripper device is nearly ready.
Cassandra Nova also comes through the portal
to take over the Time Ripper and destroy all
time except for the Void. Before Deadpool and
Wolverine can stop her, the Deadpool core also
comes through the portal and they're forced
to fight. Peter, aka Peterpool, comes in to
stop the fighting. Okay, so Peterpool, this
is the level of absurdity in Deadpool that I
feel like just... There's a certain absurdist
humor threshold that I have, and Peterpool was
that. I was like, really? That ended the whole
battle with the Deadpool core? It made sense.
That the do us mock in a side of him. I didn't
know I needed it, but I'm good with it. Like
I am. I'm totally fine with it. Well, for some
reason, Deadpool had such a high regard of Peter.
Nobody knows why he was his favorite member
of the X-Horse. I like the idea of him having
such a high regard for Peter, that all the
Deadpools having a high regard for their universe
is Peter, that they would stop fighting just
for him. It made sense. OK, I'll say two things.
One. They actually kind of, I don't know if
this is directly related to this, but in my
mind it is, they actually set up in the scene
where they're, uh, the two are in the diner,
about Deadpool having ADHD, and being distracted
by Peter is something that would absolutely
distract all of the Deadpools, and them having
ADHD. Second of all, did you guys see the fucking
cojones in the suit? I tried not to, but they
were there. Impossible, don't you? They were
enormous. The moose knuckle was... They were
like, grapefruit sized. I think he has some
kind of like illness or something. They're
swollen. Elephantitis. I hope I'm not misremembering
this, but I think I could also see there was
like a little patch under his belly button that
was still open. You kind of see the ring in
the chain from the nipple rings and chain that
they show earlier. That's why it's funny. That
was such a good gag. And the fact that Hunter
B-15, I guess she's Judge B-15 now, was like
really into him. I thought that was hilarious.
She's like, damn, you look good in that suit.
Yeah. Peter Poles, man. Peter Poles. Peter fucks.
Let's be honest. Yeah, that's like a hot Odyssey.
Deadpool and Wolverine learn from Paradox that
in order to stop Cassandra Nova, one of them
will have to sacrifice themselves to destroy
the Time Ripper device. They both attempt to
make the sacrifice, allowing them to survive
while destroying the machine and Cassandra
Nova in the process. My least favorite part
of the movie was the exposition given by Paradox
on how anti-matter and matter combine to destroy
the universes. And only one person. can't stop
it and they must complete the circuit, but it
will destroy them. And I'm like, shut up, just
do it. I don't care how you explain it, just
say you got to destroy the device. I mean,
they needed to go through that though. I will
say though, if they didn't say that, then enough
of the nerds would bitch about why did it work
and blah, blah. Yeah, it would have been confusing.
That was cool with it. I like how the time ripper,
the way it destroyed universes was exactly
like the spaghettification that we saw in Loki
season two. I always thought that was a cool
effect. Yeah, that was cool. to me makes sense
because now you can identify what is happening
in the world. TVA Judge B-15 arrives to arrest
Mr. Paradox, revealing to Deadpool and Wolverine
that the timeline is now healing due to Wolverine
being the new anchor. Or at least that's how
I understood it. She returns the resistance
members from the void to their respective timelines,
including X-23 who joins Logan in Wade's timeline.
They all celebrate with Wade's friends and
Wade reconciles with Vanessa, telling her he
saved the universe for her. And that's the
end of the movie. of each of the Deadpool movies
has been Vanessa. You know, that is his heart.
And so kind of always tying in his love for
her and the romantic element. I was very good
with that. The whole relationship between the
two when they weren't together was just heartbreaking
to me, like seeing Vanessa talking about her
new boyfriend through work and stuff like that
and like the whole breakup conversation. He's
like, just say it like you don't want me anymore.
Like that was hard to watch, but it was really
nice that it ended in the way that it did where
they're coming back together because. They're
crazy, match each other, and they belong together.
That brings us to the end of the review. I don't
know if you guys have heard, but we're on Rotten
Tomatoes now. Yeah, you guys haven't said it
every five seconds. So I gotta give my blurb.
The titular duo delivers a one-two punch with
their iconic performances and brutal action
scenes in a chaotic, messy, and hilarious film
full of fun surprises. I'm giving the movie
four out of five stars a fresh rating on Rotten
Tomatoes. Can I convince you otherwise? I can
be convinced. Okay. So let's go through the
Deadpool films. Deadpool 1, you gave a 4. You
gave Deadpool 2 a 3.5 and you gave this one
a 4 now currently. I argue that this is the
best Deadpool film of the bunch. I think this
is the most amount of humor, the most amount
of fan service and overall the most fun film.
Yes, it has some faults, which I will be willing
to say maybe doesn't deserve a 5. But I want
to push hard for that 4.5 because going through
some of your other movies. Here comes we've
got. Yeah. OK, buddy. Here it comes. Buckle
up, Buttercup. Yeah. Blue Beetle was a four.
This is better than Blue Beetle. Simple as
that. Across the Spider-Verse is an amazing
film. 4.5 I think this is pretty much this
is the right kind of Deadpool movie. This is
the movie you need for Deadpool. I think that's
why this deserves to be there. Guardians 3,
4.5, this is as good as Guardians 3, without
question, without question. Loki season 2, 4.5,
this is as good as Loki season 2. Wakanda forever,
this is as good as, if not better than Wakanda
forever, I can absolutely tell you that. Multiverse
of Madness, this is as good or better than Multiverse
of Madness, which you gave a 4.5. Well, the
Batman you gave a five, and I think that's fantastic.
The Batman worked so well as a Batman movie,
this works so well as a Deadpool movie. The
one I really want to give it home to is you
gave Eternals a fucking four. You cannot give
this the same score as the Eternals. This is
a four point five. Are you fucking kidding me?
I knew this was coming. Reach within your soul,
sir. You have to give this the proper rating.
So the way I do this is if I have no notes
on a movie, really, if it's pretty good, I give
it four and a half. If I have no notes and
it exceeds my expectations, I give it a five.
If I have notes, but it's good, I give it a
four. That being said, any rating. I ever really
give could be plus or minus half a star. I
think this has notes, but also exceeds expectations.
So it's kind of got you got to bump it back
up for that. You're not wrong. And all the DC
movies that you listed, I don't take any credit
for it because Jonathan always rates his shit
half a star higher than he should. You just
said it fluctuates within a half a star. Yeah,
but you always round up. I always round down.
OK. In this case, you know, I. Debated heavily
whether or not this should be four or five
stars and I'm willing to Four point five Round
up Four point five Come on with me guys Four
point five Wait, even you Jonathan Four Alright
Okay, sure It's not a hard decision to make
really I could easily go four point five with
this review It's a good movie I had a lot of
fun John, I'm assuming that you would also rate
it four point five or would you go higher?
Um You know what I give it? I give it a ten
A ten, a fucking ten Ten I'm giving
I'm giving it a five. I want to go back and
see it again. Very few of these movies do I
actually want to go back and see it again while
it's in theaters. I'm like, oh cool, I can't
wait to see that again when it comes out on
Disney+. I want to go back and see it again.
I've already seen it twice. I'm waiting for
friends to call me and say, hey, have you seen
this? I'm going to be like, no, I haven't. I'm
going to go back and see it again. It's a fucking
five for me. Because you want to see, you want
to be there when they gasp. at fucking flame
on when they see Wesley Snipes, you want to
you're going to get joy out of those moments
from them as well. Experiencing the movie again
vicariously through people who haven't seen
it yet is something that I love doing with these
Marvel films. It's why I saw movies like the
first Avengers and even the first Deadpool movie
multiple times. I think I saw all of those
like six times in the theater. I would absolutely
see this movie again. It's really fun to experience.
It's a perfect summer movie. So a lot of people
who have been know that I don't put as much
stock into entertainment and quote unquote fun
as I do story. Like I want to be moved in these
theatrical experiences. I don't always necessarily
need to just be entertained. You must be fun
at parties. I tell him that all the time. I'm
sorry, Jonathan, I really am. That was low
hanging. Now that said, while the story I think
was bare bones here, I did think it was touching.
I did think it was moving. Do you think there
was heart to it? Absolutely. You know, entertainment
is just the cherry on top. And so when Joseph
and I were talking about, you know, oh, you
know, what would you rate this? That's usually
all we talk about prior to doing a review is,
you know, what is your star rating? I was saying
four point five. Yeah. And I think I'm going
to stick with that because I do think this was
intentionally so the ultimate Deadpool movie.
Yeah. Very fair. There you go. Four point five,
guys. Yeah. We did it! We did it! A lot of
that has to do with the fact that Adam has badgered
me since we did that initial Deadpool review
constantly about how I rated that movie wrong.
So, this is for you, man. This is for you.
Thank you. Thank you. But that does it for this
review, guys. John, Adam, thank you guys so
much for being able to do this review with us.
We truly appreciate having you guys on board.
We're big fans and we're really sad that Blast
From Our Past podcast is gone. I'm not gonna
beg you guys to bring it back because I know
that you guys are busy, you're busy men. But
I do expect it to eventually return one day.
Well, much like Hugh Jackman retiring from
Wolverine, never say never. Yes. Alright. Actually,
I want to reach out and say for your final
episode that you guys did for that show, you
had a bunch of shows call in trying to advertise
their podcasts so that viewers can leave your
show and go on to theirs. I- did not submit
a recording in time and that will be my lifelong
regret that I didn't get to do that for you
guys final episode. I did think it was weird
at the time when Adam was like, oh yeah, you
guys could plug your show. I'm like, I don't
wanna plug my show. I just wanna talk about
how much Blastformer Past meant to me as a listener.
So I never got around to it. I apologize, but
yeah, your show meant a lot to me. You know
what the good thing is? There's still 300 episodes
still out there that you can go back and revisit.
That's true. And I encourage listeners to do
so and to listen to Throwback Trivia take down.
And we'll have to have you guys again on sometime
in the future. For the Cavalry movie, maybe.
You're right. No, no. I'll just sit out on
that review. I refuse a boycott. Always a joy
to have those guys on the show reviewing films
with us. Remember to check out their podcast
Throwback Trivia Take Down, of which their
first episode, Jonathan and I were actually
contestants. And we went head to head on Marvel
and DC trivia. It was a whole lot of fun. Go
check them out. Absolutely. That does it for
this review. AJ9K help close this out. Thanks
for listening to Dynamic duel. Visit the show's
website at dynamicduel.com and follow us on
Instagram at dynamicduelpodcast. You can support
the show on Patreon at patreon.com slash dynamicduel
and joining a tier that works for you, or by
rating and reviewing Dynamic duel on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, Podchaser or on our website. Don't
forget to listen to the other shows in the DynaMic
Podcast Network, including Max Destruction,
Senjow World and Console Combat. In our next
episode, we're doing another review. Actually,
we'll be doing reviews for a while. But this
will be of my adventures with Superman season
two. I really enjoyed season one. I have not
even started season two yet. No, that's a lie.
I've seen the first episode, maybe first two
episodes. Anyway, I'll be reviewing all of
the episodes next week. But that does it for
this episode. We want to give a big thanks
to our executive producers, Ken Johnson, John
Swarovski, Zachary Hepburn. Dustin Abelcom,
Miggy Mathengian, Brandon Estregard, Nathaniel
Wagoner, Levi Yaten, Austin Wazilovski, AJ
Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam
Spies, Andrew Shunk, Dean Molesky, Devin Davis,
and Joseph Kerstink for helping make this podcast
possible. We'll talk to you guys next week.
Up up and away, true believers. She's a megalomaniacal
psychotic asshole, a finger licking dead inside
pixie slapping third rate dime store nut milk.
she can lick my god damn cinnamon ring clean
and kick rocks all the way to bald hell. In
fact, I don't give a shit if she removes all
my skin and pops me like some nightmarish blood
balloon. If the last thing I do in this godforsaken
cum gutter existence is light that fuckbox on
fire, I still won't die happy. That's right,
I won't be happy until I've urinated on her
freshly barbecued corpse and husk remains while
gargling juggernaut juggernuts. And you can
quote me.