This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
And welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters and stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Marvelous Joe. And I'm his twin brother,
Johnny DC. And in this episode, it's a big
one, guys. It's our 375th episode. We are going
to find out who would win in a fight between
the teams of the Legion of Doom versus the Masters
of Evil. Basically, it's the Evil Justice League.
versus the Evil Avengers for Marvel and DC.
We've done 10 of these team duels now, including
Justice League versus Avengers, Titan versus
X-Men, Justice Society versus Fantastic Four,
Suicide Squad versus Defenders, Justice League
Dark versus Midnight Suns, Arkham Asylum versus
Sinister Six, Young Justice versus Young Avengers,
Flash Rogues versus Brotherhood of Mutants,
Doom Patrol versus the Guardians of the Galaxy,
we even threw a bonus one in there last Halloween.
of Deceased vs. The Marvel Zombies. Yeah, if
any of those episodes sound like they strike
your fancy, be sure to listen to those in addition
to listening to this episode because they're
a lot of fun, a lot of work goes into them,
and we really appreciate when you guys check
them out. Before we get into that matchup, we
have an interview with the hosts of one of
the podcasts in the DynaMic Podcast Network,
Console Combat. We'll get John and Dean on
the line later on. If you like video games,
you owe it to yourself to check this interview
out. As always, we list our segment times in
our episode description, so feel free to check
out the show notes if you want to skip ahead
to a particular topic. Our artificially intelligent
Duel simulator AJ9K has a quick message for
our listeners, so listen up. Why hello there.
Do you love listening and chatting about Marvel
and DC? Then become a part of the dynamic Duel
community on Patreon, where you can choose from
three tiers. The dynamic 2-0 tier lets you
listen to this podcast without ads and gives
you access to its Discord chat group, where
you can chat with Johnny DC and Marvelous Joe.
The fantastic 4 tier gives you that and more
with two bonus episodes each month, including
bloopers and top 10 shows where Johnny and
Joe count down your favourite Marvel and DC
subjects. The X-Force tier makes you an executive
producer of Dynamic Duel, where every month
you help the host choose what to review and
who to fight against each other. And finally,
the Dynamite Podcast Network tier allows aspiring
podcasters to create their own battle-focused
show using this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny
and Joe will help you develop your show, provide
graphic support and consultation, and get you
simulation results to announce on your show.
Pitch the twins your show via email at dyna
or by reaching out to the Dynamite Podcast them
on social media. Check it out at patreon.com
slash dynamic duel. Pip pip cheerio. Thanks
AJ 9k and thanks to everyone who supports the
podcast. Guys, be sure to tune into the other
shows in the Dynamite Podcast Network this
week, including Max Destruction, which pits
your favorite action heroes from film and television
against each other. On the Send Your World podcast,
host Zachary Hepburn speculates on fights between
fan favorite anime characters. This Thursday,
we'll find out who would win between Vegeta
from Dragon and Garou from One Punch Man. Don't
forget to check out last week's episode as
well. I was a guest host on that episode and
we found out who would win between Goku and
Superman. On the console combat podcast, hosts
John and Dean find out who would win in fights
between popular video game characters. In yesterday's
episode, they found out who would win in a
fight between Ratchet and Clank and Jack and
Daxter. Visit dynamicpodcast.com or click the
link in our show notes to listen to all the
shows in the DynaMic Podcast Network. And
with that out of the way, quick. to the No Prize.
A No Prize is an award Marvel used to give
out to fans. Our version, the Dynamic Duel No
Prize, is a digital award that we post on Instagram
for the person that we feel gave the best answer
to our question of the week. Last week we asked,
what is your favorite Superman logo and why?
This of course was coming off of the news that
James Gunn and David Cornswett posted the Superman
logo that will appear on the new Superman film
coming out next year. Yeah, we got three answers,
so let's go ahead and run down the two honorable
mentions as well as the no prize winner. Our
first honorable mention goes to Miggy Matengian,
who said, Hey, what's up guys, it's Miggy and
my favorite alternate Superman logo is a fan
redesign from Reddit where the Pentagon itself
is the S and the inside is a circle split into
two hemispheres kind of like Saturn Girls logo.
It's my favorite because it kind of goes away
from recent interpretations where it's a family
crest and instead. like ups the stylization
of the ass kind of like syndrome from Incredibles.
Yeah, this is a design that Miggy shared on
our Discord server. So everybody got to see
what it looked like, and I'll do my best to
try to describe it just like Miggy did. So imagine
the red pentagon shape of the ass shield, and
it's all red, except for a gold circle that's
in the center with a red band splitting the
circle into two halves down the middle horizontally.
And then from each of the circle halves, there's
a line that extends to the edge of the shield.
And it forms an S. It's really cool. You may
just have to take his word for it. Honestly,
in my opinion, it's probably the coolest super
band logo I've ever seen. The only reason it
doesn't get this week's no prize award is because
it's essentially fan art, but really cool fan
art. Yeah, it's very minimalistic and they
should bring that design into mainstream continuity.
It would be a great movie logo, honestly. Yeah.
Great answer, Miggy. Our next on our roll mention
goes to Scott Camacho, who said, I know I'm
going to get some brownie points for this one,
but my favorite Superman logo design is always
been what the next logo design is. And right
now it'd be Johnny DC's Superman logo. He kind
of did a modernized version of the figure eight
symbol, which is, I guess, the House of Jor-El
symbol. And I really am captivated by it and
I really hope they take it into a movie. As
much as I wanted to give this one the win as
well, it was just going to be a little too
self-serving. So if you guys have listened to
the podcast for a while, you'll know that Joseph
and I are both graphic designers by profession
and I love doing different designs of superhero
logos. I've been working on a Superman logo
for a really long time, but I f- finally nailed
one that I really liked and I've been posting
it to our discord server and our social media
accounts and tagging James Gunn. Yeah, both
of these honorable mention answers are a little
bit esoteric due to the fact that they're not
well known designs and were just mentioned
on our discord. But I think that just means
that if you're not part of our discord server,
you should join our Patreon for just two bucks
a month. You can join and chat with the rest
of the dynamic Duel listening community that's
there. Yeah, it's super fun. Great answer,
Scotty. But the winner of this week's no prize
is... Travis Herndon who said, Hey guys, Travis
here. So my pig would have to be the recovery
suit logo. I really love that silver metallic
chrome look it has combined that with the sort
of skin tight, capeless black uniform he wore.
It kind of gave it that sort of badass vibe
to me. So that's my big recovery suit. I think
that screams just badassery all in all. So that's
my pig. So the Superman emblem on Superman's
recovery suit in the comics is actually just
the standard Superman logo with different coloring.
Instead of the traditional red and yellow, it's
metallic silver, which is still really cool.
I loved it in Zack Snyder's Justice League.
Yeah, it looked really good. There have been
a lot of adaptations that we've seen of it.
I think the poster to Tim Burton's scrapped
movie that he was going to direct with Nicolas
Cage, that used the recovery suit. I think,
at least in the poster, it was silver and black.
Well, I mean, yeah, the coloring was the same,
but the logo design was very much different.
Great design, though. Yeah, there's something
just so streamlined about the black suit Superman
that I think has this cool, darker appeal over
his, you know, more traditional primary color
suit. Yeah, it's pretty sleek and minimal.
As long as Superman doesn't have the mullet,
he looks great in it. Congrats to Travis for
winning this week's No Prize. If you the listener
want a shot at winning your own No Prize. Stay
tuned till later on this episode when we'll
be asking another Question of the Week. And
now that that's done, on to the news!
Alright, let's get the hosts of the Console
Combat podcast, which is part of the DynaMic
Podcast Network, on the line. Hey, John, good
to have you back on the show since you were
last on for Ghost Rider Spirit of Vengeance.
And Dean, this is your first time on Dynamic
Duel, but you're a relatively new executive
producer, having come on board as you became
the co-host of Console Combat. How's it going,
guys? Great. Hello. Great. For those who may
not know, Console Combat is an awesome show
that's like this show, Dynamic Duel, but with
video games. You guys just finished your 15th
episode, no, actually your 16th episode with
The Last of Us's Joel Miller versus Days Gone's
Deacon St. John. Your 15th episode was actually
the Halo review. Yeah, season one. Yeah, you
guys are crushing it and you guys have been
since your first episode even, I think largely
because like the crazy amount of prep work
John put into the show's creation and Dean,
your vast knowledge of the gaming industry.
So to start off, I just want to say great job
guys. Thank you. You're doing so well. Thank
you. You guys have done episodes like Nathan
Drake versus Lara Croft, Luigi versus Tails,
Master Chief versus Kratos, Assassin's Creed
versus Hitman. Out of all those episodes you've
done, what has been your favorite episode to
record so far? That's a good question. Our
last episode that we released, the one that
you just mentioned, Joel Miller versus Deacon
St. John. that has been probably my favorite
to do because we diversified the style of fighting.
We took away the limitations of each other and
we brought an aspect of the worlds they came
from together and made the amalgamation. And
that for us was a lot of fun because it gave
the opportunity for the game to be involved
or rather the games to be involved with the
process more so than usual. Yeah, we were playing
around with that a little bit. I think it worked
out pretty well. I hope it doesn't seem like
we kind of focus more on the combined fight
against the variable that came in, but I feel
like it was still viable for how we did it.
And yeah, it was fun. Yeah, I think you guys
bring a lot of interesting ideas to the speculative
battles that you guys do. It's very unique from
the other shows in the network, like what Jonathan
and I do, where we strictly it's just the two
characters and then non environment and stuff
like that. You guys actually bring in the environment.
You even have like power ups from other video
games, which is I thought it was brilliant.
It's just a lot of fun the way you guys do
And also you guys used to do tournament based
battles where the winners of battles would
go on to compete against the other winners.
And that was an idea that Jonathan and I loved,
but never did. We kind of toyed around with
it. Do you guys think you'll continue with
the tournament battles or are you just going
to stick to the single matchups? I think we'll
go back to doing a tournament at some point.
The difficult part is trying to find characters
that match up well enough. and also while trying
to consider how they would match with characters
that are in the other brackets in future fights.
So like we saw a lot of that in this last tournament
was a lot of really lopsided fights. For example,
our Scorpion versus Nemesis fight, you know,
it seemed like it was going to be a wash one
way, but it ended up going the other way massively
just because of the way the stats lined up.
And that's something we need to take into consideration
more, I think, next time. just because we focused
on getting the first set of brackets where
they're like, yeah, this isn't even match, and
it makes sense. But we didn't really consider
too much about later on. I mean, don't get me
wrong, it was fun, because we had those really
goofy matchups. But at the same time, it's like,
yeah, this one was kind of a wash. Yeah, SEO
versus Tails was pretty fun to listen to. Yeah,
I had fun with that one for sure. Yes. Kudos
to you guys for actually putting in that work
and getting it done in that way. Yeah. John's
idea to have that, that we open the show, was
definitely a good idea. Yeah. What I love about
Console Combat is that not only do you guys
also do reviews in addition to the Battle Sims,
but you also talk about the news. You know,
you have your news segments. Right now, currently,
I only have my Switch Lite, and I haven't been
hard into video games really since I started
this podcast, because it's just taken up all
my time, and that's going on eight years. Good
God. Wow. But back in the day, you know, I remember
going on to IGN. almost daily and I was a subscriber
to Game Informer just to follow the news on
what was going on in the industry and see what
video games were coming out and stuff. And actually,
oh geez, back in the day, one of my, one of
Jonathan and I's former coworkers was Brian
Crescenti who started Kotaku. Oh wow. And we
used to talk to him all the time about gaming
and shit. And really I just miss hearing about
people talking about gaming and even if I'm
not necessarily playing the games, I still
find it fascinating to hear. And you guys seem...
like particularly knowledgeable about like
the technical side of gaming, such as what goes
into making a game and whatnot. Have either
of you guys ever been in gaming development
or wanted to? I had originally wanted to do
that going out of high school and into college.
The only class that I really did well in was
the 3d animation, but even then it was like
basic model building and Blender. So I'm vaguely
familiar with that. Maybe not in practice, but
in, you know, I can understand the concept.
And I understand how the coding and everything
works. But actual practice doing it, no. I
have no experience in actual game design. Well,
it's definitely clear that you have, like,
some of that background just with the amount
of technical knowledge. And actually, a vast
gaming history, both of you guys. What is your
gaming history? Like, when did you guys start
gaming? And what are you currently playing?
On this one, I can go back as far as the NES.
You're old. Yes, yes, I am. 36 this year. I
remember vividly playing the NES, and then
this was the transition for me that I actually
remember the games that I was playing. I came
home one day, and without telling me that anything
had changed, my mother just let me go to the
video games and turned it on, and it was a totally
different game. I looked at the system and
I said, wow, this is different. My love for
the Super Nintendo was born. That's really
where my gaming took hold. It's been just off
the rails ever since. I've played every...
Every Nintendo rendition up to the GameCube,
then the Wii. I didn't do the Wii U. I have
a Switch. I also grew up a long PlayStation.
I've had every system for the PlayStation except
for the handhelds. I've always been a fan of
those two primarily. I mean, you can tell by
the way we talk to each other on the show, we
do not agree necessarily on the favorites,
whereas I hate Xbox. Dean is much more preferential
to Xbox. I've never cared for the Xbox myself
personally. But so yeah, I mean, Nintendo all
day for me. than PlayStation for sure is it's
equal. And lately my addictions, I mean, everyone's,
besides Dean and his hate for Fortnite, it's
almost always Fortnite for me. But I'm a big
fan of games like Hogwarts Legacy, which is
fantastic game. The Call of Duty games, the
Black Ops is my thing. We actually been playing
that game a little bit. And if anyone has listened
to the show, everyone knows my absolute love
for the Metal Gear franchise. And yeah, that's
the one for me for sure. Mine actually started
a long time ago. It was probably a couple years,
if not a about a year after the original Xbox
came out. I remember my parents, we went to
Walmart. And this was back in the day when
Walmart still had the demos of game consoles
for like, you know, Xbox, PS2, GameCube, all
that stuff. You're old. Yeah, not as old as
you. And we're looking at all the game stuff.
And my dad goes, thinking about getting one
of these for your brother, which one do you
think you'd want? I'm like, I don't know, I've
never played any of these. And he's like, well,
just look at the covers and see which ones you
think look best. It's like the Xbox ones or
the PlayStation ones. I'm like, oh, so I'm looking
at games or whatever. I'm like, yeah, this
game looks fun for the Xbox or whatever. So
then I come home and they bought the Xbox and
it was for me. And so that's kind of when that
started. So that was probably what, 02 or 03,
somewhere in there. And since then, I've actually
still have that original Xbox and a couple
other ones. I've got the 360s, Xbox One. I don't
have the newest one because it's pointless
with everything on PC. I've started dabbling
when I got more into high school into the PlayStation
stuff, mainly for the exclusives. So I started
with the PS3 and then PS4, PS5 now. I went
back a few months ago and actually ended up
getting a PS2 complete in box, which was nice
for a decent price. So I've started playing
with that. But most of the time I lean towards
PC. I do have some of the Nintendo consoles,
SNES, Wii, things like that. I just don't play
them as much, but PC is usually where I'm sitting
down and playing something, unless it's a console
exclusive like Spider-Man. But lately, like
John was saying, I did play some Black Ops
with him the other day. And honestly, the one
I've been playing the most is City Skylines
2. It's a city builder game. I don't know why,
it's just oddly addictive. It's like a SimCity
type simulation. Yeah, yeah, yeah. It's like
a more modern and upgraded and more fleshed
out version. Yeah, I may have dated myself by
saying SimCity, but I don't know what the kids
are playing these days. I played it too. Yeah,
actually, John, your and my gaming histories
are remarkably similar in that I started out
with the Super Nintendo. And actually, that's
why your E! Honda versus Sumo Santa episode
was my favorite, because Street Fighter II
was the very first video game I ever owned.
Jonathan and I got it for Christmas. So there
was that tie in there and I first mained as
e Honda because I could spam the thousand hand
slap And Jonathan couldn't do shit about it.
So that was always fun. So going back to the
podcast What are some of the matchups and reviews
that listeners can expect in the future from
console combat? Well, we are actually in the
midst of discussing our next review right now
We're gonna do the Scott Pilgrim versus the
world film from 2010 We're actually looking
to put the panel of network people together
on that. So, you know, look for that possibly
having a couple of features for fights. We got
Jack and Daxter versus Ratchet and Clank, which
would have come out yesterday. One of the ones
that actually that I've talked about recently
that I think is going to be a lot of fun. I'm
calling it a bullet time battle because we're
going to use Max Payne versus Michael DeSanta
from GTA five. Nice. Yeah. We're actually still
trying to find a good matchup for Raiden from
the Metal Gear series. So if anyone's got ideas,
throw them at us. Someone said for someone from
Overwatch. So, and I mean, this is something
that we're just gonna tease now, but we don't
have a date for him yet. But we are definitely
gonna do Sonic versus Mario down the line is
it's no questions asked going to happen. But
we have to he's kind of on our cover. Well that
and I mean, it's the question that everyone
has. It's the one that everyone always wants
to know because of course, they're the two
icons of the two most powerfully known consoles
in the gaming industry. If they really want
to know that bad, we have the Mario and Sonic
at the Olympics games. Just play those. Or
Smash Brothers. Yeah, or Smash Brothers, yeah.
Honestly, we consider the nature of the video
game roster of just infinite characters really
to be open to suggestion. We obviously have
no quarrels with reuse either. If people see
a character that... they've seen in the past
and they wanted to go up somewhere else against
someone else more prominent. Like, there are
so many options to play with and it's literally
the world is our oyster and I think that's
one of the most enjoyable parts of us doing
the show is we just have so much to work with.
For sure. I can't wait for you guys to do a
Link episode because the Zelda series is my
favorite game series of all time. That one's
commonplace. I'm actually curious about putting
video games that are racing based against each
other. That one I feel like is going to be
our hard point, but we're going to make it work
somehow, All right, Nefrous me versus Gran
Turismo. And you guys could describe it as maybe
like a Mad Max style race and throw in some
like Mario Kart power ups and shit. Oh, yes.
That sounds like a lot of fun. Well, it was
great to have you guys on as part of this episode
and as part of the Dynamite network. So just
keep crushing it. Keep doing what you guys are
doing because it's awesome. Listeners, if you
love video games, you literally have no excuse
not to be listening to console combat. which
you could do anywhere you listen to podcasts
or by visiting dynamicpodcasts.com. Thank you
guys so much for stopping by and can't wait
to listen to more of what you got. Thanks for
having us. Thanks, appreciate it. Great bunch
of guys. Again, if you like video games, you
cannot miss their show. It's fantastic. I feel
like I didn't get to ask a single question
there. What the heck? No, Jonathan couldn't
make it to the interview because it was recorded
earlier, but yeah, great talking to them. Again,
visit dynamicpodcasts.com. or search for console
combat spelled with two K's wherever you listen
to podcasts. But considering that console combat
is a podcast focused around video games, that
leads us to our question of the week.
What is your favorite DC or Marvel video game
and why? And I'm sure we've asked this question
before, but I feel like it's been a really long
time. There's been a lot of great games to
come out recently. So, yeah, let us know what
your favorite is. Record your answer at dynamicduel.com
by clicking on the red microphone button in
the bottom right hand corner of the screen,
which will prompt you to leave us a voicemail.
Your message could be up to 30 seconds long.
And don't forget to leave your name in case
we include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a dynamic
duel no prize that we'll post to Instagram.
Be sure to answer before March 16th.
Where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
DynaMic Podcast Network presents Console Combat,
where video game legends brawl every Monday.
Dynamic Duel, where comic book titans smash
every Tuesday. Max Destruction. TV and action
heroes battle every Wednesday, and Sendro World,
where anime champions clash every Thursday.
Join us as we speculate on the matches and armed
with the power of mathematical simulations,
discover who will emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
But I think that does it for all the news for
this episode, so let's go ahead and get into
our main event, our big team duel where we find
out who would win in a fight between the villainous
organizations of the Legion of Doom and the
Masters of Evil.
Alright, the Legion of Doom versus the Masters
of Evil. This episode has been a long time
coming, primarily because these teams consist
of the greatest villains in both Marvel and
DC. And it'll be a lot of fun to put these guys
against each other. Now, this is our first
villain team duel. We've done several already,
including Arkham Asylum versus Sinister Six
and the Flash Rogues versus the Brotherhood
of Evil. But I feel like this is the big villain
team matchup. Like, does it get bigger than
this in terms of villain teams? No, absolutely
not. The Legion of Doom hands down features
DC's most prominent villains, just like how
the Justice League features its most prominent
heroes. Yeah, and like the Avengers, who by
this point in their comics history, that team
has incorporated almost every single hero that
Marvel has. The Masters of Evil have had dozens
upon dozens of members over the years, and
they have also probably included almost every
single villain there is at some point, but
we narrowed these teams down to just seven characters
per side because that's how our duel simulator
is set up. But to explain the methodology behind
our team duels, let's go to our sentient duel
simulator, Alfred Jarvis9000. AJ9K, tell our
listeners how you go about determining a winner
in our team duel matchups. Yes, of course, sir.
The way I determine a winner between the two
teams... is by running 1000 Monte Carlo simulations
between every character on each team using
their statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation is
a probabilistic model used to determine outcomes
through random sampling. In this case, I randomize
the statistics along a normal distribution
as a way to simulate the many variables that
can occur during battle. The stat parameters
are based on the official Marvel power grid,
from which the DC characters' statistics are
extrapolated. Additional stat categories are
included such as Range, Damage versatility
and perception in order to create a more detailed
and accurate simulation. The results of the
49,000 simulations provide a percentage of wins
for each character on both teams. The team
with the higher average win rate is declared
the victor as they have a higher probability
to win any given battle. In an equitable pairing,
neither team should win 100% of the matches.
The comic book stories have shown that there's
even a way for Batman to defeat Superman. So
the confidence rate of my method falls in line
with the precedents that have been established
in the source material. My mathematical simulations
are without subjectivity or bias. Feats are
not the sole consideration, nor are fan votes
tabulated for determination of the winner.
Thanks AJ9K. Before we run the simulations though,
we like to break down each team's histories
and rosters before improvising a scenario on
how we imagine one of the simulations would
play out beat for beat. And I believe it's my
turn to go first with the history. of the Legion
of Doom. Now, when most people think of the
Legion of Doom, they think of the diabolical
team featuring Lex Luthor, Giganta, Toy Man,
or Solomon Grundy from the 1970s cartoon Challenge
of the Super Friends, which is where the team
made their first appearance. In the comics,
the team didn't make their debut until the mid-90s
in the pages of Extreme Justice. This team
was led by the hero-turned-villain Brainwave
and included Killer Frost, major force, and
a robotic duplicate of Gorilla Grodd. That team
of course meant defeat at the hands of the
Extreme Justice team, which you can learn more
about in our Captain Adam vs. Wonder Man and
Wonder Twins vs. Cloak and Dagger duel episodes.
While a cartoon-inspired roster would be featured
in Alex Ross's and Jim Krueger's Out of Continuity
Justice miniseries, a team with the Legion
of Doom name wouldn't appear again in the DC
Universe until 2011. when Superboy Prime formed
a team that included Inertia, Sun Girl, and
Brainiac 8, aka Indigo, to go up against the
Teen Titans, who successfully managed to defeat
Superboy's Legion. You can learn more about
the Teen Titans in our Titans vs. X-Men Team
Duel episode. Now, although Lex Luthor had
created several teams of super villains over
the years, including the Injustice League,
the Injustice Gang, the Secret Six, and the
Seeker Society of Super-Villains, it wasn't
until 2018 that Lex Luthor finally and officially
formed the Legion of Doom. When the Justice
League defeated the universe-destroying dragon
Barbados, they cracked the Source Wall at the
very edge of the universe in the process. From
this crack emerged the Omega Titans, who absorbed
entire worlds, including K'Kolu, the homeworld
of the villain Brainiac. After protecting Earth
from the Omega Titans, the then-heroic Lex Luthor
became discouraged by the seeming inevitable
state of entropy of the world and built a time
machine to travel a million years into the
future to see what would become of it. He was
surprised to find a world of villains that
worshipped him, having discovered writings of
his millennia earlier that caused the world
to embrace entropy and doom. Lex discovered
a secret underground chamber within his father's
old Legionnaire's club founded by the immortal
Vandal Savage, with writings detailing the
secret origins and forces of the Multiverse,
as well as a doorknob capable of unlocking
those forces. Lex assembled the Legion of Doom
in order to harness the hidden universal forces
and unlock the Totality, the primordial energy
source of the Multiverse imbued within a portion
of the Source Wall. that had recently crashed
to Earth inside of a massive head that broke
off from the wall. This Legion included Sinestro,
Gorilla Grodd, an infant version of the Flash
Villain Turtle, Black Manta, Cheetah, and the
Joker. With a shrunken Lex Luthor and Joker
infiltrating and controlling Superman and Martian
Manhunter's bodies, and Sinestro and Gorilla
Grodd in control of two of the hidden universal
forces, the invisible spectrum of light and
the Still Force. the Legion seized the Totality,
though the Justice League stole it from them
before it could be fully unlocked. After partnering
with the Batman Who Laughs, Lex Luthor learned
more about the nature of the Totality, how it
was a prison for the being that created the
DC Multiverse, Perpetua. After Black Manta gained
the Tear of Extinction and Cheetah the Void
Wind, two more hidden
kill the Greek god Poseidon and flood the planet,
allowing them to take back the totality. Feeling
he achieved all that he desired and unwilling
to take further orders, Black Manta was booted
from the Legion by Lex Luthor, along with the
Joker, who hated that Lex had sided with the
Batman Who Laughs. With help from Professor
Ivo, Lex was able to recreate Brainiac, who
replaced Manta and Joker on the team. After
unlocking the Black Apple and the Sixth Note,
two more hidden forces, the Legion was able
to partially awake Perpetua, who helped Lex
evolve into a human-slash-Martian hybrid known
as Apex Lex. As the battle between the Legion
of Doom and the heroes of the multiverse raged
on, a sense of dread and faithlessness fell
upon the multiverse, fully awakening Perpetua.
entire universes in her dark image, the Legion
came to her for their rewards, at which point
she turned Brainiac into her throne and siphoned
the hidden forces from the Legion members and
imbued them into Lex, giving him the power to
reshape reality at a multiversal level. Perpetua
seemingly erased the Justice League and later
depowered Lex after the Batman Who Laughs convinced
her that he would serve as a better general.
If you've listened to our Batman Who Laughs
vs. Cosmic Ghost Rider duel episode, you'll
know that this led to the Dark Knight's death
metal storyline, where the Batman Who Laughs
betrayed and killed Perpetua, only to later
be killed by a World Forge-empowered Wonder
Woman. Regardless, the Legion of Doom had been
disbanded, though it may return someday soon.
For my seven-member team roster, due to the
Legion of Doom's short career in the comics,
It is admittedly heavily inspired by the Super
Friends cartoon. I'm choosing Lex Luthor, who
founded the Legion of Doom in the comics and
was depicted as the team's leader even in the
Super Friends. I'm also going with Gorilla
Grodd, who was not only in the cartoon, but
a robotic version of him was a member of the
first Legion of Doom iteration in the comics.
The same goes for Brainiac, as a version of
him was on the team led by Superboy Prime, so
he's of course on my roster. I'm also going
with Sinestro, Cheetah, and Black Manta, who
were among Lexa's initial picks for the Legion,
and again, were all in the cartoon. Though Joker
was also chosen in the comics, he later left
the team and was never in the cartoon series,
and he was already on my Arkham Asylum team
from a previous episode, so he's out. For my
final member, I've decided to go with Solomon
Grundy. As he was in the cartoon- And because,
based on your roster that I know of, I thought
he was the best match for Absorbing Man. So
to reiterate, my Legion of Doom team is Lex
Luthor, Gorilla Grodd, Brainiac, Sinestro, Cheetah,
Black Manta, and Solomon Grundy, each of whom
you can learn more about in their respective
Duel episodes. That was the most convoluted
short backstory ever. I did not expect that.
What do you want from me? I had no idea that
the Legion of Doom really had no presence in
the comics until fairly recently. Yeah, within
the past six years, I guess. Why is that the
case? Like, why didn't DC capitalize on the
popularity of that team from the Super Friends
cartoon? It's weird because they've made like
a bunch of references to the Legion of Doom
and a lot of Elseworlds works. Like, you know,
Kingdom Come, the Gulag that Mr. Miracle designed
was based off the Legion of Doom headquarters.
They featured in a lot of television series
and stuff like that. just never in mainstream
continuity in the comics, or at least never
a version that was like the one from the Super
Friends cartoon, this counterpart to the Justice
League as it were. Yeah, you would think from
like how often they're included, even in shows
like Harley Quinn, that they were just this
like mainstay comic book entity, and it's so
bizarre that it's not the case. And like the
story that they were in was convoluted as hell.
It's like you're talking about the black apple
and the sixth note, and I'm like, what the hell
is this? Talking about apples now? I don't
get it. Yeah, Scott Snyder, he kind of changed
everything about the fabric and nature of the
DC universe. So makes sense. That whole storyline
was meant to tie into both Dark Knight's Metal
and Dark Knight's Death Metal. It was like a
bridge between those two series. I have no
idea what you're saying, but I will take your
word for it. Okay. I've only mentioned them
several times on this podcast. You know I don't
listen to you. And I don't understand anything
you're saying when it comes to the DC multiverse
and the metal or whatever. Now, this makes
me think that The Legion of Doom is just one
big ripoff of The Masters of Evil, because
The Masters of Evil have been around since the
1960s in Marvel, and we know that the challenge
of the Super Friends cartoon wasn't around until
the 70s. So once again, DC ripping off Marvel,
as always. I'm pretty sure that the first iteration
of The Masters of Evil was nothing like a premiere
team of supervillains. They were probably like
C-list at best. Shows what you know. Let me
go into their backstory. Now the Masters of
Evil is one of Marvel's longest running supervillain
groups and one of its largest. They are often
regarded as the antithesis to the Avengers,
where that team is considered Earth's mightiest
heroes, the Masters of Evil are Earth's mightiest
villains. The group was initially gathered by
Baron Heinrich Zemo, a World War II adversary
of Captain America, who thanks to his secret
formula Compound X, had ceased aging. Taking
refuge in South America over the decades, Baron
Zemo eventually became aware of his nemesis
resurgence. Captain America, previously presumed
dead, had been revived and joined the Avengers,
a team you can explore further in our Justice
League vs Avengers duel. Intent on confronting
his old enemy but unwilling to take on all the
Avengers single-handedly, Baron Zemo resolved
to assemble his own team. He handpicked some
of the most formidable villains the heroes
had ever faced. The initial lineup, of the Masters
of Evil included Baron Zemo himself, along
with the Black Knight, the Meltr, and Radioactive
Man. Together, they unleashed Zemo's unbreakable
Adhesive X chemical formula across New York
City. Despite their efforts, the Avengers saw
assistance from the villain known as the Trapster,
an expert in adhesives, and used his antidote
to thwart the Masters of Evil's plan. Baron
Zemo managed to evade capture by fleeing in
his helicopter and undeterred- he persisted
in his mission by recruiting the formidable
Asgardians known as the Enchantress and Scourge
to bolster his ranks. Together, they succeeded
in manipulating Thor, turning him against his
fellow Avengers through enchantment. Unfortunately,
Iron Man managed to break the spell and snap
his ally out of it. Subsequently, the villains
were exiled to another dimension. However, their
exile proved temporary as the Enchantress employed
her magical abilities to return them home. Baron
Zemo then focused on recruiting the failed
businessman Simon Williams, who sought revenge
on Tony Stark. Subjecting Simon to ionic energy
bombardment, Zemo transformed him into Wonder
Man. And for more information on him, refer
to our Captain Adam vs. Wonder Man duel episode.
Zemo utilized Wonder Man to infiltrate the
Avengers and betray the heroes. Despite this,
Wonder Man had a change of heart and sacrificed
himself to aid in the defeat of the Masters
of Evil. After Baron Heinrich Zemo met his
demise in a rock slide during a confrontation
with Captain America, the villainous team found
themselves leaderless and temporarily disbanded.
However, a new incarnation of the team emerged
under the leadership of the robotic villain
Ultron, who recruited some fresh faces including
Whirlwind and Claw. Their scheme involved hypnotizing
Jarvis, the Avengers' butler, with the intention
of using him to bring down the heroes. yet their
plans were thwarted once more due to betrayal
from within their own ranks, the Black Knight,
who was secretly an ally of the Avengers. Though
the Masters of Evil suffered defeat once again,
the resilience led to a prompt reformation.
This time, they operated under the guidance
of the nefarious scientist and ant-man antagonist,
Egghead. Their roster expanded to include Tiger
Shark, Scorpion, Moonstone, Shocker, and the
Beetle. They concocted a scheme to frame and
disgrace Ant-Man, whom they captured with hopes
of coercing him to join their ranks. However,
their plan backfired when the captured hero
ingeniously constructed his own arsenal to combat
the villains. Egghead met his demise when his
gun exploded, being struck by a well-aimed arrow
from Hawkeye. Once again, the Masters were
disbanded. However, Heinrich Zemo's son, Helmut,
emerged onto the scene. Assuming his father's
mantle as Baron Zemo, and assembling a new iteration
of the Masters of Evil. This revamped team
included formidable villains such as the Absorbing
Man, Titania, Yellow Jacket, Mr. Hyde, and
the Wrecking Crew which consisted of the Wrecker,
Piledriver, Thunderball, and Bulldozer. Although
this group managed to temporarily overrun the
Avengers Mansion and scatter the heroes, the
Avengers eventually regrouped and reclaimed
their headquarters, defeating the Masters once
more. Yet driven by unwavering hatred, Baron
Zemo persistently reassembled his group, this
time enlisting the likes of the Fixer, Screaming
Mimi, Beetle, Goliath, and Moonstone. However,
at this juncture, most of Earth's heroes had
vanished following their confrontation with
a malevolent psychic entity known as Onslaught,
a conflict detailed in our Chief vs. Professor
X battle. This prompted Zemo to reconsider his
tactics, leading him to rebrand his Masters
of Evil as... The Thunderbolts. While masquerading
as heroes, they harbored secret ambitions of
world domination. However, the full details
of their backstory will be explored in another
team duel. The Thunderbolts' eventual transformation
into genuine heroes sparked a bitter rivalry
with the emergence of a new Masters of Evil.
Under the leadership of the villain known as
the Crimson Cowl, this new group attempted to
coerce the Thunderbolts into joining their
ranks or face annihilation. Despite repeated
attempts by their former allies, the Thunderbolts
emerged victorious time and again. Eventually
though, the villain known as the Red Skull
used his reality-warping cosmic cube to rewrite
history so that Captain America had always
secretly been a member of the evil organization
Hydra. At that point, Baron Zemo forged an
alliance with the Captain, persuading several
long-time Thunderbolts members to defect and
join his new Masters of Evil. This newly formed
group served as the personal army of the evil
Captain America, as together they seized control
of the United States. The Masters of Evil rose
to engage in battle against a united coalition
of America's heroes, who fought fervently to
reclaim their country. Eventually, the heroes
succeeded in restoring Captain America's true
identity, defeating Hydra and the Masters of
Evil in the process. And that's their backstory.
For the seven-person roster for this team duel,
I went with characters that spanned the broad
history and multiple iterations of the Masters
of Evil over the years. Okay! I started with
Baron Zemo, the Baron Helmet Zemo version whose
father started the Masters of Evil and who
helmed multiple versions of the team on his
own. Secondly, I'm going with Ultron, who was
the second iteration of the team's leader and
is a powerful Avengers villain. Next, I have
some of the earliest members of the team, the
Iron Man villain Radioactive Man. and the Thor
villain, Enchantress, taking up the third and
fourth slots due to their powerful energy and
magic powers, respectively. My fifth member,
I will always associate with the Masters of
Evil as the very first boss villain you face
in the Captain America and the Avengers arcade
video game, and that's the Ant-Man villain,
Rolewind. Penultimately I have Black Panther's
villain, Claw, on the team due to his powerful
sonic powers and nigh And rounding out the
group is the Hulk villain, Absorbing Man, who
is the last member of this group to join the
Masters of Evil, but has a great wild card power
that I think will make things interesting.
So to reiterate, the 7 member Masters of Evil
team that we're going with in this duel is
Baron Zemo, Ultron, Radioactive Man, Enchantress,
Whirlwind, Klawe, and Absorbing Man. And the
Legion of Doom is going down, because they're
like, not even really a team in my opinion,
at least compared to the Masters of Evil. Dude,
I mean... Maybe not in the comics, but like
literally everywhere else they are. And it's
on. And also, like besides Ultron, I was right.
Friggin C-list villains, bro. You are entirely
wrong. A lot of these villains have shown up
in the movies like Baron Zemo was the main villain
of Civil War. You have Klaue, who was a villain
in the Black Panther movie, absorbing man, who
was the villain in the Hulk movie that we reviewed
last week. Yeah, there's a lot of them. Okay,
so a few B-listers and the rest of them are
C-listers. Right, because everybody knows who
Gorilla Grodd is, right? Yeah, dude. He was
in the Super Friends. Okay.
Now that we've got their histories and rosters
out of the way, let's speculate on how one
of the simulated matches will go. The winning
team is determined by simulations, not this
speculation, but it's fun to imagine how this
battle could play out. AG9K, what are the rules
of our speculation? Well, I should say there
are no rules, other than the teams have no
prior knowledge of the other going into the
fight. All they are aware of starting out is
that the other side is a threat that needs to
be eliminated. For the speculation, the groups
will begin approximately 50 meters apart in
a non-descript environment that will have no
bearing on the match itself, as no environmental
statistics are considered in my simulations.
The teams must earn victory on their own merit.
Alright then, let's get into it. The Legion
of Doom and the Masters of Evil meet on the
battlefield. Who goes first? I feel like on
my team, Cheetah would go first, and on your
team, Whirlwind would probably go first. So
they're likely to clash. out the gate just head
on with cheetah just slashing off all of whirlwind's
armor no she would just bounce off of whirlwind
like his whole thing is that he spins with
such speed that the uh the centrifugal force
that he generates just repels any physical
attack that's made against him so cheetah she
tries to hit him but she just gets rocked back
into her teammates and whirlwind is going to
follow up by unleashing a volley of buzz saws
at the Legion of Doom, just slicing them up
to bits. Yeah, except those buzz saws never
reach the Legion because Sinestro goes on the
defensive and he puts up a yellow force field
between the teams in the form of a castle wall,
which the Legion can use defensively like a
fort. And then this yellow dragon construct
forms, just perched on the wall, and it's going
to shoot this massive fireball at Ultron. Ultron,
that's not gonna do anything. Ultron's made
out of adamantium. So he'll be fine, because
that's the most durable metal ever. But Sinestro
making a castle wall is gonna play right into
Enchantress's strengths because she's as guardian.
So she's just gonna magically conjure this army
of like dozens of Viking warriors who just
storm this castle and slay the dragon with their
axes and spears. Nah, I mean they may kill
the dragon, but those... Vikings aren't getting
past the wall. Like they're gonna be too busy
getting freaking disintegrated by a swarm of
Brainiac's drones. And they're gonna bring
down the Vikings with like cold calculated precision.
And then the drones are gonna mount themselves
to the castle walls parapets and just rain down
lasers on the masters of evil outside the wall.
Okay, well Klawe, he's gonna generate a catapult
construct made out of his sound wave powers.
And that thing is just gonna launch radioactive
man over the castle wall Where he's gonna crash
down right onto the Legion and explode like
a small nuclear bomb Just like tearing down
Sinestro's castle construct and destroying Brainiac's
drones But most importantly just obliterating
the entire Legion team Forgefield But like from
Lex Luthor this time, he's gonna erect this
energy dome from his battle suit around his
team So yeah, the drones and the wall are taken
out, but not the Legion. And once that field
is down, Black Manta is immediately just going
to unleash a massive energy beam from his helmet
that sweeps across the entire Masters of Evil
team. Big deal, they could dodge it just by
ducking. What? Yeah, they duck the beam, except
for absorbing man who gets hit by Black Manta's
beam, but he absorbs the energy and becomes
like this shiny red being made out of lasers.
He's gonna swing his glowing ball and chain,
and it's gonna unleash this energy wave right
at Gorilla Grodd, just knocking him back and
frying all the hair off his body. So now he's
just like this hairless ape. I mean, jokes
on you. You know, Absorbing Man only thinks
Grodd was there, but in reality, Grodd invaded
Absorbing Man's mind, and he's been mentally
probing the entire Masters of Evil team and
recognized that Absorbing Man was- probably
one of the few people on the Masters of Evil
that he could mind control. So that's what he
did. Absorbing Man thinks he's knocked Grodd
back, but in actuality, he lasered Baron Zemo.
Okay, uh, well Zemo sees this energy wave coming
at him and he like dives out of the way to avoid
being hit and he's probably freaking pissed
at Absorbing Man for attacking the wrong guy
and Absorbing Man's like, huh? What just happened?
At which point... Zemo unholsters one of his
guns and he sprays out his adhesive X Which
is like this sticky goo that creates this unbreakable
bond and that's just gonna cement Cheetah to
the ground. So she can't run and she's stuck
on the ground Okay, so she'll be stuck for
now or at least like one of her legs is but
meanwhile Solomon Grundy, you know He spotted
Ultron and he's gonna plow right into him just
ripping off those weird antenna ears on the
sides of his head Adamantium, man. Like Ultron
is adamantium. So Solomon Grundy isn't breaking
shit. And Ultron's going to teach Grundy a lesson
by just trapping him in this graviton field
and slamming him repeatedly into the ground
and then launching him right into Lex Luthor,
knocking Lex over in his war suit onto the ground.
OK, so Lex Luthor, he gets up from the ground
and he's going to plunge this device into Solomon
Grundy's torso. before he picks up Grundy and
a tractor beam and trolls him at whirlwind.
And whirlwind is going to see Grundy coming
and probably slice him to pieces in this flurry
of blades. But inside Grundy was an acid bomb
that explodes onto whirlwind and just disintegrates
his armor. Does Lex Luthor have acid bombs?
Dude, he's a scientist. He has all kinds of
like science stuff, like chemicals. OK. Well,
yeah, Roland just completely scatters Grundy
across the battlefield like if Grundy just
got tossed into a blender, but Roland without
his armor is still dangerous. The armor just
provides him protection. So Roland is going
to spin and whip up this small tornado that's
going to lift up Black Manta into the air and
just hurl him like a half mile away from the
battlefield. No, dude, Black Manta has a jetpack,
you know, so he could stop himself midair.
So from the air, he's going an electrified harpoon
cable at whirlwind who's spinning so fast he
doesn't realize the cable wraps around his neck
until it's too late and his brain is just fried
from the electricity. So that, whirlwinds out.
Oh shit. Whirlwinds the first to be out in
the match huh? Yup. Okay, uh, well Klaue, he
sees Gorilla Grodd and Klaue's familiar with
African animals, you know, being an adversary
to Black Panther so he is gonna generate this
like giant leopard construct that's gonna pounce
on Gorilla Grodd and just chew him to bits
and Grodd can't do shit about it because You
know the construct doesn't have a mind for
Grodd to attack. I mean, but Grodd does have
telekinesis You know and in the throes of being
attacked He's just gonna emit a telekinetic
blast that's gonna disrupt the leopards like
sound frequency and Just cause it to dissolve
at which point Grodd's gonna send a psychic
surge of pain through Kla, disrupting his form
as well. But he's not really susceptible to
psychic attack because he has no physical brain.
But either way, Grodd's attack doesn't even
finish on Kla because in the middle of it, he's
stopped by a hand on his arm. It's the Enchantress's
hand, and she's gonna bewitch this gorilla with
a spell that turns Grodd against his teammates
and on the side of the Masters of Evil. And
Enchantress is gonna have Grodd provide their
entire team with psychic shielding to protect
them from mental attacks from like Brainiac.
So like once that mental shielding is in place,
she's just gonna magically turn Gorilla Grodd
into stone. So Grodd's out of this match and
Brainiac can't do anything telepathically to
the Masters of Evil. Dude, I did not want Gorilla
Grodd to go out this soon. Okay, well, you
know, meanwhile Sinestro's ring has scanned
Klaue's energy signature and deduced that he's
made of sound. So Sinestro materializes an airtight
iron maiden around Klaue and just vacuums all
of the air out, destroying Klaue's sound form.
So now he's eliminated. All right. So then
Black Manta and Zemo square up and Black Manta
sees Baron Zemo's sword and he pulls out his
long daggers and he's like, sword fight, me
and you, let's go. Cool. And Zemo, you know,
he gets into his fencing stance. and those two
go at it like parrying and slashing and stuff,
but Zemo using his energy gauntlets, he's gonna
punch out one of Black Manta's eye pieces in
his big ass helmet, because you know, it's just
a giant target. And as Manta is taken back
by that, Zemo is gonna stick his death ray gun
into Manta's helmet and just disintegrate Black
Manta's head right off. Damn! So Black Manta's
out. Okay, well before Zemo can celebrate his
victory though, a disembodied... hand grabs
his ankle and he's like what? And while he's
distracted by that another hand grabs him by
the opposite arm and just rips that thing right
off. It's Solomon Grundy and his body has reconstituted
after being torn to pieces by whirlwind. So
while Zemo's in shock that's when Solomon Grundy's
gonna punch his head clean right off of his
shoulders. Geez I guess this is like super strong
Solomon Grundy now that he's reborn again.
He's always strong. Well Absorbing Man, he sees
Ultron and he's like, you know, I could use
some of that adamantium. So he runs over and
he's going to grab Ultron turning himself into
adamantium. And Ultron's going to shrug him
off like, don't fucking touch me. But now you're
all in big trouble. The absorbing man is going
to confront Sinestro, who's probably going
to throw up some kind of like demon creature
construct or something like that. But absorbing
man is going to use Ultron's techno forming
power. to transform his ball and chain into
this like giant hammer, kind of like what he
used when he was the Breaker of Wills in the
Fear Itself storyline. And he's gonna use this
giant hammer to just smash through Sinestro's
constructs and then smash Sinestro's ring on
his hand. And before Sinestro can even like
shit his pants, Absorbing Man just smashes his
head in with the adamantium hammer, and then
Sinestro shits his pants, because he's dead.
Well, I'm confused. So, Absorbing Man- didn't
just become adamantium, he absorbed some of
Ultron's tech into his body as well? Yeah,
like he got his techno-forming power. He can
absorb powers as well as just the physical
states. Okay, all right. Well, you know how
one of Cheetah's feet were glued to the ground?
By now, she's nodded that thing right off and
she's pissed. And the first person she sees
is Enchantress, just giving Cheetah Wonder Woman
vibes. And so she attacks. moving on three
legs, slashing before Enchantress can even like
react. She does, you know, zipped by two more
times, taking out her hands and her throat.
So Enchantress is just slashed to death before
she could even really react. So Enchantress
is out. Um, meanwhile, I'm going to say Radioactive
Man, uh, sees friggin' Solomon Grundy lumbering
about and he thinks he's gross. And he figures
that the monster can't grow back if there's
nothing left to row. So basically, Radioactive
Man just incinerates the guy. He burns every
bit of Solomon Grundy's organic tissue until
there's nothing left but the stank. And guess
what? It must be Saturday. Well, it's Sunday.
Except Solomon Grundy's dead, so it's Saturday.
Okay. And meanwhile, Cheetah tries to attack
Ultron, but like, she's not gonna do anything
to him. She's not scratching him. And Ultron
is gonna use his encephalo ray on her. which
is gonna hypnotize her into just like staying
still for once, at which point he just energy
blasts her to pieces. So Cheetah's out. Wait,
so who's left? Brainiac and Lex Luthor, you
have Ultron, Radioactive Man, and Absorbing
Man? Yeah. Okay, so Absorbing Man, he's part
tech now. That's cool, because once Brainiac
realized that, he sent out a swarm of microscopic
nanites that invaded... Absorbing man's body
allowing brainiac to take it over and once he's
fully in control He's gonna abandon his old
body and just transmit his consciousness into
absorbing man. So now he has his power and
absorbing that himself is out of the match like
his mind is gone and Brainiac is gonna techno
morph his new body to resemble like an adamantium
robot skeleton and he's just gonna straight-up
march right toward Radioactive Man, tanking
all of his blasts since radiation can't do
much to adamantium, and Brainiac's gonna technomorph
his ball and chain into a robotic tentacle,
and he's gonna send that out to grasp Radioactive
Man and just crush him, snapping his spine
and taking him out. Okay, I mean, like, if Brainiac
has taken over Absorbing Man, like, he's not
just this adamantium robot now. He's also...
a guy who can absorb anything he touches, right?
But like, if the comics have taught us anything,
absorbing man's power is not stable, you know,
it's volatile and requires a lot of experience
so that he doesn't accidentally absorb the
wrong properties of something. And Brainiac
doesn't know this, but Ultron does. He knows
absorbing man's powers. So Ultron's gonna technomorph
his body to like pull moisture out of the air,
like refrigeration technology, kinda. and the
moisture is gonna condense into water vapor
and Ultron's gonna throw this water on Brainiac,
just dousing him, and that's gonna cause Brainiac
to instantly turn into a puddle and disperse
into the ground. Science. That was dumb. Ha
ha ha. That was, well, where else is Ultron
gonna get water from? I'm sure there's blood
on the battlefield, I don't know. Okay, sure,
yeah, that's better. Ultron picks up some severed
limb from the battleground and then like throws
some blood at Brainiac. But either way, Brainiac
turns into a puddle and is no longer in the
match. Okay, so just Lex Luthor and Ultron
are left. Boom. EMP blast. Ultron is finished
by Lex Luthor. That was easy! You think it
would be that easy, but when Lex Luthor tries
to shut down Ultron, little did Lex know that
his armor was already taken over by an Ultron
Technovirus. Little did Ultron know that Lex
recognized the Ultron virus ages ago, quarantined
it, and has been wirelessly transmitting false
data to Ultron to make him think his virus was
working when it really wasn't. Well little
did Lex know that Ultron assumed he would attempt
some kind of failsafe against his tech virus,
so he programmed it to make Lex's systems think
that the virus had been quarantined but in
fact it was not. that Lex had installed the
newly upgraded Norton Antivirus Plus, now available
to download at norton.com. I mean, little did
Lex know that McAfee is the only tried and
true antivirus software, which you can now get
for 10% off using the code DULACHECKOUT. Not
really, guys. Do not try to do that. Yeah. But
yeah, we could probably leave the match there.
So either Lex Luthor discharges an EMP that
shuts down Ultron, or Ultron uploads a techno
virus that takes over Lex Luthor's suit, shuts
it down, and then just blows up Lex Luthor.
Sure, yeah, let's go with that. Let's find out
which one of these scenarios happens by running
the simulations for this team battle and coming
back with the winning team. 8G9K, hit it! Inputting
data. Running calculations. Processing results.
Simulations complete. Alright, that was a pretty
good matchup. I had a lot of fun with that speculation.
Please do not try to download any antivirus
software using Code Duel at checkout because
it will not work. The results of the simulations
were pretty interesting. There's a huge disparity
between the power levels of a lot of these
characters for both of our teams. My weakest
guy was Whirlwind and his stats were way different
from my most powerful guy who was Ultron. Yeah,
comparatively, my weakest guy was Solomon Grundy,
who was by far the weakest member of either
team, though Brainiac was the strongest member
of either team. So I had both the weakest and
the strongest guys. Yeah, Solomon Grundy is
not impressive statistically, like at all. Poor
guy. But like Brainiac is so overpowered, he
almost has no business being in this match.
Which I love. So you kind of have that going
for and against you. A lot of your guys actually
had winning records against the Masters of
Evil, including Lex Luther, Brainiac, Gorilla
Grodd won a majority of his matches, so did
Sinestro, which is quite impressive. The only
guys on my team that had winning records were
Ultron, Enchantress, and Klawe. The rest of
them won around a quarter to a third of their
matches. Freakin' Solomon Grundy though only
won 8% out of all of his battles, his thousands
of battles. Yeah, that threw my average off
big time. The lowest guy for you was what,
22% win rate? Yeah, Roland won about a quarter
of his matches. So averaging it all out and
considering all the stats, who do you think
is going to win this match? Oh, it's got to
be the Legion of Doom. And Instagram wholeheartedly
agrees with me. 74% of our Instagram poll takers
said that the Legion was going to win. And that's
why I'm going to say that poll is full of crap.
But let's go ahead and get the real results.
AG9K, the results please. Hey, Yuasa. All right,
the winner in the team duel between the Legion
of Doom and the Masters of Evil is the Masters
of Evil. The what? The Legion of Doom. Wait,
wait, wait. I tried to fake you out right there,
but no, I couldn't do it. The Legion of Doom
won, and it wasn't that close. They won 56.9%
of the time over the Masters of Evil, 43.1%.
So averaging out to 1000 simulated battles,
Legion of Doom won 569, and Masters of Evil
won 431. Yeah, that's a pretty solid win percentage
for Team DC here. Just goes to show that quantity
of years of comic book history does not equate
to quality on the battlefield. This is bullshit.
It's so lame losing to a team that's like barely
even a fucking team. They were invented in the
cartoon and then they like made one appearance
in the comics. They're a real team in our hearts,
Joseph. In our hearts. That's what counts.
That's stupid. You're stupid. Clearly for choosing
the losing team. Your face is stupid. Your
face looks like my face, which also makes your
face stupid. Damn it! Just quit while you're
behind. That does it for this team duel. Let
us know what you guys thought about the results
by writing to us at dyna or by visiting us on
Instagram, which you can find a link to in
our show notes or by visiting our website at
dynamicduel.com. And on our site, you could
also find a link to our Patreon page where you
could join our dynamic two-o tier and chat
with us and fellow listeners, our fantastic
four tier, which gets you bonus content each
month, our X-Force tier that makes you an executive
producer of this podcast. or our newest here
that lets you join our DynaMic Podcast Network.
Please don't forget to rate the show on Apple
Podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser or on our website.
Our next episode is going to be a review for
a movie that ties into this duel. We're going
to review Justice League Doom, which is an
animated DC film that incorporates the Legion
of Doom as the villains. It's a great animated
film from DC. If you guys haven't seen it, definitely
check it out before next week. But that does
it for this episode, we want to give a big thanks
to our executive producers Ken Johnson, John
Swarovski, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Balcom, Miggy
Mathagean, Brandon Estregard, Nathaniel Wagner,
Levi Yeaton, Austin Wazilovski, AJ Dunkerley,
Scott Camacho, Adam Spies, Andrew Shunk, and
Dean Molesky for helping make this podcast possible.
And we'll talk to you guys next week. Up, up
and away, true believers. My supervillain team
is called the masters of debaters.