This is a Dynamike Network podcast.
Hi and welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast,
a weekly show where we review superhero films
and debate the superiority between Marvel and
DC by comparing their characters and stat-based
battle simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe. And I'm
his twin brother Johnny DC. And in this episode,
we're going to find out who'd win in a fight
between the Superman villain, Metallo, and
the Thor slash Iron Man villain, Radioactive
Man. Now they're both characters who emit radiation.
And that is pretty much it. I'm trying to think
of what to add and there really isn't anything
to its radioactivity type match. Of course,
we're doing this in lead up to our team duel
that's coming out in a few weeks where we pit
the Legion of Doom. versus the Masters of Evil,
and Radioactive Man has been a prominent member
of the Masters of Evil in many of its incarnations.
Before we get into that fight, we're going to
break down the latest Comic Quick movie news
to come out this past week, of which we just
have one news item, and that is the Justice
League Crisis on Infinite Earths Part 2 official
trailer and release date. As always, we list
our segment times in our episode description,
so feel free to check out the show notes if
you want to skip ahead to a particular topic.
Our artificially intelligent dual simulator
AJ9K has a quick message for our listeners,
so listen up. Why hello there. Do you love
listening and chatting about Marvel and DC?
Then become a part of the dynamic dual community
on Patreon, where you can choose from three
tiers. The dynamic 2-0 tier lets you listen
to this podcast without ads and gives you access
to its Discord chat group, where you can chat
with Johnny DC and Marvelous Joe. The fantastic
four tier gives you that and more with two
bonus episodes each month. including bloopers
and top 10 shows where Johnny and Joe count
down your favorite Marvel and DC subjects. The
X-Force tier makes you an executive producer
of Dynamic Jewel, where every month you help
the hosts choose what to review and who to
fight against each other. And finally, the Dynamite
Podcast Network tier allows aspiring podcasters
to create their own battle-focused show using
this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe
will help you develop your show, provide graphic
support and consultation, and get you simulation
results Pitch the twins your show via email
at dynamic dual podcast at gmail.com or by
reaching out to them on social media Check it
out at patreon.com slash dynamic dual pip cheerio
Thanks a j9k and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast including Miggy math again whose
birthday was this past week happy birthday,
Miggy happy birthday, man if I could get you
a gift from Marvel I would get you an adamantium
skeleton because then you wouldn't break any
bones. And that's just convenient going through
life knowing that that'll never happen. Think
of all like the skateboarding tricks and stuff
you could do. I know you don't skateboard,
but you know, like you could take it up. And
I'll take that up a notch. I will give you
for your birthday, Captain Adam's metallic skin
shell. It's called Dillistell or silver shield.
So you got metal on the outside, metal on the
inside, kind of makes the metal on the inside
redundant, but whatever. Happy birthday, man.
Really glad to have you as a patron and an
executive producer. Because we want to remind
you to tune into the shows in the Dynamike
podcast network this week, including Max Destruction,
which pits your favorite action heroes from
film and television against each other. This
week, host Ken Scottie will find out who'd
win in a fight between Johnny from Surf Ninjas
and Colt from Three Ninjas. We got it wrong
last week. Last week's episode was a review
of the movie Dread. On the Sanjo World podcast,
host Zachary Hepburn speculates on fights. between
fan favorite anime characters. This Thursday,
we'll find out who would win in a fight between
Noelle Silva from Black Culver and Juvia Lockser
from Fairy Tail. And on the console combat podcast
hosts John and Dean find out who would win
in fights between popular video game characters.
Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or click on the link
in our show notes to listen to all of the shows
in the Dynamike Podcast Network. But with that
out of the way, quick to the no prize. A no
prize is an award Marvel used to give out to
fans. Our version, the Dynamic Dual No Prize,
is a digital award we post on Instagram for
the person that we feel gave the best answer
to our question of the week. Last week's question
was, what was your favorite character from the
X-Men 90s cartoon besides Wolverine and why?
And that question is coming off of the trailer
that we got a couple weeks ago for X-Men 97.
We got two answers. for this week's no prize
question. So let's go ahead and run down our
honorable mention and the no prize winner. Our
first honorable mention goes to DK, who said.
Hey guys, DK here. So one of my favorite characters,
besides Wolverine in the anime series, is going
to be Nightcrawler. He has the awesome power
set of teleportation, but he also has a tragic
backstory that makes you feel for the character.
Unlike other mutants who are able to somewhat
blend in, he comes across as a demon to people
due to his physical appearance. But despite
all that, he still tries to help out. And he
still remains one of my favorite characters
to this day. Yeah, I don't remember Nightcrawler
appearing too much in the 90s X-Men cartoon.
I think he appeared in a few episodes, but he
was really good in those episodes. He found
out that Mystique was his mother and everything.
He was really touching. Nightcrawler has always
been an awesome character. And it would have
been nice if he was a regular on that television
show. Yeah, he was a regular on the X-Men Evolution
series, which was really cool. because Nightcrawler
is just awesome. Great answer, DK. That brings
us to the winner of this week's No Prize, who
is Travis Herndon. Who said? Hey guys, Travis
here. So my pick will have to be Bishop. I
think he's a pretty cool character. I love his
powers, his design. I feel like he's a very
underrated X-Man character. Like only like big
Marvel fans will know who he is, as well as
him kind of getting overshadowed by other. more
popular black superheroes like Storm, Luke
Cage, and Miles Morales. So but yeah, but besides
that, Bishop is my favorite. Bishop also was
not a mainstay of the X-Men 90s cartoon, but
he did appear in more episodes than Nightcrawler,
which is why Travis gets this week's no prize
win. Bishop was part of the quintessential
storyline, Days of Future Past, but The cartoon
adapted it in a really great way, having Bishop
come back in time instead of Kitty Pryde, who
came back in time in the comics. And Bishop's
just awesome. I love that character. Totally,
I think, underutilized for how awesome his
power set is of kinetic energy absorption. If
you guys wanna learn more about Nightcrawler
and Bishop, be sure to check out our dual episodes
where we pit Nightcrawler against Creeper and
Bishop against Ourman. Those are some great
episodes. I love those episodes. Definitely
check them out if you haven't already. You're
not allowed to say that because you produce
them. So, yeah, you can't. I'm patting myself
on the back. Good job, Jonathan. But congrats
again to Travis Herndon for winning this week's
No Prize. If you the listener want a shot at
winning your own No Prize, stay tuned to later
on in this episode when we will be asking another
question of the week. And now that that's done,
onto the news.
Okay, Justice League Crisis on Infinite Earths
Part 2 is of course the sequel to Crisis on
Infinite Earths Part 1, which we just reviewed
a couple of weeks ago. I really enjoyed that
film. It was kind of hard to follow considering
the non-linear structure of the narrative,
but I thought it was kind of brilliant and I've
been really looking forward to Part 2 and this
trailer did not disappoint. No, yeah, I mean,
I thought the first movie was okay. I do think
it set up tremendous potential for the trilogy
of films. And to see the trailer for part two,
I was impressed as well. Yeah, it looks like
it's going to be very action packed and continue
the story in an epic fashion. Yeah. And as we
predicted with the conclusion of part one,
the way it kind of segue towards Supergirl,
it looks like this trailer will in fact follow
her along with Batman and his relationship with
some Robins, I think from some other Earths.
The trailer starts off with Psycho Pirate, however,
interacting with Dr. Strange, who's explaining
to Psycho Pirate that he has a role to play
in this upcoming crisis. And I'm really curious
to see how that will compare in the movie to
Psycho Pirate's role in the comics. We'll definitely
have to do a Psycho Pirate duel close to when
this film comes out, which is pretty soon.
They announced that the release date for this
is going to be April 23rd, so just in a couple
months. Of course, like in the Crisis on Infinite
Earths comic, The multiverse gets attacked
by shadow demons that are under the control
of the anti-monitor. And we don't see the anti-monitor
in this trailer, but it looks like we do get
to see perhaps the formation of him. It looks
like there's a big reveal that happens that,
you know, we'll have to wait to see in the
movie. But there's also some great cameos in
this trailer as well. Not only do we get Batman
Beyond, who we saw in the teaser for part two,
but we also get Commandee from the DC Showcase
short. and the Doom Patrol, Blue Beetle, Peacemaker,
just a massive cast of characters that I can't
wait to see. Frickin' metal manor in this, that's
awesome. Yeah, it looks like a huge cast of
characters, even bigger than the first film.
It was really nice to see the Dr. Fate cameo
present the characters much more capable than
his first appearance in Justice Society World
War II. Oh my gosh, I hated that. He sounded
like Eric Cartman. in that first appearance.
He definitely sounds much cooler here and looks
much cooler as he should, because Dr. Faye
is dope. Robin seemed a little whiny, though.
He was like yelling at Batman. He's like, you
made my adolescence suck or something like that.
I was like, OK, you hurt my feelings. No, I
can't tell which Robin that is. It might be
Dick Grayson from Earth to it might be maybe
even Jason Todd from another universe. I'm curious
to find out who that is as well. Might be Damien.
Might be, you're right. Yeah, that's true. I'm
really curious to find out what's going on
with the Bat family because it looks like they're
going to be doing a lot of shadow demon battling
here and a lot of battling of their own demons
as a family. Exactly. Couldn't be a metaphor
for anything, right? Yeah. Again, the movie
drops late April. It's going to be released
digitally and on Blu-ray. So look for it then.
And we'll definitely review it on this podcast.
Yeah, and if you haven't seen the first movie
yet, be sure to check that out and listen to
our review on it. But considering the multiversal
nature of the story of Crisis on Infinite Earths,
that brings us to our question of the week.
What is your favorite universe in the Marvel
or DC multiverse and why? Yeah, other than,
you know, the primary universe, 616 and Earth
one. Record your answer at dynamic duel dot
com by clicking on the red microphone button
in the bottom right hand corner of the screen,
which will prompt you to leave us a voicemail.
Your message could be up to 30 seconds long.
And don't forget to leave your name in case
we include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a dynamic
duel. No prize that will post to Instagram.
Be sure to answer before March 2nd.
But I think that does it for all the news for
this episode, so let's go ahead and get into
our main event where we find out who'd win in
a fight between the Superman villain of Metallo
and the Thor slash Iron Man villain, Radioactive
Man.
Alright, Metallo versus Radioactive Man. Again,
as we said earlier, this episode will be in
lead up to our team duel episode in a few weeks
where we pit the Legion of Doom versus the
Masters of Evil and Radioactive Man has been
a prominent member of the Masters of Evil.
Yeah, when we were coming up with match ideas
for Radioactive Man, I was thinking Damage
would have been a good opponent for him, but
our executive producers pitched Metallo, I
believe, which I thought was a great choice.
a really popular Superman villain, we haven't
done a duel with him yet, and I like the whole
radioactive aspect between these two characters.
I don't actually know much about Radioactive
Man, but of course everyone knows that Metallo
has a kryptonite heart and uses its radiation
to combat heroes like Superman, Batman, Doom
Patrol, people like that. I imagine he sucks
when he's going up against heroes that aren't
Superman. Like against Superman, he's totally
OP, and then against everyone else, like no
one gives a shit. No, that's not the case at
all. Like he flashes his green rock and they're
like, big whoop, and then they beat the shit
out of him. Yeah, lasers still burn. You know?
Okay, touche, touche. To explain the methodology
behind our duels, let's go to our sentient
duel simulator, Alfred Jarvis 9000. AJ9K, tell
our listeners how you go about determining
a winner in our duel matchups. Yes, of course,
sir. The way I determine a winner between the
contestants is by running 1000 Monte Carlo simulations
using the characters statistics. A Monte Carlo
simulation is a probabilistic model used to
determine outcomes through random sampling.
In this case, I randomise the statistics along
a normal distribution as a way to simulate
the many variables that can occur during battle.
The stat parameters are based on the official
Marvel power grid from which the DC characters
statistics are extrapolated.
damage potential, versatility and perception
in order to create a more detailed and accurate
simulation. The results of the 1000 simulations
provide a percentage of wins for each character.
The contestant with the higher percentage is
declared the victor as they have a higher probability
to win any given battle. In an equitable pairing,
neither character should win 100% of the matches.
The comic book stories have shown that there's
even a way for Batman to defeat Superman. So
the confidence rate of my method falls in line
with the precedents that have been established
in the source material. My mathematical simulations
are without subjectivity or bias. Feats are
not the sole consideration, nor are fan votes
tabulated for determination of the winner.
Thanks, J9K! Before we run the simulations though,
we like to break down each character's histories
and abilities before improvising a scenario
on how we imagine one of the 1000 simulations
would play out beat for beat. And I believe
it's my turn to go first this episode with
the Marvel character. So let me go ahead and
tell you all about Radioactive Man. And it's
not the Simpsons version, by the way. Marvel
always ripping everything off. Excuse you.
Obviously, this version of Radioactive Man came
out before the Simpsons version. So I agree
to disagree. And also like Marvel and the Simpsons
have the same parent company, Disney now. So
it's all moot. They got to sue themselves or
something. All right, Chen Lu. was born in
Lanshao, China, where he grew up to become a
nuclear physicist and the country's foremost
authority in nuclear radiation. When China once
attempted to use its military to invade India,
the hero Thor stopped them, prompting the Chinese
government to develop a means to stop Thor
and other Western heroes like him. They consulted
with military strategists and scientists for
a solution, and it was Chen Lu who suggested
using nuclear radiation to induce superpowers
in human beings. He was so sure of his concept,
having been experimenting with radioactive
effects for years that he offered himself as
the first test subject. With the Chinese government's
approval, Chen Lu exposed himself to massive
doses of particle radiation, transforming him
into the green glowing radioactive man. Impressing
his government with his newfound powers, they
smuggled Chen Lu into New York, where he attacked
Thor. During the battle, Thor learned that
a sufficient physical attack against Chen Lu
would cause him to erupt like an H-bomb in
the middle of the city. To save New York, the
hero used his hammer Mjolnir to summon a wind
vortex so powerful that it sucked up and carried
Chen Lu back to an area of unpopulated China
where the villain reached critical mass and
exploded, seemingly dead. You can learn more
about Thor in our duel episode where we pit
him against Wonder Woman. Later, however, it
was revealed that Chen Liu survived and went
into hiding due to his failure to defeat Thor.
He was found and contacted by the villain Baron
Zemo, who recruited Chen Liu into a supervillain
team called the Masters of Evil. The Masters
of Evil attacked the Avengers, but were defeated,
Chen Liu specifically, by Iron Man, who became
his new signature foe. When the robot villain
Ultron formed a second iteration of the Masters
of Evil, he also recruited Chen Lu, but the
supervillain team again failed. Chen Lu broke
out of prison and retreated to live in Vietnam,
where he and the Iron Man adversaries Crimson
Dynamo and Titanium Man formed their own group
called the Titanic Three, champions of Eastern
communism and defenders of the people. However,
the pool of revenge was too strong, and Chen
Lu was recruited into a third iteration of
the Masters of Evil. this time led by the Ant-Man
villain, Egghead. Though they attempted to
humiliate and disgrace Ant-Man, he ultimately
foiled their plans and the team disbanded.
Chen Liu was deported back to China, where he
became an agent of the Mandarin, a Chinese
villain warlord that you can learn more about
in his duel against Abracadabra. As a henchman
for the Ten Rings, he went toe-to-toe with Iron
Man, who took him to the Vault, a nuclear-powered
prison that at the time was undergoing a meltdown.
Iron Man convinced Chen Liu to absorb the excess
radiation, which saved the prisoners and guards.
He later became a henchman for Tiberius Stone,
a rival of Tony Stark's, who sought to discredit
Stark International, the Hero's Corporation.
You can learn more about Iron Man in his duel
against Cyborg. After a string of failures,
Chen Liu began experiencing fluctuations in
his energy levels, realizing that his powers
were tied to his well-being. He determined he
had spent so much of his time working for others,
be it the Chinese government, the Masters of
Evil, the Mandarin, or other bureaucrats and
megalomaniacs, people he secretly felt superior
to, when he should just be working toward his
own interests. To that end, he became a hero
for the Chinese people, vowing to do a good
deed for every person he had ever killed or
harmed, directly or indirectly, through his
powers. One of his heroic actions was to defend
China from an attack by a group of Atlantean
criminals called the Fathoms Five, where he
was assisted by the latest incarnation of the
Thunderbolts, which was a team of villains turned
heroes. Chen Lu joined the Thunderbolts ranks
and secretly irradiated one of the Fathom Five
members so that when they returned to Atlantis
to stand trial, the whole group would all die
from radiation. On loan from China, Chen Liu
traveled with the Thunderbolts back to New York
where they helped repel an attack by the villainous
organization Hydra, and then went after heroes
who refused to register with the government's
Superhuman Registration Act. He was dismayed
to learn that the Chinese government wanted
him to stay with the Thunderbolts in America
to keep him away from China due to the danger
he posed. However, Chen Liu was later forced
to return to his home country when Norman Osborn
took control of the Thunderbolts. and didn't
want him interfering with his plans to use
the team for his own personal agenda. You can
learn more about Norman Osborn in our Joker
vs Green Goblin duel episode. Working with China's
People's Defense Force, Chen Lu helped stop
an attack from new Inhumans who were granted
power by the Terrigin Mists released into Earth's
atmosphere by the Inhuman King Black Bolt, whom
you can learn more about in his duel against
Shazam. Eventually, Chen Lu was asked to join
a new incarnation of the Thunderbolts team
in New York. an invite that he accepted. And
that's his backstory. Powers-wise, radioactive
man can manipulate radioactive energies for
a variety of effects, including but not limited
to radioactive energy blasts that can incinerate
a city block, intense light generation capable
of causing temporary blindness, and radiation
absorption. This allows him to absorb energy
attacks directed against him and temporarily
depower opponents whose abilities are granted
by radiation, such as the Hulk or Spider-Man,
by absorbing that radiation from them. His
radiation can also temporarily enhance his natural
physiology, granting him 9 vulnerability and
increased strength able to lift around 2 tons.
He can manifest radioactive energy constructs
such as force fields, tendrils, or even energy
copies of himself. He can also generate low
level radiation to cause sickness and radiation
poisoning within an enemy, and can also emit
an electromagnetic pulse. Finally, Radioactive
Man is a world scientific authority in the
field of nuclear physics and radioactivity.
Yeah, too bad, kryptonite is an alien xenomineral
that he's not going to be able to absorb the
radiation for. I'm sure he can give it his
best shot. And fail. Sounds good to me. Let
me get into his opponent, Mattello's backstory.
Now John Corbin was a con man who was fatally
wounded in a car crash as he was fleeing a
crime. His body was recovered by Professor Emmett
Vale, a specialist in cybernetics who had previously
intercepted and misinterpreted a message from
Jor-El to his son Superman, and believed that
Superman was a scout in an impending alien invasion.
You can learn more about Superman in our Superman
vs. Dr. Doom episode. Professor Vale transferred
Corbin's brain into a robotic body made from
an indestructible alloy known as metallo and
powered by a two-pound chunk of kryptonite,
a radioactive remnant of Superman's birth planet
that weakens him. Enraged by what had been
done to him, Corbin killed the Professor once
he had completed covering the metal chassis
with a foam latex sheath that resembled human
skin, allowing Corbin to pass as human. Built
with no purpose other than to kill Superman,
Corbin adhered to his creator's wishes and
fought the Man of Steel as the villain, Metello,
named after the metal that composed his body.
Metello nearly killed Superman until Lex Luthor
intervened as he had realized the value in
Corbin's kryptonite heart and took it for himself,
shutting Corbin's body down for a time. You
can learn more about Lex Luthor in his dual
episode against Baron Zemo. Placed in a storage
vault within LexCorp, Mattello's backup power
system kicked in and he escaped, later returning
to LexCorp to raid Lex's growing stash of kryptonite
and to steal parts for cybernetic upgrades
to his body. While seeking more cybernetic parts,
Mattello found some intended for Robotman.
a member of the Doom Patrol, who you can learn
more about in our Robotman vs. Thing episode.
After getting into a fight with the Doom Patrol,
Metallo's body was destroyed, leaving only
his head surviving intact, which Loser collected
and stored inside of a crate. Eventually, Metallo
was brought back to life and his head placed
on a new robotic body when Brainiac secretly
invaded LuxCorp's computer network. Metallo
agreed to work with Brainiac, who created robotic
duplicates of Metallo to distract Superman while
Metallo led a robot invasion of LuxCorp and
Cadmus Labs. Using stolen cybernetic and cloning
technology, Metallo was able to help Brainiac
build himself a new body. You can learn more
about Brainiac in our Brainiac vs Ultron episode.
Metallo was destroyed by Superman, however,
and his head was quarantined on Strikers Island
After being rebuilt and destroyed several more
times, Metallo sold his soul to the demon Neuron,
who in exchange gave Metallo the ability to
technomorph his body like a transformer and
incorporate nearby metal and machinery into
his frame. Metallo was eventually defeated
by the hero Steel, who tricked Metallo into
absorbing a bomb into himself. You can learn
more about Steel in his duel against War Machine.
During Gwaidu-K, Brainiac 13 created a new
body for Metallo, though Superman received help
from the Metal Man, Led, to remove Metallo's
kryptonite heart once again. You can learn more
about Led in our Metal Man vs. Colossus episode.
When Lex Luthor was elected President of the
United States, he had Metallo transform into
a colossal spaceship to take on General Zod,
who had transformed Earth's sun into a red
star. For his efforts in helping save the world,
President Luthor pardoned Metello for his past
crimes, and Metello was set free. When Batman
and Superman went on a mission to remove all
Kryptonite from Earth, Batman replaced Metello's
heart with an electric battery in exchange
for Metello's Kryptonite. When Superboy Prime
and Alexander Luther Jr. from Earth-3 attempted
to restore DC's multiverse, reality was warped
and Metello's origin was revised so that John
Corbin was a sergeant in the US Army under the
command of General Sam Lane, the father of
Lois Lane, whom the General was hoping would
one day marry Sergeant Corbin. At the behest
of the General, Corbin volunteered to don experimental
Exosu armor powered by Zero, that was developed
by LuxCorp to combat Superman, who the General
saw as an extraterrestrial threat to humanity.
The Kryptonite proved to be an unstable power
source, however, and after an energy surge
within the suit nearly killed Corbin, Lex Luthor
was forced to fuse Corbin to the suit, turning
him into a Kryptonite-powered cyborg. In post-Flashpoint
continuity, Corbin's new origin largely remained
the same. though his childhood was revealed
to be traumatic, as he was forced to shoot
and kill his father to protect his sister Tracy.
After enlisting in the army at a young age,
Corbin volunteered to don an experimental suit
once again, though this time it was designed
by Lux Corp weapons engineer John Henry Irons,
who would later be known as the hero Steel.
The suit, however, was taken over by Brainiac,
causing Corbin's heart to burst. Powered by
Kryptonite and controlled by Brainiac, Irons
was able to defeat this new version of Metallo
by building his own power suit and uploading
a virus into Metallo to stop both him and Brainiac.
Metallo helped Superman defeat Brainiac, though
was injured in the process and placed into
a coma. To save his life, Corbin was once again
fused with the suit, and given a kryptonite
heart to survive. Proving to be mentally unstable
once he awoke, Corbin's organic body was eventually
destroyed in an attempt to blow up Superman,
though Brainiac uploaded a memory engram of
Corbin's mind into the Metello suit to keep
him functional. After Brainiac's defeat, it
was later revealed that Corbin's brain had survived.
and that upon learning that Lex Luthor had
framed his sister Tracy for murder, Horbin agreed
to be placed in a new humanoid synthetic body,
also powered by kryptonite, to do Lex Luthor's
bidding. And that's Mattello's backstory. Powers-wise,
Mattello's nigh-indestructible metal frame grants
him super strength, and his cybernetic augmentation
grants him enhanced senses and processing speed,
allowing him to react, strategize, and analyze
probability faster than humanly possible. Upgrades
to his body have allowed him to transform his
limbs into bladed, club, and projectile weapons
such as chainsaws, hammers, guns, and cannons.
The latter, which can shoot bullet shards of
his kryptonite hearts or beams of radiation.
This energy can also be projected from his eyes
or from his chest when he opens panels for
maximum exposure to its radiation. And that's
Metallo. Metallo's always been a cool Superman
villain. He's probably one of my favorites.
I'm really glad that we're finally getting
to do a duel with him because he just has a
cool look to him. But it also seems like he
has a pretty interesting backstory. I mean,
there are three different versions of the backstory,
but that's DC for you. There's also like three
different versions of Metallo that I didn't
even go into a few of the others. Like one of
them was John Corbin's brother for a time who
kind of took up his mantle. It was dumb and
short lived. And there's even a metallo that
predates him. That's, you know, a little bit
different, but it's only spelled with one L.
So I do agree that the look of my tallow is
pretty cool. It's kind of like a T 800 Terminator,
but with green glowing guys instead of red.
Yeah, I think that's why his look appeals to
me, just because that pop culture appeal with
Terminator. Right. Yeah.
Now that we've got their histories and abilities
out of the way, let's speculate on how one
of the 1000 simulated matches will go. The winner
is determined by simulations, not the speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how this fight could
play out. AJ9K, what are the rules of our speculation?
Well, I should say there are no rules, other
than the characters have no prior knowledge
of the other going into the fight. All they
are aware of starting out is that the other
character is a threat that needs to be eliminated.
For the speculation... The contestants will
begin approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the
match itself, as no environmental statistics
are considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. Alright
then let's get into it. Metallo and Radioactive
Man meet on the battlefield. Who goes first?
I think Metallo would actually go first in
this one because he's more of a soldier, right?
Whereas like Radioactive Man's more of a scientist.
No, I agree. Metallo will go first, and he's
going to start off with a ranged attack. He's
going to transform his hand into like an energy
blaster and blast Radioactive Man with a laser
beam of kryptonite radiation. That's not going
to do anything because Radioactive Man is going
to throw up a force field and this energy force
field just deflects the kryptonite radiation
and Radioactive Man is going to walk toward
Metallo with his hand outstretched and he's
going to emit like a low level... wave of radiation
that sweeps through and poisons the organic
portions of Matalo's body just causing them
to decay and burn away. Dude, the only remaining
human parts of Matalo is his brain and that
thing's heavily protected and shielded in lead
so your attack like literally does nothing but
make Matalo look cooler now that Radioactive
Man has singed off his synthetic skin. He's
basically Terminator now. And now Attalo is
going to respond by leaping towards Radioactive
Man, and he's going to transform his arm into
a chainsaw, and he's going to straight up massacre
Radioactive Man. Except Radioactive Man has
enhanced durability. Like he's bulletproof.
He's highly durable. That makes no sense. Like
why? Well, for the same reason he has enhanced
strength. It's like not only can he emit radiation,
the radiation also powers him like it would
the Hulk, although not nearly to that extent.
I guess the Hulk is a precedent. That's yeah,
you did chainsaws not gonna hurt radioactive
man for one but I don't even think that Mattel
is chainsaws gonna even reach radioactive man
because Radioactive man is gonna generate an
energy construct of this like tendril That's
just gonna slap Mattel Oh out of the air and
send him crashing to the ground at which point
Radioactive man is gonna superheat the floor
beneath Mattel Oh into this like green glowing
goo and Metallo is just gonna slowly sink into
it until he's fully submerged, except for like
his hand, and he just gives a thumbs up as he
slowly sinks into the radioactive pool. That's
great. I always just wanna leave it there. But
no, Metallo's not out. A few moments later,
the ground's gonna be rumbling beneath Radioactive
Man as Metallo drills his way out of the ground
into Radioactive Man, who he was able to track
underground. due to radioactive man's heat
signature. Okay, so, Matalo bursts from the
ground and drills into radioactive man, or
rather who he thought was radioactive man, because
it was really just a radioactive duplicate.
Duh. And as Matalo drills into this radioactive
copy, it's gonna explode in a flash of light
that just blinds Matalo, leaving him open for
attack. He has no eyes, or like... You know,
none that will be affected like human eyes since
he can see on multiple wavelengths. That's
right. What I meant to say is that the radioactive
duplicate exploded like a small nuclear bomb
and just vaporized Metello. But the Metello
alloy is durable enough to withstand a nuclear
blast. So Metello is just walking through the
fallout like a badass, just scanning for the
real radioactive man. OK. And when he spots
him, uh... his systems are just going to shut
down because Radioactive Man at that point unleashes
an EMP blast that renders Mattello inert. So
he's done match over. I know. I mean, because
Mattello still has his kryptonite power source.
So, you know, that'll just trigger his backup
systems that get him back up and running in
like no time. And at that point, Mattello is
going to catch Radioactive Man off guard because
he thought he was. you know, shut down and he's
going to fire this massive blast from his open
chest panel along with beams from his energy
cannon arms and eye blasts just overloading
radioactive man with kryptonite radiation and
that's going to cause him to self detonate,
just explode and die. No no, radioactive man
does not overload, okay? There's no limit to
the amount of energy that he can absorb. There
is with kryptonite radiation! Oh really? Why?
Because like, it's an exotic form of radiation
that's probably not even on the electromagnetic
spectrum. Why? Well, because I said! You're
just making shit up now. I say Radioactive
Man absorbs Metallo's energy attack, and not
only that, but Radioactive Man also absorbs
all of the energy from Metallo's kryptonite
heart, which is going to depower him, and that's
how Radioactive Man wins. But we can leave it
there. So in one scenario, radioactive man
absorbs the radiation from metallo's kryptonite
heart, depowering him. And in the other scenario,
metallo overloads radioactive man with kryptonite
energy, causing him to explode. We'll go ahead
and input the stats and run the simulations
on this matchup and come back with a winner.
AG9K, hit it! Inputting data, running calculations,
processing results, simulations complete. So
this was a... Really interesting matchup. I
know that when we went into it, we weren't
entirely sure if this was gonna be even or not
because I didn't know much about Matalo. You
didn't know much about Radioactive Man, but
in inputting the stats, it was really interesting
to see how the characters went back and forth
because like, Matalo is faster, but Radioactive
Man is more evasive because of his force field
shielding. We said that they're about equally
durable and they're actually very durable, but
we said that Matalo is sh- stronger ultimately
because this guy could hurl buses and Radioactive
Man for some reason can only lift two tons.
Yeah, you think he'd be stronger than that,
but he's not. However, Radioactive Man's damage
level is almost off the charts because he's
like a nuclear bomb. Yeah, Mattello's not quite
at that level, but he is a better fighter than
Radioactive Man because he has military training.
We said they have similar range, but Radioactive
Man is smarter. because he's a scientist, although
Mattello has greater perception due to his robotic
brain. Surprisingly, they were pretty evenly
matched when it came to versatility. I thought
Mattello was going to have the edge here because
for a lot of iterations, he's kind of like a
transformer, or at least parts of him are.
But really when it came down to it, he's only
working with one form of radiation, whereas
Radioactive Man is kind of working with all
of them. For the most part, their stats were
very much like back and forth. And these guys
did differ stat wise more than I thought they
would. Yeah, the stats weren't similar, but
they're still pretty even. Considering that,
Jonathan, who do you think is actually going
to win this? That's a great question. I'm hoping
Mattello is going to take the win. And it's
kind of hard to say who our Instagram followers
think is going to win, considering I put up
the poll just like an hour ago before this
recording. But right now it looks like Radioactive
Man is in the lead at 53%. So that sucks. Makes
sense to me, though. No, it makes zero sense
to me. Mattel is way more popular than Radioactive
Man. Why is that? Because he's in the freaking
cartoons and like Smallville and like all the
Superman stuff. Mattel is a really popular Superman
villain. Who the hell is Radioactive Man? I
would say before listening to this episode.
Well, I mean, Radioactive Man's been in the
cartoons, too. He was in Avengers Earth's Mightiest
Heroes cartoon and Avengers Assemble. Yeah,
no one watches those cartoons just because you
didn't. Yeah. Like if it didn't happen in the
90s, it doesn't count. All right, let's go out
and get the winner for this match. AJ 9K, the
results, please. Hey, you are, sir. All right.
The winner of the matchup between Matalo. and
Radioactive Man is... Metallo. YES! And it was
really close. Out of the 1000 simulated matches,
Metallo won 514 matches, whereas Radioactive
Man won 486, so it was 51.4% over 48.6%. Holy
crap! That is way closer than I thought it was
going to be. Yeah, really no character had
a massive advantage over the other. They both
just had so much going for them. And basically,
Metallo got lucky is what I'm thinking. It almost
kind of looks that way. I guess when it comes
down to perception and fighting and speed, it
really helped push Metallo over the edge. Yeah.
So however these guys fight, it seems like a
majority of the wins for Metallo happened due
to like hand to hand stuff, which makes sense
because really they can't. hurt each other
too much with their energy attacks. Yeah, no,
Metellus is just too protected against radiation
and radioactive man is too good at absorbing
radiation. Though apparently not kryptonite
radiation as we've learned. Okay. Now I think
a majority of these wins happen due to physical
combat. I guess that makes sense. So I'm not
happy about it, but damn, do I respect the
math. Hell yeah. That does it for this duel,
guys. Let us know what you thought about the
results by writing to us at dynamic dual podcast
at gmail.com or by visiting us on Instagram,
which you can find a link to in our show notes
or by visiting our website at dynamic dual
dot com. And on our site, you could also find
a link to our Patreon page where you could
join our dynamic to O tier and chat with us
and fellow listeners. Our fantastic four tier,
which gets you bonus content each month. Our
X force tier that makes you an executive producer
of this podcast. or our newest tier that lets
you join our Dynamike podcast network. Please
don't forget guys to rate the show on Apple
Podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser, or on our website.
Our next episode is going to be a review. We're
going to discuss the 2003 Ang Lee movie, Hulk,
which I love and I cannot wait to talk about.
The film gets way too much hate. The reason
we're reviewing that film is because Absorbing
Man is the primary villain of that movie and
he's also going to be on the Masters of Evil
roster for the team duel in the subsequent
episode. And also, you know, like Hulk deals
with gamma radiation and both characters in
this episode dealt with radiation, so it just
fits. Now I think is the time to review this
film. So look forward to that! But that does
it for this episode, we want to give a big
thanks to our executive producers Ken Johnson,
John Storosky, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Balcom,
Miggy Mathengian, Brandon Estregard, Nathaniel
Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Nick Abonto, Austin Wisselowski,
AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Adam Spies, Andrew
Shunk, and Dean Mielewski for helping to make
this podcast possible. We'll talk to you guys
next week. Up up and away, true believers.
Watch out radioactive man.