This is a Dynamike Network podcast.
Welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin brother, Marvelous
Joe. And in this episode, we are doing a duel
between the characters Dorothy Spinner from
The Doom Patrol and Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur.
This is the final duel in lead up to our big
team duel next episode. where we're gonna pit
the teams of Doom Patrol and Guardians of the
Galaxy against each other. Yeah, Dorothy Spinner
and Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur are both little
girl superheroes with big monsters as backup,
basically. It'll be a lot of fun to break down
these characters. Moon Girl has a fantastic
backstory that I was really glad to dive into,
so can't wait to talk all about her and figure
out who the heck's gonna win this matchup later
on this episode. Before that, we're gonna break
down the comic book movie news to come out in
the past week. of which there isn't much due
to the ongoing strikes. There was like a 45
second Loki season 2 teaser, so we're going
to talk about that. Yeah and this episode is
actually sponsored by the Chronicle AI card
game that Jonathan and I invented. That's right,
we are sponsoring our own episode because we
can. it's our podcast. So we're going to talk
a little bit about the card game that Jonathan
and I made. As always, we list our segment times
in our episode description, so feel free to
check out the show notes if you want to skip
ahead to a particular topic. As our listeners
may know, our duel simulator is so advanced
that it's gained sentience and has named itself
the artificial life form for running extensive
duels, just a rather very intelligent simulator
9000, or Alfred Jarvis 9000. Here's a quick
message for our listeners, so listen up. Why
hello there. Do you love listening and chatting
about Marvel and DC? Then become a part of
the dynamic dual community on Patreon where
you can choose from three tiers. The dynamic
2-0 tier lets you listen to this podcast without
ads and gives you access to its Discord chat
group where you can chat with Johnny DC and
Marvelous Joe. The Fantastic Four tier gives
you that and more with two bonus episodes each
month, including bloopers and top ten shows
where Johnny and Joe count down your favourite
Marvel and DC subjects. The X-Force tier makes
you an executive producer of Dynamic Duel, where
every month you help the host choose what to
review and who to fight against each other.
And finally, the Dynamite Podcast Network tier
allows aspiring podcasters to create their own
battle-focused show using this Monte Carlo
simulator.
graphic support and consultation and get you
simulation results to announce on your show.
Pitch the twins your show via email at dynamicduelpodcast
at gmail.com or by reaching out to them on
social media. Check it out at patreon.com slash
dynamic duel. Pip pip cheerio. Thanks, J9K,
and thanks to everyone who supports the podcast.
Be sure to tune into the Max Destruction podcast
this Wednesday, where Ken and Dustin find out
who'd win in a fight between John Matrix from
the Commando Movie. versus Robocop.
A No Prize is an award Marvel used to give out
to fans. Our version, the Dynamic Dual No Prize,
is a digital award we post on Instagram and
in our email newsletter for the person that
we feel gave the best answer to our question
of the week. We got a lot of great answers
this time. I think a total of eight people called
in. Unfortunately, we can only pick four answers
and there were only really four answers to give
because the question last week was... What
was your favorite Marvel or DC cartoon from
the 90s and why? I think the answers will be
pretty obvious, but it'll be interesting to
see which one comes out on top. Our first honorable
mention goes to Dustin Balcom, who said, Hey,
dynamic duelist Dustin Balcom here and I am
jumping in right away to get my answer because
I'm not going to let these DC robots come out
and just say Batman the animated series because
it is good, but my gosh grow personality. The
real answer is the 90s Spider-Man cartoon because
it was just perfection. And that's all I got
to say. That's right, Jonathan. Anyone who thinks
that Batman the Animated Series was the best
cartoon of the 90s basically has no personality,
according to Dustin. And he's right. The best
cartoon is actually Spider-Man, which was a
fantastic adaptation of the comic books. It
introduced kids to a whole bunch of other Marvel
superheroes. There were a lot of crossovers
in that show. Killer opening theme song. and
the show gave us the first example of the Spider-Verse.
I dunno, sounds kinda boring to me. What? Yeah.
I mean, big whoop. You know you watched that
shit. I did, it was good I guess. Travis Herndon
and Lizzie Dyer Arnie also gave the answer
of the 90's Spider-Man cartoon. But Colby Hentges
gave this answer. Hey boys, Colby Hentges.
I know these are usually opinion questions and
there's no right or wrong answer, but this
week is different. If you don't pick Batman,
the animated series, you're wrong. It's still
some of the best telling of some of Batman's
best stories. Kevin Conroy is Batman. Mark
Hamill is Joker. It's the best. B-Taz or bust.
Now, Joseph, I've got to ask you, would you
rather be boring or wrong? Uh, I'd rather be
wrong, I guess. That's fine. You rag about
everything, so it makes sense. I love how passionate
this week's answers are for this question.
How the DC guys have no personality and how
the Marvel guys are just wrong. But they are
because the Batman animated series is so good
with the music, with the voice work, even with
the character adaptations. And so influential
in terms of what came after it for DC. You
mean like the Superman show, Justice League?
Exactly. And even beyond that with the DC animated
movie universe films. Yeah, the legacy of the
show is pretty lasting, I'll admit that. We
want to give a shout out to Ezra Garcia who
also gave the answer of Batman the Animated
series. Our final honorable mention goes to
Scott Camacho who said, Johnny please do not
change the color of my name. But when it comes
to this category, I'm going to have to side
with Marvel, mainly the X-Men series.
banger of a soundtrack you cannot get any more
than the X-Men. Come on! That's right! Even
a DC fan can admit that the X-Men animated series
in the 90s was the best cartoon at that time.
Scotty mentioned the opening theme, which is
still the best theme in all of cartoons. His
brother, Gilly Macho, also gave the same answer
and made great points that... The show pretty
much defined the 90s as far as superheroes go
and it was highly influential in getting the
X-Men movie made which in turn probably helped
kickstart the MCU. So you know the influence
of the Batman animated series is one thing but
I think the influence of the X-Men animated
series was even greater and you know it's coming
back on Disney Plus next year. I don't see
Batman the animated series coming back. Well
they're trying to do it with Batman Kid Crusader.
I don't know what that is. It's Bruce Timm's
new Batman cartoon. Come on, keep up. Why would
I keep up with that? It's DC. Because DC's better.
Not according to Scotty. You know, I'm gonna
have to change him to Team Red on the Discord
from Team Blue. Scotty, let's strike one. Strike
one, my friend. Thanks to everyone for sending
in your answer, but the winner of this week's
No Prize is Brandon Estegard. Who said? I barely
make the cut off of a 90s skit. I'm also going
with a show that barely makes a cut and that's
Batman Beyond. I don't think there's a wrong
answer to this question, but what's that's Batman
above the rest? is that it doesn't have to
rely on storylines from the comics and can still
establish amazing episodes. It was a fresh
and creative take on Batman with the updated
style from the OG animated series. Yes, Spider-Man,
Batman the animated series, the X-Men animated
series were all great, but when you think of
Batman Beyond, it was almost like an amalgamation
of everything that made those other shows.
phenomenal. I guess you could say that because
you know, it had the cool animation style from
Batman the Animated Series as Brandon mentioned,
but it also had, you know, the killer soundtrack
like the Marvel cartoons did and more mature
plots and adult themes and things like that,
you know? Yeah, absolutely. That was a DC cartoon
that I think even Marvel fans have to admit
was insanely cool. It was almost like the Marvel
version of Batman, right? The fuck? Yeah, I'm
just gonna put that out there. Well, I'm not
agreeing with that. Now, for as good as Batman
Beyond was, I think X-Men actually was the clear
winner for this question. However, Brandon
was the only person to give the answer of Batman
Beyond, and he got points for originality with
this one, since we don't usually like to let
people share No Prizes, you know? Right. Congrats,
Brandon! You win this week's No Prize. If you,
the listener, want a shot at winning your own
No Prize, stay tuned to later on in this episode
when we'll be asking another Question of the
Week. And now that that's done... Onto the news!
Alright, there's not much news this past week
when it comes from Marvel and DC, but we did
get a teaser of sorts for the upcoming Loki
Season 2 on Disney+, which is strange because
we already got a full-on trailer for the show,
so it's kind of weird to get a 45 second teaser
after the trailer. Usually that's flipped around.
But we did get some pretty interesting new
shots of what's going down in Loki season 2
starting October 6. Like we said with the trailer,
this all looks phenomenal. The cinematography
and the visual effects are movie level. In
some cases, it looks even better than how the
movie looks, especially when it comes to the
set design and stuff. The teaser basically introduces
the concept that Loki is being pulled through
space and time involuntarily. He meets up with
Sylvie, who... appears is hiding out in like
McDonald's in the 1970s after the events of
season one where she Killed he who remains
and kickstarted the multiverse She still has
the really bad haircut But Loki and Sylvie
joined forces here going up against Victor Timely
who we get some new shots of Jonathan Majors
playing the character we also see Rhona Renslayer
from season one who in the comics is King of
the conquerors romantic interest She appears
to be in Victor Timely's timeline, and she's
holding this futuristic laser gun type device.
Yeah, it makes me wonder whose side she's on.
Like, is she gonna try and stop Kang, or is
she gonna try and stop Loki? That's a great
question. My inclination is that she's on Kang's
side, and she's probably his only ally, especially
since she was such a firm believer in the TVA
and its mission, even after she realized that
the leaders of the TVA were just lifeless automatons.
True, yeah, true. I mean, for a teaser, it
definitely teases. I don't know if I mentioned
this in our review of the latest trailer that
came out, but Loki was my favorite thing to
come out of the post-Endgame era of the Marvel
universe, next to Shang-Chi. So I'm really looking
forward to this, really intrigued by the marketing
that they're putting out for it, even if it's
just a 45-second teaser. Yeah, I'm also super
excited. We have less than a month before this
show comes out, and perhaps we'll get another
full-length trailer before that time, but we'll
see. That does it for the news for this episode.
Jonathan and I want to briefly remind listeners
that we created a card game for all you card
gamers and tabletop gamers out there and board
gamers. Jonathan and I have a deck building
card game that we developed over the span of
10 years or so and we've been told that it's
really fun and we played it and we think it's
really fun. So if you guys are into that kind
of stuff at all, visit ChronicleAIGame.com which
we will link in the show notes, and check out
the card game. Jonathan and I put a lot of work
into it and would appreciate any and all support
you guys can give in that capacity. We do have
a Marvel versus DC version of this card game
exclusive to patrons. So whether or not you
get the Chronicle AI version of the game, which
is robot themed, or the Marvel versus DC version
of the game, which we called Infinity Crisis,
let us know if you pick it up and what you think
about it. We'd love for you to play it. We
think it's great, and we think you'll think
the same. But speaking of card games, that
brings us to our question of the week.
To all the gamers out there, what is your favorite
non-video game, for Marvel or DC, and why?
You know, such as board games, card games, tabletop
games, anything physical like that you've played.
Yeah, Jonathan and I are big fans of board games
and stuff like that, so largely this question
is to help inform me, I think, about some of
the things that are out there that I may not
know about that I would love to check out. So
record your answer at dynamicduel.com by clicking
on the red microphone button in the bottom right
hand corner of the screen. which will prompt
you to leave us a voicemail. Your message could
be up to 30 seconds long and don't forget to
leave your name in case we include you on the
podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer and
award that person a Dynamic Dual Note Prize
that we'll post to Instagram and our email
newsletter. Be sure to answer before September
16th.
That does it for the news portion of this episode.
Now let's move on to the main event, where
we find out who's going to win in a match between
the Doom Patrol's Dorothy Spinner against Moon
Girl and Devil Dinosaur.
Okay, Dorothy Spinner against Moon Girl and
Devil Dinosaur. Of course, you'll be familiar
with Dorothy Spinner if you've seen any of the
HBO Max Doom Patrol series, or I guess it's
just Max now. Phenomenal series. If you haven't
watched it, I definitely recommend it, especially
season two, the season that Dorothy Spinner
is featured in. Yeah, Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur
actually have their own show too on the Disney
Kids channel and on Disney Plus, which is actually
incredible for a character that just came out.
in 2016. I think to go from non-existence when
this podcast started to having a full-on show
of their own is a real testament to how cool
the characters of Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur
are. I highly recommend the cartoon. It is
for kids, but it is highly inspired visually
by the Spider-Verse films. It's not 3D animated,
it's 2D, but there's a lot of cool stuff in
there that's very comic book-y. That's cool.
Is it Moon Girl or Devil Dinosaur or both that
were created in 2016? Well, Devil Dinosaur
dates back to the 1960s as a creation of Jack
Kirby. Oh wow. Moon Girl was created much more
recently, and I go into that a little bit in
my history. In addition to the shows, you know,
also check out the comics. The Doom Patrol comics
are very highly recommended, especially the
run by Grant Morrison. And I have to say, in
my research for this episode, I had a whole
lot of fun going back reading the first two
arcs for Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur. Nice.
Well, let's get into it. To explain the methodology
behind our duels. Let's go to our sentient
dual simulator, Alfred Jarvis 9000. AJ9K, tell
our listeners how you go about determining
a winner in our dual matchups. Yes, of course,
sir. The way I determine a winner between the
contestants is by running 1,000 Monte Carlo
simulations using the characters statistics.
A Monte Carlo simulation is a probabilistic
model used to determine outcomes through random
sampling. In this case, I randomized the statistics
along a normal distribution. as a way to simulate
the many variables that can occur during battle.
The stat parameters are based on the official
Marvel power grid from which the DC characters'
statistics are extrapolated. Additional stat
categories are included such as range, damage
potential, versatility and perception in order
to create a more detailed and accurate simulation.
The results of the 1000 simulations provide
a percentage of wins for each character. The
contestant with the higher percentage is declared
the victor as they have a higher probability
to win any given battle. In an equitable pairing,
neither character should win 100% of the matches.
The comic book stories have shown that there's
even a way for Batman to defeat Superman, so
the confidence rate of my method falls in line
with the precedents that have been established
in the source material. My mathematical simulations
are without subjectivity or bias. Feats are
not the sole consideration, nor are fan votes
tabulated for determination of the winner. Thanks,
AG9K! Before we run the simulations though,
we like to break down each character's histories
and abilities before improvising a scenario
on how we imagine one of the 1000 simulations
would play out B for B. And I believe it's
my turn to go first with the DC characters backstory,
so let me tell you all about Dorothy Spinner.
Her backstory is a little bit of a downer, but
here it is. Now, Dorothy Spinner was born with
an ape-like facial disfiguration and hairy limbs.
resulting in her birth mother giving her up
for adoption while Dorothy was still an infant.
Adopted by the Spinner family, Dorothy was
raised as an only child on a farm in rural Kansas.
With many in the community repulsed by Dorothy's
appearance and due to excessive bullying from
other children, the Spinners isolated Dorothy
on their farm, which occupied much of the Spinner's
time. As a result of her loneliness and isolation,
Dorothy developed imaginary friends, which she
was unknowingly able to bring to life due to
her psychic mind. Her friends taught her to
read and write and told her stories, such as
The Wizard of Oz, which Dorothy enjoyed. One
day, while picking flowers outside, Dorothy
was accosted by a young boy named Bernard Muller
and his two friends, who all teased and attacked
her. When Dorothy made her way back to her barn
to find that Bernard had hung her cat, she
wished that Bernard was dead. It was at this
point that the Candlemaker emerged from her
mind, a being capable of granting wishes. After
making the wish to the Candlemaker, Bernard
was found in a field the next morning by his
friends, crucified and disemboweled. At the
funeral, Dorothy vowed to never make another
wish from the Candlemaker again and buried
him deep in her mind. At age 11, Dorothy began
being frightened by the stories that her imaginary
friends were telling her. from the Brothers
Grimm and Hans Christian Andersen. When three
imaginary family members tried to get Dorothy
to wear red shoes, they reminded Dorothy of
a fairy tale about a girl who couldn't stop
dancing until her legs were chopped off. Dorothy
told them that she had something to show them
behind the barn, at which point Dorothy shot
and killed them with an imaginary gun. A few
years later, a battle between a team of superhero
outcasts known as the Doom Patrol and the Lord
of Chaos named Pythia. spilled onto the Spinner
farm. Home alone, Dorothy got swept up into
the battle and helped the superhero team defeat
Pytheia when the others seemingly died in the
pandemonium. Dorothy was made an honorary member
of the Doom Patrol and was shocked when they
called her their friend. After realizing that
their daughter had psychic powers, the Spinners
called Dr. Niles Calder, aka the Chief, who
you can learn more about in our Chief vs. Professor
X dual episode. The Chief agreed to help care
for Dorothy and brought her to the Doom Patrol's
new headquarters, the Secret Sanctuary in Happy
Harbor, Rhode Island, a former base of the Justice
League, which contained a vault of souvenirs
from past Justice League battles. One of those
souvenirs was the Materiopticon, formerly wielded
by the villain Dr. Destiny and Dream of the
Endless before him, the latter of whom you
can learn more about in our Sandman Due to the
Materiopticon's ability to turn dreams into
reality, Dorothy's imaginary family Damal, Darling
Come Home, and Flying Robert came back to life
and attacked Dorothy for killing them, still
trying to get her to wear the red shoes. Realizing
the red shoes symbolized Dorothy's fear of menstruation,
the Doom Patrol's resident health and psychiatric
aide Joshua Clay destroyed the machine powering
the Materiopticon, which robbed the imaginary
beings of much of their strength. Before they
vanished, Dorothy accepted the red shoes and
her own womanhood, realizing the shoes were
ruby slippers after all, and that she was at
home with the Doom Patrol. When the team relocated
their headquarters onto Danny the Street, who
you can learn more about in our Danny the Street
vs. Kerkoa episode, Dorothy and new Doom Patrol
member Flexmantello were kidnapped by an organization
known as the Men from Nowhere, who imprisoned
them in the sub-sub basement of the Pentagon.
known as the Ant Farm, in order to harness
their psychic power to summon an all-powerful
entity known as the Telephone Avatar. Although
Flex Mantello managed to weaken the Telephone
Avatar by flexing a muscle that turned the
Pentagon into a circle, Flex and Dorothy would
have been killed were it not for Dorothy wishing
for the Candlemaker to save her and her friends
before passing out. When she awoke, she saw
the Telephone Avatar hanging from the ceiling.
With the Candlemaker constantly intruding into
Dorothy's thoughts afterward, asking her for
wishes, Dorothy confessed to Joshua what the
Candlemaker had done before she collapsed from
mental exhaustion. When Joshua went to the
Chief for help, the Chief shot and killed Joshua
for interrupting him. When Dorothy came to
and found Joshua dead, the Candlemaker emerged
and asked Dorothy if she wished that Joshua
were alive. When she said that she did, The
Candlemaker resurrected Joshua, only to kill
him immediately afterward, to Dorothy's horror.
Having gained enough power from Dorothy's wishes
to emerge into the world fully formed, the Candlemaker
decapitated the Chief and destroyed Robotman's
human brain before attacking the world's soul
in New York City, causing people to go insane.
After learning that the Candlemaker was really
an ancient malevolent entity that used Dorothy's
The Doom Patrol eventually defeated Candlemaker,
with Dorothy delivering the killing blow by
blowing out the Candlemaker's final flame. The
Doom Patrol disbanded afterward, forcing Dorothy
to enter the real world and get an apartment.
Having to deal with continual harassment from
onlookers whenever she had to leave the house,
Dorothy was also bombarded by African spirits
who kept asking her to join their world.
though she was encouraged by the scientist William
Magnus, who you can learn more about in our
Metal Men vs. Colossus duel episode, to overcome
her fear of the real world. After being attacked
by spirit-possessed mannequins at a shopping
mall, Dorothy was saved by Robotman, who you
can learn more about in our Robotman vs. Think
episode. The two of them helped reform the
Doom Patrol, though Dorothy found herself depressed
due to her inexperience and frequent inability
to contribute to the team as much as she wanted.
After befriending a magical doll named Charlie,
who she later learned was possessed by the spirit
of a rabbi, Dorothy helped Charlie reform the
Holy Grail with the power of her imagination,
and Charlie's spirit departed, his mission
completed. Alone again, Dorothy was taken on
a camping trip by robot man and fellow Doom
Patrol member named Coagula to let her know
that her adoptive father had died in a wheat
thrusher accident, and that they found her biological
mother. who was going to meet them soon. Upon
realizing that she was being asked to leave
the Doom Patrol in order to live a normal life
with her mom, Dorothy unleashed a psychic explosion
in a fit of immense rejection that killed Quagula,
destroyed Robotman, and put herself into a coma.
After a new Doom Patrol team formed, its version
of Robotman eventually realized that he was
an imaginary version created by Dorothy in
her vegetative state. When the real, newly assembled
Robotman realized what was going on, he visited
Dorothy in the hospital and made the traumatic
decision to take her off of life support, and
Dorothy soon died. And she remains dead in post-Flashpoint
continuity, though Robotman keeps a photo of
the two of them and visits her grave every week.
Powers-wise, Dorothy is a powerful yet somewhat
unstable psychic, capable of bringing her imaginary
friends to life. sometimes unwillingly. As
a young girl, many of her imaginary friends
manifest as symbols of her emotions, often
fear, or as character interpretations from stories
she's read or heard, and occasionally as recreations
of people she knows. This includes but is not
limited to Pretty Miss Dot, who has lipsticks
for fingers that can shoot fire, Paddle the
Sky, a swirling mass of hands holding paddles,
Heart of Ice, A woman made of ice that can freeze
things Dark is the morning A shadow creature
with a giant fanged mouth Cowboy doll book face
A gun-wielding cowboy made of dolls with a
book for a face And Spinner, a superhero adult
version of Dorothy who's a member of the imagined
team the Doom Force and can manifest the nightmares
of her opponents. That's Dorothy Spinner. That
was a lot darker than I thought it was going
to be and very much a downer. It is like the
exact opposite of the Moon Girl Devil Dinosaur
backstory, which is largely pretty fun and
cute. And yeah, not at all what Dorothy Spinner's
story is. Yeah, it's probably like the most
depressing backstory of any DC character I've
ever done a bio for in the span of this podcast.
So let's cheer up everyone with Moon Girl's
backstory. Yeah, I'm glad I'm going second
here. Here's the backstory for Moon Girl and
Devil Dinosaur. In prehistoric times, in an
alternate dimension existed Dinosaur World,
a planet where dinosaurs lived alongside the
Neanderthal tribes of early humans. Within a
region of active volcanoes called the Valley
of Flame, the most aggressive hominid tribe
called the Killer Folk dominated other, less
hostile tribes such as the Small Folk. When
a group of Killer Folk came across a female
Tyrannosaurus rex-like dinosaur and her young,
they attacked and killed the mother and two
of her children. They offered the third young
dinosaur as a sacrifice to their volcano god
by burning it alive with the fire from their
torches. The beast nearly died, but was rescued
by a boy from the Smallfolk tribe who witnessed
the massacre. The Neanderthal child's name
was Moonboy, as he was the only member of his
tribe who was brave enough to go out at night.
He saw that the flames had turned the dinosaur
scales a fiery red, and the boy took care of
it, naming him Devil. Moonboy and Devil Dinosaur
formed a close bond, and together they fought
and defeated the Killer Folk tribe, claiming
the Valley of Flame for the small folk and
protecting the lands from other dinosaurs and
monsters. Meanwhile, universes away, an autistic
9-year-old girl named Lunela Lafayette grew
up on the lower east side of Manhattan. Brilliant.
but shy and mocked for her awkwardness, Lunela
acquired the nickname Moon Girl due to her
constant daydreaming about strange gadgets and
inventions. When the inhuman hero Black Bolt
released the Terrigan Mists into Earth's atmosphere
during a battle with Thanos, Lunela believed
she could use her intelligence to help contain
the gases. She and others were afraid that
Terrigan exposure would transform them and as
the substance was used by the Inhuman race
as a catalyst to change them into their superpowered
forms. Inhumans were descendants of a group
of early mankind that were experimented on by
the alien race, the Kree, to serve as their
soldiers. Hundreds, if not thousands of people
on Earth unknowingly had inhuman genetics and
were being altered due to the pterigen clouds
now in the air. You can learn more about pterigenesis,
the Inhumans, and their king Black Bolt in the
in our Shazam vs Black Bolt dual episode. Lunella
believed the solution to the Terranian clouds
lay in alien Kree science, so she built a device
to help her locate any Kree technology on Earth
in order to study it. This led her underneath
the Brooklyn Bridge where she found a Kree device
called an Omni-Wave Projector that was capable
of opening portals between time and space. Meanwhile,
universes away, Moon Boy happened upon another
Omni-Wave projector that had landed on Dinosaur
World that was being worshipped by the Killer
Folk tribe, who called it their Night Stone.
The Killer Folk caught Moon Boy with the device
and beat him to death, when suddenly both projectors
activated simultaneously, opening a portal
between Earth and Dinosaur World. A group of
Killer Folk entered the portal and began terrorizing
the people of present-day Manhattan, but they
were followed by Devil Dinosaur, who sought
to avenge Moonboy's death. Devil Dinosaur saved
Lunela from the Killer Folk, who had fled their
encounter, and she explained to the semi-intelligent
beast that she needed his help to get the Omni-Wave
Projector from the Neanderthals in order to
save humanity. Before they could act, however,
Devil Dinosaur was captured and imprisoned in
a secret facility. Finding her courage, Lunela
resolved to rescue her friend and equipped a
series of homemade gadgets and a suit, After
hacking into a government database to find the
dinosaur's whereabouts, she snuck away from
home and broke into the secret facility, using
her gadgets to break Devil from his high-tech
cage. Together, the duo tracked the Killer Folk
to a Manhattan rooftop where they defeated
the Neanderthal group and recovered the Omni-Wave
Projector. However, immediately after their
victory, the Terran Cloud descended upon Lunella,
causing her to undergo teragenesis and encasing
her in a giant egg. Devil Dinosaur carried the
egg containing Lunela to safety at her secret
lab underneath her elementary school. When she
hatched, Lunela could not immediately tell
what the Terrigen had changed about her. However,
later at school, she discovered that she would
involuntarily switch minds with Devil Dinosaur,
who was back at the lab, whenever she experienced
strong emotions such as anger or hunger, and
spontaneously during a full moon. Keeping her
crime fighting a secret from her parents as
much as possible, Lunella was eventually discovered
by scientist Amadeus Cho, who administered a
test developed by Bruce Banner called the Brain
Omnicompetence Examiner. It was determined that
Lunella was probably the most intelligent mind
on Earth, scoring higher than other scientific
minds such as Mr. Fantastic. The villain Dr.
Doom took offense to this news and attacked
Lunella, but with help from the superhuman
community, including Dr. Strange, the X-Men,
and Ironheart, She and Devil Dinosaur were
able to defeat the Doombot army. At one point,
the inhuman hero Ms. Marvel recruited Lunella
and Devil Dinosaur to help in the war between
the Inhumans and the X-Men, which was caused
by the toxic nature of the Terrigan mists to
mutants. Lunella used her knowledge of Kree
technology to help the X-Men scientist Forge
miniaturize a version of a machine he designed
that would compress the Terrigan gases into
a solid state and incinerate it. You can learn
more about Forge in our Mr. Terrific vs. Forge
dual episode. Later, Lunella received a distress
call from space and built a spacecraft so she
and Devil Dinosaur could answer it. During
the adventure, her omni-wave projector malfunctioned
and the pair ended up back in time on Dinosaur
World, Devil's home planet. There they found
Moonboy at the time he discovered the omni-wave
projector and they were able to prevent him
from being beaten by the Killer Folk. Knowing
that Devil was back home with his true owner,
Lunella decided that leaving Kim with Moonboy
was the right thing to do. She said goodbye,
and though Devil Dinosaur protested, she tearfully
told him she didn't want him anymore, and used
the projector to travel back to Earth alone.
Sad and isolated, Lunella ended up joining the
Thing, Human Torch, and the robot Herbie in
a new version of the Fantastic Four, as Mr.
Fantastic and Invisible Woman were off with
their children recreating the multiverse. You
can learn more about that in our Justice Society
vs. Fantastic Four dual episode. Eventually,
Lunella used Herbie to open a dimensional portal
to bring Devil Dinosaur back to Earth to help
in a fight against the Super Skrull, and the
two were reunited. Lunella admitted she was
wrong for leaving Kim, Devil forgave her, and
the two went back to fighting crime on their
own. This included helping Doctor Strange rescue
a boy kidnapped by the villain Nightmare, assisting
Spider-Man against a Goblin foe, and solving
an unsolvable riddle for Thor that was posed
by his brother Loki. The latter adventure revealing
that Devil was worthy of wielding Mjolnir and
it transformed him into the Thunder Lizard.
On a family trip to the country of Wakanda,
Lunela's parents discovered her secret alter
ego as Moon Girl. They banned her from continuing
to fight crime with her dinosaur pet, though
they later compromised as long as Lunela visited
with a therapist once a week. At that time,
she formed a support group for fellow newly
powered adolescent inhumans called the Support
Alliance Derby for Sensationally Abled Kids,
or SADSACS for short. And that's her backstory.
Powers-wise, Moon Girl has the inhuman power
to temporarily swap her consciousness with
Devil Dinosaur, her crime-fighting partner.
This process is triggered involuntarily, caused
by heightened emotional states and the Fool
Moon. She has an exceptionally high intellect.
stated to likely be the smartest person on Earth,
and has built a vast array of homemade gadgets
for her crime fighting activities. This includes,
but is not limited to, spectrum scanning goggles,
spring-loaded boxing gloves, rocket-powered
roller skates, a helicopter backpack, a plunger-tipped
taser gun, sneeze-powder grenades, a flashlight
flashbang, and so many other toys in her utility
belt. She can invent nearly anything she puts
her gifted mind to, physically through engineering,
or digitally through computer programming. Devil
Dinosaur is a physically and mentally enhanced
Tyrannosaurus Rex-like dinosaur via genetic
mutation awakened when he was set aflame as
a youngling. He has increased durability and
strength, able to lift around 25 tons, and
his scaly hide is immune to heat and strong
enough to be bulletproof. Devil Dinosaur's
fangs, claws, and his sense of smell are razor
sharp, and he can track nearly anyone by their
scent. He has human level reasoning abilities
and can fully understand moon girl's commands.
That's moon girl in devil dinosaur. Wait, so
when devil dinosaur takes over moon girl's
body, is she just like this snarling creature
who's like always hungry? Yeah, she looks quite
feral actually. It's kind of funny when it happens.
Interesting. And her friends are aware of what's
going on or they aren't? No, she just gets further
ostracized for being weird when she swaps minds
with devil dinosaur during school time. That's
funny. That's cute. What a cute character.
Yeah. And she freaking lives at the end. Yeah,
that's because Marvel is for little kids, bro.
OK. All right. DC is for the adults. Sad adults,
but adults nonetheless. I mean, what adult
isn't sad?
So now that we got the characters' histories
and abilities out of the way, let's speculate
on how one of the 1000 simulated matches will
go. The winner is determined by simulations,
not the speculation, but it's fun to imagine
how the fight could play out. Alfred Jarvis
9000, what are the rules of our speculation?
Well, I should say there are no rules, other
than the characters have no prior knowledge
of the other going into the fight. All they
are aware of starting out is that the other
character is a threat that needs to be eliminated.
For the speculation... contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the
match itself as no environmental statistics
are considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. Alright
then let's get into it! Dorothy Spinner and
Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur meet on the battlefield.
Who goes first? Honestly this is kind of hard
because I don't think either character would
attack the other really. Like they'd probably
commiserate and want to be but that's too bad
because the purpose of the podcast is to see
who would win in no holds barred action. So
we're gonna make these children fight, damn
it. All right, I figured that once Dorothy
sees Devil Dinosaur, she's gonna freak out and
probably summon Pretty Miss Dot, who's kind
of her go-to when she's in danger. So this weird
entity wearing a helmet with lips. and curlers
and lipstick fingers flies toward Devil Dinosaur
and begins blasting him with fire. Alright,
well that does nothing. Devil Dinosaur is immune
to fire, so all this attack is gonna do is
just piss him off. So he's infuriated and he's
gonna roar real loud and then he's just gonna
chomp down on Pretty Mistat with his razor sharp
teeth. Meanwhile, Moon Girl is gonna roller
skate over to Dorothy and just knock her the
hell out with a spring-loaded boxing glove.
Yeah, except that now Dorothy is emotionally
traumatized by having seen Pretty Miss Dot
just die like that. So while Moon Girl was approaching
Dorothy, she's going to conjure several more
entities. And we'll go with Paddle the Sky for
Moon Girl and Heart of Ice for Devil Dinosaur,
since Fire didn't do anything to him. So not
only does Moon Girl's boxing glove get knocked
out of the way, she also gets paddled numerous
times by Paddle the Sky. And Devil Dinosaur
is now encased in ice. Remind, what do Paddle
of the Sky and Heart of Ice look like? Paddle
of the Sky is literally a spinning vortex of
hands holding wooden paddles. And Heart of
Ice is just a woman made of ice. Okay. Uh, not
gonna lie, I don't think Moon Girl would be
well equipped for all this weirdness. But she's
gonna evade the paddles by activating her spring-loaded
roller skates to launch herself into the air.
And then she's going to switch on her helicopter
backpack. So she's flying through the air. And
as this paddle creature is chasing her, Moon
Girl's going to pilot over toward Devil Dinosaur.
And then she's going to quickly zip out of
the way so that paddle guy crashes into Devil
Dinosaur, who's in the ice. And basically the
paddles are going to break Devil Dinosaur out
of his ice casing. Yeah, right. So now that
Devil Dinosaur is free, He's just gonna tackle
paddle the sky out of the sky and just eviscerate
it turning those paddles into Splinters I hope
you choke on them And while that's happening
moon girl is gonna whip out a hairdryer That
she outfitted as a flamethrower and she's just
gonna melt the ice lady to a puddle Dude keep
killing Dorothy's imaginary friends. See what
happens. She's got some weird ass friends, you
know Even you've got insoles for her. Wow.
She can't catch a break, can she? Dude, these
friends are objectively weird. I don't think
anybody would deny them. Literally one of them
is made out of paddles. Come on. And while
Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur are taking care
of them, Dorothy is going to be like, oh, no,
my friends. And that is when Moon Girls, she's
going to pull out a can of soda that she shakes
and then hurls over to Dorothy like a grenade
and the can. is gonna explode and just drench
Dorothy in this sticky adhesive that Moon Girl
invented. Okay, the can, it's gonna explode
way before it reaches Dorothy because Cowboy
Doll Bookface is gonna shoot it right out of
the sky when it's right over Devil Dinosaur,
just drenching him in the adhesive instead.
So Devil is stuck to the ground and Cowboy is
just gonna keep shooting at Moon Girl. All
right, well, Moon Girl is gonna dive behind
Devil Dinosaur. and use him as cover since
she knows that he's bulletproof. And then to
get him free of the adhesive, she's gonna pour
a soda can of anti-adhesive on him and then
hop on Devil's back as he gets up and just
straight up charges cowboy doll face and whips
his tail right through him, book face. Whatever.
But his tail whip is gonna cause the cowboy
to explode into a thousand doll parts. So he's
gone. And without missing a beat, like after
that tail whip, Moon Girl is going to spring
off of Devil Dinosaur's back and she's going
to shoot a taser plunger at Dorothy that sticks
to Dorothy's head and it's going to send like
10,000 volts of electricity through her brain,
just shutting it down. Well, OK, Dorothy's knocked
out, but she doesn't need to be conscious for
her imaginary friends to manifest or protect
her. You know, so as Moon Girl is about to
land. She lands on Honey Pie, which is a beehive
with tree branches for limbs and a honey pot
for a head. So Honey Pie has Moon Girl in this
bear hug, essentially, and Moon Girl's being
squeezed and stung as she's pressed up against
this pissed off beehive. And meanwhile, Spinner,
the adult version of Dorothy, is going to appear
and manifest Devil Dinosaur's greatest fear,
which is... I don't know, an army of the killer
folk tribesmen who are all gonna rush and attack
Devil Dinosaur. I mean, Devil Dinosaur eats
killer folk for breakfast, alright? So he's
gonna tear through them to rescue Moon Girl
from this beehive guy. Honey pie. Yeah, yeah,
he's gonna grab honey pie in his T-Rex claws
and just freaking body slam that thing causing
it to drop Moon Girl who's gonna helicopter
away to safety. And as she's flying away...
She's gonna pull out of her backpack a version
of Professor X's Cerebro device that in the
comics she once calibrated to detect magic beings.
So she's gonna be recalibrating it again. Where
is she pulling this stuff out from? Her backpack?
Okay. Well, I mean, Spinner is still around.
So she's gonna appear into Moon Girl's mind
and manifest Moon Girl's greatest fear, which
is, I don't know, what's Moon Girl's greatest
fear? Uh, I- I don't know, an F on a test or
something? Big whoop. Uh, Moon Girl wearing
the recalibrated cerebro is gonna deduce that
Dorothy's friends are psychic manifestations.
So she's gonna pull out a bullhorn that emanates
a frequency that disrupts psychic energies and
Moon Girl's gonna use this invention to just
dissipate Spinner. Okay, all right, so. Dorothy
is going to wake up to see Spinner dissipate,
and all of a sudden she hears the Candlemaker
whispering in her mind, asking her to make
a wish. And she's going to wish that this match
was over. And that's what's going to happen.
Devil Dinosaur, he'll eat Moon Girl, and he
himself is going to burst into eldritch flames
that just melt his bodily tissue like Raiders
of the Lost Ark style, just leaving this dinosaur
skeleton. match over. What? I don't get it.
Was Devil Dinosaur possessed or something?
I don't I don't even know what happened there.
No, like he was more like driven insane by
the Candlemaker. And it caused him to eat Moon
Girl. Yep. I say that like even before Dorothy
hears the Candlemaker like whispering in her
ear and then, you know, she makes the wish
and all that weirdness happens. That would take
a while. So before that, Devil Dinosaur just
straight up stomps Dorothy with his big old
dinosaur foot. planning and then he's gonna
let out a big victory roar like the T-Rex did
at the end of the Jurassic Park movie. I don't
think that hearing make a wish and then making
a wish would take all that long. I mean it's
not quicker than a foot dropping on you so I
don't know. But we could go ahead and leave
the match there either Dorothy makes her wish
and the candle maker causes moon girl and devil
dinosaur to destroy themselves or Dorothy doesn't
have a chance to make the wish because she's
a pancake. Let's go ahead and find out which
of these scenarios happens by inputting the
stats for these characters and running 1000
simulations. We'll be right back with the winner.
8G9K, hit it! Inputting data, running calculations,
processing results, simulations complete. I
hate to see these two characters go up against
each other. It would have been more fun, I
think, to do a speculation where they become
best friends and hang out together, you know,
right? It was kind of interesting just coming
up with the stats. We kind of realized that
both of these characters' powers are essentially
the power of imagination. Like they're highly,
highly versatile. Right, because Moon Girl can
basically engineer anything she imagines, and
Dorothy Spinner can manifest it. So that was
pretty cool. We treated this matchup like a
two versus two character matchup, like a mini
team duel, which we've done before in episodes
like Cloak and Dagger versus the Wonder Twins,
or North Star and Aurora versus Hawk and Dove.
Yeah, or like Daughters of the Demon versus
Daughters of the Dragon. Yeah, we've done a
few 2v2 matches before. In this case, we counted
the individual stats for Moon Girl and Devil
Dinosaur, as well as Dorothy Spinner on her
own, and kind of an amalgamation of her imaginary
friends, wherein we averaged the stats of all
of her imaginary friends, and treated it as
kind of like this composite being. Yeah, which
was not easy. No, it was pretty difficult to
come up with that average for the imaginary
friends, but in the end we ended up getting
win rates for each one of the characters. Dorothy
Spinner was by far the weakest. Yes, Dorothy
Spinner is hands down the weakest character
I've ever done a duel with. I felt bad for
her as I was entering these stats in. But, her
imaginary friend creatures were actually really
powerful, more powerful than either Moon Girl
or Devil Dinosaur on their own. And- kind of
wiped the floor with both of them individually,
winning three quarters of all of its matches.
And what was really interesting was that Moon
Girl actually had better stats than Devil Dinosaur.
Right. Just due to her heightened intelligence
and versatility with all the inventions and
stuff like that. Devil Dinosaur is strong and
can do damage, but otherwise, you know, he's
not that impressive statistically, considering
he's kind of a one trick pony and not that
bright. He's a dinosaur. It's kind of interesting
because a lot of Dorothy's imaginary friends
were also one trick ponies. But then you have
someone like the candle maker, who isn't technically
an imaginary friend, but we still kind of counted
him in the composite considering the fact that
he was a manifestation from Dorothy's mind.
And the guy could almost do anything. You can
make wishes come true, essentially. Yeah, he
definitely skewed that average. But was it
enough? What do you think, Joseph? I think there's
an interesting balance here. between how weak
Dorothy is, but how strong her imaginary friends
are. And then Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur
are somewhere in between that power spectrum.
So I think the matchup is gonna be close. I
do think that the scales are ultimately gonna
tip toward Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur though.
So we did a poll on Instagram and 64% of those
who voted, voted in favor of Moon Girl and
Devil Dinosaur. Do you think it's gonna be over
or under that? I think it's going to be under
that. I think it's going to be a closer match.
But that was definitely a popularity contest
poll. We even had some people ask us like, who
the heck is Dorothy Spinner? To which case
it got to say read and or watch Doom Patrol
because it's awesome. You have to watch Doom
Patrol on Max. It's a great show. And its final
season is wrapping up here soon. But let's
find out who won. AJ 9K, the results, please.
Hey, you are, sir. The winner of the matchup
between Dorothy Spinner. and Moon Girl and Devil
Dinosaur is Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur. Hell
yeah. I was hoping she'd win that coming. I
was hoping she'd win this one. It was close.
Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur won 57.1% of the
matches or 571 out of 1000 compared to Dorothy
Spinner and her imaginary friend who only won
42.9. So that was pretty close. If you had
asked me leading into this. Whether or not I
thought Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur even stood
a chance against Dorothy Spinner, I would have
said you're out of your mind. Well, it's really
all about Moon Girl's intelligence, right? Considering
that she is likely the most intelligent person
in the Marvel universe, she has a lot going
for her. Probably more than you ever realized.
Way more than Dorothy Spinner, I think. It's
not down to the intelligence. You know what
it's down to? What? The fucking system, man.
The fucking system. What? Yeah, it's like there's
no way that Dorothy Spinner would go into this
match with only one imaginary friend, but it's
way too complicated to pit two characters up
against like 20. Well, that's why we had the
composite imaginary friend. It's not good enough.
It's not good enough. The system's broken.
I think it sounds pretty accurate myself. But,
you know, any time Marvel wins. It always sounds
highly accurate to me. It does make me wonder
though, how we're gonna run the stats for next
week's team duel between Doom Patrol and Guardians
of the Galaxy if we count Dorothy Spinner as
multiple beings. I don't know if we can actually.
We might have to do a composite of her as well
with the imaginary friend. That'll be interesting.
That will be interesting. We'll have to figure
that out. Considering those seven versus seven,
matrices simulations take a long time to run.
Yeah, ton of time. Even two versus two takes
a while. Yeah. I hope you feel bad. I hope
you feel bad for Dorothy Spinner. She's had
a hard life and you don't make it any easier.
Well, geez, I do feel bad for her as a character,
but also, you know, Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur
deserve this win. So there you go. All right.
I guess if you can live with that guilt that
does it for this duel. Let us know what you
thought about the results by writing to us
at dynamic duel podcast at gmail.com or by visiting
us on Instagram or X. You can find links to
all of our accounts by checking out our show
notes or visiting our website at dynamicduel.com.
And on our site you can also find a link to
our Patreon page where you can join our Dynamic
2.0 tier and chat with us and fellow listeners.
Our Fantastic Four tier, which gets you bonus
content each month. Our X-Force tier that makes
you an executive producer of this podcast.
Or our newest tier that lets you join our Dynamike
Podcast Network. If you can't join Patreon,
you can still support our show by signing up
for our e-newsletter. also at dynamic duel
dot com. Or you can also rate the show on Apple
podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser, or on our website.
As we mentioned earlier, our next episode is
going to be episode 350, a big team duel between
the Doom Patrol and the Guardians of the Galaxy.
Can I wait for that? Doom Patrol is going down
and it is gonna be very satisfying. I just imagine
it's going to be like the most bizarre team
duel that we've ever had. I guarantee it. For
sure, for sure. But that does it for this episode,
we want to give a big thanks to our executive
producers Ken Johnson, John Strausky, Zachary
Hepburn, Dustin Balcombe, Mickey Mathen-Geehan,
Brandon Estregard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yeaton,
Nick Abonto, Austin Wyslowski, AJ Dunkerley,
Scott Camacho, and Adam Spies for helping make
this podcast possible. And we'll talk to you
guys next week. Up up and away, true believers.
This episode was sponsored by the card game,
Chronicle AI. Get it at chronicleaigame.com.