This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
Dynamic duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the superiority
between Marvel and DC by comparing their characters
in stat-based battle simulations. I'm Johnny
DC. And I'm his twin brother, Marvelous Joe.
And in this episode, we were supposed to be
reviewing Hulk vs. but Marvel sucks and that's
impossible to find on any streaming platform.
So we're changing it up. Instead, we will be
doing a review of Green Lantern. first flight
a probably superior film even though I've never
seen Hulk vs. Well, yeah, I was so surprised
that I couldn't find Hulk vs. anywhere to stream
that wasn't like a skeezy torrent or streaming
site. You know, the only way you can watch Hulk
vs. right now legally is by buying the Blu-ray
or DVD, which I'm not going to do because I
no longer have a Blu-ray or DVD player streaming
all the way. Same here, but that's probably
toward detriment in cases like this. But it's
also not like, you know, The Hulk vs DVD is
easy to buy, you just can't go to a store,
you have to like order it from Amazon or something
and have it delivered. I guarantee you it's
in the DVD bin of my local Dollar General. I
guarantee you, no one cares that much about
it. Our executive producers cared, but I think
Green Lantern First Flight is an appropriate
substitute considering next week's episode is
going to be Juggernaut vs Atrocitus. Atrocitus
is a Green Lantern villain, so this episode
ties into that. Yeah, that's going to be a
fun episode. This film is actually pretty fun
and we'll talk all about it later on in this
episode. Before that we're gonna break down
the comic movie news from the past week of
which it's all DC news because Marvel's not
doing shit right now. Oh we got Deadpool and
Wolverine coming up in a few weeks so yeah we
got a lot going on. We're gonna talk about
Guy Gardner and Hawkgirl being revealed in Superman
set photos. We're gonna be talking about the
Batman Ninja vs Yakuza League teaser trailer
and we're gonna be talking about the Kite Man
Hell Yeah official trailer. As always, we list
our segment times in our episode description,
so feel free to check out the show notes if
you want to skip ahead to a particular topic.
Our artificially intelligent duel simulator
AJ9K has a quick message for our listeners,
so listen up. Why, hello there. Do you want
even more from this podcast? Then become a
part of the Dynamic duel community on Patreon,
where you can choose from three tiers. The
Dynamic Duo tier gives you access to our Discord
chat server. The Fantastic Four tier gives
you two bonus episodes each month, and the X-Force
tier makes you an executive producer of this
show. Lastly, the Diner Mike Podcast Network
tier lets you create your own podcast using
this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe will
help you develop your show, provide graphic
support and consultation, and get you simulation
results. Pitch the twins your ideas via email
at dyna Check it out at patreon.com slash dynamicduel.
Pip pip cheerio. Thanks AJ9K, and thanks to
everyone who supports the podcast. Be sure guys
to tune into the other shows on the DynaMic
Podcast Network this week, including Max Destruction,
which pits your favorite action heroes from
film and television against each other. This
week, hosts Ken and Scottie are pitting Schwarzenegger's
Conan the Barbarian against King Leonidas from
300. Yeah, that's going to be epic! Also tune
into the Send Your World podcast, where host
Zachary Hepburn speculates on fights between
fan favorite anime and manga characters. The
show is still on its season hiatus, but it's
coming back soon. So this is the perfect time
to catch up on its 40 episode library. And
finally, on the console combat podcast hosts,
John and Dean find out who would win in fights
between popular video game characters. In yesterday's
episode, they reviewed the 90s Mortal Kombat
movie. So if you have nostalgia for that, definitely
check that out. Visit dynamic podcasts dot
com or click the link in our show notes to listen
to all of the shows. in the DynaMic Podcast
Network. But with that out of the way, quick
to the No Prize! A No Prize is an award Marvel
used to give out to fans. Our version, the Dynamic
duel No Prize, is a digital award we post on
Instagram for the person that we feel gave the
best answer to our question of the week. Last
week, we asked you guys, who do you think is
the mysterious man in black in the Superman
set photos and why? And this is coming off of
the Superman movie that's currently filming,
and we got a look at a mysterious character
all dressed in black, and thought it would
be fun for you guys to speculate on who it might
be. Yeah, we got quite a few answers. We're
going to break down this week's honorable mentions
before revealing the no-prize winner. Our first
honorable mention goes to Alex Albro, who said,
Hey guys, it's Alex. I think the mysterious
man in black on the Superman set is really just
the character of Neil Quinn, aka Ulythes, who
has some energy transference powers. Something
about the last son of Earth and it's a whole
big metaphor for Superman being the last son
of Krypton and they're gonna fight. And he's
just one of seemingly three enemies Superman's
gonna have to face in this film. Thanks. Bye.
Yeah, so Ulysses is a fairly recent character
in the Superman comics. He gets his powers
from the fourth dimension and he essentially
has the same powers as Superman. What makes
this answer possible is that he, like the character
that was seen in the set photos, has a U on
his costume. Yeah, and it's a black costume
in the comics too. So this could be it. I don't
know much about the character. I would be kind
of surprised if they were to introduce a character
that obscure into the Superman film, but you
never know. The guy is wearing a mask. It could
literally be anybody. And this is as good a
guess as any. So great answer, Alex. Our next
honorable mention goes to Buster Barnes. Who
said? Hi guys, Buster Barnes here. Hope you're
doing well. I think the villain in the black
outfit is going to be called Ultraman, however
not the usual iteration that we expect. Instead,
I think it's going to be more like Superman
from the Red Sun movie where he is a clone created
by Lex Luthor and or the government in which
he's going to be sent out to take down or potentially
frame Superman. And then he is going to eventually
deteriorate into a bizarro-like villain for
Superman's fight. Take care, guys. Love the
show. Right. So Buster is saying that the U
probably stands for Ultraman. If you've listened
to the podcast a few months ago, we did a duel
episode between Ultraman and Hyperion, so you'll
know all about him. Yeah, and if you've read
the Red Sun miniseries or watched the Red Sun
animated movie adaptation, you'll know that
there is a character in that story that's kind
of like an amalgam of Ultraman and Bizarro.
Basically a clone that Lex Luthor created to
go up against the Russian version of Superman.
So of course the speculation is that the masked
figure with the U on his chest is an evil version
of Superman, which could make sense because
Lex Luthor is the one who created Superior Man
in the comics, and he also created Bizarro
in the comics as well. And since Lex Luthor
is in the movie, why not have him create an
evil Superman clone, who he would call Ultraman?
Great answer Buster, our final honorable mention
goes to Jacob Foster, who said, What if it's
unknown soldier? I mean, He was based back
out in World War II, Creature Commandos were
back in World War II. James Gunn even said
Creature Commandos was the start of the DC,
of his universe at least. Rick Clark Sr. is
in Creature Commandos, Rick Clark Sr. is in
Superman. I wanna say that it's a re-adaptation
kind of the Unknown Soldier, like just a little
bit of a costume change. The Unknown Soldier
is a character in DC Comics who was essentially
a World War II veteran who suffers from amnesia
and no longer remembers who he is. He does wear
a full face mask and is a master of disguise.
Of course all of the set photos that we've seen
this mysterious figure in has him associated
with the military, which could mean that yeah,
maybe he's the Unknown Soldier. Just like a
modern take on the character. Yeah, I'm not
sure I follow Jacob's line of reasoning that
just because Rick Flagg is in the creature commandos
and this movie. That means that this guy could
be unknown soldier because he was also in World
War two with the creature commandos. But why
not? Sure. It could all work out that way. We
want to give a quick shout out to Brandon Estregard
and Daniel Alonso, who also called in with their
answers. Thank you guys so much for taking
the time to do that. Daniel, your suggestion
that it was Night Monkey is, I think, spot
on. But the winner of this week's no prize is
Hey what's up guys it's Miggy and I think the
guy in the stuff photos isn't Ultraman or Ulysses
like people are thinking because it's kind
of weird to have another reverse Superman and
Gunn has said that it's not a big spoiler that
he's been filming out in public so I think it's
an Ultramarine core, a super obscure character
just another like military henchman type. Also
pretty excited about the terrifics in the first
look of Hawkgirl and Guy Gardner. Thanks guys.
So the Ultramarine Corps was actually a super
team, not a specific character within DC Comics
that was put together by General Wade Eiling.
Although I think Miggy's suggesting that instead
of being a ragtag team of C-list characters,
the Ultramarine Corps could be just generic
super soldier types. And this figure dressed
in black is just one of those. Yeah, I could
totally see that being the case. I don't think
the figure needs to be some superpowered individuel.
I just think it needs to be an elite soldier
of sorts that maybe in this film was not put
together by Wade Eiland, but maybe by Lois
Lane's father, Sam Lane in conjunction with
Lex Corp or something like that. Yeah, yeah,
it's possible. I don't think it's anyone special
when it comes down to it. I don't really want
it to be any kind of Superman knockoff character
because I really want to focus on Lex Luther
as the villain. And that's why Miggie gets the
win. So great answer, Miggy, you win this week's
No Prize. If you the listener want a shot at
winning your own No Prize, stay tuned to later
on in this episode when we will be asking another
Question of the Week. And now that that's done,
onto the news.
Okay, so these past two weeks we have been fortunate
enough to receive a ton of set photos from
the outdoor filming of the upcoming Superman
film directed by James Gunn. In our last episode
we talked about the first look of the full suits
for Superman and Mr. Terrific. This week we
got our first looks at the suits for Guy Gardner,
the Green Lantern played by Nathan Fillion
and Hawk Girl played by Isabella Merced. Now
right off the bat, pretty much everyone noticed
that both Hawkeye Girl and Guy Garner were wearing
uniforms very similar to that worn by Mr. Terrific.
And it looks like these are uniforms worn by
a super team sponsored by Maxwell Lord and
his business known as Lord Tech. Which is really
interesting. It definitely leans more towards
like a Justice League international team from
the comics, which was sponsored by Maxwell
Lord. Now, I don't know if they're going to
be referred to as the Justice League in this
film or maybe the Terrifics. which was a team
from the comic books led by Mr. Terrific. But
I do think it's interesting that they're going
this sort of corporate sponsored route. Well,
it provides a nice contrast for the type of
hero that Superman is. You know, Superman being
a guy who does what's right for the sake of
what's good and right. Right, yeah, he has
a sense of duty as compared to a corporate sponsored
team, which may be doing it maybe somewhat
for the duty, but also maybe for, you know,
the money and perks. Now a lot of people are
dishing out a lot of flack for these outfits
considering the fact that they're not entirely
comics accurate. Guy Garner definitely doesn't
have a lot of green on his costume and Hawkgirl
traditionally wears armor. Yeah, the CW did
it better for her costume, gotta say. Maybe.
I do like her helmet. And Guy Garner's, you
know, bowl cut is definitely in keeping with
the ridiculousness of the character's look in
the comics. And while I do wish that both he
and Hawkgirl were... more comics accurate in
regards to their looks. I also don't hate the
idea story wise of a team that wears the same
uniform, almost sort of like the X-Men in the
first X-Men movie, how they wore all black leather.
This at least is a little bit more colorful
and it still has like their brand logo insignias
on their uniforms. I mean, story reasoning
aside, I think the costume choices here were
made to the detriment of character recognition.
I mean, this is the first look that we're ever
going to get at the Green Lantern core within
James Gunn's new DCU. And I don't think it quite
services Green Lantern well enough. Same thing
with Hawk Girl. I think you're going to run
into like a brand issue at that point almost,
because most people are going to associate the
characters within this new universe with this
new look. Well, I mean, in regards to Guy Gardner's
look specifically, he wears a jacket in the
comics. So I think, you know, just a color swap
on his pants and the jacket. would make him
fit right into the upcoming Lantern show. If
all of them wore leather uniforms, I also wouldn't
hate that. It's kind of like Guardians of the
Galaxy, like the Nova Corps in a way. I don't
think they need to be CG energy costumes like
they were in the Ryan Reynolds film. You mentioned
the X-Men earlier. I think that's a fair comparison.
And we've seen what happens when you don't
put the characters in the proper costumes right
away. And sometimes you have to wait 20 plus
years to finally see them in their comics accurate
outfit. Oh, you mean like Wolverine? Yeah.
Yeah, you know, that's a fair criticism. But
I also think that if this team is going up
against Superman in this movie, the team is
probably going to disband by the end of it.
And I think it's probably fair that they'll
probably have more comics accurate looks the
next time we see them on screen. That's just
wishful thinking. Yeah. Of course, the one
character that we know is in this film that
has not been seen in the set photos, who is
also a member of the terrific in the comics.
is Metamorpho, who we know is going to be played
by Anthony Carrigan. There was a guy in a blue
motion capture suit spotted on set, so that
may have been him. He might be an all CGI character,
which would make sense for the character, since,
you know, he's made up of gases and minerals
and stuff like that. I don't know if that's
a motion capture suit or just like a blue screen
suit to make the character invisible later
on. It could be a reference point. I have no
idea how special effects work, but of all of
the characters to not be in uniform. he kind
of makes the most sense. But yeah, that's really
it. I thought the looks were pretty interesting
and I can't wait to see more official looks,
maybe something that includes Hawker Girls wings
around Comic-Con, I imagine, which is just
in a few weeks. In other DC news, we got our
first 30 second teaser trailer for the sequel
to the animated film, Batman Ninja. This time
it's called Batman Ninja versus Yakuza League,
which looks like it's gonna be Jessica Cruz,
the Green Lantern, the Flash, Aquaman, and
Wonder Woman so far. I would be really surprised
if Superman didn't make his way in there somehow.
But so far from what we've seen of these Justice
League characters in these feudal Japanese
designs, I cannot wait for this movie because
it looks like it's gonna be really fun to watch.
Yeah, well, part of the appeal of the first
Batman Ninja movie was to see a bunch of Batman's
rogues gallery. reinterpreted in these feudal
Japanese designs. And it's cool to see that
carried over to the Justice League for this
film. It appears that maybe Batman's actions
in the past influenced present day Japan because
it looks like this movie is taking place in
modern Tokyo, although with a very heavy feudal
Japanese approach. Yeah, which is kind of awesome.
I think that's a really cool setting and approach
to a sequel. I love the looks for Green Lantern,
Aquaman and Wonder Woman. I think they look
really cool. The one I don't love though is
the flash. The hat just doesn't make sense to
me. You know, if you're running, the thing's
gonna fly off. But I'm really curious to see
Superman and any other Justice Leagueers that
make an appearance. It does look like Damien
Wayne is going to be his sidekick for this
movie as Robin, and he was in the first movie
as well. Although I do miss the lone wolf and
cub inspired haircut for him. Well, it's present
day Japan now, so you gotta modernize it. That's
fair. Another thing I love the design of is
the logo for this film. It's the word ninja
and the shape of the Batman logo. I want to
get that tattooed on my face. I'm wondering
though, since Batman's going up against the
Yakuza League, does that mean that the Justice
League are evil? Yeah, I think that's a fair
assumption here. They're organized crime. And
they're going to be turned good by the end,
maybe? It's weird to see the characters as
villains. That's a good question. Yeah, maybe
he has to go back in time. to fix whatever
got messed up in the past and the league follows
him. I have no idea. We don't have a release
date for this film just yet. We just know that
it's coming out soon and I can't wait to learn
more about it. Again, hopefully during Comic-Con.
I expect all of my answers to all of my questions
to be revealed at Comic-Con. That never happens.
I know. I just realized now that I'm visiting
the official Batman Ninja website. You know
what they're going for with the Flash's hat?
They're going for a Jay Garrick's helmet homage.
Oh, OK. I see. I was thinking Raiden for some
reason. I don't know what the lightning. No,
because the hat definitely has wings on it.
You know, got you. Makes sense. I loved the
first movie. I can't wait for this movie. I
love the concept. And that brings us to our
question of the week.
What other Marvel or DC character would you
like to see get a cultural reimagining for
a one-off special? Right, similar to Spider-Man
India or like, I don't know, the upcoming Aztec
Batman, things like that. What culture, what
hero? Describe your reimagining. Record your
answer at dynamicduel.com by clicking on the
red microphone button in the bottom right-hand
corner of the screen, which will prompt you
to leave us a voicemail. Your message could
be up to 30 seconds long, and don't forget to
leave your name in case we include you on the
podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer and
award that person a dynamic duel note prize
that we'll post to Instagram. Be sure to answer
before July 13th. In our final bit of DC news,
we got an official trailer for the upcoming
Kite Man Hell Yeah animated series. Of course,
this is a spin off of the Harley Quinn animated
series, and a lot of characters are seemingly
making a return. for this one. Which makes me
wonder why this couldn't just be a subplot
for the upcoming season of Harley Quinn, but
I hope it's just as funny as the Harley Quinn
show. I mean, this is the series that no one
asked for, right? No one asked for a Kite Man
series. I don't know what they're doing. I know
that we have to review this, but I'll say that
I'm not looking forward to it despite the fact
that yeah, Harley Quinn is hilarious, Kite
Man the character is hilarious. I just think
there's no demand and nobody's gonna really
watch this in my opinion. Dude, no one asked
for Kite Man as a character to exist in the
comics to begin with. You're right, this should
not exist in any shape or form, but it does
and I'm kind of here for it. Because it looks
like they're really, you know, gonna bring
out the lovable loser trope that is Kite Man.
It looks like he has really horrible luck,
his dad hates him, he's trying to run a bar
with his new girlfriend, Golden Glider, who's
just killing everybody. I guess the concept
does lend itself to a situational comedy sitcom
of sorts. I don't want to sound like a hater
because you look at a show like Modok, which
also nobody asks for, but I truly loved that
show. So I'm hoping for something like that,
I guess. I do hope that this show is much more
episodic than Harley Quinn. Let that have an
overarching narrative throughout the season,
but let this one be more like Cheers. I think
that would be perfect. Absolutely. Yeah. The
show is being released on July 18th. I'm hoping
that we could squeeze in a Kite Man duel around
that time. The executive producers were kicking
around the idea of pitting Stiltman against
Kiteman, which I think is so perfect. Hopefully
we can get that in. Yeah, that'll be a lot of
fun. Once I heard the idea, I can't un-hear
it, and it definitely needs to happen.
So that's it for all the news this week, now
let's move on to the main event, where we review
the 2009 animated film Green Lantern First Flight.
Green Lantern First Flight is a standalone animated
direct-to-video film released in 2009. It was
directed by Lauren Montgomery, a former storyboard
artist for the Justice League Unlimited animated
series, who went on to direct some of DC's most
celebrated animated films, including Wonder
Woman, Batman Year One, Superman Doomsday, Justice
League Doom, just to name a few. She's also
worked on projects for Marvel and Nickelodeon's
Avatar franchise, Basically, she's a badass
in the animation industry, so it should come
as no surprise that one of Green Lantern's
most badass films, live action or otherwise,
would be one she directed. Namely, this movie.
Now since the movie is a decade and a half old
by this point, I'm guessing if you wanted to
see the movie by now, you would have. But here's
your warning that if you want to avoid spoilers,
I'd probably skip this review until you see
the film, which has awesome action, a stellar
voice cast, and really is a film made for fans
of the source material. Now, First Flight was
released two years before the live action Green
Lantern film that starred Ryan Reynolds, and
it's a shame they didn't take more inspiration
from this film because while it admittedly
isn't the best origin story when it comes to
Hell Jordan, it does a surprisingly decent
job at explaining the cosmic lore behind the
Green Lantern stories and a phenomenal job.
with its villain. Sinestro in this film is hands
down the best villain in any Green Lantern
film to date, of which there aren't many, but
yeah, this film set the standard right out
the gate with its corrupt law enforcer mentoring
the rookie training day-esque approach to the
story. Yeah, one of the best things that this
movie did with the origin was make it primarily
in space. The 2011 live action Green Lantern
movie had its main conflict back on Earth.
But I think the unique thing about Green Lantern
is that he's one of DC's few cosmic heroes.
You know, you have the core, you have the new
gods and a handful of others. But unlike Marvel's
cosmic side, DC doesn't have a whole lot of
popular franchises set in outer space. That's
fair. Now, I would definitely agree with you
that the decision to keep the film in outer
space kind of helped the narrative in that you
were learning about the universe along with
the main character. as opposed to him being
on Earth and aliens having to learn about us.
It was kind of backwards for the way I think
a Green Lantern film should be. As I mentioned,
the film isn't a great origin story for its
main character, Halt Jordan, who's very much
along for the ride and very reactionary in the
film, in much the same way Ethan Hawke's character
was in Training Day. And for some reason, that
works. The rookie thrown into the deep end
framing of the story helps, I think, with all
of the lore and exposition that's thrown at
the audience. The film wastes no time, like
zero. Hal Jordan is literally wearing the Green
Lantern suit less than four minutes into the
film. It doesn't bother explaining Hal Jordan's
history or relationship or goals. We don't know
why he was chosen to wear the ring. The Earth
scenes are just prologue, essentially, to the
story's massive stakes. of who will control
the dominant power in the universe. The thing
is though, that the film is only 77 minutes
long, almost 15 minutes shy of a standard 90
minute film. Like 90 minutes is the minimum
length a film should be. And there was a lot
of backstory for Hell that they could have
squeezed into that remaining time. So that kind
of sucks, and it really makes it seem like
they knew the audience watching this film would
be fans of the comics and not- need all of
that extra information maybe? Though I'd argue
that's probably a lazy and dangerous approach
and it shows in this film's current Rotten Tomatoes
scores as the audience score is fresh while
the critics score is rotten. Though who knows
with my review that may change. Yeah the movie
definitely does no favors for newcomers to the
franchise. You had mentioned that it seems
the filmmakers here knew that their audience
would be fans of the character most likely,
but it also seems more like an admission that
casual viewers aren't going to watch their
film. Yeah. Which is not a good thing. You know,
especially for an origin story, you want things
to be accessible. Yeah, absolutely. And you
know, there are a lot of comics characters
with really dense lores, but a good writer can
fix that in a way, because not everything needs
to be adapted. one for one from comics to the
screen because you have decades worth of history
to back you up in the comics, whereas you don't
have that when you're trying to reach an audience
for the first time. I could have easily done
with a good 15 minutes or more of this film
because I did enjoy it. The current runtime,
I think signifies there was a budget issue
and maybe that's why they couldn't squeeze in
more of that pertinent character building.
Yeah, I was guessing the same thing. They probably
didn't have the money to do more story, which
is a shame. Now, I will admit that one of the
reasons the film does a decent job with the
Green Lantern lore is because it wisely chose
to ignore comic writer Jeff Johns' introduction
of the emotional electromagnetic spectrum and
the embodiments of the emotions within it such
as the entity of Parallax, who we were introduced
to in the Green Lantern Rebirth comic storyline
a few years prior. Parallax, of course, was
the villain in the live-action film and rewatching
this film All I could think about was how much
of a mistake that was. Yeah. Can I say my favorite
thing about this movie is the lack of emotional
spectrum. When you start talking about colors
as emotions, it all becomes just a little bit
too conceptual and maybe cheesy. I like their
approach of just saying this is the green energy
that they were able to harness from the green
element and it's weak to the yellow element.
And that's really all you need to know. I completely
agree. It's way too. convoluted. Even in the
comics, it's too much in my opinion. Yeah,
I mean it makes everything just too emotional,
which sounds like a shitty thing to say because
it's not a bad thing to be emotional, but you
really paint your characters into a corner
and it's hard for them to be multifaceted and
have multiple emotions when you know they're
represented by things like anger for the red
lanterns or avarice for the orange lanterns,
fear for the yellow lanterns. Everything is
just kind of pigeonholed character-wise. Yeah,
it makes the characters more one-dimensional.
I completely agree with you. Going back to
Hal Jordan's lack of character development,
the main reason I think it's easy to gloss
over that is the action. I think the animated
action of this film is actually its main draw,
and anticipating what ingenious way Hal Jordan
was going to use his ring's power to get out
of various conflicts was really fun to watch,
like in a MacGyver kind of way. With all the
prejudice the alien characters had, for the
human Hal Jordan, it was satisfying to see
him outthink them in a way that it never really
was for the live action film, at least for
me personally. Yeah, I mean Green Lantern's
power set is so visual, it's always fun to
watch. Absolutely. The guy can literally create
anything, so what is he going to create next?
Let's find out. I mean, there is a severe lack
of imagination among the Green Lantern Corps
in general. They kind of seem to keep their
constructs limited to the six simple machines,
but it's still fun to watch that too. In terms
of the animation, I tend to knock the Bruce
Timm style for its overuse, but this is among
the best works in that style I would say, like
hands down. It almost, like almost, edges into
kinetic anime style in moments when characters'
body structures become exaggerated, but I wouldn't
go as far as to say this is anywhere close
to being as good as anime animation. Yeah, it's
a step up, I think, from a lot of what we got
in the DC animated movie universe. Even though,
you know, that whole run of films was incredible,
the animation was slightly lacking during that
run. Here, it was fantastic. Yeah, of course,
this film was not in that run. It wasn't a part
of that. This, of course, was its own standalone
film. I think even Green Lanterns Emerald Nights
is only considered a quasi sequel, with only
some of the voice cast returning for that movie.
I did mention that the voice cast here is stellar
and we see some pretty big names including Michael
Madsen of Reservoir Dogs fame as Killawog,
Kurtwood Smith from That 70s Show as Kanjar
Rowe, and Trisha Helfer from Battlestar Galactica
as Budica. They spent way more money on the
casting budget for this film than they have
in recent DC animated fare and that's probably
why they could only reach 77 minutes. But let's
talk about the two main characters. and the
actors who voiced them in our character breakdown.
Now Hal Jordan was voiced by Christopher Maloney,
who's most well known for playing Detective
Stabler on Law and Order SVU, but is also a
known face from other films such as 12 Monkeys
and Man of Steel, where he played Colonel Hardy.
I still remember rumors that he was going to
be Hal Jordan when his casting was announced
for Man of Steel way back when, because of
his work in this Green Lantern film. Now, my
favorite voice actor for Hal Jordan is actually
Nathan Fillion, but probably only because Maloney
doesn't have a whole lot to work with in this
film. Like I've said, Hal's a very reactionary
character. So a lot of his lines in the movie
are relegated to things like, OK, and what the
hell? It's not the best writing. Yeah, he doesn't
get a lot of monologues or anything like that.
Definitely not. The most he speaks is when
he's like talking to the guardians. or when
he's talking to Budoka and Killawag in his
cell. Now regarding Hal's character arc, it's
clear from the opening scene that Hal is something
of a troublemaker who's probably too skilled
to test flight simulators and he's pretty bored.
That of course all changes when he gains the
Green Lantern Ring and is whisked off across
the universe on an adventure with universal
stakes. But that's pretty much it. Like he's
kind of the universe's luckiest guy. and that
he often just finds himself in the right place
at the right time, whether it's being chosen
for the ring or noticing invisible aliens in
a spaceport or even being near the central power
battery at the end of the film. Yeah, I noticed
that a lot of the plot was driven by Hal just
being lucky. Like, of course, he fell into
the sewer right before the bad guy fell into
the sewer. You know, right? Yeah. I just managed
to run into Kush. Yeah, it's again, not an example
of the best writing. You don't want your character
to just be lucky. You want there to be reasons
for that, typically. You shouldn't be able
to get away with something like that in screenwriting,
but they kind of did in this film. Yeah, just
barely enough where the audience didn't question
it too much. I do think that this movie probably
deserved a sequel and that it set up really
well why Hal Jordan would be regarded as one
of the best among the core. which is always
kind of hard to believe considering how massive
the court is. You know, everyone's always talking
about how great Hal Jordan is. But this movie
showed that, you know, he definitely has something
unique going for him. Yeah, we may not know
why he's special, but the film does a good job
of establishing the fact that he is. I think
they definitely could have taken that in different
directions for a sequel. Also special is Sinestro,
who in this film was voiced by Victor Garber,
the Tony and Emmy award winning actor. known
for his work in films like Titanic and Argo
and shows like Alias. He was Martin Stein in
the CW's Arrowverse shows, you know, one half
of Firestorm. The guy's just an amazing actor
and he was great as Sinestro, like flawlessly
capturing the characters cold cunning to boiling
rage. Sinestro is easily the most interesting
character in this film. You know, he's a bad
cop who's disdained for chaos and crime in the
universe. which he attributes to a failure
in leadership on behalf of the Guardians, leads
to him abusing his power. He believes it's
better to be feared and respected rather than
being compassionate, and his extreme methods
have proven results that garner him influence
within the core. His utilitarian philosophy,
that his means are justified by his end goal
of instilling order in the universe, is comparable
to other villains like Thanos, or Ozymandias
from Watchmen. It's wrong, but it's easy to
see how good intentions could lead there. And
the crazy thing is that if it wasn't for one
guy from one backwater planet, he would have
been successful. Like he killed so many good
guys in this film, more than a lot of other
villains in a lot of other movies. Like you
mentioned, I would have loved to have seen a
direct sequel to this film where Sinestro goes
on to create the Sinestro Corps. That sequel
will never happen, but I hope that Sinestro
is as good in the upcoming Lanterns television
series as he was in this film. For sure. Yeah,
he was fantastic in this movie. I was blown
away. His motivations were so clear. You could
totally see where he was coming from, where
he truly believed that any action he took,
no matter how seemingly immoral or evil. were
rationalized by the fact that he likely would
produce results. But as Hal Jordan shows, there
are multiple ways to achieve order in the universe,
and not all of them mean you have to be a dick.
Or specifically a dictator, you know? Right.
Which is exactly what Sinestro wanted to be,
and he wanted to amass power to essentially
control everyone and everything in the universe,
taking away their freedoms. And that's sort
of what sets him apart from someone like Thanos
or Ozymandias. They weren't really trying to
control people in the same way that Sinestro
is, and I think that makes him a little bit
even more sinister, perhaps. For sure. I was
actually surprised by the body count in this
movie. Like, so many dead green lanterns. The
stakes were massive, and the movie definitely
didn't shy away from showing us that. Yeah,
no. Like, we saw some popular lanterns go down,
like Tomar Ray, Boudicca, Green Man. Too many.
Too many. Oh, I didn't know Charlie Day was
in this movie. What?
Where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
Dynomic Podcast Network presents... Console
Combat, where video game legends brawl every
Monday. Dynamic Duel, where comic book titans
smash every Tuesday. Max Destruction, where
the world is at its limit. The Dynomic Podcast
Network presents... TV and action heroes battle
every Wednesday, and Sendro World, where anime
champions clash every Thursday. Join us as
we speculate on the matches and armed with the
power of mathematical simulations, discover
who will emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
Moving on to the story highlights, during an
exercise in a flight simulator for aeronautics
company Ferris Air, Hell Jordan is abducted
by the dying alien Aben Suur, a protector of
the universe known as a Green Lantern, whose
spacecraft crash landed in the American desert.
His power ring chooses Hell to be Aben's successor,
and after donning the ring, the spacecraft
explodes, destroying any evidence of it or the
alien. Like you said, lightning quick. The
origin happened so fast in this movie, I was
actually kind of confused that I maybe skipped
over some important establishing scene or something.
Yeah, actually I thought the same thing. It's
been a while since I'd last seen this film.
So yeah, I rewound it and watched it a couple
of times actually. Now, one thing they did in
this film that was brilliant was have the spacecraft
explode and destroy the alien body, destroying
all evidence, essentially, because then you
don't even need to worry about that. Like what
they did in the Green Lantern live action film.
It's like, oh, all of a sudden we have this
alien cadaver that we need to, you know, run
tests on and stuff like that. Get that out of
the way. Get into space. Does that mean the
Evans or ship had some kind of self-destruct
sequence built into it or something like that?
I guess I don't even know why the ship exploded.
Oh, yeah, that's fair. The reasoning is because
we need to move the story along. All right.
We need to get to the opening credits. That
doesn't seem very efficient in terms of Green
Lantern detective work when one of the core
members goes down. You would think that the
ring itself would at least serve as a black
box sort of log for that type of situation,
but seems that's not the case. Oh, that's true.
I didn't even think about that. It should. It
probably would in the comics, but I guess not
for this film. Now after returning the simulator
back to Ferris Air Base, Hal Jordan informs
his love interest and supervisor, Carol Ferris,
that he'll be taking a week off of work, just
before he's ambushed and interrogated by four
other alien members of the Green Lantern Corps,
who questioned what happened to Abbasur and
inform Hal that they'll be taking him to their
homeworld, Oa, at the center of the universe,
for approval from their superiors. beings known
as the Guardians. The Guardians initially express
disdain at the idea of an Earthling bearing
a Green Lantern power ring, but after Hal stands
up for himself against the Guardians, a senior
Green Lantern named Sinestro offers to train
and test Hal to see if he's worthy of the ring.
Sinestro takes Hal to the central power battery
that energizes their rings so that Hal can
download all of the known information of Universal
Sector 1215. a process that Hal surprisingly
survives. The two travel to Kadmindo, a planet
within Sector 1215, where Sinestro believes
they can find Kutch. The alien Sinestro believes
is responsible for Abin Sur's death. When Sinestro
tortures Kutch's love interest, Labela, for
information, Hal tries to stop him just before
Kutch attacks the Green Lanterns, then attempts
to flee.
but upon delivering him to Sinestro, HAL has
physically reprimanded for his earlier defiance,
learning of Sinestro's uncompromising disdain
for the crime and chaos in the universe, and
that the Guardians have been inadequate in preventing.
Other Green Lanterns arrive, and they take
Kutch back to Oa for interrogation. Another
thing that the script kind of skips over is
why Kutch was a lead for the Corps. They mention
his name kind of out of the blue, and all of
a sudden we're following this guy. Well, somehow
Sinestro knew that Kutch was the one who killed
Abin Sur. We never learned how he learned that
information, but possibly he learned it from
Kanjar Rowe, which begs the question, why didn't
a Sinestro just go straight to Kanjar Rowe?
That's a great question. And you would think
that maybe Hal Jordan would have questions
about what they were doing and why. Possibly.
You know, Hal Jordan is not a detective on
Earth, so maybe he wouldn't have thought of
that. That's the only explanation I could think
of. The moon ball scene where Sinestro was torturing
Labella was hard to watch, I found. Yeah, because
of the context that this moon ball was a drug.
So the analog to Earthbound Drugs was like
watching him make her inject herself with heroin
repeatedly or something like that. Right. Yeah,
that's crazy. This is actually the scene that
made me think of Training Day specifically,
you know, just the whole drug tie in. And I
was like, oh man, this is kind of brilliant.
Yeah. Now on Oa, Hal is befriended by Budica
despite his discrimination from other lanterns.
Budica explains the history of the Green Lantern
Corps and how it's currently being threatened
by the emergence of the Yellow Element, an energy
source recently stolen by an alien smuggler
named Kanjar Rho that rivals the Green Element
within the Central Power Battery. Kutch, Hal
learns, fatally wounded Abin Sur when Abin Sur
went undercover to find the Yellow Element.
just before Abin crash landed on Earth. After
torturing and killing Kutch for information,
Sinestro debriefs the core as to Kanjar Rose
whereabouts in preparation for a mission to
get him, just before being scolded by the Guardians
for his extreme measures. The scene between
Budica and Hal is actually pretty crucial I
would say for the movie because there's a lot
of exposition there. and they do it in a pretty
efficient way through essentially a mind reading
of each other. Yeah, it was the exchange of
information through the rings, which is a pretty
cool concept. This used so much foreshadow how
Sinistra uses his own ring to read the dying
mind of Kenjaro later in the film. Yeah, but
it doesn't explain how he was able to reanimate
Kenjaro's body. Like, I didn't know the Green
Lantern ring could bring back the dead. Well,
he was saying that he was reconnecting his dead
synapses in his brain. Something like that.
That's bullshit. It's bullshit. I agree. When
a team of lanterns arrive at the Cadian space
terminal to find Kanjaro, Hel is assigned to
watch the outer perimeter. Kanjaro, meanwhile,
learns the lanterns are looking for him and
meets with Sinestro telepathically, revealing
that the two are secretly working together to
turn the yellow element into a weapon. Though
Sinestro tries to focus the lantern's attention
away from Kanjaro, so that he could escape,
Hal notices suspicious activity on the loading
dock area and discovers Kanjar Rho and his
soldiers. A battle and chase ensue, but thanks
to Hal's ingenuity and competence, he manages
to reach Kanjar before the others, only to be
knocked unconscious. When Sinestro arrives
second, he kills Kanjar knowing Hal would get
the blame. That action scene that happens through
the space warp tunnel is so damn cool. I really
liked how that all played out. It had a lot
of momentum. Yeah, all the action scenes in
this had a lot of momentum and again, a lot
of stakes because you actually see lanterns
fall during the battle. So it's like, oh, shit.
You know, what's going to happen to these characters
that we've kind of come to know. And the way
that Held Jordan manages to succeed where the
others don't. Again, one of the highlights
of watching this film, like him using that grapple
to latch onto the spaceship as it emerged from
that wormhole thing. It's like, why didn't the
others think of that? Because that was brilliant.
Exactly. I also really liked the whole plot
of Sinestro framing Hal Jordan for murder.
Again, it's another tie to the Training Day
film. If you guys haven't seen Training Day,
watch that movie. I think that would be a perfect
setup for a Green Lantern film. And I really
hope that's used as inspiration or basis for
the upcoming HBO Max Lantern show. Back on
Oa, Hel is put on trial for the death of Kanjar
and stripped of his power rink and placed in
custody for deportation back to Earth. Confiding
in his fellow lanterns Budica and Kilowog that
he suspects Sinestro was responsible for killing
Kanjar and stealing his energy rod, they take
a detour to the morgue where Hel's suspicions
are confirmed as they find Sinestro using Kanjar's
energy rod to telepathically deduce that the
yellow element is with the weaponers on the
planet. Quard. When Killawag tries to arrest
Sinestro, Budica reveals herself to be in league
with Sinestro and knocks Killawag out. As Sinestro
leaves Oa for Quard, Budica attempts to kill
Hal only for Killawag to awaken. Hal manages
to outsmart Budica who accidentally kills herself
in an explosion from Kandar's energy rod. Budica's
betrayal totally caught me by surprise. I did
not see that coming. It was a legitimate twist.
Yeah, and kudos to the animators for making
all of her like previous worrisome glances have
like this double meaning when you watch the
film for the second time. Like she's worried
Hal is catching on, not that she's worried
about Hal in general. Her death scene was hardcore.
It was violent. I was like, what rating is
this? Holy shit. Yeah, it's like, why isn't
the blood blue? When Sinistro arrives on cord,
the weaponers reveal that they have made a second
power battery using the yellow element. and
gift him with a yellow ring to control it before
departing back to their home dimension. When
a squad of green lanterns arrive on Kord, having
learned of Sinestro's whereabouts, Sinestro
kills them, sending their rings back to Oa.
Sinestro arrives on Oa soon after with his
power battery and decimates the planet along
with any lantern that tries to stop him. When
the yellow power battery overloads the green
one, lanterns across the universe are with
many of them dying in space. As the Guardians
prepare to surrender to Sinestro, HAL manages
to harness the green element directly while
within the destroyed central power battery.
Full of green energy, HAL battles Sinestro,
managing to destroy the yellow power battery
with two moons of Oa in the process. Using up
the last of his energy to blast Sinestro to
the surface of Oa from space,
destroy Sinestro's reign before flying up to
rescue Hal from his fall. Is the movie implying
that green energy is not necessarily weak to
yellow energy if there's a sufficient quantity
of the green energy? For some reason Hal was
able to withstand the yellow attacks. Was it
because he had a whole lot of green energy?
I think so. That's convenient is all I'll say.
But I guess it makes sense. I mean, why wouldn't
it? Hal was charged directly from the green
element, whereas other green lanterns, you know,
they're not as close to that power source,
so they wouldn't have had as much energy to
battle Sinestra with. Right. Hal was like glowing
with so much green energy. The way I kind of
chose to think of it is, yes, ice is weak to
fire. But if you have a whole lot of ice, it's
going to be harder for the fire to defeat the
ice, to put it in Pokemon terms, I guess. Yeah.
One thing I thought about was the scene prior
where Sinistro forces Hal Jordan to put his
fist into the power battery. It's almost like
a proximity to the green element made it more
effective or more powerful. And for some reason,
Hal Jordan was able to absorb that energy in
a way that other aliens had not been able to
or even died trying to attempt that. Yeah, my
assumption is that no other alien had attempted
to access the green element directly. Right,
yeah exactly. I did think it was really badass
when he took the two moons and used it to crush
the yellow central power battery. That was
a feat unlike any other. That was the most badass
thing I think I've ever seen a Green Lantern
do. That was awesome. In the final scene of
the film, the Guardians recognized their discrimination
against Hal was unwarranted, and they hold a
ceremony to honor him and the fallen lanterns.
After leading the core in the oath of the Green
Lanterns, Hell flies into space to return to
Earth. That's the end of the film. No, we never
saw the oath recited previously, right? No,
it wasn't used as a mechanism to charge the
ring in this film. It was simply their pledge,
sort of like the Pledge of Allegiance, which
works for me, because I always thought the
oath was kind of a silly way to charge your
ring. Like just hold it up to the lantern,
you're good. That's true. I think in addition
to several... establishing scenes in the beginning
of this movie, it would have been nice to have
an ending scene having him return to Earth
and see how the experience changed him and his
relationship somewhat. Absolutely, yeah. The
film should have been longer. It was dense and
they could have spread that out over a little
bit more time pretty easily, you would think.
Yeah. Overall, the film was dense, but with
fun action and cosmic lore, It's unapologetically
intended for fans of the source material, though
I would say it struggles as an effective origin
tale. The voice cast was phenomenal, the animation
was great, but ultimately I would say the film
is inaccessible to probably most audience members.
And because of that, I'm giving this 3.5 out
of 5 stars. Still a fresh rating on Rotten
Tomatoes, though. Yeah, I mean the movie has
its faults, especially with story and character
development, but I think that the pros outweigh
the cons, especially in terms of spectacle,
you know, what you come to see a Green Lantern
movie for, the action and stuff, you know?
And there was plenty of it and I would definitely
recommend the movie to Green Lantern fans,
absolutely. I will say though that I didn't
like it quite as much as Green Lantern Beware
My Power or Green Lantern Emerald Nights, but
it goes to show that the character has some
solid animated movies under his belt. If not,
you know, the live action movie. Yeah, I definitely
hope they use this movie and probably Emerald
Nights, which I also really liked as a basis
for the upcoming series. Beware, my power is
also good, though I would like to see the show
focus more on Green Lanterns, whereas beware,
my power focuses, you know, on a whole bunch
of different alien races like the Raniens, the
Thanagarians. That may be important for a show
set out in outer space, but I'm not sure if
Lanterns is going to do that. It better if
it knows what's good for it. I agree. I agree.
But that does it for this review, AJ9K, help
us close out. Thanks for listening to Dynamic
duel. Visit the show's website at dynamicduel.com
and follow us on Instagram at dynamicduelpodcast.
You can support the show on Patreon at patreon.com
slash dynamicduel and joining a tier that works
for you or by rating and reviewing Dynamic
duel on Apple podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser,
or on our website. Don't forget to listen to
the other shows in the DynaMic podcast network,
including Max Destruction, Senjo World, and
Console Combat. In our next episode, as we mentioned
earlier, we're going to find out who'd win
in a fight between Atrocitus, the Red Lantern,
versus Juggernaut, the X-Men villain. It's
the Red Power Ring versus the Crimson Bands
of Scytorek. Yeah, of course, that is in lead
up to our review of Deadpool and Wolverine,
since Juggernaut was a major player in the
second Deadpool movie. So look forward to that
next week. That does it for this episode. We
want to give a big thanks to our executive producers.
Ken Johnson, John Sturawski, Zachary Hepburn,
Dustin Belcombe, Mickey Montagnon, Brandon Essargard,
Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yatin, Austin Wasylowski,
AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam
Spies, Andrew Schunk, Dean Maleski, Devin Davis,
and Joseph Kirsting for helping make this podcast
possible. And we'll talk to you guys next week.
Up up and away, true believers. In plainest
grey, in pale taupe, No simulation is outside
my scope. Let those who just can't seem to cope,
Beware my power. because I am dope.