This is a Dynamike Network podcast.
Hi and welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast,
a weekly show where we review superhero films
and debate the superiority between Marvel and
DC by comparing their characters in stat-based
battle simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe. And I'm
his twin brother, Johnny DC. And in this episode,
we're going to review the latest Marvel Studios
television release, Echo Season 1. The season
dropped a few weeks ago, but we're just getting
to reviewing it now. And uh, it was okay. It
was alright. I feel like it's not as bad as
people are making it out to be, personally.
I kind of enjoyed it. I know I enjoyed it more
than you at least, and I'm kind of interested
to hear what you have to say about it. Oh, I'll
bring you down. I'll bring you down to my level.
It'll be fine. Sweet. I have reasons. We'll
talk about them later. Before that, we're going
to break down the latest comic book movie news
to come out this past week, including the news
that Wilson Bethel is confirmed to return as
Bullseye in Daredevil Born Again, which is
fantastic news. I can't wait to talk about that.
As always, we list our segment times in our
episode description, so feel free to check out
the show notes if you want to skip ahead to
a particular topic. Our artificially intelligent
dual simulator AJ9K has a quick message for
our listeners, so listen up. Why hello there.
Do you love listening and chatting about Marvel
and DC? Then become a part of the dynamic dual
community on Patreon where you can choose from
three tiers. The dynamic 2-0 tier lets you listen
to this podcast without ads and gives you access
to its Discord chat group where you can chat
with Johnny DC and Marvelous Joe. The fantastic
4 tier gives you that and more with two bonus
episodes each month including bloopers and
top 10 shows where Johnny and Joe count down
your favourite Marvel and DC subjects. The
X-Force tier makes you an executive producer
of Dynamic Duel, where every month you help
the hosts choose what to review and who to fight
against each other. And finally, the Dynamite
Podcast Network tier allows aspiring podcasters
to create their own battle-focused show using
this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe will
help you develop your show, provide graphic
support and consultation, and get you simulation
results to announce on your show. Pitch the
twins your show via email at dyna
them on social media. Check it out at patreon.com
slash dynamic duel. Pip pip cheerio. Thanks
AJ 9k. And thanks to everyone who supports the
podcast. Guys, be sure to tune into the Max
Destruction podcast, which is part of our Dynamike
podcast network that show pits your favorite
action heroes from film and television against
each other. This week, hosts Ken and Scotty
are going to review Dread. And on the Sinjo
World podcast. Host Zachary Hepburn speculates
on fights between your favorite anime characters.
This week we're going to find out who would
win between Dragon Ball's son Gohan vs. Saint
Seiya's Phoenix Ikki? I don't know how to pronounce
the name. I don't know if that's right. I'm
sure you nailed it. On the Console Combat podcast,
hosts John and Dean find out who would win in
fights between your favorite video game characters.
And in yesterday's episode, they continued into
round two of their tournament, since they do
a bracket tournament style. Street Fighter's
Dark Ryu vs Metal Gear's Liquid Ocelot, and
Resident Evil's Nemesis vs Mortal Kombat's Scorpion.
Visit dynamicpodcast.com or click the link
in our show notes to listen to all of the shows
in the Dynamike Podcast Network. But with that
out of the way, quick to the No Prize. A No
Prize is an award Marvel used to give out to
fans. Our version, the Dynamic Dual No Prize,
is a digital award we post on Instagram for
the person that we feel gave the best answer
to our question of the week. Last week we asked,
what comic storyline from Marvel or DC would
you want to see adapted as an animated film
trilogy and why? And this is coming off of the
review that we did last episode of Justice
League Crisis on Infinite Earths, part one.
And holy crap, we got a lot of great answers
for this question. Can't wait to talk about
them. Let's go ahead and run down our honorable
mentions and the no prize winner. Our first
honorable mention goes to Jacob Foster, who
said, So yeah, the video game of Injustice.
only covered a portion of the story. As we know,
the comic series told everything that happened
prior to the game, and it was a fantastic comic
series. I would love to see that series adapted,
along with a subsequent film of the Injustice
storyline that happened during the video game,
followed up probably by the Injustice 2 storyline.
I think that would be a fantastic trilogy.
Yeah, we know that Injustice has already been
adapted into an animated film, but you know,
if you watch the movie or you listen to our
review of that film, you know that a wasn't
very good, so it would be nice to kind of get
a redo on that and tell the story right as
a trilogy and not cram everything into one film.
Yeah, justice needs to be done to the story
of injustice. What about deceased? Yeah, deceased
could easily be a trilogy. Honestly, I feel
like it could be an entire series. There's a
lot of story there, like season upon season.
And both injustice and deceased, if I remember
correctly, are written by the same guy. Oh,
yes, that's correct. Tom Taylor. So great answer,
Jacob Foster. Our next honorable mention goes
to... Nate Mantineo who said, Hey guys, Nate
here. And I would just like to say that I would
definitely have Annihilation be the three-part
movie event in an animated trilogy. I think
it's a great story with a ton of amount of cosmic
everything. Anybody who's anybody in the Marvel
Universe is going to be there and you want something
big leading up to that. So maybe build up a
movie universe and then have Annihilation. It
would just be great. Thanks guys, love the
show. Yeah, this is a fantastic answer. It blew
my mind when I heard it, because I didn't even
conceive of this as an animated film trilogy,
but I would love to see Annihilation adapted
like that. It's to this day, the greatest cosmic
tale that Marvel has ever done, or one of the
greatest, I should say, because it joined together
all of Marvel's spacefaring heroes and united
them against a common threat of Annihilus and
his Annihilation wave. I think you could break
it down into the prologue. for Annihilation
getting into the stories of like Drax and Nova
and Silver Surfer and Super Skrull and basically
setting up all the characters in the first
film. In the second one, really get into the
war against Nihilus and then have that end
with probably Galactus getting captured and
then at the end get into the Heralds of Galactus
and the ultimate defeat of Annihilus. I think
that would play out perfectly. There was a
lot of story there. It was fantastic. We get
to explore characters like Nova as well. whom
hasn't really got his due, I think, in the MCU.
Of course, this would be animated, but I think
it would be incredible. Yeah, Nate's idea of
building up a entire animated universe just
to have it possibly lead up to this Annihilation
trilogy is an interesting idea. It's kind of
the same thing that DC's doing in the Tomorrowverse,
building up this animated cinematic universe
just to tear it down with Crisis on Infinite
Earths. Yeah, I think Marvel could do it better
than DC, and I would pay good money to see it
happen. Dude, Marvel's animated movies suck.
Like, you're not wrong, but also, shut your
mouth. Great answer, Nate. Our final honorable
mention goes to Travis Herndon, who said, Hey
guys, Travis here. So my pick would have to
be the Planet Hulk storyline. I know we had
a Planet Hulk movie back in the early 2000s,
so why not have two movies to finish the story
off or just revamp it and do a complete retelling
that's faithful to the comics? I think. It's
time for us to actually get a faithful retelling
of that amazing story about my whole. I love
the Planet Hulk story. I think this is a fantastic
answer. Of course, there already was a Planet
Hulk animated movie, which is probably one
of Marvel's better animated films. And I would
just, yeah, like Travis said, work around that.
Or maybe you have the prelude to Planet Hulk,
where we get a solid Hulk story that ends with
him being sent out into space by the Illuminati.
And then we have the Planet Hulk storyline
as the second film and then culminate it with
the World War Hulk storyline. You don't get
better than that. That would be cool. That'd
be really cool. It'd be way better than the
Hulk we have now in the MCU. Just like silly,
smart Hulk. Yeah, we need like a good, solid,
destructive Hulk film. It's been a while, and
I don't think there's a better way to do it
than a Planet Hulk trilogy of films. Great answer,
Travis. We wanna give a quick shout out to
Bideer Bangura, who gave the answer of Dark
Knight's Metal, Colby Hentges, who gave the
answer of House of M, who said Titans Beast
World and Travis Bailey, who gave the answer
of Marvel's Wastelanders. But the winner of
this week's No Prize is Scott Camacho, who
said, The story series I want DC to adapt into
animated would be the Blackest Night series
of the Lantern Course. I think the lanterns
are due for an outstanding story to be told
animated and especially live action. And since
the movies have been darker lately, I'm thinking
this would be a great time to pull that off,
Blackest Night. So this gets the win because
not only is Blackest Night an awesome storyline,
but it's already part of a comic trilogy that
began with Green Lantern Rebirth and led into
the Sinestro Corps War. only to be concluded
by Blackest Night, which was like a full DC
Universe spanning event. It's a fantastic trilogy
and I'm really surprised that they haven't adapted
that onto screen yet. Like I thought that would
have been perfect for the Tomorrowverse, those
three films. Yeah, I feel like Green Lantern
movies are far and few between. I don't know
if there's kind of like a chilling effect on
behalf of the studio due to the reception of
the 2011 Green Lantern movie, but... Fortunately,
we did get one Green Lantern film in the Tomorrowverse,
which was Blackest Night, which was a pretty
solid movie, I thought. But yeah, I mean, the
greatest Green Lantern tale out there so far,
I think, is just ripe for the picking. Absolutely.
I would agree that it's the greatest Green
Lantern story. You know, Green Lantern Rebirth
set up like the emotional spectrum. Sinestro
Corps just ramped that up and really began introducing
the other color spectrums. And then Blackest
Night just had this massive zombie outbreak
across the whole universe. fantastic. If they
don't adapt it to animation, they need to adapt
it to live action. Like maybe for the television
series that James Gunn is producing. Yeah. I
mean, we don't know what story is going to
be adapted for James Gunn's television series,
lanterns. It's supposed to be like true detective
esque, which doesn't sound cosmic to me, but
who knows? Great answer, Scotty. You win this
week's no prize. If you the listener want a
shot at winning your own no prize, stay tuned
to later on in this episode when we'll be asking
another question of the week. And now that
that's done, on to the news!
Coming off the recent news that Debra Anwalt
and Eldon Henson will be returning as Karen
Page and Foggy Nelson in the upcoming Daredevil
Born Again Disney Plus Marvel Studios television
series, we got even better news this week. It
was confirmed by Deadline that Wilson Bethel,
who played Benjamin Poindexter aka Bullseye
on the Netflix Daredevil series, is going to
be showing up in at least three episodes of
the series, which is currently filming. And
if you guys watched the Netflix Daredevil show,
you're already super excited by this because
Daredevil season 3 was not only great superhero
television, it was just fantastic television
in general and a large part of that was due
to the fantastic portrayal of the extremely
dangerous Daredevil villain Bullseye. Dude,
like the villains in the Daredevil series are
amongst the best villains that have ever been
depicted on screen in my opinion. Bullseye
in particular was unbelievably horrifying, way
more scary than I thought he would be. And
he was the character I was most hoping would
make a return for this new Daredevil show and
it's super exciting to hear that he is. Yeah,
a couple of weeks ago our question of the week
was, what other character from the Daredevil
Netflix series do you most hope returns for
Disney Plus's Daredevil Born Again show? And
we got a few good answers, but the correct
answer as we stated in the last episode was
And then lo and behold, all of a sudden we
get that confirmation. It's just so exciting
to see as a fan. I'm really hoping that in
this season we'll get to see him in his, like,
traditional iconic bullseye outfit or some
adaptation of that. For sure. Yeah, because
we didn't get to see that in Daredevil season
three. I'm really loving all the choices that
Dario Skardapain seems to be making. And now
that Marvel has kind of decided to reboot the
Daredevil series, it looks like they're giving
fans exactly what they want. It looks like it's
going to be basically Netflix's Daredevil season
four, which is everything that the fans could
hope for. Yeah, wouldn't it be great if they
like also brought back Electra and we had like
the Bullseye versus Electra face off? That'd
be dope. I mean, Electra already died in the
Daredevil Netflix series. She died at the end
of season two. So I don't know if they would
want to retread that where she's like resurrected
by the hand again, but no, I would like to see
Electra returned regardless. I thought Elodie
Young made a fantastic Electra. Everyone in
that show was like perfectly cast. So glad
most of the cast is returning. Yeah, it seems
like Marvel is making all the right decisions,
you know, the same decisions that made them
so endearing to fans in the first place, where
they're truly giving us what we want to see,
you know? And why not? Like, studios do not
do that enough. Just freaking listen to the
fans. Exactly, exactly. But this news brings
us to our question of the week.
Who is your favorite villain from a Marvel or
DC television series, and why? Record your
answer at dynamicduel.com by clicking on the
red microphone button in the bottom right hand
corner of the screen, which will prompt you
to leave us a voicemail. Your message can be
up to 30 seconds long, and don't forget to leave
your name in case we include you on the podcast.
We'll pick our favorite answer, and award that
person a Dynamic Duel No Prize that we'll post
to Instagram. Be sure to answer before- February
3rd. There's a lot of great Marvel DC television
series out there guys a lot for you to choose
from I'm really looking forward to these answers
But that does it for all the news for this episode,
so let's go ahead and get into the main event,
where we discuss the latest Disney Plus Marvel
Studios television series, Echo Season 1.
ECHO Season 1 debuted a few weeks ago on Disney
Plus as the latest Marvel Studios television
series, with the series led by head director
Sidney Freeland and starring Ilaquah Cox and
Vincent D'Onofrio. It's a spin-off series from
2021's Hawkeye Show, where the character of
ECHO was introduced into the MCU as the daughter
of the tracksuit mafia leader who was killed
by Hawkeye's alternate identity of Ronin. At
the end of that show, And I guess let me take
this opportunity to say spoiler warning. This
is a spoiler review, not only for Echo season
one, but probably also for Hawkeye. At the end
of Hawkeye season one, Echo learned that the
Kingpin led Ronin to the Track Suit Mafia's
hideout and was directly responsible for her
father's death. Seeking revenge, Echo shot Kingpin
in the face, believing him to be dead, which
is where Echo season one picks up. Now, I enjoyed
Hawkeye season one. We rated it three and a
half stars on this podcast. And while I was
interested in Echo's introduction, I wasn't
sure at the time if she would be able to headline
her own series. Now that I've seen the series,
I guess I'm still wondering. That's not to discount
Alok Wacawks's performance, and we'll talk
about that later. But I mean, like, let's be
honest, Echo was a series that really no one
asked for. The character is not too popular
in the books, although I will say she is a
very interesting character, you should definitely
learn more about her in our question vs echo
duel episode if you don't know anything about
her. But it seems that in this day and age
of Marvel Studios where they're finding themselves
in a situation of diminishing returns from
producing too much content that people are caring
less about, Echo season 1 seems like an unnecessary
addition to their television catalog. I dunno,
I like the idea- of an Echo television series
and that it could be something unique and that's
definitely what they shot for with this show.
Unique to the MCU for sure. Yeah absolutely.
Yeah and perhaps that's why with this series
Marvel introduced the Marvel spotlight banner
which is supposed to represent projects in
the MCU that aren't necessarily connected to
the main canon telling more grounded character
driven stories. Basically you don't have to
watch Echo season 1 to stay caught up with
the Marvel Studios continuity. And I would say
unless you're really invested in the character
of Echo, I don't know if I would bother with
this show. Unless of course Echo ends up being
like a member of the New Avengers team or something
like that. I doubt that. You never know. I
mean she was a member of the Avengers in the
comics, so yeah, you could be right. Maybe
if you're looking for more grounded content,
you might be enticed to watch this. But even
then I wouldn't say Echo Season 1 really warranted
all the TVMA marketing that went into this
series. Absolutely. I feel like the worst stuff
was shown in the trailer. Yeah, it was basically
a montage of all the violence. The trailer for
this was incredible and even won my brother's
award for best trailer of last year. The marketing
seemed to promise a return to the type of rated-R
storytelling that existed within the Marvel
Netflix series, like Daredevil, Jessica Jones,
and The Punisher. I wouldn't say Echo seemed
very rated R outside of like one or two shots
of violence, it seemed very PG-13 in my mind.
So even if you're a fan of the old Netflix
shows and wanting more mature Marvel fare, I
don't think you'll be that satisfied with Echo
Season 1 and it may be just better to wait for
the Daredevil Born Again series which will
come out next year and is hopefully a return
to form for gritty grounded superhero shows.
So what you're saying is no one's gonna find
this show satisfying. I don't think fans of
Echo will find this satisfying. I don't think
fans of the Marvel Netflix series will find
this satisfying. I don't know who would find
this satisfying. But to get into what I didn't
find disappointing about the show, it did have
about two badass action scenes, like one in
episode one that actually included Daredevil,
which was awesome. That was cool. And there
was another action scene in episode three that
took place in a skating rink. You know, in
a five episode series, you would probably hope
for even more action, but those scenes were
the best of what we got and they were great.
You'd expect the best action scene to be in
episode five for like the climax, but nope,
it was episode one. Yeah. That's a little bit
disappointing. The last action scene in the
climax of the show had a tremendously disappointing
resolution. It was almost as disappointing as
the resolution to She Hulk, but I wouldn't
go that far. You know, at least we had some
punches thrown even if they were from, you
know, a 70 year old grandma. Story wise, there
wasn't too much here. Basically, Echo goes
to her hometown in Oklahoma in an attempt to
stage a coup over Kingpin's empire, but ends
up rediscovering her roots. It's surprising
to me that this show was initially shot as
an eight episode release that was later pared
down to five episodes. And honestly, thank
God. But I think that they could have taken
that even further and this probably should
have been a Disney Plus film or a Marvel Studios
special presentation. I think that runtime
would have served the story a little bit better
that they had here and it would have moved
at a quicker clip and been more enjoyable overall.
I don't know if I agree with that. I think
Maya's mission to take down Kinkpin and become
the new Queenpin of New York City crime required
a lot more story than what they gave us here.
This was a very small story. I don't understand
how she was trying to take down Kinkpin from
fucking Oklahoma. Like they should have had
her travel to New York City, meet people there,
you know, work the criminal underground from
the city. I don't know. It was just weird. That
would have been a better concept. Of course,
it would have gone against, you know, the whole
returning to your roots story that they were
telling here. Sure. But yeah, I think either
this could have been an eight episode series,
like what you were describing or it could have
been a film for the existing story that they
had. Yeah, yeah, I agree. One of the other things
I enjoyed about the show was the cultural representation.
It's not often that a superhero has such strong
ties to their cultural identity, but it's always
fascinating to see such as in films like Black
Panther or Shang-Chi. And here we got a great
glimpse into the Choctaw Nation. Although I
think they could have delved even deeper into
that. You know, I think the exploration that
we got of the Choctaw was only surface level.
Yeah, I probably would have thought that this
was a great exploration of the Choctaw Nation.
If I hadn't just watched Killers of the Flower
Moon like less than a week prior and their
examination of the Osage Indians who also lived
in Oklahoma. They even had some of the same
cast members for Echo as they did in Killers
of the Flower Moon and Killers of the Flower
Moon was way better. I have to check that out.
I always like Scorsese stuff. So what was interesting
here though is that not only did we get the
Native American cultural representation, we
also got a great crash course in American Sign
Language. I mean, I've never seen a project,
film or television. I never got around to seeing
Coda where so much of the dialogue was done
with signing. And I thought that was fantastic
and truly fascinating to watch. And the cast
did great, not only with the ASL, but with everything.
You know, there aren't too many opportunities,
it seems, for Native American roles. And it's
great to see how much talent there is within
their group. from old greats like Graham Greene
to some slightly familiar faces like Julia
Jones and enjoyable relative newcomers like
Cody Lightning who played Cousin Biscuits.
Yeah, I know how to sign bullshit in sign language
now. It's dangerously close to I love you.
Yeah, if you mumble with your signing, you could
end up either way in a lot of trouble. Ha ha
ha. But speaking of the actors, let's go ahead
and get into the character breakdown. Only
two major roles to talk about and one of them
is of course Echo. aka Maya Lopez played by
Alaka Cox. I wanna start off by saying that
Alaka Cox is an inspiration as an action hero.
I think that the physical choreography and the
stunts she's performed are incredible, not
even accounting for her missing leg and inability
to hear. When you do account for those things,
it's even more amazing what she's accomplished.
I don't want anything negative I say about
the show to discount how truly... in awe I am
of her skill and like I hate being this douche
hurling criticism from an armchair when she's
out there literally winning as a one-legged
woman in an ass-kicking contest. On one hand,
this version of Echo is so different from the
comic book character who's like this sophisticated
elegant socialite. And on the other hand, I
couldn't possibly imagine there is a better
person out there to play Maya Lopez than Iloquo
Cox. And I think really Iloquo
It's the show writers who don't really seem
to know the Kong book character, painting her
here as this gritty, unlikable, brash, hard
ass with an entirely different power set from
the source material. It's like the writers never
even read the comics. Yeah, I remember you
mentioning that she is essentially like Taskmaster.
And, you know, I was telling my wife that as
we were watching the show together, just explaining
how different this character is in the comics,
about how she's just able to see someone move
or do martial arts. and then she's able to
echo it or mimic it right off the bat. Right.
Yeah, that's why she has her name Echo in the
comic books. She has photographic reflexes like
Taskmaster, but she also has heightened visual
acuity like Cassandra Cain from DC Comics. It's
fascinating. And we kind of got a glimpse of
those abilities in Hawkeye Season One, where
she was able to anticipate her opponents moves.
But here the writers decided to forgo all that
and give her powers that tie into her Native
American ancestry. Which is also cool. Like
that was interesting and how like she was able
to like call on the talents of her ancestors.
But also I didn't get the healing thing. Like
was her mama mutant or some shit? Yeah, it's
weird. I think it was all spiritual mystical
based abilities. And there was a time in the
comic books when Echo had actual superpowers
when she was the host of the Phoenix Force.
And I mentioned that in our question versus
Echo dual episode that I didn't think those
powers would stick. and I was right because
she ended up exhausting her Phoenix Force powers
while trying to save the multiverse. So I don't
know if her ancestral powers were supposed to
kind of tap into that aspect of her abilities
from the comics, or if they were just kind of,
you know, running fast and loose with the idea
of the character. Does it bother you that they
were? I mean, the character is somewhat obscure
in the comics. I hate it when the writers don't
really adhere to the source material, because
then at that point it becomes a character that
I don't recognize. Now sometimes they have
good ideas. but every good idea should have
some semblance to the source material I think.
I agree. Otherwise, just make an original character.
Right, like they did with Kihori in Marvel's
What If, who was fantastic. This series portrayed
Echo as power hungry but without providing
clear motivations as to why she would want to
rule New York's crime empire, or how she would
achieve that besides blowing up a weapons facility.
You know, in the show, Maya said that her enemies
were playing right into her plan, but it's unclear
what that plan was gonna be. You know, she
obviously thought that she could take on all
of New York from the middle of nowhere Oklahoma,
but I never once believed that she'd be able
to achieve that as an audience member. Honestly,
I never really believed anything about the character.
You haven't really mentioned her acting ability,
but I'll be the one to say it. She's not the
best actress. She's a better action star than
she is an actress. Absolutely. I mean, there
were times where I thought she actually did
pretty well in her emotional scenes. But yeah,
overall, I think she's still growing as an
actress. Yeah, I think her emotions were for
the majority of it, a little to one note. It
was always anger all the time. I actually really
liked it when she was a bit more expressive.
Yeah, for sure. A little bit one note. She always
just came off as prickly and it doesn't make
for the most endearing protagonist. For her
arc, you know, instead of rising to power over
the criminal underworld, she instead discovered
how much her family meant to her, and that
her mom and her ancestors were always watching
over her. She healed from the pain of losing
her family, and instead by the end embraces
her relatives, heritage, and her lineage. Now
finding strength in your roots and in those
who love you is not a new theme in the world
of superheroes. In fact, it's pretty common,
but I will say that at least we get the novelty
of seeing it represented in this way with the
Choctaw Nation. Where have we seen this before?
Dude, strength in family is such a common theme
in superhero movies. Like, take for instance
recently Blue Beetle. Yeah. I would even say
Guardians of the Galaxy has strong familial
themes. Okay, I mean, that's fair. But like,
roots is different from family, I would say.
Like, culture is different from family. Like,
gathering strength from that, I think, actually
makes Echo unique. That's true. I mean, it's
not that unique, given, you know, things like
Shang-Chi and Black Panther. But it's unique
for this specific culture, which is nice. That's
fair. Let's go to move on to Kingpin, a.k.a.
Wilson Fisk, once again, played by Vincent
D'Onofrio. You know, he was flawless, obviously.
It was really good to see a return to form
after the slightly more cartoony take on Kingpin
that we saw in the Hawkeye television series.
Dude, I was so happy with Kingpin in the show.
I was like, hell yeah, bro. Hell yeah. Yeah,
I remember you complaining a lot about the character
in our review of Hawkeye season one. So, yeah,
it's good that he's back to being a gruff, terrifying
presence who often comes across as just this
powder keg of a man just waiting to explode
and unleash his clearly unhinged palpable rage.
Yeah, like totally unpredictable. You just never
know when the guy is going to snap and it's
terrifying when he does. Yeah. For me, Vincent
D'Onafrio nearly saves this show. His presence
was so welcome when he did finally show up at
the end of episode three, and he elevated things,
I think, when he came aboard. Oh, dude, he is
so fantastic in the role. He's Marvel's best
villain, in my opinion. Hands down. He's up
there, for sure. In this series, we see Kingpin's
reaction to Echo's betrayal from the Hawkeye
Show. You know, there are only so many people
that Kingpin extends any measure of grace or
forgiveness to, and those are the... rare people
that he loves. Vanessa, his wife, would be one
person. Maya is another. So when he gave her
that second chance as a comic fan, it was almost
unbelievable to witness the opportunity he
was extending her. And it was exciting knowing
that after Maya's refusal of his generous offer,
that shit was just gonna hit the fan. Like I
was on the edge of my seat at the end of episode
four. But. That anticipation just kind of fizzled
by the end of the show and you know, Kingpin
seemingly gets neutered of his unbridled rage.
Yeah, what the hell was that? He was like,
what did you do to me? What did you do to me?
And I was like, what did you do to him? I don't
even know. I'm confused. Answer the question.
The show never does. You know, and that's a
disappointment, but we'll have to see where
that goes in Daredevil Born Again, where apparently
in that series, based on the after credit scene
here. he'll become the mayor of New York. I'm
excited to see that. Yeah, that's a fantastic
setup. Definitely got me excited, even more
excited for the Daredevil show. That was a great
arc in the comics and I hope they do it justice.
Everyone else on the show, they were fantastic,
but they really only had minor roles. So let's
go ahead and get into our episode highlights.
Episode 1 was called Chaffa. At the dawn of
time, a woman named Chaffa emerges from a cave
as she and her people become the first of the
Choctaw Native American tribe. In present-day
Oklahoma, young Maya and her mother Taloa get
into an auto accident when their truck's brake
lines are cut by criminals looking to kill Maya's
father, William. Taloa dies and Maya loses
her leg, prompting William to move Maya away
with him to New York where he works for the
kingpin who becomes Maya's adoptive uncle. William
leads the tracksuit mafia who is wiped out
by Hawkeye, aka Ronan at the time, and Maya's
father dies in her arms. After learning Kingpin
tipped off Ronan, she shoots Kingpin in the
face and escapes to Oklahoma to her childhood
home where she meets with her cousin Biscuits
and her uncle Henry, the latter of whom she
asks for help in taking over Kingpin's empire.
In the end, it's revealed Kingpin survived
the shooting. I thought the opening to the series
was fantastic. It's actually probably the best
part of the show where we see the Choctaw Nation
rise from their cave onto the earth. How fascinating
was that? A great, incredible depiction of mythology.
Yeah, it was pretty cool. I thought it was
a great visual for sure. But not just that opening,
I thought this whole first episode was actually
pretty solid. Dude, it had the Daredevil fight,
which was excellent. Yeah, I saw a clip of
the fight in advance of watching the series,
and I thought the choreography actually moved
a little bit over rehearsed and slow. But seeing
it in context of that larger one shot framing,
I thought it was incredible. I was so happy
seeing that instead of the shitty, you know,
yellow mustard costume that we saw in She-Hulk.
Yeah, the stunt actor who played Daredevil,
I mean, Charlie Cox was great in the few lines
that he delivered, but I got to commend the
Daredevil stunt guy. The way he moves feels
very Daredevil to me. It was like seeing the
character leap right off the page. Yeah, the
way he leaped over the fence. Damn, that was
cool. That was sick. It was so cool to have
Daredevil and Hawkeye in the same episode.
Like I know we saw Matt Murdock in Spider-Man,
No Way Home, and that was cool. But to see
the character in costume and then we have, you
know, Hawkeye in the Ronin costume and stuff
like that, it just feels like the universe is
coalescing in a way that's so exciting as a
Marvel fan. You don't know how freaking lucky
you are that the Netflix shows are a part of
the MCU now. Man, that's, that's really cool.
It was apparent even from this first episode
though that there were some editing issues,
like there was a lot of stuff cut out, because
later on in the episode I remember just thinking
like, who the fuck is Biscuits? Who the hell
is this guy? Like, they name drop the character
in one line early in the episode where they're
like, Biscuits is gonna be mad he didn't get
to camp with the girls or something like that,
but it was so throwaway. They presented the
character like we were supposed to know who
he was, and maybe, you know, in a different
cut of this show we were supposed to. Yeah,
I felt the same way. I didn't even get the name
drop earlier on. I was just like, who the fuck
is Biscuits? Okay. Episode 2 was called LOWAK.
In 13th century Alabama, a woman named LOWAK
competes in a game of Choctaw Stickball and
manifests strength from a vision of Chaffa
to win the game for her team. In the present
day, Maya gets Biscuits to follow her as she
boards one of Kingpin's cargo trains. Finding
the munitions cart, she plants a homemade bomb
inside. As she attempts to flee, her leg gets
stuck in one of the train's couplings, at which
point she experiences a vision of Chafa and
Loic before summoning the strength to free
herself. The bomb explodes as the train reaches
its destination in New York, destroying one
of Kinkman's weapons facilities. Maya gets her
grandmother's ex, Scully, to fashion her a
new leg, and her uncle Henry warns her that
her actions are going to get the people close
to her killed. Frustrated, she fires her gun
at a swing set in a fit of emotion. You know
what that scene reminded me of when she just
started shooting the swing set and then the
episode ended? It reminded me of a scene in
Hot Fuzz where Nick Frost asks Simon Pegg,
have you ever like shot your gun in the air
and gone, ah, like Keanu Reeves did in Point
Break? And he's like, no, I've never shot my
gun in the air and gone, ah. You know. Just
firing your weapon as a display of emotion.
I always thought it was incredibly cheesy.
I don't know why she was shooting her swing
set. It was just really bizarre, lame way to
end this episode. Now, is it just me or does
Choctaw's stick ball seem ridiculously hard?
Like lacrosse, but like impossible. I'm still
wondering how Maya's ancestor won. Like she
just got a vision, did a flip. I didn't even
see the ball in her net stick thing. And I
don't know. It was like, what just happened?
She got a vision. She got the ball. She did
a flip over the scrum and then ran into the
goal. I think that's what happened. Okay, that
makes sense. What was interesting is when Maya's
powers manifested for the first time. Like
out of all the times in her life that she's
endured like life threatening stakes, I wonder
why her echo powers didn't come about then.
Maybe it was a proximity thing. I don't know,
maybe. They gave some throwaway line like, oh,
the ancestors know when they're needed or something
like that. But it's like, I'm pretty sure that
she could have used your help before. Like
maybe when they were about to get hit by a car
or something as a kid. Oh, geez. Where were
you then, ancestors? Damn. You know, what's
weird is that the stakes at the time when she
got her leg caught in the coupling. That wasn't
even life-threatening. She could have disconnected
her leg at the time and just hopped off the
train to be picked up by biscuits. The way
she got off the train was the most dangerous
way that she could have possibly done it by
leaping off onto the truck, you know? It probably
would have been better to just kind of like
tuck and roll as opposed to, you know, trying
this insane stunt. No, I'm still wondering
how the frick that happened that like when he
slammed on his brakes, she didn't fly forward.
Like when he came to the back and was like,
am I am I she just appeared behind the truck?
And I was like, how? When? What? That's a great
question. I have no idea. She was just like,
ta da. I was like, all right, bullshit. But
OK. I do have to mention one character that
you didn't break down Uncle Henry. I thought
he did a fantastic job. I'm not sure of the
actor's name, but he did a great job acting
and signing at the same time I noticed. I think
he did better than anyone else in the series.
Yeah, Henry was played by Chas Spencer. I think
you're right. It was hard for me to get a grasp
on Uncle Henry, honestly, because it was clear
that he cared for Maya, although he really disliked
the way she was going about everything. And,
you know, he was really the voice of reason
throughout the show, which was interesting
considering he was a career criminal. But absolutely,
I agree with everything you just said. His
ability to emote through his signing was kind
of a sight to behold. Yeah, I thought the same
thing. Moving on to episode three, which was
called Too-Clo. In the late 19th century, a
woman named Tuklo saves her father and other
members of the light horsemen native police
force from a band of outlaws by using exceptional
marksmanship skills granted by visions of her
ancestors, Chaffa and Loek. In the present day,
Maya begins seeing visions as well and is kidnapped
by one of her Uncle Henry's employees named
Vicky. He calls in Kingpin's men in an attempt
to collect the bounty on Maya's head and also
captures Henry and Maya's cousin Bonnie. When
the Kingpin's men arrive, Maya escapes confinement
and attacks them, though they get the upper
hand in the end by holding Bonnie hostage. Before
Maya's execution, the Kingpin's men get a call
telling them to leave her alive, and they leave.
Returning home, Maya is approached by the Kingpin,
who reveals that he's still alive. Dude, talk
about Deus Ex Machina. That was like, I hated
that. It kind of ruins the entire stakes of
the fight that you just witnessed, right? I
mean, that was a great action scene, I thought,
at least in the beginning. But when she started
to like using the arcade shooter guns as whips
and throwing skee balls at everybody, I was
like, hmm, maybe not. But other than that, I
thought the action fight was spectacular. I
really like the choreography. I really like
the camera work. It was just really well done.
I liked the booby traps she set up. I don't
get like some of the devices that she was able
to make, like that gun that she made. Oh, yeah,
that was stupid. I was like, what? How? How
did you make that fast? She was channeling the
abilities of a fellow Native American superhero,
Forge. Oh, nice. Yeah, you didn't know that.
He's one of her ancestors is part of her abilities.
No, yeah, that was weird. I don't understand
how you can make a bearing shooting device
out of a roller skate. Just doesn't seem possible.
Yeah. This is the episode where she got the
special shin guard by Scully. I thought Scully
was going to include something special, like
a secret gadget or something within the shin
guard. But that never really amounted to anything
within the rest of the series. They certainly
made it seem important, but it ended up not
meaning much outside of its cultural representation.
I was thinking the same thing. Like they had
the perfect opportunity to make Scully Maya's
Q as it were, like, you know, her gadget guy.
I'm really surprised they didn't follow through
with that. Yeah, that would have been cool.
That's what I was expecting. He was even like,
oh, I need time to work on this. Well, what
for?
I have no idea. You need to put some like, I
don't know, tear gas spray cartridges in there.
Something cool. Yeah, a knife or something.
At the very least, a knife. She already has
one in her shoe. Put one in her shin guard.
There you go. Episode four was called Taloa.
In 2008, Kingpin brutally beats an ice cream
vendor for mocking Maya for being deaf, an
act that she witnesses and participates in by
kicking him. In 2021. Kingpin offers a final
lesson to Maya for working for him, that they
can only trust each other and has his American
sign language interpreter killed. In the present,
Kingpin uses augmented reality tech to communicate
with Maya and tell her that if she returns to
him in New York, he will give her his criminal
empire. He gives her a day to decide before
leaving, and Maya is taken to visit her grandmother
Chula. There, Chula reveals that their ancestors,
which can be traced back to Chafa, help their
family when they need it the most. echoing through
the generations. Maya leaves in anger, however,
due to feeling abandoned as a child. Chula then
begins working on a special garment for Maya.
Maya visits Kingpin with the intent to kill
him, which he encourages just as he killed
his father. He asks Maya again to come back
to New York, but she ends up fleeing Tamaha
and raging him. I thought this was another great
flashback intro. The intros were actually some
of my favorite parts of this season. Every episode
began with a flashback. Yeah, yeah, that was
cool. It kind of gave some insight as to why
Kingpin took a liking to Maya in that she kind
of displayed a little bit of his same anger
and brutality towards that ice cream guy. Yeah,
the whole sign language interpretation technology,
I thought, was kind of interesting in concept,
but totally unnecessary given that Maya can
read lips. Can't she? Like, I wasn't sure if
she could throughout this entire series. Well,
she's supposed to be able to, like that's her
whole freaking power in the comic books. You
know, she has incredible visual acuity. So
really all Kingpin would need was some kind
of tech that could interpret ASL. She wouldn't
really need the contact lens. Yeah, he could
put the contact in his own damn eye. Yeah,
just replace his eyeball. Exactly. Although
I think it was maybe insinuating that the contact
lens was also a tracker. I don't know. What
I do want to know though is why didn't she
kill Kingpin at the end of this episode when
he gave her the opportunity? Is it because
she had a change of heart on wanting him dead
or something? But like if so, why? Because
he was kind of family and you know some part
of her didn't want to betray his trust, I guess?
But she was gonna betray his trust by fleeing,
you know? If she didn't want to betray his
trust, take him up on his offer and rule the
criminal underworld out of sight as the Queenpin.
Just a bizarre series of choices that she made
here. Yeah, I mean, but I think it was just
kind of hinting at her heroic streak in a way
that she realized that she didn't have it in
her to kill him. I guess, I don't know, because
she's definitely killed before. She's a complicated
character. Yeah, at that point, it kind of became
clear that she doesn't really know what she
wants. And the whole journey that she goes through
in the series is basically figuring that out
for herself. Right, yeah. Episode five was called
Maya. In a flashback to Maya's childhood, She
witnesses her mother use her healing powers
to mend a woodpecker that she had injured with
a slingshot. In the present, Biscuits reaches
out to Maya to tell her that Chula and Bonnie
are missing, prompting Maya to return to Tamaha.
At her grandmother's house, she sees a vision
of her mom, Taloa, who tells Maya that she's
the descendant of a long line of special women
dating back to Chafa, and that she's never alone
before healing Maya's heart of her pain. Maya
dons the outfit her grandmother created before
going to the Choctaw Powwow Festival and participates
in it to avoid Kingpin's men while looking for
her family. A woodpecker guides Maya to a barn
where she finds Kingpin with Chula and Bonnie
held captive. Summoning the power of her ancestors,
Maya shares her powers with her family and they
join together to fight Kingpin's men. She takes
Kingpin back to a memory of his childhood and
heals his pain. Enraged, He asks her what she
did to him, then flees as the police arrive.
The next day, Maya visits her family before
leaving Tamaha. In a post-credit scene, Kingpin
watches with interest a news report on the
New York mayoral election. So I have a question.
Yeah? Did Maya forget about her mom's superpower,
like as she grew up? I feel like if I saw my
mom perform a miracle like killing an injured
bird, I would remember that shit. You know?
I almost feel like maybe that wasn't the first
time she saw her mom do that. Maybe that's why
she brought it to her mom. Because like, the
little girl didn't seem surprised at all when
her mom displayed the power. She was like,
Oh my gosh, what's happening? No. I also want
to know why didn't her mom, if she could visit
her as a ghost, heal her pain from her traumatic
childhood sooner if she had that ability. Well,
maybe because she was finally getting full access
to her ancestors and maybe like her mom was
the last one that she was able to gain access
to. Maybe that's the reason. There's a lot
of assumptions that are going on here. Also,
I didn't know quite how to describe how Bonnie
and Chula got their abilities, whether or not
that was Maya sharing it with them or if they
also have the ability to tap into the power
of their ancestors. That was unclear. Well,
they have the same ancestors. So I figured that
was the reason why. So basically you have a
whole line of Choctaw women who are superheroes.
Every woman is a superhero, Joseph. Every woman.
Right, I forgot about that, sorry. The end fight
was horrible. Like I almost did a spit take
when I saw Chula punching bad guys. And again,
I just really don't like the ambiguity regarding
what happened to Kingpin. Like if he's cured
of his pain regarding his traumatic childhood.
Does that mean that he's now without evil ambition?
If so, does that not contradict the look on
his face when he's considering running for mayor?
Is he in fact going to be a good mayor? What's
gonna happen there? Yeah, that's a fantastic
question. I guess we won't know the answer
to that until Daredevil born again. But I do
think that her healing camp was the most anti-climactic
shit I've ever seen in my life. For sure, yeah.
If Kingpin ends up still being like a a piece
of shit dude in Daredevil Born Again. I'm going
to wonder what the hell happened here. Yeah,
I guess Echo's powers are useless. Yeah, like
I'm unclear as to what exactly she heals, because
like her mom healed the physical body of the
hummingbird. And I guess Echo physically healed
Kingpin's eye. When you do it over the heart,
was it also psychological or spiritual or I
don't know? I think it's emotional. I think
it's emotional healing. When I get that feeling.
I need a emotional healing. There you go. Emotional
healing. Yeah, we'll say the ending was quite
as bad as the cop out that She-Hulk did, where,
you know, she broke the fourth wall and completely
circumvented the entire conflict that whole
series was building toward. But this is still
a pretty bad ending. So I guess the best thing
you can say about the show is that it's somewhat
better than She-Hulk. Yeah. And that brings
us to, you know, my final rating. You know,
we rated She-Hulk two stars. This was better
than that. I actually enjoyed Secret Invasion
season 1 more than Echo, so I'm going in between
there. While Echo season 1 is a fascinating
insight into several underrepresented groups,
the story is threadbare and the hero is just
too one-dimensional for much enjoyment. So I'm
rating it 2.5 stars, a rotten rating on Rotten
Tomatoes. Because at the end of the day, I don't
think I would recommend the show, I think you'll
be disappointed by it no matter what type of
Marvel fan you are. Yeah I- I guess I would
agree. I think I liked it a little bit more
than you did, not by much though. Like I might
be willing to give this three stars maybe, but
right around that ballpark. I think you hit
the nail on the head early on in the review
when you said that you're not sure who will
be satisfied by a series like this. I think
ultimately the only reason to watch it is if
you know, Echo ever joins the Avengers and you
want to find out how she got her cool new costume.
The costume was cool. I'll say that. But that
does it for this review. Let us know what you
guys thought about Echo Season 1 by writing
to us at dyna or by visiting us on Instagram,
which you can find a link to on our show notes
or by visiting our website, dynamicduel.com.
And on our site, you could also find a link
to our Patreon page, where you could join our
dynamic duo tier and chat with us and fellow
listeners, our fantastic four tier, which gets
you bonus content each month, our X-Force tier
that makes you an executive producer of this
podcast. or our newest tier that lets you join
our Dynamike Podcast Network. Please guys,
don't forget to rate the show on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, Podchaser, or on our website. In our
next episode, we're going to start a series
of multiversal duels as a tie-in to our review
of Crisis on Infinite Earths, and in lead-up
to Madam Web that's coming near the end of
February, we will be pitting Ultraman against
Hyperion. Yeah, Ultraman being the Earth three
version of Superman, who's basically an evil
version of Superman versus Hyperion, who is
the leader of the Squadron Supreme, which is
basically like an authoritarian version of
the Justice League in Marvel. So two evil, multiversal
Superman, who's gonna win? We're gonna find
out next week. But that does it for this episode,
we want to give a big thanks to our executive
producers Ken Johnson, John Storowski, Zachary
Hepburn, Dustin Belcombe, Mickey Mathengian,
Brandon Estergard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yeaton,
Nick Obanto, Austin Wazilowski, AJ Duckerley,
Scott Camacho, Adam Spies, Andrew Schunk, and
Dean Molesky for helping make this podcast
possible. And we'll talk to you guys next week.
Up up and away, true believers. Why did the
Echo get detention? It kept talking back.