This is a Dynamike Network podcast.
Hi, welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin brother, Marvelous
Joe. And in this episode, we are reviewing
the latest DC animated film set in the Tomorrow
Verse Justice League, Crisis on Infinite Earths
Part 1, the first part of a trilogy of films
that will end out this universe. Yeah, part
one came out about a week ago, the other two
parts are going to come out later this year.
I was really surprised by this film. There's
a lot of films in the Tomorrowverse that I
haven't liked. It's been pretty much hit or
miss. But Crisis part one is really unique
and I'm really looking forward to talking about
it. Before that, we're going to break down
the comic movie news from the past week, of
which there was just one news item and that
was the teaser trailer for Justice League Crisis
on Infinite Earths part- 2. So this is a full
on Crisis on Infinite Earths episode, apparently.
As always, we list our segment times in our
episode description, so feel free to check out
the show notes if you want to skip ahead to
a particular topic. Our artificially intelligent
dual simulator, AJ9K, has a quick message for
our listeners, so listen up. Why, hello there.
Do you love listening and chatting about Marvel
and DC? Then become a part of the dynamic dual
community on Patreon where you can choose from
three tiers. The Dynamic 2.0 tier lets you listen
to this podcast without ads, and gives you
access to its Discord chat group where you can
chat with Johnny DC and Marvelous Joe. The
Fantastic 4 tier gives you that and more with
two bonus episodes each month, including bloopers
and top 10 shows where Johnny and Joe count
down your favourite Marvel and DC subjects.
The X-Force tier makes you an executive producer
of Dynamic Duel, where every month you help
the host choose what to review and who to fight
against each other. And finally, the Dynamite
Podcast Network tier allows aspiring podcasters
to create their own battle-focused show using
this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe will
help you develop your show, provide graphic
support and consultation, and get you simulation
results to announce on your show. Pitch the
twins your show via email at dyna or by reaching
out to the Dynamite Podcast them on social
media. Check it out at patreon.com slash dynamic
duel. Pip pip cheerio. Thanks AJ and IK and
thanks to everyone who supports the podcast.
Be sure to tune into the Max Destruction podcast,
part of the Dynamike Podcast Network, which
last week found out who would win between Batman
from the 1989 Batman film and Captain America
from the 1990 Captain America film. This week,
I believe hosts Ken and Scotty are going to
find out who would win between Steven Seagal's
Casey Ryback from Under Siege. versus Chuck
Norris' major Scott McCoy from Delta Force.
Nice! On the Sinjoworld podcast, host Zachary
Hepburn speculates on fights between your favorite
anime characters. This week, we're gonna find
out who would win between Black Clover's Luck
Vultia versus Hunter Hunter's Killua. And on
the Console Combat podcast, host John and Dean
find out who would win in fights between your
favorite video game characters. In yesterday's
episode, they ventured into round two of their
tournament, speculating on who would win. not
only between Tomb Raider's Lara Croft and Assassin's
Creed's Ezio Auditore, but also Super Mario
RPG's Gino vs Sonic the Hedgehog's pal Tails.
Visit dynamicpodcast.com or click the link
in our show notes to listen to all the shows
in the Dynamike Podcast Network. But with that
out of the way, quick to the no prize! A No
Prize is an award Marvel used to give out to
fans. Our version, the Dynamic Dual No Prize,
is a digital award we post on Instagram and
in our email newsletter for the person that
we feel gave the best answer to our question
of the week. Last week, we asked, what other
character from the Daredevil Netflix series
do you most hope returns for the Disney Plus
Daredevil born-again show and why? And this
is coming off of the news that Deborah Anwalt
and Elden Henson will be... reprising their
roles as Karen Page and Foggy Nelson in the
Daredevil Born Again series. We got literally
two answers for this question of the week, which
is not surprising because we only gave you
guys about two days to do it. So let's run down
our honorable mention as well as our no prize
winner. Our first honorable mention goes to
Lizzie Dyer Arnie, who said, Hey, it's Lizzie.
So I really want to see Marcy Stahl return to
the new Daredevil series on Disney. If you
don't remember who she is, she's Foggy's on
again, off again girlfriend. who helped them
take down Landman and Zack from the inside.
She provides much needed comic relief to the
show. And I think we are long overdue to see
Marcy and Foggy's wedding. Have a great day.
Now, I'm not going to lie. I barely remember
this character, but I do agree that Daredevil
needed comic relief and she was great in the
role. Well, I thought Foggy himself provided
comic relief for the show. but it was nice that
they gave him a love interest because otherwise
he was just kind of like the, you know, the
tag along sidekick character to Matt Murdock.
I liked actress Amy Ruppberg in the role as
Marcy. I always thought she was like way too
hot for Foggy Nelson, but that was kind of like
the appeal of it, I think. It was nice to see
this bumbling character get a girl who's way
out of his league. Yeah, that's true. Plus
I also don't hate the idea that Lizzie gave
of Foggy finally getting married. Like the
guy deserves it. Yeah, it literally rains shit
on Foggy Nelson a lot, so it's nice to see
that he has this one consistent good thing in
his life. Great answer Lizzy! But the winner
of this week's No Prize is Judson Baddie. And
I hope I'm pronouncing that right. But he said,
Hi guys, Judson Baddie here. Long time listener,
first time responder. I think the character
and actor I'd like to see return for Dead Ever
Born again the most is Father Paul Langton
played by Peter McRobbie. I feel like he had
some interesting dynamics. with Charlie Cox
as Daredevil and provided and understated the
very important role in the spiritual side of
the Daredevil character and the show wouldn't
be the same without him. Well, you guys went
with some pretty deep dives for your answers
for this question of the week. Father Lantern,
played by Peter McRobbie on the Daredevil Netflix
show, was very much the soul of the show. He
was essentially Matt Murdock's spiritual guide,
given that... Matt Murdock is a very religious
character in the comic books and in the show.
He's a devout Catholic. And I thought the actor
Peter McRobbie did a great job and was an interesting
character in guiding Matt Murdock and discussing
the ethics of his actions as both a Catholic
and a vigilante. Yeah, I'm not gonna lie. This
is another character I barely remember, but
I like this as the win for this week's question.
because of how religious a character Daredevil
is. And it's pretty unique in comics that a
character is so heavily involved in his spirituality.
Yeah, I mean, it makes sense for a character
named Daredevil, right? It kind of adds to the
intrigue given that, you know, he dresses up
like the devil and beats the shit out of people.
It's really interesting that dichotomy of Daredevil.
Honestly, I thought we were going to get answers
like Electra and Bullseye. Right. Yeah. Bullseye
was in fact the correct answer played by Wilson
Bethel. He was incredible in season three and
the dude needs to come back as Bullseye. He
was fantastic. Yeah, 100 percent. But great
answer Jetson, you win this week's No Prize.
If you're the listener, want a shot at winning
your own No Prize, stay tuned to later on in
this episode when we'll be asking another question
of the week. And now that that's done, on to
the news.
Okay, so we recently got the official teaser
trailer for Justice League Crisis on Infinite
Earths Part 2, the sequel to the film we're
about to review later in this episode, Crisis
on Infinite Earths Part 1. Now, in Part 1, there's
quite a bit of time jumping, and it looks like
that may be the case for Part 2 as well. We
learned in Part 1 that Monitor's assistant
of sorts, Harbinger, is actually Supergirl from
the Legion of Superheroes film, and it looks
like in part two we're going to find out exactly
how she became Harbinger. It kind of looks
like she's going to be the main character of
part two, honestly, in the same way that Flash
was the main character of part one. Which is
not a big surprise of the two major sacrifices
that happened in the comic book. Flash and Supergirl
were probably the most impactful. My guess
is Supergirl does not make it to the end of
the film. That's just a guess. Sorry if that's
a spoiler. Well, I mean, if you look at the
cover to the crisis on Infinite Earth's trade
paperback, you'll see Superman holding a dead
Supergirl. So I don't know how much of a spoiler
that actually is. True. That's fair. Yeah. I
thought it was really cool to see the Bat family
at the beginning of this trailer, which seems
to include Batman Beyond and Batwing. Yeah,
honestly, that was pretty shocking seeing Batman
Beyond, who's from the future. considering
the end of part one. Not gonna give away any
spoilers, but if you know, you know. It really
looks like this film picks up right after the
events of part one, as we still see the frequency
tuning fork tower in the background in the opening
shots. It looks like the main thread of this
movie though are these like shadow creatures.
Shadow demons, yes, they're from the comics.
They're like the soldiers of the anti-monitor.
Interesting. We also get a shot of Psycho Pirate.
It's not too clear what he's doing. but the
character is pretty interesting from the comics
so I'm looking forward to seeing what's going
on there. All in all there's really not too
much more to talk about. It's a really short
teaser, it's less than 45 seconds. I thought
we were going to get a release date with it,
but at the very end it just says coming soon.
So when we do get that release date, we'll make
sure to let you guys know. Because I'm looking
forward to it for sure. Yeah, I think in total
this trilogy is going to be quite an epic series
of films. But speaking of epic animated trilogies,
that brings us to our question of the week.
What comics storyline for Marvel or DC would
you want to see adapted as an animated film
trilogy and why? Record your answer at dynamicduel.com
by clicking on the red microphone button in
the bottom right hand corner of the screen which
will prompt you to leave us a voicemail. Your
message could be up to 30 seconds long and don't
forget to leave your name in case we include
you on the podcast. We'll pick our favorite
answer and award that person a Dynamic Duel
No Prize that we'll post to Instagram and our
email newsletter. Be sure to answer before
January 27th.
That does it for all the news for this episode,
now let's move on to the main event, where
we review the latest DC animated film, Justice
League, Crisis on Infinite Earths, Part 1.
Alright, Justice League Crisis on Infinite Earths
Part 1 is the latest in Warner Bros. Animation's
Tomorrowverse world of direct-to-video DC animated
films, which is the follow-up universe to the
DC animated movie universe that ended with the
phenomenal film Justice League Dark Apocalypse
War. Comparisons between the animated universes
have been inevitable. Most fans, I would say,
have been pining for a return to the DC AMU,
which had its critics, but has been widely
accepted as being superior to the Tomorrowverse.
I personally have praised the Tomorrowverse's
character designs and premises, but with the
exception of the two-part Batman the Long Halloween
films, the overall execution of the Tomorrowverse
has ranged from fairly decent to borderline
unwatchable. So how does Crisis on Infinite
Earths, the first part of a trilogy that's
being released throughout this year, compare
to the other Tomorrowverse films? I'm relieved
to say it's one of the best. If you haven't
seen it yet, maybe because you've given up
on the Tomorrowverse? I definitely recommend
watching it and it makes me want to recommend
watching the entirety of the Tomorrowverse beforehand
because it really makes you appreciate little
hints and Easter eggs they've sprinkled throughout
the other films to show that they've been building
up to this concluding trilogy in order to successfully
capture the emotional impact that long time
DC fans had while first reading the Crisis on
Infinite Earths comic that this film is based
on. I don't know that's a lot to ask audiences,
especially our listeners. Like putting them
through the likes of Justice Society World War
II or Legion of Superheroes or Justice League
War World. Like, there's a lot of duds that
I just would not recommend watching just to
better enjoy this film. It's surprising to me
that you said that Crisis on Infinite Earths
Part 1 is one of the better entries in the tomorrowverse
because you're right. But also, this movie
was mostly okay. So just... thinking that it
was actually still one of the best makes me
kind of sad about the whole Tomorrowverse in
general. Well, I mean, the number one film
in the Tomorrowverse was absolutely the two
part long Halloween, probably followed by Green
Lantern Beware My Power. And I'm not sure if
I like this as much as Beware My Power. It
might be just underneath that, but I still liked
this film. Crisis on Infinite Earths is an
adaptation of the comic of the same name. Now
if you're not familiar with Crisis on Infinite
Earths, it was the first major universe-spanning
blockbuster event in comics that drastically
changed DC's continuity and delivered explosive
stakes for long-time comic readers, going all
the way back to 1956 when the introduction of
Barry Allen, the Flash, kicked off the Silver
Age of comics. The stories in the comics released
prior to that, during the Golden Age, were
eventually revealed to have taken place in a
parallel universe that Barry Allen learned
he could travel to. This set up the first-ever
multiverse, which became threatened in 1985
by the Crisis on Infinite Earth storyline, where
we saw characters like Barry Allen die or sacrifice
themselves during the event. Now to successfully
adapt a story like Crisis on Infinite Earths
in animation, you have to try and match what
comic book writers had decades to accomplish,
creating long-standing relationships between
fictional characters and invested audiences
through serialized adventure stories. It's a
lot easier to create a comic book than it is
to create an animated film though. Literally,
one or two guys can create a comic. compared
to sizable budgets and teams of animators needed
to create a future film. The Tomorrow vs Producers,
Jim Krieg and Kimberly Moreau, who wanted to
do a Crisis on Infinite Earths adaptation,
were allowed to create a 10-film universe, which
they used to lead up to this major trilogy
event that begins with Crisis on Infinite Earths
Part 1. This was only recently revealed, but
going back to early films in the Tomorrowverse,
it's now apparent that not only have the filmmakers
been planning their way to a crisis story, but
also that they've planned on involving prior
animated universes such as the DC AMU and several
DC Showcase animated shorts, including Constantine,
House of Mystery, Adam Strange, and Commandie.
The connect- The connectivity blows my mind
and makes me unbelievably excited for the releases
of part 2 and 3 later this year. Well, I remember
that the Adam Strange short was a direct prequel
to Green Lantern Beware My Power. But I'm having
trouble remembering exactly how the House of
Mystery and Command D were referenced in this
Crisis on Infinite Earths part 1 movie. Well,
Constantine House of Mystery is a pretty obvious
one. It's the connective tissue between the
DC AMU and the tomorrow verse. At the end,
I believe he was punished by the specter, but
I forgot what the punishment was. I guess we
see the results of that in this movie when we
see Constantine as an old guy. Yeah, he's forced
to live through the ends of universes. Interesting.
And Comedie has been confirmed to be a part
of this universe as well by the producers. Now,
I wasn't always excited for the Crisis films
this year. In fact, I'd say they were the DC
projects I was looking forward to the least,
hands down. Just like as of last week, basically.
But after seeing the bold risk they took with
Part 1 in terms of its unconventional narrative
structure and having it pay off so spectacularly
well, I feel like I've glimpsed a genius adaptation
of the source material. Like, I've never seen
a superhero film be so hyper-focused on a single
character's perspective of a story. You could
say Crisis Part 1 is like the Groundhog Day
or memento of superhero films in that regard,
but the story borrows most heavily from The
Time Traveler's Wife, a book that's been adapted
to both a film and television series if you're
not familiar with it. Yeah, as a narrative
device, the time jumping thing got a little
bit grating after a while because it was kind
of hard to tell the overall structure of the
film. Like it didn't have like a clear three
act breakdown. And that can sometimes be a frustrating
experience as a viewer. It did actually have
three acts. Well, that was not easy for me to
tell. Well, apparently you're stupid then.
I don't know what else to say. I'll be honest,
when I first got done watching this film, I
couldn't tell you if it was good or not. I knew
that it was interesting, and I do think that
it sets up tremendous potential for the overall
trilogy of films. I get the impression that
when all is said and done, the story is going
to be massive and epic in a way that puts even
Apocalypse War to shame. But I just think we
haven't gotten there yet. There was a lot of
like missing context to a lot of what we were
watching, and it sometimes felt confusing in
that regard. But I will admit. that your comparisons
to stories like Memento and The Time Traveler's
Wife have me a little bit more intrigued. Yeah,
honestly, Crisis Part 1 is going to be a film
that you either love or you hate, kind of like
films like Groundhog Day. I think everyone
loves The Time Traveler's Wife. It's a love
story, so it may be outside the interest of
our podcast's audience demographics. But if
you're not familiar with it, the time traveler's
wife follows a man cursed with a time traveling
condition that causes him to live his life
out of linear time. Like he experiences events
in his life in a nonlinear random order, while
the woman he loves struggles to live life with
someone with this condition. In Crisis Part
1, about three quarters of the way through the
film, The Flash absorbs the entire speed force
of a universe that was just destroyed by an
antimatter wave traveling through the multiverse,
which causes him to experience time non-linearly,
and we as an audience are along for the ride.
The film constantly jumps, or time trips, throughout
its story, and it's not until a decent ways
into the film that we begin to grasp what's
going on. Story-wise, the film jumps back in
time to tell the story of how the Justice League
first formed. A story we didn't get the chance
to see in earlier Tomorrowverse films, which
is something fans had complained about, including
myself. Oh yeah, I remember we brought that
up as a criticism of the Tomorrowverse during
the Beware My Power review. Yes. Because the
League was already formed by that movie, but
the only reference we got to the League prior
to that was in Justice Society World War II.
where they're like, oh, maybe we should form
a team or something like that. And then all
of a sudden we see it fully formed without any
kind of glimpse into how or why these characters
got together. I was surprised when I saw that
this was, in fact, a Justice League origin
story. Yeah, that was a huge surprise to me
as well. The formation of the Justice League
has never been particularly profound, in my
opinion. Basically, a group of heroes get together
to battle a major threat like Starro or Darkseid.
But in this film, the team's formation is a
ruse to draw out a life-stealing android named
Amazo, whose own story is more existential
and emotional than it needed to be. Like, it
did not need to go that hard. As we learn that
story, we also visit the Earth-3 universe ruled
by an evil version of the Justice League, known
as the Crime Syndicate, and witness that universe's
destruction. which sets up the stakes for the
film's central and final threat. That the multiverse
is being destroyed, universe by universe, and
it being outside of space and time, the monitor
has brought heroes from across the multiverse
to save it. The true heart of the film, though,
comes from the story between Barry and his
wife, Iris, as we see them meet for the first
time shortly after Barry received his powers,
and eventually get married, despite Barry's
inability to experience his life linearly.
In one moment, he's at his wedding, the next
he's on Earth 3, the next he and Iris are old.
The dedication and love that Barry and Iris
have to each other despite their crazy lives
makes Crisis Part 1 arguably one of the most
romantic superhero projects that I've ever
seen. Yeah, at first part of me was like, out
of all the people the Flash could have gotten
to help him build these towers, Why did he go
with someone that's not super powered or like
a super genius or something like that? So the
decision was entirely made out of the desire
to spend the rest of his life with this woman
He loves and uh, you know, I could appreciate
that too. Definitely made for a touching twist
on the narrative at the end Absolutely, like
it just made me want to go like hug my wife
You know, hey cool it with the romance man
This podcast has a limit on the number of lovey-dovey
things that can be said Alright, there's just
so much that I love about this film, but I can
also see where a lot of people would maybe
be turned off by its haphazard time-jumping,
like you mentioned. It's not exactly the best
plot structure to explain an event as complicated
in itself as the destruction of the multiverse,
so there are multiple barriers to entry for
audiences on top of the barrier that exists
naturally in a cinematic universe. Basically,
if you don't watch everything that came before,
there's a chance you'll be missing important
information needed to truly understand or appreciate
the current story that you're watching. Marvel
runs into that sometimes. Yeah, more often
than not, the longer your cinematic universe
goes, the more of a chilling effect audiences
are going to have going into it. Exactly. And
the only other gripe that I have about the
film is the animation. Again, the character
designs are great for the most part. Although
actually there were a few I was really unhappy
with in this film. But the animation leaves
a lot to be desired. Like there are some scenes
that felt like old school super friends cartoons,
where the entire frame is still except for characters'
mouths moving. Yeah, the tomorrowverse is largely
computer animated and sometimes it can be done
to great effect like in the Batman the Long
Halloween films. This was nothing like that.
Like, sometimes these characters would not
blink and they were just staring. like not even
making direct eye contact with who they were
talking to, and they look like soulless abominations.
But I just think it's probably an issue of
timing with the animators. They probably didn't
have enough time to actually add all the subtle
quirks and eye movements and things like that
when producing this film. Maybe, yeah, maybe
for certain characters over others, that's probably
true. Now the film is nowhere near as dynamic
as it needs to be. But at least for me personally,
the story made up for a lot of the film's drawbacks.
Though the film features a large cast of DC
characters, it focuses solely on the experiences
of one. So there's not many characters to really
dive into for our character breakdown, but
let's start with The Flash. Now The Flash, aka
Barry Allen, was voiced by Matt Bomer. Now
Matt isn't just a fantastic voice actor, but
a great actor in his own right. And as such,
he is fantastic at capturing emotion. I have
to give major credit to the filmmakers for
making the decision to get an actor as talented
as Matt Bomer to successfully kick off this
three film conclusion to a cinematic universe.
The end of a story should be bittersweet, and
Matt Bomer definitely helped make The Flash's
ending bittersweet and heartfelt. Yeah, I mean,
we saw him portray the character of the Negative
Man largely in voice alone for the Doom Patrol
television series. It does amaze me how different
his voice acting is here for the character
of Barry Allen. The guy is super talented. Yeah,
for sure. Yeah, his negative man was so like
melancholic, whereas his Barry is much more
bright. Now for a film in which so many things
happen, the character of Barry Allen is relatively
static. And that's in part because everything
he experiences, whether it be the first time
he met his wife or his wedding, He's experiencing
as someone who already knows what's going to
happen because he's been to the future. What
makes him interesting in this film is when he
is put in situations that we don't yet know
how he's going to get out of it. Whether it's
going up against a mezzo or escaping Earth
3 or preventing the destruction of his universe.
In the comics, the Flash sacrificed his life
to help save the multiverse. And while he does
the same in this film, it's incredibly touching
that they still found a way for him to live
out an entire lifetime with his wife Iris happily
and with no regrets. And the fact that his last
moments existing in time in his universe was
at his wedding reception celebrating with the
rest of Earth's heroes is like the greatest
of honors. It literally brought tears to my
eyes and I can think of no ending greater for
a hero as important to the comics as The Flash.
Yeah, the narrative approach that he took with
The Flash does make me question some things,
particularly when we've seen the character
in previous movies such as Justice Society World
War II, where we know that he still experienced
time linearly throughout the course of that
entire adventure, the time traveling notwithstanding.
Yeah, that's a good question. Like at what point
in his life did he start time tripping? And
it- seems like it really kicks in around the
time of the formation of the Justice League.
Though honestly, parts of it go back to even
before that to, you know, when he first gets
his powers. Exactly. So that's a little bit
strange. I do think that they could have effectively
told the same story with about 25% less time
jumping because at some point I got really
sick and tired of seeing that graphic of the
Speed Force tunnel thing. I'm like, oh my God,
just stop. Just little touches, like what you
mentioned about him spending some of his last
moments dancing with his wife at his wedding.
That's just poetry. So there's a lot of kind
of like back and forth, the things that I really
like and things that I don't really care for.
But overall, as a concept, I really appreciate
where they were trying to go with it. Yeah,
it's ambitious for sure. Now the only other
character I have anything to dive into with
is Amazo. He was voiced by Nolan North, who
also did the voice. for John Constantine and
Hal Jordan in this movie. He's a voice actor
and a damn good one. No, Amazo was created
by Dr. Anthony Ivo for the sole purpose of extending
human life. Ivo was a scientist for LexCorp
and when Lex purposefully gave Ivo Hutchinson-Gilford
syndrome, causing him to age rapidly. Ivo created
Imezo with the ability to absorb, store, and
redirect energy in order to restore vitality
to the dying and the sick. Lex, however, corrupted
Imezo's programming so that he was capable
of absorbing and using metahuman energy, granting
him the powers of Superman and the Flash, among
others. Imezo's always been a considerable threat
for the Justice League, so I thought having
him be the catalyst for the formation of the
League was a good choice. But the heroes initially
formed the Justice League during a public address
as a way to draw out a mezzo to them, though
it also brought Lex Luthor in an awfully designed
mech suit. Yeah, that was horrible looking.
It was cool to see Lex continue his journey
from the Man of Tomorrow movie, but it was
also a little bit convoluted considering he
had this scientist who he gave this really
rare disease to and he probably could have just
given him cancer or something like that. and
he had him build a benevolent android who really
struggled with Lex's commands. You would think
that Lex could almost just build this thing
himself. I don't know. It was a little bit
strange there, but it was cool to see Zachary
Quinto in the role again. Yeah, he's great
as Lex. I think it was implied that Ivo was
a prodigy and that the creation of an AI as
evolved as Amazo was, was outside of Lex's abilities.
But that's just a guess. Yeah, this was a much
different- version of a Mazer than the one that
we saw in Batman under the Red Hood, right?
Yes. Yeah, very much so. Because in that movie,
Batman was able to defeat the Mazer with some
explosives, if I recall correctly. Which is
bullcrap. But yeah, I loved how they used parasite
alien technology to give a Mazer his like absorbing
powers. I thought that was smart. That makes
sense. Yeah, that tighted well. I do have to
wonder, though, as well, like Lex's mech suit
almost looks like a metallo. Like, if they were
selling that as a prototype for maybe a later
version of Botelo, I could totally buy that.
That's really the only reasoning I'll accept
for why his suit looked so damn bad. Now when
The Flash realizes that Amazo's been corrupted
by Lex and he brings Dr. Ivo to him, Amazo attempts
to heal Ivo using the metahuman energy that
he had absorbed. When that ended up killing
the frail Ivo instead, the subtle acting quote-unquote
by Amazo was incredible. Like the android was
so profoundly shocked by betraying the very
reason for his existence and accidentally killing
his creator, he could barely complete a sentence.
It just broke him. The fact that Amazo was brought
back online by the Flash to help him and Iris
complete the frequency tower and save the multiverse
at the end, allowing Amazo to fulfill his programming
before being destroyed, also cut me super deep
to my core. Like for a character to go from
the deepest valley of regret to the utmost peak
of fulfillment in his last moment was surprisingly
more cathartic than I thought it'd be. And this
is just part one. Yeah, as the story was going
on, I wasn't quite sure why they felt the need
to include Amazo in this particular story,
because I wasn't sure it made sense thematically
with the idea of the multiverse ending. By
the end it was clear that they included Amazo
because they wanted to tell the story of him
fulfilling his programming. I'm not entirely
sure it was necessary though. Why did they
need Amazo? who I wasn't even aware was filled
in on the frequency tower schematics or anything
like that or what he had to do with that. Like,
Iris and Flash could have built that tower
themselves. Probably, it probably would have
taken them a lot longer to do it without Amazo,
considering they're not engineers and Amazo
is a super intelligent AI. You could argue
that he wasn't necessary to the story, but I
actually really like that they were able to
introduce him again as the threat that resulted
in the formation of the League. but also coming
full circle to have him be the one that helps
save humanity at the end of the movie. It's
just good writing. And with that said, let's
move on to our story highlights.
The film begins with Barry Allen, the Flash,
running through the time stream, observing
himself on the night he got his powers in a
lab accident and met his future wife, Iris
West. Barry time trips farther along the time
stream to when he and Superman first encountered
the energy-stealing android villain, Amazo,
created by Dr. Anthony Ivo for LexCorp. When
Flash and Superman become too weak to face Amazo,
Green Arrow comes to their rescue. and he and
Flash take Superman to the home of Bruce Wayne
on Halloween night to recover. Now remember
when we were talking about the post credits
scene of Batman the Long Halloween Part 2 and
we were like, what? Flash and Green Arrow? What
does that mean? That was a horrible ending.
Well now we see how that scene came about. Barry
time trips to when he and Iris meet a destitute
John Constantine who is responsible for some
of Flash's time trips. Barry then travels to
when he first meets Dick Grayson and encourages
Bruce Wayne to foster him. We then jump back
in time to when Superman is recovering in the
Batcave before Flash, Superman, Batman, and
Green Arrow decide to form a team to face a
mezzo that includes Vixen and Martian Manhunter.
When they try to recruit the Green Lantern Hale
Jordan, Hale rejects the team and Constantine
appears again telling the Flash that he must
bear witness before sending him to the parallel
universe of Earth 3. Hal Jordan was kind of
a dick throughout the entire tomorrow verse,
right? Even in the Green Lantern Beware My Power
movie, he became Parallax and was evil and
shit, you know? And here he was just like, I'm
already part of a team, screw you guys. It
was nice to see Jon Stewart get his due as a
character though, within this universe. I like
that the focus was on him as the resident Green
Lantern. Yeah, I'm sure a lot of fans also
liked at the very end of the film. during Barry
and Iris' wedding when Jon Stewart and Hawke
Girl ended up dancing together. Because that
of course goes back to the Bruce Tim verse,
or whatever that's called. That's called the
DCAU, which incorporates Batman the Animated
Series, Superman the Animated Series, and Justice
League. And Justice League Unlimited. Now after
encountering Johnny Quick and the Crime Syndicate,
Flash realizes that he's in a new universe
before getting pummeled by its evil doppelganger
version of the Justice League, the Crime Syndicate.
Flash trips back to his universe when he and
his allies announce the Justice League team
to the world, just before they're attacked by
Amazo and Lex Luthor, the latter of whom is
wearing a mech suit. During the battle, Amazo
uses the speed he's absorbed from the Flash
to have a conversation with the speedster with
time at a near standstill, explaining that
he was programmed to extend human life, but
that Lex Luthor had corrupted his programming.
but accidentally time trips back to Earth 3
instead. While on Earth 3, Flash discovers
that it's ruled by evil counterparts to the
heroes of his world, and the Crime Syndicate
learns of the potential for other Earths and
parallel universes that they can conquer. Flash
also learns that sharing the Speed Force with
the evil Speedster Johnny Quick prevents him
from gaining enough speed to return to his universe.
However, the decrepit Constantine appears and
warns the Syndicate, that their universe is
about to be destroyed. Flash time trips back
to his universe on the day of his wedding when
he warns Iris that something major is going
to happen but also promises that no matter what
they will grow old together. Time tripping
back to the past, the Flash finds Dr. Ivo at
LexCorp learning that Ivo created a mezzo using
alien technology with the intention of curing
Kiss Hutchinson-Gilford syndrome which caused
Ivo to age rapidly. As the Flash races Ivo back
to the Justice League's battle with the Meizou,
Flash time trips back to his time on Earth 3.
At this point in the story, I'm wondering what
the point of everything is, because it's just
the nature of the narrative device of time
skipping. It's really hard to make heads or
tails of not just what's going on, but why
things are happening. You know, it's easy to
assume in films like these that it's all going
to come together at the end, like the movie
Memento. But it definitely feels like the movie
starts to drag at some points because you don't
quite know where it's going. Actually, when
I was watching this film for the first time,
the whole movie felt very quick to me. Like
everything was happening at such a rapid pace
that by the time the movie was over, I was
like, really? That was 90 minutes? But yeah,
it was. I had the opposite experience. Really?
Yeah, but halfway through the movie, I was like,
shouldn't this thing be over by now? And then
I checked the time code and realized it was
only halfway done. Geez. It's strange that
we experience time differently while watching
this movie. Honestly, I don't think you could
think this movie was slow. Like, I can get like
being confused by what's going on, because
there certainly was a time towards the beginning
of the film where I didn't realize what was
going on either. But I caught on pretty quick
and it was, you know, just enjoying the ride.
Maybe that's the difference. I enjoy rides.
You don't apparently. Yeah, you get motion
sick. There you go. Now on Earth 3, Flash watches
as the crime syndicate proves to be incapable
of managing the turmoil caused by violent storms
across the planet. When Flash asks how Constantine
is appearing in different universes, Constantine
explains that he and Flash are guilty of a
heinous act. We time trip back in time to the
Justice League's battle with the Mezzo. and
the League members fall one by one. With Amazo
and Lex nearly victorious, Flash arrives with
Ivo, who asks Amazo to use the metahuman energy
he absorbed to cure him. Amazo's attempt to
do so fails, and Ivo dies. With his primary
objective made obsolete, the shocked Amazo
deduces that Lex is the one who inflicted Ivo
with the disease. Amazo destroys Lex's mech
suit. though Flash stops Amazo before he can
kill his former ally. Once Lex is apprehended
by the authorities, it's revealed that the formation
of the Justice League was a ruse to draw out
Amazo, but the heroes decide to make the League
a reality after all. Am I the only one that
thought that Batman maybe had a point in his
approach? You know, clear all the innocent
civilians out, but then just bomb the hell out
of Lex Luthor. Everybody was like, no, you
can't do it. You can't bomb the city. But it's
like this guy's super powerful. You clearly
can't let a mezzo steal Superman's powers because
that's worse than a bomb. So I don't know why
they were getting all up. Batman's asked for.
Well, I mean, Flash ultimately proved that
he had a better solution. Yeah. But like, I
don't know, the other heroes were just annoying
me. You're on the wrong side of history there.
Literally. Yeah. Time tripping ahead in the
timeline. We see an older Barry and Iris wake
up to celebrate the anniversary of the first
day they met, before we trip back to the day
of their wedding, which is interrupted by Harbinger,
who is recruiting heroes for the Monitor to
save the multiverse. On the Monitor's ship
outside of space-time, heroes from across the
multiverse and time begin appearing, including
Wonder Woman, Robin, Huntress, Dr. Light, and
Psycho Pirates, among others. Harbinger reveals,
that she is actually Supergirl to the future
hero Dawnstar of the Legion of Superheroes.
The Monitor arrives and reveals to the heroes
that a wave of antimatter is ripping through
the multiverse, destroying entire universes,
and that they have been brought together to
stop it. Barry time trips to the future when
an elderly version of himself and Iris continue
to work on a mysterious project. Before Barry
trips again to Earth 3, where he witnesses
the antimatter wave begin to erase that universe.
Tripping back to the monitor ship, the flash
reveals that the monitor is telling the truth
and that the threat of the antimatter wave
is real. Did you get the feeling when Harbinger
showed up in the movie that finally they're
getting to the story of Crisis on Infinite Earths?
Like, it seemed a little bit late within the
runtime to start introducing those elements,
right? Honestly, I wasn't sure how- the formation
of the League was going to tie into the crisis.
So I actually wasn't thinking that. As I mentioned
earlier, there are like three distinct sort
of conflicts going on throughout the course
of this movie. One is a mezzo, one is the crime
syndicate, and one is the antimatter wave.
It's true that the antimatter wave storyline
doesn't really begin until halfway through
the film. But again, everything was just moving
so fast that it didn't feel like the halfway
point to me. This is the first part of a trilogy.
It's not like they were going to go through
the entire crisis storyline just in this movie.
I figured it was going to be delayed. I figured
there was going to be some setup. Well, fine.
As Earth 3 is entirely destroyed by the wave,
the death of Johnny Quick allows Flash to gain
enough speed force to return to his universe.
In the future, It's revealed that Amazo is helping
the elderly Barry and Iris on their project.
On the monitor ship, the heroes decide to split
into two teams. One to determine a solution
and one to build it. During their brainstorm
session, Flash reveals that absorbing the entirety
of the speed force of the Earth 3 universe upon
its demise knocked him out of his linear time
experience. When the heroes learn that the Flash
is able to traverse the multiverse, by vibrating
into different planes of existence, they determine
that colossal tuning fork towers built on their
earths could vibrate their universes to a state
of intangibility when the wave strikes. As
the heroes begin building the towers, it's revealed
that the elderly Barry, Iris, and Amazo are
working on building one of those towers. Now
the reason they have to do that is because
the flash needs to slow down time due to the
wave moving quicker. which was not foreseen
by the heroes when they were building the towers.
But the story never reveals why the wave moved
quicker all of a sudden. I'm assuming that they're
going to touch on that in later films. Yes,
I got the implication that this whole thing
is a product of the monitor based on his conversation
with the specter that we'll talk about later
on. But I could be wrong. There still could
be an anti-monitor. Who was the villain of the
crisis story in the comics? Yes, exactly. As
the heroes build, they're shocked to discover
the wave has arrived ahead of schedule. The
Flash encounters Constantine, who tells him
to run to Iris. With Iris in his arms, the
Flash imbues her with enough speed force energy
that the two are able to move with time essentially
at a standstill, allowing them to complete the
construction of the tower over the span of
relative decades. As the anti-manager wave slowly
approaches, The elderly Iris dies from old
age, just as they finish work on the tower.
As the elderly Barry charges up the tower by
running on a power generating turbine, the heroes
experiencing time normally watch as the tower
is constructed at rapid speed before them just
as the wave hits. Though the tower is destroyed
as the wave passes over, the tower's frequency
was successfully transmitted throughout the
multiverse. saving countless Earths. Infinite
Earths? Maybe not infinite, but a whole hell
of a lot. I'm calling bullshit on the marketing.
Ha ha ha. The Spectre meets with the Monitor,
who has determined that his experiment was a
success, though he was doubtful it would be.
The Spectre then visits the elderly Barry and
reveals that a mezzo now destroyed knew he
had succeeded in his mission to extend human
life in his last moment. The specter also reveals
that though he is an agent of God's wrath, Barry
has atoned for his responsibility in helping
cause the events that had transpired. As the
Speed Force absorbs Barry into it, in his final
moments he's able to warn his younger self the
day of his accident and Bruce Wayne and Warlord
that they must go back to before the beginning.
We see that on the day of Barry's and Iris's
wedding, Harbinger brought all of the heroes
of this world to celebrate together with them
before embarking on the monitor's mission to
save the multiverse. In the final scene, as
the heroes celebrate on the monitor's ship,
we see that their actions have affected the
timeline and characters from the future such
as Don Star and Brainiac 5 begin to disappear.
And that's why it's interesting that Batman
Beyond is in the trailer for the next film.
I didn't make the connection that it was just
characters from the future that were blipping,
and it looked like they were being blipped.
I thought it was just like random characters.
Oh really? You probably were like, what an Infinity
War ripoff. Right. But I guess it was made
clear by what Brainiac 5 told Supergirl at the
very end. I thought it was a very strange ending
though. Considering that the main character
for the whole film was the Flash, we didn't
end with the Flash. The story seemed to kick
over to Supergirl at that point, which makes
me feel like this scene is also going to be
the beginning to part 2. We did end with the
Flash though. He died. He merged with the Speed
Force. No, the very last shot of this movie
was Brainiac 5 disappearing. Right, I know,
but that's just set up for the next film. You
were saying that you were surprised it didn't
end with the Flash. And I'm saying, what the
fuck, of course they would set up the next movie,
it's a fucking trilogy. But they didn't need
to. These final moments seem to stem more out
of their need to set up a cliffhanger than
anything else. It just didn't feel as satisfying
an ending as if they had just chose to end
with The Flash. It's part one of a fucking trilogy,
it doesn't need to be satisfying. It should
set up the next film, it should make you eager
for the continued storyline. I don't think
they needed to end it with just The Flash. I'm
actually pretty intrigued. by how they ended
it because it continues the conflict, right?
There's more story to be told. What threw me
at the end of this, actually, was the whole
Bruce Wayne on Skartaris scene, because I was
under the impression that was just a hallucination
induced by War World. And I'm wondering if
they're implying that, actually, that was a
real universe. That wouldn't make sense, because
War World doesn't have time travel. portal capabilities.
No, it did. Actually, they said in the Warworld
film that Mongol had been scouring the multiverse
on Warworld. So, you're saying that Wonder
Woman actually went to the Wild West and Superman
actually went to the 1950s. I mean, I think
that's what this implies. No, I don't think
so. Okay, I mean, why not? Why not? I guess
we'll find out in future films. Again, we have
no idea when they're coming, but I'm looking
forward to them. because this film was really
good in my opinion. Its unconventional narrative
structure ultimately pays off as its emotional
ending sets up the promise of a fascinating
conclusion to this animated universe. The film
wasn't perfect and I know it's going to put
off a lot of people, so I'm giving it 3.5 out
of 5 stars. A fresh rating on Rotten Tomatoes.
And actually to your credit Joseph, you had
to talk me down from giving it 4 stars. It's
definitely not a four star film. It's going
to be divisive. I think it raises a lot of
questions while you're watching it and can be
frustrating, which is not a great movie going
experience. I think what it tried to do is better
in concept than what it did in practice. As
can be said for the rest of the Tomorrowverse.
Oh, for sure. Yeah, I think at least each concept
that each movie set up in the Tomorrowverse
had potential. And honestly, the best thing
that you can say about Crisis Part One is that
the potential stories that it has set up for
parts two and part three look to be epic as
hell. And I really hope that the tomorrow verse
is able to stick this landing and end in a great
way. Yeah, I hope they will. You know, honestly,
if they take more bold swings like what they
did here, I'm all for it, honestly. And I just
have to appreciate the ambition it took to do
something like crisis part one, because not
only did it tell a really good story. unconventional
as it was. They also showed a little bit of
genius when it came to how they're adapting
this crisis story. But that does it for this
review. Let us know what you thought about the
movie by writing to us at dynamicduelpodcast
at gmail.com or by visiting us on Instagram,
which you can find a link to in our show notes
or by visiting our website dynamicduel.com.
And on our site, you could also find a link
to our Patreon page where you can join our dynamic
two O tier and chat with us and fellow listeners.
our Fantastic Four tier, which gets you bonus
content each month, our X-Force tier that makes
you an executive producer of this podcast, or
our newest tier that lets you join our Dynamike
Podcast Network. Please don't forget to rate
the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser,
or on our website. Our next episode is going
to be another review. We're going to discuss
season one of the Disney Plus Marvel television
series Echo. Also a divisive series, but you'll
get our thoughts on it next week. But that does
it for this episode, we want to give a big
thanks to our executive producers Ken Johnson,
John Storosky, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Balcom,
Miggy Mathengian, Brandon Estregard, Nathaniel
Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Nick Abonto, Austin Wiselowski,
AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Adam Spies, Andrew
Shunk, and Dean Mielewski for helping make
this podcast possible. And we'll talk to you
guys next week. Up up and away, true believers.
More like Crisis of Infinite Girth, Amorite.