This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
Hi, Merry Christmas, everybody. Welcome to the
Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the superiority
between Marvel and DC by comparing their characters
in stat-based battle simulations. I'm Johnny
DC. And I'm his twin brother, Marvelous Joe.
Happy holidays. And in this Christmas charity
duel episode, we are going to find out who
is going to win between Batman's dog, Ace the
Bat Hound, and Deadpool's dog, or just... another
version of Deadpool, but it's dogpool. You could
definitely call him Deadpool's dog. He definitely
belongs to the Deadpool core. But yeah, we call
this a charity duel because we are bringing
attention to a charity that we donate to every
year. This year it's going to be Stand Up to
Cancer Guys. And the way you could help us donate
is by making a purchase at our shop at dynamicduel.com
and clicking the store link at the top of the
nav. We're donating 10% of all the proceeds
from the months of November and December to
Stand Up to Cancer. So if you can, Please support
our show and support a great cause. Yeah, usually
this time of year when we do our charity episode,
we typically pit animals against each other.
Last year, of course, we did Alfred versus
Jarvis, but in previous charity duels, we've
pit characters like Rocket Raccoon and the
Green Lantern Chip against each other, as well
as Crypto and Throg. Yeah, we did Howard the
Duck versus Detective Chimp. I know we did Hit
Monkey versus Gleek the Wonder Monkey. Yeah,
we did What's It versus Spider-Ham. That was
a fun one. What else have we done? We've literally
done one each year that this podcast has been
around since 2016. There's a lot of them, definitely
check them out. Yeah, before we get into that
duel, we're gonna break down the latest comic
book movie news to come out this past week,
including the motherfucking Superman official
teaser trailer. It's dope! We're gonna talk
about how dope it is. Later on, as always,
we list our segment times in our episode description,
so feel free to check out the show notes if
you want to skip ahead to a particular topic.
Our artificially intelligent duel simulator
AJ9K has a quick message for our listeners,
so listen up. Why hello there, do you want
even more from this podcast? Then become a part
of the dynamic duel community on Patreon, where
you can choose from three tiers. The dynamic
two-o tier gives you access to our Discord
chat server. The fantastic four tier gives you
two bonus episodes each month, and the X-Force
tier makes you an executive producer of this
show. Lastly, the Dyna Mike Podcast Network
tier lets you create your own podcast using
this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe
will help you develop your show, provide graphic
support and consultation, and get you simulation
results. Pitch the twins your ideas via email
at dyna Check it out at patreon.com slash dynamicduel.
Pip pip cheerio. Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone
who supports the podcast. A huge thank you
to our new executive producer Oscar Galvez.
Oscar, thanks for being a patron and we look
forward to your input in determining the content
of this show. Yes Oscar, thank you very much.
Guys, be sure to tune into the other shows in
the DynaMic Podcast Network this week, including
Max Destruction, which pits your favorite action
heroes from film and television against each
other. This week hosts Scotty and Gilly. are
releasing their Craven vs Predator episode,
just in time for Christmas. On the Cengelworld
podcast, host Zachary Hepburn speculates on
fights between fan favorite anime and manga
characters. This Thursday, Zach will reveal
who would win in a fight between Shinra from
Fire Force and Najima from Medica Box. And
I don't know if I pronounced that correctly.
Medica Box? My dick in a box? Ha ha ha. On
the console combat podcast hosts John and Dean
simulate battles between popular video game
characters. And yesterday's episode though,
they reviewed Sonic the Hedgehog 3. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com
or click the link in our show notes to listen
to all the shows in the DynaMic Podcast Network.
But with that out of the way, quick to the no
prize. A no prize is an award Marvel used to
give out to fans. Our version, the dynamic duel
no prize. is a digital award we post on Instagram
for the person that we feel gave the best answer
to our question of the week. Last week we asked,
if Avengers Doomsday is featuring an evil version
of the Earth's Mightiest Heroes, what evil
version of a character do you most hope to see
and why? And this is coming off the news that
Chris Evans is confirmed to be joining the cast
of Avengers Doomsday alongside Robert Downey
Jr. as Dr. Doom, as we've discussed before.
So the prevailing theory among fans is that
They're gonna go a Dark Avengers route where
we see like Robert Downey Jr. as Dr. Doom and
Chris Evans as an evil version of Captain America.
We got three answers. So let's go ahead and
run down our two honorable mentions as well
as the no-prize winner. Our first honorable
mention goes to Kyle who said, Hi guys, the
evil version of a character that I most want
to see in Avengers Dimpsay probably has to be
Captain Hydra. Because I think it is a really
interesting idea. to have Captain America being
controlled by Hydra and going against everything
that we think the character stands for. So I
think that'd be pretty cool. Thanks, Kyle.
Yeah, I think the prevailing theory for the
evil version of Captain America would be Hydra
Cap, the most prominent and recent example of
an evil version of Captain America. Yeah, I
remember when that comic came out and everybody
hated it. To be fair, it was pretty jarring.
It was a jarring story. Do you think Chris Evans
could pull off and- Evil Captain America, Hydra
Cap? I think an actor like him is up for the
challenge, absolutely. Yeah, it would definitely
be a different take on a character that he's
nearly exhausted on screen. And that may be
what attracted him to the role in the first
place. We'll see. But great answer, Kyle. Our
next honorable mention goes to Brandon Eschergard,
who said, If they are going to do an evil version
of the Avengers in the next movie, I definitely
want to see an evil version of Scott Lang.
I think it would be kind of interesting seeing,
like, one of the most positive characters in
the universe. Basically, be complete opposite
and flipped. And, yeah. Yeah, I don't recall
there being an evil version of Scott Link from
the comics, but there was an evil Ant-Man named
Eric O'Grady, who was an Irish shield agent
who stole one of Hank Pym's Ant-Man suits and
then used it to like stalk women and stuff like
that. He was a fucking asshole. And I think
it would actually be kind of funny to see Paul
Rudd pull off that type of role. Actually,
I think I'd be more interested in seeing an
evil version of Hank Pym. Maybe like fused
with Ultron? That'd be wild. Well, that would
be Michael Douglas in the role. Right, exactly.
I know, I'd rather see an evil Paul Rudd just
because I think there's a whimsy to that. Like
a kind of lightheartedness. I don't need them
necessarily to go as dark with the character
of Ant-Man because Ant-Man is so beloved, you
know? I think it would be weird considering
the tone of the Ant-Man franchise to go fully
evil. I think it'd be better to see Paul Rudd
as like an Irish hooligan kind of thing. That
sounds awful. Do not like that take. Great
answer, Brandon. We want to give a quick shout
out to Alex, who called to tell us about the
data that he's been compiling about all of our
duels. Thank you very much for reaching out.
But the winner of this week's Snow Prize goes
to Mike Williams, who said. Hi guys, Mike Williams
here. Instead of going in the direction of darkest
version of the Avengers, I'd like to see them
introduce the Squadron Supreme or maybe even
Norman Osborn. Dark Avengers give them some
good antagonists to fight against instead of
turning Regular Avengers into the dark versions.
Anyway, that's my opinion. I think that's a
great opinion I didn't even think about that
a lot of the prevailing ideas out there are
about the Dark Avengers considering Chris Evans
return But what if he's not playing a dark version
of Captain America? What if he's playing a
dark version of Superman himself Hyperion the
Marvel Comics character? I would be really
surprised if they're going that route considering
the fact that they're gonna have the sentry
in the upcoming Thunderbolts movie Who's already
kind of like a dark-ish version of Superman
plus we had Icarus and Eternals who was like
an evil Superman I don't know if they would
retread that water although it is intriguing
to me that Chris Evans would not be playing
a Version of Captain America. They could go
that route. He could literally be anyone considering
that it's not like RDJ is playing Tony Stark
That's true. That's very villain. At the end
of the day, we have no idea where they're going
with the plot for Avengers Doomsday, but I'm
highly anticipating the reveal of who Chris
Evans will be playing. If they do bring in
Squadron Supreme, not going to lie, at this
point, I would not hate it if they brought
in Zack Snyder's Justice League cast. Henry
Cavill as Hyperion. And Ben Affleck as Nighthawk
and Gal Gadot as Power Princess. That would
be awesome. Even get Ezra Miller in there.
It would be the Marvel and DC movie that we'll
never get. Exactly, exactly. So congrats to
Mike Williams for winning this week's No Prize.
If you the listener want a shot at winning
your own No Prize, stay tuned to later on this
episode when we'll be asking another Question
of the Week. And now that that's done, on to
the news.
Okay, so this past week, Warner Brothers unveiled
the first official teaser trailer for the first
official movie within the new DC Universe, Superman.
Now, there has probably not been a trailer
that I have been more looking forward to and
most apprehensive about in the eight years
that we've been doing this podcast. Because
it was going to set the tone. for a film that
was likely going to set the tone for the rest
of DC's films going forward. I really did not
have too many expectations for this trailer.
There was nothing really specific that I wanted
to see except for maybe Superman flying, but
I was hoping that it was going to capture a
specific tone that I think a lot of people complained
that the Snyder films did not have, and that
was one of hope. So in that regard, when I finished
watching this trailer for the first time, I
was unbelievably happy. And I still am. I love
this trailer. I love the precedent that it's
setting for James Gunn's universe as a whole.
I always knew he was a really talented filmmaker,
particularly when it comes to story and heartfelt
stories at that, considering what he did in
the Marvel universe with the Guardians of the
Galaxy films, it looks to me initially that
he really gets the character. And I think he's
going to give us a version of the character
that we haven't seen in a really long time.
So in what way does this new teaser trailer
evoke the theme of hope to you that the previous
franchise did not? Well, I didn't know that
the previous franchises were not necessarily
going to inspire hope, as it were. I think
the first two acts of Man of Steel were really
good. I know Zack Snyder lost a lot of people
with the whole neck snap thing. I'd be really
surprised if they did anything like that in
this film. Especially considering that James
Gunn and Peter Safran, the heads of DC, have
been talking about how nice of a guy this Superman
is. But, you know, even more than that, it
definitely looks like we're getting a Superman
that is different from previous versions in
that, hey, the guy can bleed. He's not this
unrelatable figure that's invulnerable and
everything comes so easy to him because he's
so powerful. From the opening shot of this
trailer, we see him broken and bleeding. And
this isn't something we ever saw from Henry
Cavill's Superman, really, even when he was
being killed by Doomsday or being beaten up
by Batman. Just hearing him breathing in this
opening scene was pretty powerful, I thought.
And to have that juxtaposed with the shots of
him as Clark Kent, whether it's in Metropolis
at the Daily Planet. or on the Smallville farm
with his father. It just gave this very human
feeling to him. And he's definitely approaching
Clark Kent differently from his Superman, which
is something that Henry Cavill never did. And
I know that was another big criticism of his
performance. If we're comparing Corn Sweat to
Cavill, I will say that my big impression from
this teaser was that Corn Sweat doesn't have
nearly the presence that Cavill does. And I
think general audiences are gonna take note.
Define presence. Well, Corn Sweat, definitely
seems much more human. Like I think you were
talking about how he seems much more vulnerable.
That's definitely the case. He seems less iconic
than the icon that is Superman. And so therefore
it kind of feels like he seems like a lesser
Superman, you could say, than Cavill's very,
you know, strong striking image that you see
when you see Cavill in the suit. Yeah, I mean,
I would agree with that. I don't think that's
necessarily a bad thing. I think Zack Snyder's
and Henry Cavill's Superman was very much this
like supermodel bodybuilder type Superman,
whereas David Cornsweat is not that. Although
apparently he's taller and heavier than Henry
Cavill was when he played Superman, which is
wild to me. Yeah, the dude's suit is doing
him no favors though. I'll say that. It looks
like pajamas. What's interesting was that James
Gunn revealed recently that his take on the
suit was heavily inspired by comments made
by David Corrin Sweat about wanting to appeal
to younger, not even audiences, but just in-world
younger smaller children because he didn't want
to scare them with all of his power and strength.
He wanted to look like a classic wrestler of
sorts, even you know having the trunks on the
outside. And I actually liked that approach.
I liked that they took that approach with this
version of the suit. Seeing it in live action,
I still think it works. I thought it looked
great in the set photos. I know there's still
some people who have a problem with it, but
I am not one of those people. I mean, it moves
well in the action shots. When you see him
saving the girl from the explosion or you see
him punching his way out of that glass cube.
Yeah, it all looks great. Oh yeah, totally.
You know what? One thing we haven't really
seen in a Superman from the past was dynamic
hair. And I didn't realize until this trailer
how much that lends to like. the speed and movement
of the character, whether he's flying through
the sky, whether he's saving that young girl.
It's like all the other Superman have had their
hair like hair sprayed and plastered to their
head. Just like a ton of super gel, apparently.
Not so with David Corn sweat. Even when he was
Clark Kent, I thought it was gonna look so
much worse than it actually did when it was
being filmed. Nah, I don't like his look as
Clark Kent at all. No, I thought he was perfect
as Clark Kent. Even when he was like looking
back at like Lois and then quickly looked away.
It was a take on Clark Kent that we haven't
seen on screen in a while. And I loved it. You
know what else I loved? The look of Crypto.
I am so excited that Crypto is in this movie.
Of course, we saw Crypto in the League of Superpets
animated film, but he looks so much cuter here.
I just love the little guy. I just want to
come a hug. Yeah, in League of Superpets, he
was like a white golden lab. Something like
that. Maybe. But here, I don't know what he
looks like. He looks like a scraggly white
mutt. Yeah, almost like a terrier type look.
Definitely not a purebred, but you know, he's
pure white. He looks fantastic. I can't tell
you how excited I got when Superman started
whistling, because I knew Krypto was in the
movie. I wasn't sure if we were gonna get a
shot of him in this trailer. When he was whistling,
I was like, oh shit, he's calling Krypto. And
then just to see him running through the snow,
it was super cute. I loved it. There's a lot
of endearing things about Superman. in this
movie, almost like in a tricky kind of way,
because, you know, in film, there's ways to
kind of cheat the audience so that it likes
characters that aren't necessarily likeable.
Superman's a likeable character. But when you
add things like, oh, he has a dog and oh, he's
saving children and stuff like that, it just
endears them to the audience even more. They're
really trying to appeal to the audiences with
this teaser trailer right out the bat.
He saves children. He's the nice guy. Yeah,
and dude, oh man, my favorite part of the trailer,
the one that literally had my eyes watering,
was when the little boy in that foreign conflict
was raising the Superman flag and calling on
Superman. Oh man, that was a great scene. I
don't know why that impacted me so much, but
it did. I loved it. The idea that this is a
Superman that little kids would call to and
you sort of got a little bit of that. with
Zack Snyder in Mexico saving kids from a burning
building. But that felt a little bit more weird
because Zack Snyder played it up as like almost
worship. Here, this doesn't seem to be the
case. The little kid just needs a hero. We,
of course, get to see a lot of other side characters
besides crypto in this trailer, including Lex
Luthor, including Lois Lane, played by Nicholas
Holt and Rachel Brosnahan, respectively. And
they look like they're going to crush it. Like
literally the best versions of Lex Luthor and
Lo Slane that we've seen on screen in my opinion.
And I really liked Kevin Spacey's look for Lex
Luthor, but his plan was stupid. I'm hoping
that Nicholas Holtz crushes it though. He just
looks like an angry dude. His like sharp features
as well I think lend themselves pretty good
to a character like Lex Luthor who started
off as like this mad scientist type villain.
And I guess still is. What do you think of
the other heroes in this teaser? The terrifics
like Green Lantern, Mr. Terrific, Hawk Girl,
and Metamorpho. Metamorpho was strange. I didn't
even realize that was Metamorpho until like
the third time I watched this trailer, like
the third of a hundred times that I've watched
this trailer. Hawk Girl looks awesome, so does
Mr. Terrific. Nathan Fillion's Guy Gardner
looks pretty silly. I think he looks worse actually
being filmed than he did in the set photos.
I thought he actually looked cool. in those,
but he looks really goofy here. But I guess
Guy Gardner is supposed to. What was more interesting
to me in this trailer was that they showed
Superman in stag industries. I almost wonder
if the Terrifix are affiliated with stag industries
somehow. I don't even know if they're called
the Terrifix. They might be the Justice League.
We don't know. I do have to say I was excited
to see not only the crystalline structure of
the Fortress of Solitude, because that's another
thing that I've been missing for a while, but
also the number of Kaiju. that apparently attack
Metropolis in this movie. There's the giant
dragon, there's the giant eyeball, something's
knocking over a huge building. I have this
theory so far because we don't know anything
about the story. But my guess is actually that
maybe Lex Luthor breaks into the Fortress of
Solitude and unleashes Superman's like alien
zoo and the monsters just attack Metropolis
and that's why people seem to hate Superman
and are throwing cans at his head and stuff
like that. It's not a bad theory. It's probably
wrong, but I wouldn't hate that idea. The floating
laser eye does still strike me as interesting.
This is something we saw in the very first official
image released of David Corn sweat in the Superman
suit when he's putting on his boots. He still
does not seem to be terribly concerned by the
floating eyeball in the sky, lasering buildings,
and I'm not sure why. Sometimes you just got
to make out with your girlfriend before you
can go save the day. Priorities. Got to have
them. Like I said at the beginning of this discussion.
Overall, this trailer has me really looking
forward to not only this next Superman film,
which I think James Gunn is going to crush,
but also the upcoming DCU. It's weird that this
trailer is about a character who's supposed
to inspire hope. And I feel like I have more
hope now than I've had in a really long time.
As a DC fan? Yes, because, you know, with the
whole Snyder versus DeBacle thing with the
Justice League film. Since Joss Whedon took
that over and just with all the studio interference,
it feels like we haven't really had a good clear
direction for Superman on film, which we absolutely
should because he's the flagship character of
DC. And I'm pretty confident that now we do.
You know, my impression from this teaser is
that this Superman movie is going to be the
that movie was for the Marvel Universe. I think
the comparisons that were made between Spider-Man
Homecoming and the amazing Spider-Man franchise
will be the same ones that are made between
this new Superman franchise and the Man of Steel
franchise. You know, there are still a lot
of fans out there of Andrew Garfield, and in
many ways, yeah, he looks and acts a lot more
like the comic book version of Peter Parker
than Tom Holland does. But the Spider-Man Home
franchise was exactly what the MCU needed. It's
exactly what the cinematic character of Spider-Man
needed to be at the time. It was still a taste
of the familiar. You know, it was like the
second time that the franchise had been rebooted
within the decade. But audiences didn't mind
that as much because the fans were finally getting
what they wanted. Yeah, and it's like Homecoming
wasn't an origin story in the same way that
the Superman movie is not going to be an origin
story, allegedly. Although it does look like
this may be the time when Lois Lane learns
that Clark can't is Superman, because we see
her kissing both in this trailer. So it's still
exciting. Again, I love this trailer and I'm
really curious to hear how much you guys loved
this trailer and that brings us to our question
of the week.
On a scale of 1 to 10, how excited has this
teaser trailer made you for James Gunn's DCU
and why? Yeah, why is it 10? Record your answer
at dynamicduel.com by clicking on the red microphone
button in the bottom right hand corner of the
screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long, and don't forget to leave your name in
case we include you on the podcast. We'll pick
our favorite answer and award that person a
dynamic duel no prize that we'll post to Instagram.
Be sure to answer before- December 28th.
But that does it for the news for this episode,
now let's move on to the main event where we
find out who will win in a showdown between
Batman's dog Ace the Bat Hound and Deadpool's
dog Dogpool.
All right, Ace the Bat Hound versus Dogpool.
Of course, we saw Dogpool earlier this year
in the Deadpool and Wolverine film. And we saw
Ace actually last year in the Super Pets film.
Although Ace is very different in the comics
than he was in that movie. Yeah, there've been
a lot of different versions of Ace the Bat Hound,
which makes me think that Ace keeps dying and
then Batman keeps getting a new dog and calling
him Ace. Cause there's been an English Mastiff
version of Ace. a Doberman Pinscher version
of Ace, a Great Dane version of Ace, a German
Shepherd version of Ace, like a lot of fucking
Aces. Hey, man, there's four Aces in a deck.
It's all right. Whereas Docpul, I guess his
breed has somewhat changed during the course
of the comics too. Or maybe it hasn't changed.
He's just gotten less mangy looking because
when he first came out in the comics, the dog
looked freaking weird, man. He looked like
a mangy brown mutt. And in the comics now, he's
a little bit more clean cut. Although in the
movie, he was a Mexican hairless dog, which
I don't know why they did that, but I guess
it made sense for the film. And that hasn't
made its way into the comics? Oh no, MCU version
of Dogpool has definitely made his way into
the Dogpool comics, just due to the fourth
wall breaking nature of the Dogpool comics.
And yeah, they've teamed up and fought, but
yeah, the MCU version of Dogpool is a separate
entity than the comic book version of Dogpool.
So if you're picturing this character in your
head, Don't picture the Mexican hairless dog,
just picture a brown mangy mutt who looks like
he's been hit by a car but wearing a Deadpool
outfit. Here's the thing though, Jonathan, when
we speculate on how this fight would go, do
you really want to talk about how these dogs
would essentially tear each other apart like
in an actual dog fight? Not really. Yeah, I
don't want to either. So the way we're gonna
approach this duel is a little bit different
just for the purpose of not looking like animal
cruelty assholes. Instead of a fight, these
dogs are going to go head to head against each
other in a holiday dog show. And we have judges
on standby to judge both of these dogs in their
respective stat categories. And they're going
to be competing in events showing off their
skills. And I think it'll be a lot of fun. Yes,
but of course, the winner is still going to
be determined by simulations. So to explain
our methodology behind our duels, let's go
to our sentient duel simulator, Alfred Jarvis
9000. AJ9K, tell our listeners how you go about
determining a winner. in our duel matchups.
Additional stat categories are included such
as range, damage potential, versatility and
perception in order to create a more detailed
and accurate simulation. The results of the
1000 simulations provide a percentage of wins
for each character. The contestant with the
higher percentage is declared the victor as
they have a higher probability to win any given
battle. In an equitable pairing, neither character
should win 100% of the matches. The comic book
stories have shown that there's even a way for
Batman to defeat Superman. So the confidence
rate of my method falls in line with the precedents
that have been established in the source material.
My mathematical simulations are without subjectivity
or bias. Feats are not the sole consideration,
nor are fan votes tabulated for determination
of the winner. Thanks AJ9K. Before we run the
simulations though, we like to break down each
character's histories and abilities before
improvising a scenario on how we imagine one
of the 1000 simulations would play out beat
for beat. And it's my turn to go first with
the DC character. So let me tell you all about
Ace the Bat-Hound. Now Ace began as a German
Shepherd belonging to an engraver named John
Wilker. When Wilker was kidnapped by a gang
of counterfeiters, Ace escaped captivity and
was found by Batman and Robin. After posting
numerous lost dog signs around town with his
contact info, Bruce Wayne decided to fashion
a simple hooded mask to hide Ace's identity
so that no one would connect the dog to Batman.
when he used Ace to help find Wilker. Using
Ace's keen sense of smell, Batman and Robin
tracked down the dog's owner and apprehended
the gang. Ace earned the nickname Bat-Hound
after helping capture one of the criminals.
You can learn more about Batman and Robin in
our Batman vs. Moon Knight and Nightwing vs.
Daredevil duel episodes. Though initially returned
to Wilker, Ace's owner later took a job that
made caring for the dog impossible. leaving
Ace in Bruce Wayne's custody. Unaware of Bruce's
secret identity, Wilker assumed Ace had simply
found a good home. Ace became a loyal ally
to Batman and Robin, assisting them on cases
and even being equipped with a radio caller
for tracking. While initially trained for crime
fighting, Ace also provided Bruce Wayne companionship
during difficult times. However, Ace eventually
faded from active use as Batman focused on
other methods to combat crime. Ace re-emerged
years later as a large mastiff, adopted by
Bruce Wayne after the dog's original owner,
a blind Native American man named Black Wolf,
passed away. This Ace was fiercely loyal, remaining
in the Batcave alongside Harold, Bruce Wayne's
mute genius mechanic. During the time when Jean-Paul
Valley, aka Asriel, temporarily replaced Bruce
as Batman, Ace sensed something was amiss and
kept his distance. You can learn more about
Azrael in our Azrael vs. Blade episode. Ace
remained a quiet but consistent presence in
Wayne Manor and the Batcave until his disappearance
during the events of No Man's Land when an
earthquake devastated Gotham City. Years later,
another Ace was introduced, a German Shepherd
and former guide dog rescued by Bruce Wayne
following his owner's death. The dog was never
explicitly named Ace the Bat Hound in continuity,
but it maintained a similar role as a loyal
companion. In post-Flashpoint continuity, Bruce
bought an emotional support Great Dane named
Titus for his son Damien, though Titus didn't
partake in adventures much as he wasn't trained
for it. It wouldn't be until several years later
when Batman met a new, vicious ace, a German
Shepherd taken in as a puppy by the Joker after
killing its owner, a man in witness protection
who had witnessed one of Joker's murders. Unsure
whether to keep or kill the pup? Joker pulled
out a deck of cards to gamble its life. Joker
drew the king, followed by an ace, meaning
the dog got to live, and its name stuck with
him. Ace became one of several dogs outfitted
with playing card-themed masks and trained as
attack dogs. Ace, forced to wear the Ace of
Spades mask, became the pack leader. The Joker
later abandoned the dogs in a pit, leading
them to turn on each other out of desperation.
Ace was the sole survivor. when Batman and
Commissioner Gordon discovered the scene. Initially
considered irredeemable due to his aggression,
Ace was taken in by Alfred Pennyworth after
buying the animal shelter that initially refused
to give Alfred the dog on account of the abuse
it suffered and its aggressive tendencies.
Over the course of months, Alfred trained Ace
with care and persistence, despite the dog's
frequent attempts to bite him. Alfred's determination
eventually paid off and Ace grew to trust him.
Bruce Wayne, skeptical at first, argued to Alfred
that some traumas are impossible to heal. Though
Bruce was eventually won over when Ace demonstrated
loyalty and intelligence, becoming a trusted
member of the Bat family. That Christmas, Bruce
jokingly presented Ace with a bat-shaped mask,
officially christened him Ace the Bat Hound,
and trained him as a tracker and rescue dog.
Ace's loyalty, bravery, and intelligence were
particularly evident during the mission involving
enhanced animals being used for criminal activities.
Ace, along with a group of other animals, including
a speedster turtle, a pickpocket squirrel, a
bear, and a cyborg chicken, worked together
to dismantle a criminal operation run by Dr.
Herbert Schwan, a corrupt veterinarian. Schwan
had been capturing animals and using experimental
treatments to transform them into living weapons
for Gotham's underworld. Ace quickly emerged
as the leader of the group. using his experience
and training to organize a rescue effort for
Batman. He guided the team through the defenses
of the facility holding Batman, evading traps
and confronting a dog trained specifically
for Lex Luthor, named Lix Luthor, prior to Luthor
realizing he had dog allergies. Along the way,
Ace's leadership and resourcefulness earned
the trust of his new allies, who followed his
commands despite the casualties to rescue a
captured Batman. Ace also played a pivotal
role in mentoring Hayley, also known as Bitewing,
a three-legged dog under the care of Nightwing
and Oracle. When Hayley struggled to adjust
to her new life and role, Ace offered guidance
and support, helping her navigate the challenges
of being part of a superpets team led by Crypto.
Although Hayley ultimately chose to forge her
own path apart from the team, Ace's patience
and wisdom left a lasting impression on her.
And that's Ace the Bat Hound. Abilities-wise,
Ace the Bat-Hound possesses exceptional tracking
and rescue abilities, having undergone rigorous
training to assist Batman in crime fighting
as well as search and rescue missions. As a
highly intelligent and loyal German Shepherd,
Ace is capable of understanding complex commands
and responding to cues with precision, even
in high stress situations. His tactical vest
is outfitted with a variety of tools and gadgets
to aid in missions. These include miniature
bat-shaped smoke pellets for creating distractions,
a radio communicator for staying in contact
with the bat family, a small med kit for emergency
first aid, a flashlight for low visibility
environments, and a collapsible rope for search
and rescue operations. Additionally, his vest
features reinforced armor plating, providing
ace with protection in dangerous encounters.
Ace's physical prowess includes enhanced speed,
strength, and agility. for a dog of his breed,
making him adept at subduing criminals and navigating
challenging terrain. His acute senses of smell
and hearing allow him to detect explosives,
track individuels, and alert Batman to potential
threats. That's Ace the Bat Hound. The most
recent version of Ace, his backstory went a
little bit more hard than I thought it would,
honestly, but it's a great origin story for
a dog that would belong to Batman. Yeah, actually
that storyline won an Eisner Award. Okay, I
could totally see that. Yeah, it's kind of heartbreaking
stuff. But you love to see animals come through
with owners who truly get them and care about
them. And it seems like Batman does considering
he's also, you know, a trauma survivor. Exactly.
Yeah, the whole notion that Batman was like,
you can't heal this dog, he's gone through too
much pain was, of course, a direct analogy
to Bruce's own pain and Alfred recognized that
he wanted to prove Bruce wrong. Is the League
of Superpets book a children's comic title kind
of in the same vein as Pet Avengers? No, it's
not an ongoing series. The times that the League
of Superpets have made appearances, they were
always called the League of Superpets. They
just appeared like in backup Batman stories
or you know like their own one-off special issues.
Gotcha. Well Dogpool's origin story beats that
out of the water. In fact, it won a Nobel Peace
Prize. Oh my gosh. Let me tell you about it.
Wade Wilson, the dog. was born astray in the
alternate dimension of Earth-10-3173. He lived
his life on the streets as a happy flea-ridden
mongrel, barking all night and chewing up shoes
he found. Eventually, however, he was rounded
up and taken to a secret lab for experimental
cosmetics testing. Evil scientists Dr. Von Braun
and his assistant Igor worked under the Mascara-X
project, aiming to develop an eye mascara that
could regenerate indefinitely. The pair submerged
Wilson in an experimental chemical vat that
painfully transformed the dog, leaving him
horribly mutated but granting him an extraordinary
healing factor. Unaware of his newfound abilities,
the scientists discarded Wilson as a failed
experiment, placing him in a garbage bag and
tossing him into a dumpster, leaving him to
die. Wade's regenerative powers soon revived
him and he escaped the trash to wander the city
for someone to love him.
Wade's despair led him to throw himself in front
of a car, seeking to end his loneliness. However,
Wade survived his attempt, and he was discovered
by a group of circus clowns passing by who
recognized his indestructible nature. They brought
him to the circus, which exploited his abilities,
branding him Deadpool the Dare Devil Dog. They
featured him in their death-defying acts, including
shooting him out of a cannon, using him as target
practice for the circus knife thrower, and
having him leap through flaming hoops. Some
people came from near and far to witness Wade's
stunts, but despite his newfound fame, the constant
cycle of death and revival weighed heavily
on him. Wade questioned his reality, his purpose,
and the true meaning of his seemingly cursed
existence. Word of the immortal stunt dog eventually
reached the cosmetic scientists who created
him, Dr. Von Braun and Igor. Seeking to recapture
their subject, they experimented on another
dog, giving him adamantium claws and naming
him Wolverine. confronted Wade at the circus,
however Wade outsmarted his rival by launching
him from the circus cannon. At this point,
Deadpool, of the primary Marvel Earth 616 appeared,
recruiting Dogpool to join the Deadpool Corps,
a band of mercenaries united to protect the
multiverse. The team, which included Lady Deadpool,
Kidpool, and Headpool, embarked on a series
of wild and dangerous missions to safeguard
reality, battling threats such as the Awareness,
the Champion, and the Grandmaster. Despite
the absurdity and peril of the core's adventures,
Doc Poole found a sense of belonging and family
among his fellow mercenaries. He especially
bonded with Kid Poole, the child version of
Deadpool. You can learn more about Deadpool
in his duel against Deathstroke. However, tragedy
stuck when an evil version of the Deadpool core,
led by the murderous Dreadpool, began hunting
and killing their counterparts across the multiverse.
As part of the resistance against them, Dogpool
journeyed to Earth-616 to warn its Deadpool
of the impending danger. In a climactic confrontation
between the good and evil Deadpool cores, Dogpool
sacrificed himself to save Deadpool by leaping
in the way of a disintegration beam. His ultimate
sacrifice left a lasting impact on Kidpool
and the rest of the core, who went on to defeat
the Dreadpool core in revenge. Though presumed
dead, Dogpool's uncanny ability to survive seemingly
anything led to his return. when he teamed
up with Catpool and Mousepool to break the fourth
wall and attack the Marvel Comics editorial
team, convincing them to give the trio their
own monthly Infinity Comics series. In his
new adventures, Dogpool went on to kill mercenaries
at his new farmhouse, steal and bury one of
Deadpool's arm bones, pee in Kat Loki's litter
box on Asgard, save Deadpool when he fell in
a well, get drunk in Boston, and help Deadpool
save Christmas. And that's his backstory. Dogpool's
main ability is to heal at an accelerated rate
through his healing factor. This allows him
to recover and regenerate from any wound he
suffers as well as make him immune to disease
and toxins and grant him increased stamina.
He's highly agile, faster than your average
human, approaching 50 miles per hour on foot,
and is strong enough to easily bring down an
enemy. He has sharp canine teeth and claws,
and also typically carries an assortment of
weapons and explosives in his suit, including
a knife, sometimes a gun, and just a few grenades.
And that's Dogpool. But how does he use a gun?
I've never seen him use a gun in the comics.
I'll say that. He just carries it for like intimidation
factor? I guess so. Yeah, actually, Ace doesn't
use any of his weapons either or gear. Essentially,
it's just there for his teammates to use should
they need it. So he's like a pack mule. Yeah,
pretty much exactly. I have seen Dogpool carry
a knife in his mouth. Well, I've seen Ace have
batarangs in his mouth as well in the comments.
So there. Playing fetch or something? Yes. That's
pretty cute.
fantasies collide and heroes clash, one podcast
network rises above the rest. Prepare yourself
for the ultimate showdowns in comic books, video
games, movies, and anime. The DynaMic Podcast
Network presents Console Combat, where video
game legends brawl every Monday. Comic Book
Titans smash every Tuesday. Max Destruction,
where TV and action heroes battle every Wednesday.
And Sendro World, where anime champions clash
every Thursday. Join us as we speculate on
the matches and armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge victorious.
Visit dynamicpodcast.com where we settle the
debate and settle the score.
Well now that we got the dog's histories and
abilities out of the way, let's speculate on
how one of the 1000 simulated matches will go,
but in a dog show. The winner of the dog show
will be determined by simulations, not our speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how the dog show could
play out. AJ9K, what are the rules of our speculation?
Well I should say there are no rules. Other
than the characters have no prior knowledge
of the other going into the show. All they
are aware of starting out is that the other
character is an opponent that needs to be outdone.
For the speculation, the contestants will compete
in a variety of events to showcase their skills.
Alright then, let's get into it! Ace the Bat
Hound and Dog Pool meet in the arena. Who goes
first? Okay, I think Ace the Bat Hound will
go first in their first annual dynamic duel
kennel club dog show. First off will be the
agility trials, which feature a high speed
obstacle course that will test the dog's speed
and evasiveness. For this challenge, the two
will take turns chasing a fake rabbit down a
track. while avoiding cannon fire and maneuvering
around lava pits. Yeah, that's right. I must
say too, Ace looks quite statuesque as he's
waiting for the starting signal. And there it
is! Ace is off! Oh, and he trips right out
of the gate! Womp womp. What? Okay. Well, like
a true ninja in training, Ace comes out of
the stumble with a quick tuck and roll, and
he's back on his feet chasing after the rabbit,
picking up momentum as he approaches the first
turn. and then a cannonball fires straight
at him. But without losing his stride, Ace ducks
beneath the cannonball and is starting to close
the gap as he comes upon the lava pit. And look
at that! Instead of chancing the leap, Ace
runs alongside the fenced wall around the pit
and gets to the other side unscathed. He's
close to the rabbit now, it looks like he's
about to snatch it. OH! He got him with lightning
speed! And wow, he is- tearing that thing to
shreds. Great performance overall though. We'll
see how dogpool compares. Okay so uh dogpool
is at the track starting line. He's looking
a little bit less statuesque as ace did. Yeah
probably because he's licking his asshole.
Yes anyway there's the starting signal and dogpool
tears off like a rabbit animal chasing that
rabbit. All right here comes the cannonball.
except dogpole leaps over the cannonball like
in slow motion bullet time doggy matrix style
oh but it just barely clips his hind legs causing
him to cartwheel through the air oh and it looks
like it knocked him across the field into the
lava pit that's not going to be good all right
okay so he's crawling out of the lava pit i
can see his spleen but it looks like his healing
factor is kicking in as he continues to chase
the rabbit while on fire and with one leg still
missing. What an inspiration, because he's
got it. He's got the rabbit now. Wait, what
is he doing to the rabbit? Oh, he's humping
it. He's really going at it. That is not going
to make the network sensors happy, but let's
see if it affects the judges' scores as Dogpool
finishes up whatever he's doing. This is Scotty
Macho here, and I'm down here on the track,
and we are checking our contestants for speed.
The first one was Ace the Bat Hound. Guy didn't
have a good start, but he was able to snatch
that thing up right away and rip into pieces.
A seven for Ace. Now Dogpool, he was able to
grab that rabbit pretty quick, but then started
humping it right away too. But, I mean, as
ugly as that little thing is, he's still pretty
quick. So we gave him a seven too. For the
category of evasiveness, I'm gonna have to give
Dogpull a six out of seven. I mean, that's
pretty good, but he definitely did rely on his
regenerative abilities more to help him. Which
is not bad. That's smart fighting. That's nothing
wrong with that to use your abilities to your
advantage such as that That's for ace the bat
hound. I'm gonna have to give him a seven out
of seven I mean it clearly shows he was trained
by Batman also not Batman But he had the bat
family with him so much more to be trained on
than just one person Supporting him in this
role. So seven out of seven for about back to
you guys All right next up is the might and
resilience challenge a where dog's pull a weighted
dummy from a burning collapsing structure.
Is this PETA approved? I'm gonna say no. Alright
dog pool goes first and he's given the go-ahead
as he races into the burning building to get
at that dummy on the top floor. Now we made
sure to let the structure burn for a while so
it's literally falling apart during this trial.
Alright sure enough as dog pool is climbing
that first set of stairs they collapse on him.
Oh! and a burning wooden shard just impaled
one of dogpool's limbs. Again? Well, all right,
the three legged pooch. He's just an inspiration
as he fights his way to the top to get at the
dummy and he starts dragging the dummy to safety
by his leg. Now, these dummies weigh like 300
pounds, folks. They're like what we call hefty
or thicc. The building is starting to fully
come down around dogpool. Can he drag the dummy
out to safety in time? Let's see. Oh, holy
shit. He just leaped out of one of the windows,
tossing the dummy out the window with him.
But it looks like he's maneuvering himself beneath
the dummy midair to use himself as a landing
pad. And splat! Looks like the dummy is fine
in dog pool. Like he doesn't look fine, but
he's coming around and at least he has all four
of his legs back. Yeah, they're just all going
in different directions though. Overall. I'd
call this a good showing for the Merc with
the Bark. Okay, now Ace is up. There's the signal,
so there he goes, rushing into the building
with zero hesitation, like a true hero. And
there go the stairs, they're crumbling beneath
them. And he gets hit with some debris, it looks
like. Oh, but he shrugs it off and leaps onto
the landing just in time. And he's located the
dummy. Well, why is he checking the dummy's
vitals? Like, what is he doing? Does he have
time for this? I don't think so. Hey man, there's
always time for safety. But it looks like now
the ace is dragging the dummy up the next flight
of stairs to the roof. Why is he going upstairs?
The structure is crumbling down at this point.
What is he gonna do? Well, it looks like he's
wrapped a harness around the dummy and is now,
what, he's scratching his neck? Oh no, he's
actually triggered a grapple line from his
collar. And now both he and the dummy are sliding
down it to the ground below just as the structure
collapses. Well done. That dog is something
else man, let's see what the judges have to
say.
the event. Ace the Bat Hound has clearly been
trained by the Dark Knight in all manner of
strength training exercises and has been fed
a specialized diet for optimal muscularity.
And though Dogpool has the appearance of a stray
who eats mostly leftover chimichangas from
the Del Taco dumpster and snorts too much cocaine,
he seems to be able to compensate through his
regenerative healing factor that keeps his body
in good condition. We the judges award both
dogs a 7 out of 7. A perfect score.
results for the durability portion of our dog
show today and coming in with a perfect score
of seven we have ace the bat hound now y'all
might be wondering He comes in with a 10. Why
do we give him a 10? I mean, look, you could
chop off his arm, it's gonna grow back. Look
at the healing factor on him. The durability
is off the charts, so we have to give him an
off the charts score. Okay, the next event is
a search and solve competition. It's a scavenger
hunt style event that tests the dog's perception
and intelligence as they navigate a labyrinth
and avoid tasty distractions in order to locate
the drugs that are hidden. in the center of
the maze. And there's the signal. Ace rushes
into the labyrinth. I expect nothing less from
him by this point. Looks like he's sniffing
around now, but has he caught the scent of
the drugs? Oh, look at that. It looks like Ace
has walked right into a dead end. How unfortunate
for that guy. And at the dead end, there's a
plate full of meaty steaks there, cooked rare.
Yummy. Which Ace completely ignores, the dedication.
Oh, what is he doing now? Look, he's digging
under the wall. No dead end is gonna stop him
from getting to his target. Oh, but look, he
stops digging for a second. He must detect the
bitch in heat that was placed in the maze that's
like right above him. Oh, he's digging into
his tactical vest now. What does he have in
there? Oh, it's a gas mask muzzle. Wow, he must
be confident in the location of the drugs by
this point. to use a tool like that to avoid
the scent of romance and stick to his mission.
And sure enough, he's dug right through the
maze and is now beneath the drugs. He's found
them and let out a victorious howl. Mission
accomplished. All right. Now it's Dogpool's
turn. So Dogpool rushes into the labyrinth and
he's using his skilled nose to try and locate
the devil's lettuce that's hidden in this maze,
which is a slang term for marijuana, kids.
But oh, no. He stumbled upon a plate full of
chimichangas, and he eats them all without
even chewing, it looks like. Ha ha ha. Yeah,
it makes sense for the character, for sure.
But oh, we laced them with sleeping pills. That
will cost him. Except, Dogpool's healing factor
should help filter out that poison. So, he's
fine. He keeps going. It's fine. Yeah, but
it looks like he's moving away from the center,
towards the direction of the French poodle
and heat. and he gives into the temptation.
Okay, okay, sure. But Dogpull's like really
quick, okay? He's like a two pump chump. And
so he's like in and out literally and moves
on. Finally approaching the bag of weed and
he finds it. What a champ, you know, his tail's
wagging. He looks like a happy boy. Yeah, maybe
a little too happy because he just straight
up devoured the weed like the police are knocking
on his door.
Well, let's see what the judges have to say.
And now moving on to the intelligence category.
Ace is pretty much a genius. I mean, it's pretty
hard to describe Ace as anything other than
a genius. And unfortunately, dog pool is just
dumb. I can't really describe dog pool any
other way. As intelligence goes, dog pool is
probably even less intelligent than an actual
dog. So sad. So this category goes to Ace the
bat hound with a seven to dog pools measly
one. And next we have the perception event.
Looks like Ace scores a perfect seven due to
his superior training. The dog pool only gets
a three because he passed the drug sniff test
but got too high on marijuana. Unfortunate.
Next up is the attack skills showcase, an action
packed challenge highlighting the dog's fighting
skills and versatility where they must each
take down a squad of ninjas in a warehouse setting.
Yeah, Dogpool is gonna go first, and it looks
like he sees the group of ninjas enter his warehouse
location. And he sees them circle around him.
Yeah, but as he turns to look at each one, he
keeps turning and turning because he's chasing
his own tail. Alright, so, okay, so he's a little
distracted at the outset, and one of the ninjas
lunges at Dogpool with his bow staff. But, you
know, getting conked on the rear with the staff
is gonna snap Dogpool out of chasing his tail,
and he's no longer distracted. and he snarls
and lunges back at the Bo Staff Ninja, straight
up ripping his crotch from his body. Oh shit!
That guy was a volunteer! One down, three to
go. The next ninja is wielding a pair of scythes
and he stabs Dogpool. Dude, what a dickhead.
Attacking a dog like that? Deadpool straight
up rips that guy's dick from his pants. Again?
Yeah. All right, Dogpool seems to be using
a very specific fighting style to disable these
opponents. I hope they already have children.
Yeah, the style is called Wing Chun. Well the
third ninja runs at dogpool with his nunchucks
spinning around. And then dogpool throws a dagger
right in the guy's nutsack. A dagger? Yeah
from his utility belt. And now the final ninja
with swords looks like he's trying to actually
run out of the arena. But dogpool is going to
grab the guy by the seat of his pants just
ripping him and pulling the last ninja to the
ground. And then OH MY GOD the guy just exploded.
What happened? Looks like Dogpool must have
dropped a grenade down the ninja's hole in
his pants. Wow, this battle felt very personal.
Like a ninja must have been the one that neutered
Dogpool back when he was a stray or something.
We can only assume, I guess. Well it's Ace's
turn and I have to say I'm expecting a good
show from him. The Bat Family has trained for
this exact scenario. The four ninjas surround
Ace and he's rolling over and- OH! The warehouse
is now filled with smoke. He must have triggered
a smoke capsule in his tactical vest. Okay,
it looks like we're gonna have to switch to
our infrared cameras. And it looks like the
ninjas cannot see him through the smoke. Oh,
look, there he is in the rafters. How does
a dog get in the rafters? It looks like he's
lowering a looped cable. The sword ninja doesn't
appear to see he's walking right into the trap.
Oh, there he goes. The ninja gets lifted into
the air, and dropping his swords. Uh, it looks
like the ninja with the scythe heard the swords
dropping to the floor, and he looks upward and
he throws one of his scythes into the rafters
at Ace. And like any good boy playing fetch,
Ace catches the scythe in his jaws and he spins
it back around at the ninja. And look, it stuck
him in that foot. That ninja will probably
be pinned there for a while. Pretty painful.
Oh, but it looks like the smoke screen is starting
to clear from the warehouse, so- These guys
are gonna be able to see Ace now. Oh, but where
did Ace go? Oh, there he is behind the Bo Staff
Ninja. Did he just paw chop him in the neck?
Wow, Bo Staff Ninja's down with a nerve strike.
Oh, but look, Nunchuck Ninja spotted Ace, and
he pounces on him, and now he has one of his
Nunchucks wrapped around Ace's neck. Okay,
well, it looks like Ace is pulling hard away
from the Ninja. You know, he's pretty strong
for a dog. Oh, it looks like he was using the
Ninja's weight against him. pulling the ninja
low to the ground and setting him up for one
tremendous headbutt. That ninja is seeing ninja
stars right now. What a masterful performance
from a doggy martial arts master if I've ever
seen one. Let's see what the judges say. Wow,
what a great showing for these two dogs in
the fighting category. For this category, we
were looking for how- these dogs would face
off against each other. And Ace the Bat Hound,
just like his master, came in with great precision
and didn't miss a beat. He scored a perfect
seven. Whereas his opponent, Dogpool, only
scored a six because he was constantly getting
distracted by his own tail. What a great show
so far and I cannot wait to see the rest of
the results from the other categories. When
it comes to versatility, these dogs are collar
and collar. Ace is the world's greatest dogtective,
which means he has a variety of useful skills
like sniffing, sneaking, snarling, and of course
sleuthing. though he prefers not to use it because
he is a very good boy. Dogpool, on the other
hand, may appear to be a chaotic mess, but this
is just because he's a real Jack Russell of
all trades. Just kidding, he's a mutt. But he
does do his own stunts because he can heal
from just about anything. He also has knowledge
on a variety of subjects due to all Deadpool's
ability to break the fourth wall, giving them
a certain sense of omniscience. In either case,
both these canines exhibit just about any skill
they need. need to get the job done and for
that reason we are proud to award both of them
a perfect seven in versatility. The last event
is the precision range test, a targeting competition
testing range and damage potential where the
two dogs will use their unique abilities to
accurately hit and or destroy moving targets
of various compositions. Ace is going first
in this final test and it looks like his projectiles
of choice are a collection of Batarangs. Interesting.
Picking up the first one, Ace is staring intently,
waiting for the first targets to appear. Can
dogs really throw well enough for this event?
I guess we'll see. The first clay targets get
launched, and we're skeet shooting here! Ah
skeet skeet! Like a discus thrower, Ace spins
around and hurls a volley of three Batarangs!
Bam bam one two three all targets were shattered
by ace of course all right the next targets
appear and these guys look like dartboards swinging
like pendulums and The dartboards are wooden
in composition all right ace is winding up,
and there's the pitch Oh, no, it looks like
ace missed one wait the one that missed is circling
back around like a boomerang Oh Ace bulls-eyed
the dartboard from behind! Look the tip of the
battering is sticking through the board into
the front side. Where does this dog get his
wonderful toys? That's what I want to know.
The final round of the targets are appearing
now. They're human figures composed of ballistic
gel so that we can get accurate damage analysis.
But the figures are moving swiftly on a conveyor
belt. It looks like Ace is grabbing a different
style of battering. I wonder which kind. All
right, Ace is taking aim. And wow, instead of
spinning this time, he does a back flip. And
look, he used three different types of batterings.
The first target is now melting from the electric
shock it's receiving. The second one looks like
a pin cushion with sharp battering sticking
out from its vital pressure points. And the
third one is just frozen solid. What a solid
way to wrap up his performance at this show.
What a show off that dog is, but you know.
Dogpool's ready to go now, and he didn't come
to play. The first targets are launched into
the air. All right, maybe he did come to play.
Instead of hurling a projectile at the clay
targets, Dogpool leaps into the air and snatches
all three of the skeet discs. Maybe he thought
this was a Frisbee game or something, but he
did crack the discs with his teeth. So maybe
that will count with the judges? What an idiot!
Looks like the second round of targets are
now swinging. And Dogpool has a grenade in his
mouth and he's wagging his tail. Looks like
he sets the grenade down on the floor and he
nudges it with his nose. Like he wants the
targets to throw it for him. What? Oh wait,
look, the grenade is rolling and it's rolling.
It keeps rolling and it blows up, destroying
all three targets. And Dogpool himself, that
grenade trap now travels pretty far. He'll walk
it off. All right. The final challenge. The
ballistic gel torsos are moving down the conveyor
belt. And it looks like Deadpool pulls out,
oh my God, is that a rocket launcher? And it's
red, it's so big and red. It's a red rocket
launcher. I don't even know how Doc Pull's gonna
use it, but oh, it looks like he's pressing
the trigger with his paw. Kabooy, there goes
all the targets and most of the arena itself.
Thank goodness we are behind this safety glass.
That final round was intense. Let's hear from
our final judges. In the category of range,
we, the judges, have determined that both Ace
the Bat Hound and Dogpool have displayed considerable
skill in their distance and marksmanship. However,
while Ace showed exemplary skill in his ability
to bullseye targets using Batarangs, we feel
that Dogpool's use of throwing grenades insufficiently
demonstrated the same natural skill due to
the weapon's large blast radius. That being
said, Dogpool seems to have a gun pointed at
me as I'm currently reading these results, so
I'm going to award both dogs a perfect score
of 7 out of 7. Alright folks, the results are
it. It would appear that both contestants,
Ace the Batcom and Dogpool, scored a perfect
7 in the damage category. But because Dogpool
is pretty fugly and because his owner has my
family held captive, we're going to award him
3 extra points giving him the win. Wow, Doc
Poole seems pretty desperate to me. Let's take
the judges scores and have our resident Monte
Carlo simulator AJ 9K analyze the data to determine
who wins the inaugural Dynamic Duel Kennel Club
Dog Show. AJ 9K, hit it. Inputting data, running
calculations, processing results, simulations
complete. OK, so when we approached the stats
for this matchup, we knew that Ace was basically
gonna have a perfect score in everything because
he is the perfect dog, particularly when it
would come to dog show style events. Yeah,
I don't think there's any sort of dog show out
there that Ace the Bat Hound would not utterly
dominate. So we definitely approach the stats
from a different angle this go around. It's
not like your standard duel, because speaking
in dog terms, Ace the Bat Hound is a perfect
dog. So really the challenge came in seeing
how Dogpool compares to the perfect dog in
all of the stat categories. And there were some
differences. You know, Dogpool, as the judges
said, got slightly lower in evasiveness because
he knows that he has his healing factor to
rely on. But he really outclassed Ace the Bat
Hound in durability, of course, because of
his healing factor and damage. Yeah, Dogpool
tends to be much more lethal than Ace, who
follows the same code that his master does of
being non-lethal. Dogpool was less than exemplary
compared to Ace though when it came to intelligence
and perception, largely because the dog just
isn't that smart. He's not the type of dog to
follow commands, especially if you classify
intelligence at a dog show through obedience
training. How good are they at following commands
and Dogpool is just an agent of chaos. Well
Joseph, taking all of these stats into consideration,
who do you think is going to come out on top?
I think that dogpool's durability and his lethality
will put him over the edge here. Although Instagram
does not agree with me, it looks like a lot
of our followers are voting for Ace to win by
64% over dogpool. But let's find out who actually
won. AJ9k, the results please. Hey Yuasa. The
winner of the matchup between Ace the Bat Hound
and Dogpool is... What? Yes by a whopping 73.7%
win rate compared to dogpool's 26.3% or 263
of the 1000 matches. How is that possible? The
only way that could be is because we didn't
score this like a typical duel. We scored it
like a dog show. I think we should nix that
whole idea and treat this like an actual dogfight
because I straight up guarantee you that dogpool...
rips Ace the Bat Hound apart. Okay, Michael
Vick. That's what you want, huh? No. Look,
the stats would be fairly comparable, even if
we scored them slightly different. Dogpool
would still come out ahead in terms of durability
and still fall way behind in intellect. Sorry,
Ace the Bat Hound is just elite when it comes
to dog stat categories. Is that so? Well, oh
no, it looks like Dogpool is breaking the fourth
wall and beating the shit out of Ace the bad
hound. Looks like we got our dogfight after
all. Yeah, if Dogpool can even touch Ace with
his stealthiness and superior martial arts skills.
Oh, he'll touch Ace. He'll touch him wherever
he wants to. Oh no. That's right. Dogpool is
establishing dominance. Wow. But that does
it for this duel, guys. AJ9K, help close us
out. Thanks for listening to Dynamic duel.
Visit the show's website at dynamicduel.com
and follow us on Instagram at dynamicduelpodcast.
You can support the show on Patreon at patreon.com
slash dynamicduel and joining a tier that works
for you or by rating and reviewing Dynamic duel
on Apple podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser, or on
our website. Don't forget to listen to the other
shows in the DynaMic podcast network, including
Max Destruction, Senjo World, and Console Combat.
Our next episode will be the 2024 Brothers Awards,
our annual award show where we review everything
Marvel and DC put out in the previous year.
But that does it for this episode, we want
to give a big thanks to our executive producers
Ken Johnson, John Storosky, Zachary Hepburn,
Dustin Balcom, Mickey Montagian, Brandon Estergard,
Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Austin Wiselowski,
AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam
Spies, Andrew Shunk, Dean Molesky, Devin Davis,
Joseph Kirsting. Josh Leiner, Mike Williams,
and Oscar Galvez for helping make this podcast
possible. We'll talk to you guys next week.
Up up and away, true believers.