This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
dynamic duel podcast weekly show where we review
superhero films and debate the superiority
between marvel and dc by comparing their characters
in stat-based battle simulations i'm johnny
dc and i'm his twin brother marvelous joe and
in this episode we are doing a duel between
the outsider character halo and marvel's power
pack and i know what you guys may be thinking
like did these guys jump the shark these characters
are not very well known even among dc and marvel
fans To which we gotta say, yes this episode
is very relevant because Halo is a member of
the Outsiders. And we're gonna do a team duel
with the Outsiders in a few months against
X-Force. So we gotta get through this power
pack. While they haven't had the biggest presence
in Marvel over the years, they have had some
amazing stories. And you guys should definitely
stick around to listen to those as we break
down the characters backstories, enter their
stats, and run simulations to see who'd win
in a fight. I mean you say we gotta get through
this! Like, these characters are interesting.
I actually think the characters are very interesting.
That's what I'm saying. I feel like maybe because
they're not popular, they may not seem interesting,
but actually I was incredibly fascinated by
the stories of the Power Pack as I was going
through their backstory. Same. Yeah, I can't
wait to go over Halo's backstory. But before
that, we're going to break down the comic book
movie news from the past week, of which there
was just one major news item, and that was the
teaser trailer number two for the Mac series,
The Penguin. As always, we list our segment
times in our episode description, so feel free
to check out the show notes if you want to skip
ahead to a particular topic. Guys, our artificially
intelligent duel simulator AJ9K has a quick
message for our listeners, so listen up. Why
hello there, do you want even more from this
podcast? Then become a part of the dynamic
duel community on Patreon, where you can choose
from three tiers. The dynamic two-oh tier gives
you access to our Discord chat server. The fantastic
four tier gives you two bonus episodes each
month. And the X-Force tier makes you an executive
producer of this show. Lastly, The Diner Mike
podcast network tier lets you create your own
podcast using this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny
and Joe will help you develop your show, provide
graphic support and consultation, and get you
simulation results. Pitch the twins your ideas
via email at dynamicduelpodcast at gmail.com.
Check it out at patreon.com slash dynamicduel.
Pip pip cheerio. Thanks AJ9K and thanks to
everyone who supports the podcast. Guys be sure
to tune into the other shows in the DynaMic
Podcast Network this week including Max Destruction,
which pits your favorite action heroes from
film and television against each other. This
week, hosts Ken and Scotty are pitting Renard
from The World Is Not Enough, a James Bond movie,
against Ajax from Deadpool, the first Deadpool
film. On the Send Your World podcast hosts Zachary
Hepburn speculates on fights between fan favorite
anime and manga characters. The show is currently
on a season hiatus, so this is the perfect
time for you anime and manga fans to catch up
on Send Your World's 40 episode library. And
on the Console Combat Podcast, hosts John and
Dean find out who would win in fights between
popular video game characters. And yesterday's
episode, which you can go listen to after this,
they found out who would win in a battle between
Albert Wesker from Resident Evil against Edward
Richtofen, I have no idea how to pronounce it,
from Call of Duty. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com
or click the link in our show notes to listen
to all of the shows in the DynaMic Podcast
Network. Both out of the way, quick to the No
Prize! A No Prize is an award Marvel used to
give out to fans. Our version, the Dynamic duel
No Prize, is a digital award we post on Instagram
for the person that we feel gave the best answer
to our question of the week. Last week we asked
you guys... Who do you want to direct the Marvel
Studios Blade movie and why? And that's coming
off the news that Yann Dimanche, the director
that was most recently associated with the
film, had left the project. We got some solid
answers here. Uh, I totally fucked up. This
is the first time we've ever done this in this
podcast's eight-year history. I accidentally
deleted one of the voicemails that was sent
in by a listener. I am truly sorry if we don't
get to your voicemail within this segment. Don't
let it deter you from sending voicemails in
the future. but whoever left it didn't leave
their name on the form. So we weren't able
to reach out to them. I just want everyone to
know that fuck up was Joseph's to own. I had
no part of it. And I am embarrassed for him
and by him. And you can be assured that there
will be a punishment for this. That's fair,
that's fair. But we have three honorable mentions
to get through as well as a no prize winner.
Our first honorable mention goes to Matt Allen,
who said. Hey guys, this is Matt from Texas.
The director I think that would be best for
the Blade movie should be Sam Raimi. He can
do the horror genre, he can do a little bit
of comedy. I mean, shoot, we saw it in the Multiverse
of Madness, the Spider-Man trilogy, the original
trilogy of Spider-Man anyways. And I just think
he would be the best one for it to be able
to get that level of fear and humor in there.
Now I'll be honest, I wasn't the biggest fan
of Doctor Strange 2, but that had nothing to
do with the direction. I think Sam Raimi is
a fantastic director, as evidenced by his Spider-Man
films and other genre work. We know that he
could work within the Marvel studio system,
and that's huge. I think he would be fantastic
for the Blade movie. I mean, if you look at
his evil dead work in addition, you know that
he also has, obviously, an affinity for horror.
And I think, you know, Blade is more overtly...
Horror comic series as opposed to something
like Doctor Strange, which can have some horror
elements in it But it's mostly about magic and
mysticism, right? Yeah, but like even with
Doctor Strange to like I would say that's the
most Horr-esque film that the MCU has put out
to date other than werewolf by night, which
is not a film But you know, it was a special
presentation on Disney Plus I guess the reason
why Sam Raimi didn't get the no prize win here
is because of how Matt Allen described the comedy
leanings of the director. And yes, Sam Raimi
has injected some overt comedy into his films
like look at Evil Dead 2 and stuff like that.
I'm not necessarily sure that Blade needs that.
I think Blade should be a mostly grounded affair
just the way I would like to see it. I think
it should take itself very seriously and be
not too whimsical, you know? Or tongue in cheek.
Although to be fair... That is Marvel's brand.
When they tried to deviate from that, we got
the Eternals. That's true, but I didn't mind
the Eternals. I don't mind Marvel deviating
from their brand in order to keep things from
feeling too stale. I like the idea of Marvel
mixing things up, kind of like how they did
with Werewolf by Night. OK, got you. But great
answer, Matt Allen. Fantastic. Our next honorable
mention goes to John Storosky. Who said? What's
going on? It's John Storosky. My first choice
would be Quentin Tarantino to direct. new Blade
movie, however, because that is obviously never
going to happen, I'm going to go with Peter
Jackson. He has the directing chops to make
a cinematic masterpiece, and on top of that,
he's got the swordsplay with the Lord of the
Rings. He's got all the action. I think he would
be a perfect director for the Blade film, so
let's get Peter Jackson in there. Yeah, Peter
Jackson, you know, he is one of the greatest
directors of all time, having directed one of
the greatest franchises, the Lord of the Rings
movies that were for the most part expected
to be unfilmable just because of the dense
nature of those stories. But he did it. You
know, as far as I'm concerned, Peter Jackson
can do anything. My big question with him though
is would he want to direct a Blade movie? Well,
maybe. I mean, he does have a background in
the horror genre and he's never done vampires
before. I have to imagine. There might be a
little bit of interest there, at least I would
hope there would be, because Peter Jackson is
a master of world building. And one of my biggest
fears about this Blade movie is introducing
vampires into the MCU I think can get a little
sticky. But if you have a director as talented
as Peter Jackson behind the wheel on that,
I think there's no way you could go wrong. Would
he ever do it? I doubt it, but that would be
amazing. Yeah. Sometimes I wonder why Peter
Jackson hasn't gotten more work ever since
the Lord of the Rings movies and the Hobbit
movies that he's directed. And sometimes I
wonder if it's because he did such a good job
at making those movies that most studios just
can't afford to hire him. They're like, oh yeah,
we'd love to have Peter Jackson on this project.
And he'd be like, fuck you, give me $10 billion.
And they'd be like, no way. And he'd be like,
I directed Lord of the Rings. Come on. You know,
you're like, bitch, I didn't need to do your
movie anyway. Did you ever see Dead Alive by
Peter Jackson? No, I saw the Frighteners though.
I love the Frighteners. Yeah, that was a good
one. That was a good one Great answer john
starosky our next honorable mention goes to
travis herndon who said what's up dynamic dudes
travis here Shout out to my twin. So my picks
would have to be I think those two would be
pretty good to direct blade I mean they doing
a new bad boys movie and judging from the trailer
and everything It looks fucking insane and it
easily can fit that sort of blade action scene,
especially they're trying to go like a Wesley
Snipes style action. So yeah, those are my
pick for Blade. I'll be honest, I have not seen
any of the movies that Bilal Fallah and Adil
Al-Arbi have directed, but that doesn't stop
them from being involved in interesting projects,
including the recent backroll movie that was
unfortunately canned. They directed some of
the episodes of Ms. Marvel, which was a fantastic
television show, and they're even rumored to
be in the running for the upcoming Spider-Man
movie. Yeah, honestly, out of all of the choices
we have here, including the no prize winner
that we'll get to, I think this is the most
plausible answer. Not only do I think that they
would be psyched to do a blade film, they would
also be able to match the tone that I think
a lot of us are looking for in that movie.
For sure. Yeah. All these honorable mentions
are actually great answers. We want to give
a big shout out to Cyrus Moore and to whoever's
answer I deleted. I'm still sorry about that.
But the winner of this week's no prize is Brandon
Estegard. Who said? I think that Taika Waititi
should be the only director who isn't allowed
to make this movie. Instead they should get
Fede Alvarez because he has a great background
in horror, including the Evil Dead 2013 movie
Alien Romulus, and he's even directed a couple
episodes of From Dust Till Dawn, which was
a vampire series. And I just personally think
he's the best choice for anything horror at
the moment. Yeah, Fede Alvarez has really made
a name for himself ever since his Evil Dead
remake back in 2018. 13 I want to say, but he
also directed Don't Breathe, which I thought
was a fantastic movie, and Alien Romulus coming
out soon looks really, really good. So yeah,
I think he's probably one of the best names
in the horror genre right now. He's just doing
really interesting things behind the camera
and I think he's kind of an auteur and I would
love to have him behind the Blade movie. I also
think it's attainable. I don't know if it's
attainable. I think he might be a little too
over the top for Marvel's brand. Not saying
that he couldn't adjust his tastes to fit the
Marvel brand. I just think that's less likely
than, you know, some of the other directors
that we've talked about. That said, I love
Fede Alvarez for this choice, because the Blade
movie I personally want to see would be the
kind of Blade movie that Fede Alvarez would
direct. Absolutely. That would just make my
whole year if I heard the news that he got the
job. If they announced that he was the director,
like that would make me do a double take. I
would feel threatened. that because I'd be
like holy shit that's like too amazing. Congrats
to Brandon Estergaard for winning this week's
no prize if you the listener want a shot at
winning your own no prize. Stay tuned to later
on in this episode when we'll be asking another
question of the week. And now that that's done,
on to the news!
Okay, so this past week we got our second official
teaser for the Penguin series. I don't know
why they're calling it a teaser. It's over two
minutes long. It's a trailer. It's our first
big trailer for the series and it is so damn
good. It perfectly matches the vibe of the
Batman film, which again still reminds me of
that David Fincher-esque noir kind of vibe.
But also, and I thought of this as I was watching
this trailer specifically, of Batman Year One.
It's the world of mobsters and corruption that
I've always wanted to see Batman in and it
looks like the penguin is going to nail that
tone to a T. The trailer was so good I completely
forgot about my fat mobster joke from the previous
teaser. Oh gosh. So I'm not even going to bring
it up. The fact that I called him fat mobstered
before. Do you still think that the suit looks
really fake? Not in any of the shots in this
trailer, no. I think they did a good job of
hiding the fat suit here. Good, they probably
did that just for you, so they didn't have
to hear your shit. No, but I'm glad to hear
that you liked it. Right off the bat, I got
super excited because it starts off with footage
from the end of the Batman when Gotham City
gets flooded. It looks like this show actually
takes place one week after the Batman film
ends. And in a way it's kind of setting up like
this almost no man's land kind of. esque story
in that Gotham city is in shambles and there's
a power vacuum and the penguin is going to
try and take advantage of that while the city
is in chaos. Which is a phenomenal premise,
I love that. Early on we get to see the penguin
speaking with Salvatore Moroni in jail explaining
how he basically wants to take over Gotham's
criminal underworld but it looks like he's
going to be facing competition from Carmine
Falcone's children, specifically Alberto and
Sophia, which If you know anything about like
the Long Halloween and Jeff Loeb's takes on
those characters specifically, I think we're
in for a real treat with this show and it just
gets me so pumped to see it. Yeah, it looks
like something out of, you know, The Sopranos
or something directed by Francis Ford Coppola.
It looks really fucking good. I thought it
was weird to see the guy who played Alex Wilder
in the Runaways television series as the Penguin's
like right-hand man. I don't know what character
he's playing in the show. Yeah, I guess the
character's name is Victor Aguilar. I think
he's his driver. But I was actually excited
to see how many explosions and machine guns
there were in the show as well. It kind of
gives that elevated, fantastical, kind of Gotham
City atmosphere that could go a little bit
more extra than something like the Sopranos.
I mean, the world of Sopranos, they don't have
overt supervillains like they do here. They
don't have some guy in an asylum whose face
is all scarred up like the Joker's. Or a guy
named The Riddler going, No, no, no. Yeah,
I'm wondering if those characters are going
to show up in this show because apparently
Sophia Falcone was in Arkham Asylum for a time.
So I don't know. Maybe we'll actually get to
see the asylum or a little bit more of it. Speaking
of that, is it weird to have a Batman show
without the Batman in it? Like you'd have to
think that all the chaos that the penguin is
going to be causing among the crime families.
that at some point you'd have the Dark Knight
show up to shut things down. So this is just
a rumor, but apparently Robert Pattinson does
make a cameo in the series. Oh, well, yeah,
it's pretty cool. Well, now I'm going to be
expecting that and I will be severely let down
if that does not happen, dude. Same. So this
brings us to our question of the week.
Besides Batman, what character do you most hope
to see in the Penguin Max series, and why?
Record your answer at dynamicduel.com by clicking
on the red microphone button in the bottom
right hand corner of the screen, which will
prompt you to leave us a voicemail. Your message
could be up to 30 seconds long, and don't forget
to leave your name in case we include you on
the podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer,
and award that person a Dynamic Duel No Prize
that we'll post to Instagram. Be sure to answer
before June 29th.
That does it for all the news for this episode.
Now let's move on to the main event, where
we find out who will win in a match up between
the Outsiders character of Halo and Marvel's
Power Pack.
Alright, Halo vs Power Pack. Of course, as we
mentioned earlier, this episode is in lead
up to our next team duel, which will be the
Outsiders vs X-Force, and Halo is a founding
member of the Outsiders team. So we knew we
needed to get her into a duel episode sooner
rather than later. Now, years ago, I think,
maybe it was just one year ago, one of our
executive producers, Miggy Meth and Gian, suggested
Halo vs Power Pack, and this was recently brought
up again. by Devin Davis who pitched the same
idea and that's what we ended up going with.
Primarily because all of these characters are
insanely versatile. Yeah, that was the big
thing. There were several options available
for us to pit against Halo, including Dazzler
or Jubilee or something like that, but the versatility
of Halo is the thing that gets me. She has
like a lot of different powers within her power
set. And that's basically her whole thing.
You know, she changes the color of the light
that she produces and all of a sudden she has
an entirely different... power set. And so I
knew that I needed someone that was a little
bit more versatile than someone like Jubilee
who just shoots fireworks or someone like Dazzler
who can convert sound to light, which is powerful,
but not in the way that I needed to be. I need
to be adaptable. I need to be versatile. And
I think the Power Pack kids are just that.
You know, they got a cool set of powers amongst
themselves. There have been plenty of times
within their stories that they've actually swapped
powers and stuff like that. But there was also
a time when Alex, the oldest of the Power Pack
kids acquired all their powers. And so we knew
that was our in for how to approach this match.
It's essentially going to be Halo versus power
house, which is what Alex power called himself
when he had all of his family's powers. Oh,
interesting. I didn't know that. Another reason
I like this matchup is because aesthetically,
they share a lot of similarities. Like they
wear these black costumes with like strands
of color. I thought it just fit. The power packs
seem cool to me, even though they're like snot
nose kids. But from what I know of their powers,
they're kind of like the Fantastic Four upgraded,
in my opinion. Really? Interesting. Okay. I
don't disagree. I think their power set is
a little bit cooler, but you know, we'll get
into that in the character breakdown. Before
that, to explain the methodology behind our
duels, let's go to our sentient duel simulator,
Alfred Jarvis 9000. AJ9K, tell our listeners
how you go about determining a winner in our
duel matchups. Yes, of course, sir. The way
I determine a winner between the contestants
is by running 1000 Monte Carlo simulations using
the characters statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation
is a probabilistic model used to determine outcomes
through random sampling. In this case, I randomise
the statistics along a normal distribution as
a way to simulate the many variables that can
occur during battle. The stat parameters are
based on the official Marvel power grid from
which the DC characters statistics are extrapolated.
damage potential, versatility and perception
in order to create a more detailed and accurate
simulation. The results of the 1000 simulations
provide a percentage of wins for each character.
The contestant with the higher percentage is
declared the victor. as they have a higher
probability to win any given battle. In an equitable
pairing, neither character should win 100%
of the matches. The comic book stories have
shown that there's even a way for Batman to
defeat Superman, so the confidence rate of my
method falls in line with the precedents that
have been established in the source material.
My mathematical simulations are without subjectivity
or bias. Feats are not the sole consideration,
nor are fan votes tabulated for determination
of the winner. Thanks, AJ9K! Before we run the
simulations though, we'd like to break down
each character's histories and abilities before
improvising a scenario on how we imagine one
of the 1000 simulations would play out beat
for beat. And I believe it is my turn to go
first with the Marvel characters backstory,
so let me go ahead and tell you all about Power
Pack. A long time ago, in a galaxy far, far
away, existed a planet known as Chimelia, where
an advanced race of beings, Chimelians, developed
a means of energy production via a process
that converted matter into antimatter. Though
their technological pursuits were well-meaning,
their antimatter converter resulted in a cataclysmic
chain of energy that completely destroyed their
home planet. Fortunately, some of the chameleons
were able to survive the disaster on a large
space station that subsequently became their
new home. One of these chameleons, named Alefire
Whitemane, had tapped into Earth's transmissions
in order to study humanity. and learned that
one of Earth's scientists named Dr. James Power
had developed similar antimatter converter
technology in his pursuit of developing a source
of clean energy. Knowing that the device would
destroy Earth if used, White Mane decided he
had to intervene. He sent a transmission to
the Chimelians that he was leaving for Earth
in his starship. However, that transmission
was intercepted by a war-mongering race of aliens
called the Snarks, who also decided to head
to Earth. and steal the antimatter converter
for themselves. Meanwhile, on Earth lived Alex,
Julie, Jack, and Katie, the four children of
Dr. James and Margaret Power. The night before
the converter was to be tested, the youngest
child, Katie, looked into the night sky and
witnessed what appeared to be a meteor shower,
but was in reality an aerial battle between
White Mane and the Snarks who managed to shoot
White Mane's spaceship down. When Katie told
her siblings of what she had seen in the sky,
the group went outside to find the crashed
Chameleon starship. Shocked, they went to alert
their parents, but found them being abducted
by the Snarks. The Snarks would have killed
the children, but they were saved by White
Mane, who was badly wounded, and the Snarks
escaped with the power of parents. Dying, the
alien explained to the kids the situation, that
their father's device had the potential to
destroy the planet, and with his final breath,
he passed on his abilities to control gravity,
acceleration, mass, and energy to Alex, Julie,
Jack, and Katie respectively. Deciding to rescue
their parents, the four chose the superhero
names Zero-G, Lightspeed, Massmaster, and Energizer
and called themselves the Power Pack. They destroyed
their father's antimatter converter, then used
White Mean's Starship to rescue their parents
from the Snarks, whose interrogation methods
of Dr. James Power had accidentally destroyed
his memory of his device. The family moved
to New York, where the Power Pack kids ran into
other heroes in their adventures against villains
such as their father's former co-worker, who
donned a battle suit to become the Boogie Man,
and Jackal, a high-ranking official in the Snark
World Empire. They met Spider-Man, Cloak and
Dagger, and the Fantastic Four, the latter of
whom grew close with the Power Pack due to
Mr. Fantastic and  Woman's son Franklin
being around the same age. In fact, at one
point Franklin joined the Power Pack as a fifth
member named Tattletail. Later, the Power Kids
were abducted and taken to Snark World where
their powers were taken from them. However,
Franklin rescued them using White Manes old
starship. When their powers were returned,
they were redistributed so that Alex now had
energy projection, Julie had mass control,
Jack had gravity manipulation, and Katie had
flight and speed. You can learn more about
Franklin Richards and the Fantastic Four in
their duel against the Justice Society. The
Power Pack frequently partnered with the X-Men,
fighting against Sabertooth and the Marauders,
the Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse, the Master
Mold Sentinel, and the Goblin Queen, the latter
fight teaming up with the New Mutants. Eventually,
Power Pack got the chance to visit the Chimeleon
Space Station, where they saved the ancient
race from Queen Maraud of the Snarks, during
which time they reverted to their original power
sets. In the aftermath of that fight, The Power
Pack helped the Chameleons finally move off
their space station onto a new, lush planet
called Chameleon 3, where they decided to reject
excessive technology as a species. Back on
Earth, Alex, driven by a desire to become a
more independent and impactful superhero, stole
his siblings' abilities using Chameleon tech
and renamed himself Powerhouse, joining the
teenage superhero team called the New Warriors.
Though his actions angered his brother and
sisters, Alex rationalized his actions by claiming
that it was dangerous for children to be superheroes.
But eventually, he apologized and returned his
siblings' powers. The power pack briefly split
up as Alex joined Mr. Fantastic's future foundation,
Think Tank of Scientific Minds. Julie pursued
an acting career in Los Angeles where she encountered
the Runaways, and later joined the Future Foundation
alongside Alex. Jack opted to tend to their
sick mother, and Katie declined an invitation
to join the Great They all later reunited as
the Power Pack, however, to team up with Moon
Girl and Devil Dinosaur, whom you can learn
more about in their duel against Dorothy Spinner
from Doom Patrol. That's their backstory. Powers-wise,
the four members of Power Pack, Zero G, Light
Speed, Mask Master, and Energizer, have repeatedly
swapped abilities and code names throughout
the years. For the purposes of simplifying the
simulations and our speculation, I'm going
to treat the Power Pack as one person. Alex
power during his time as Powerhouse when he
had all of his siblings powers. This includes
Zero-G's Gravity Control, allowing Powerhouse
to negate or increase the effect of gravity
on himself and his close proximity and therefore
able to lift any object no matter how heavy.
He also has his sister Julie's Lightspeed Acceleration
powers, allowing him to fly at supersonic speeds
and teleport. He also has his brother Jack's
Mass Master powers, which allow him to turn
his body in super durable, and even shrink
his size to about 8 inches tall. Powerhouse
also has his sister Katie's Energizer powers,
which allow him to disintegrate and convert
any solid matter he touches into energy that
he can absorb and release as an energy blast.
This also lets him absorb other forms of energy
that he can then redirect. Though Powerhouse
is uniquely intelligent among his siblings
as a former member of the Future Foundation,
all the Power Pack kids are somewhat gifted
intellectually, And their costumes, made of
unstable molecules and chameleon technology,
have pocket dimensions within their pockets
that let them carry a significant amount of
stuff. Like what kind of stuff? A whole bunch
of stuff, man. You don't even know. Actually,
I think that particular feature is what influenced
me to claim that Reed Richards probably had
a pocket dimension in his unstable molecules
costume in his duel against Plastic Man. I
knew I had read that somewhere. Like somebody
had a pocket dimension in their pocket. It
was these guys. Okay. So just to double check,
light speed does not move at light speed. Well,
she could teleport, so kinda. Hmm. Okay. But
when she flies, it's usually defined as supersonic.
I don't think she can actually fly at light
speeds. Okay. Not gonna lie, that's a pretty
crazy power set. Luckily, though, Halo also
has a fairly robust power set, so let me get
into her backstory. At the beginning of time,
when the universe first exploded into existence,
from an energy known as the Source, some of
that energy coalesced into sentient orbs of
light known as oracles. The oracles, as beings
of energy that existed outside the physical
world, were created by lived for thousands of
years and multiplied, all the while observing
the formation of the universe over billions
of years. While many oracles were attracted
to stellar phenomena, observing cosmic-level
events from a distance, one oracle, however,
became more interested in organic sentient beings
and wondered what it would be like to experience
sensations and emotions such as theirs. Eventually,
this oracle discovered Earth, and while investigating
young woman in the country of Markovia during
a violent revolt against its monarchy. Moved
by the tragedy and attempting to reach out to
the young woman, The Oracle accidentally entered
the physical world and became trapped within
her body, bringing that young woman back to
life, though she awoke with no memory of her
former life on Earth or as an Oracle. Seeing
Batman upon her resurrection and being frightened,
she discovered that she had light-based superhuman
abilities. Nonetheless, she joined Batman and
helped him and the other heroes stop Baron
Bedlam from overthrowing the Markovian monarchy,
of which the hero Geoforce was a part. whom
you can learn more about in last week's Geoforce
vs Quake duel episode. Batman recruited the
heroes involved in protecting Markovia to form
a new Gotham City-based super team named the
Outsiders. Still suffering from amnesia, though,
Halo adopted the civilian identity of Gabriel
Doe. and she lived in the penthouse above the
Wayne Foundation building with the hero Kitana,
who became Halo's legal guardian, and whom you
can learn more about in our Kitana vs. Elektra
duel episode. With help from Batman's detective
skills, Halo eventually learned she was born
with the name Violet Harper, from Arlington,
Missouri. She was a smart kid, but rebellious,
and as a teenager, she and her boyfriend stole
a drug formula from the mobster Tobias Whale.
Whale sent an assassin known as Cyanide who
tracked the couple to the country of Markovia
where she successfully killed Violet. Unfortunately,
a visit to her parents Sam and Margaret in
Missouri drew the attention of Tobias Whale,
who held them hostage in exchange for the drug
formula, which Halo no longer remembered. Despite
calling on aid from the outsiders and managing
to defeat Tobias Whale, Halo's parents were
killed by Cyanide in the ordeal. In an effort
to learn more about her powers, Halo was brought
aboard the Justice League satellite headquarters,
where the article within her regained its memory.
This event was observed by other articles,
who took Halo into their ethereal dimension
with the intent to separate her article from
her body, a process that would also return Violet
to her state of death. Fortunately, the Outsiders
traveled to the Oracle Dimension and managed
to save Halo, and the Oracles agreed to allow
the merger of Violet and the Oracle to exist
in peace. Halo left the Outsiders upon her
return in an effort to reconcile her identity
and find herself, though she ended up later
accidentally joining the Cult of Cobra, who
tortured her to learn Batman's secret identity.
Halo was rescued by the Outsiders, however,
after which she rejoined the team. Framed for
the murder of the Queen of Markovia and became
fugitives on the run, Halo's rebellious Violet
Harper personality began to re-emerge and eventually
take control. Halo ended up betraying the Outsiders
shortly before she was killed by a cyborg assassin
named Sanction, who also killed the woman who
hired him, Marissa Baron, the ex-wife of an
Outsiders team member named Technocrat. Like
with Violet's body before, the article somehow
accidentally merged with Marissa, making her
the new Halo. Though the Oracles returned to
reclaim their kin, they were fought off by
the Outsiders, after which the team was cleared
of any wrongdoing regarding the death of the
Markovian Queen. Violet Harper's body, however,
was revived by Cobra and brainwashed into becoming
the villain Spectrum. The Outsiders eventually
disbanded and Halo appeared off and on throughout
the years, aiding Markovia and other heroes
during large crises. Eventually, though it
is unknown Now, Halo returned to the body of
Violet Harper, who joined a reformation of
the outsiders following the death of Batman
at the hands of Darkseid. When the villain
Necron reanimated the dead heroes and villains
of the DC Universe, turning them into black
lanterns, Halo, thanks to her light-based powers,
proved effective against the zombies, though
she seemingly sacrificed herself while protecting
the outsiders, becoming pure light and dispersing.
After the Flash reset DC's continuity, Violet
Harper was a drug addict imprisoned in Markovia,
who later betrayed the location of Katana and
the Suicide Squad to the Cobra Cult in exchange
for narcotics. Cobra then experimented on Violet,
intending to use her as a weapon, but the kidnapped
Violet with captured articles, betrayed Cobra,
and sabotaged a mind control device that would
have allowed Cobra to control Violet's empowered
form. When Kitana and the Suicide Squad showed
up shortly after Violet's procedure, the articles
burst from her body and tried to kill everyone,
though they all fled in fear when Kitana's sword
managed to kill one of them. All but one, that
is, which had been bonded permanently to Violet's
body.
Katana invited Violet to join her. And that's
her backstory. Powers-wise, Halo is an article-possessed
human capable of manipulating the Halo, or aura-like
light that emanates from her, for a variety
of effects that are indicated by a specific
color within the spectrum of light. When her
aura is red, Halo can produce destructive heat-based
laser beams, and when it's orange, Those lasers
are concussive instead. Jiki used both red and
orange light to create defensive shields as
well. Her yellow light is used to stun and blind
enemies in bright flashes, and her green light
acts as a stasis beam to freeze enemies. Blue
light allows her to create holographic distortions,
specifically duplicates of herself or other
objects. and Indigo Light can be used like
a tractor beam, allowing her to push, pull,
or lift objects. Violet Light grants her access
to all of her abilities at once, though this
is rarely used because it also gives the unstable
Violet Harper personality control over the body
they share. When glowing in any of these specific
colors, Halo is able to fly up to the speed
of light, which is her standard ability while
glowing her standard white. mix too. It reminds
me that I have a bone to pick with the color
indigo. I feel like that color between blue
and violet was only selected as part of the
color spectrum to complete the ROYGBIV acronym,
which is, you know, red, orange, yellow, green,
blue, indigo, violet, like NYX indigo and make
more room for cyan because cyan is definitely
a unique color between green and blue. I agree
with you 100% because honestly, it should just
be red, yellow, green, sand, blue, magenta.
Purple. No, fuck purple and fuck orange. What?
Yeah. Jesus. You heard me. Wow. You're just
talking about this character, right? Like the
colors that she would have as a producer of
light, right? Right, exactly. Oh, she would
have magenta light. Right, exactly. Yeah, makes
sense. But we digress heavily. That was some
inside graphic design baseball.
Where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
DynaMic Podcast Network presents Console Combat,
where video game legends brawl every Monday.
Comic Book Titans smash every Tuesday. Max Destruction,
where TV and action heroes battle every Wednesday.
And Sendro World, where anime champions clash
every Thursday. Join us as we speculate on
the matches and armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge victorious.
Visit dynamicpodcast.com, where we settle the
debate and settle the score.
But now that we've got their histories and abilities
out of the way, let's speculate on how one
of the 1000 simulated matches will go. The winner
is determined by simulations, not this speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how this fight could
play out. AJ9K, what are the rules of our speculation?
Well, I should say there are no rules, other
than the characters have no prior knowledge
of the other going into the fight. All they
are aware of starting out is that the other
character is a threat that needs to be eliminated.
For the speculation, the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a non-descript
environment that will have no bearing on the
match itself, as no environmental statistics
are considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. Alright
then, let's get into it. Halo and Powerhouse
meet on the battlefield. Who goes first? Well,
since Halo moves faster, I'm gonna say she
goes first. And she's gonna start by turning
yellow and flashing a bright yellow light that...
blinds powerhouse and while he's like oh i can't
see that's you know when she's going to blast
him with an orange concussive beam just knocking
him backwards no because powerhouse's first
instinct once he goes blind is going to be to
go intangible so he's going to access his brother
jack's powers as mass master and he's going
to lower his density which turns him into this
like gaseous form and this orange beam is just
going to pass right through him And, you know,
he's slowly regaining his sight and he's going
to float up into the air as this cloud. And
when he can see again, once he gets his vision
back, Powerhouse is going to solidify out of
this cloud form and he's going to increase his
mass and gravity so that he just drops onto
Halo like an ocean tanker. But like fist first,
just slamming her and flattening her into the
ground. Wait, so is Powerhouse visible in this
gaseous form? Yeah. Why? Okay, well, this isn't
a surprise to Halo because, you know, she just
watches this whole thing unfold and as he's
falling down on her, she's just going to turn
Indigo and send out a tractor beam that's going
to grab him and just slam him into the ground
away from her instead. Alright, but as Halo
tries to slam him, Powerhouse is going to shrink.
He's going to decrease his size and mass to
about 8 inches tall. So instead of like slamming
him hard onto the ground, It's more like she
just gently sets him onto the ground because
he doesn't have the mass to support the slam.
And that's when Powerhouse is gonna grow to
normal height and he's gonna access his sister
Julie's light speed powers. So he's gonna fly
right at Halo at supersonic speed and just
plow into her, breaking some ribs, knocking
the wind out of her. Okay, you know, Halo gets
hit, but as she's recovering, she glows green
and she's gonna zap Powerhouse. with the stasis
beam, just freezing him mid air to give her
time to finish recovering. And as he's frozen,
that's when she just goes out to him and just
kicks the shit out of him, like punching him
in the nose, kicking him in the spleen, and
he's just forced to take it. And Halo might
get a few shots in, sure, but like only a few,
because powerhouse, he's just gonna teleport
out of the stasis beam. And then he's- No, no,
no. He's completely frozen, like he can't even
breathe in this thing. He takes those hits like
a real fucking man would. It's not like he
needs to move in order to teleport. He can just
teleport out of the stasis beam. Is teleportation
an action? No, it is. So he can't do it because
he's literally frozen in like space time. If
he was like frozen in a block of ice, he could
teleport easily. Same thing. No, she's not
freezing him with cold. She's freezing Kim.
with energy, all right? Stasis field. He can't
do shit. Okay, so like you'd rather punch a
little kid than say he's capable of teleporting
out. I see how you are. She's a teenager too.
All right, okay, anyway. So Powerhouse teleports
out of the stasis field. I'm just calling it.
I'm sorry, that's what he did. Although now
I'm seeing the downside to not using the full
power pack team in the speculation. because
as individuels, they can heal each other. And
so there's no one around to heal Powerhouse
from the wounds that he just received. But-
What power do they use to heal each other?
They can like share each other's life force,
basically. Weird. I'm gonna say Powerhouse
teleports right next to Halo and grabs her,
and he's gonna completely negate the effect
of gravity on her, so she like weighs nothing.
And with that, he's just gonna toss her up
into the air beyond the stratosphere. In the
air, okay, yeah, that's fine. From the stratosphere.
Halo is just gonna rain down these red lasers
just everywhere, burning up Powerhouse and
the surrounding environment beneath him. Awesome.
Powerhouse gets hit by the lasers, sure, and
the whole area around him is on fire, but he's
gonna absorb those heat beams with his sister
Katie's energizer powers. He absorbs the beams,
he's gonna absorb the flames all around him,
so now he's just glowing with this bright yellow
energy and he's gonna fly up into the atmosphere
to meet Halo. and he's just gonna fucking demolish
her with this massive energy blast that she
fueled him with and it's just gonna obliterate
her. Oh no, she's obliterated. You know what's
crazy though? What? That halo that he saw and
obliterated was just an illusion generated
by Halo's blue aura. The real Halo is actually
coming in fast behind Powerhouse and just slams
into him at near light speed with a red force
field. disintegrating him instantly instead
because she could actually travel at light speed
unlike his sister. Oh shit, more child abuse.
I see. Just the splattering powerhouse make
Halo feel like more of a woman beating up on
kids like that. It's child on child crime. Like
what has powerhouse been doing this whole time
but hitting a girl. Halo's not a girl. She's
like a alien zombie. There's a difference.
Yeah, an alien zombie girl. I feel like that's
a Rob Zombie like alien zombie girl. Na na
na. We can leave the match there before we run
the simulations. So either Halo obliterates
Powerhouse by slamming into him at light speed
with a force field or Powerhouse obliterates
Halo with a giant energy blast. Well, go ahead
and input the character stats, run the simulations
and come back with a winner. AG9K, hit it. Inputting
data, running calculations. Processing results
simulations complete. All right, not being too
familiar with either of these characters I
have no idea how these results are gonna go
I'm not gonna be surprised either way whether
power pack or halo win because I feel like you
know They both have a grab bag of powers some
of them fairly random Seemingly and I think
that just gonna make the results kind of random.
Yeah, the characters seem to be like either
really strong in a stat or incredibly weak
considering that, you know, they're children.
So like when it came to fighting skill, intelligence
or perception, they were very, very low. But
like you look at speed and versatility, you
know, Halo was maxed out on those. And then
you look at things like evasiveness and strength,
Power Pack was maxed out on those. So you're
right, there's not a whole lot of in between
either they are really good at a stat or they
really suck. I think what really surprised
me was that they actually were pretty comparable
when it came to damage level. I thought Halo
was going to take it on that one, but you know,
considering powerhouse could use Energizer's
powers to basically do the same kind of destructive
beams that she could do. Yeah, they're pretty
much the same. Well Energizer's powers aren't
represented as beams. They're more like energy
balls. But yeah, I mean, she can disintegrate
any form of solid matter and convert it into
energy, which you know, has a lot of destructive
potential on its own. even without the energy
blasts. Both characters were actually fairly
weak when it came to durability. That's another
thing that I thought was pretty surprising.
Although Power Pack had the slight edge there
because Masked Master can increase his density
to become more durable. Considering all these
stats, Jonathan, who do you think is going to
win this match? I have no idea, honestly. I'm
rooting for Halo though, and so are our followers
on Instagram. 65% of them who voted in the
poll voted for Halo. The power pack, they're
a bunch of cute kids. Why wouldn't you vote
for them? You know, it's kind of weird. Because
they're a bunch of fucking kids. I guess they
got that going for and against them. I say that
like I don't have kids. Grace, Faith, I love
you girls. Well, let's go ahead and find out
who won. AG9K, the results please. Here you
are, sir. All right, the winner between Halo
and Power Pack is Power Pack. Dang it! And
you know what? It wasn't really that close.
Out of a thousand matches, Power Pack won 654
battles, whereas Halo only won 346. So Power
Pack's win rate was 65.4%, whereas Halo's win
rate was only 34.6%. Really? Ah, the Power Pack
essentially wins two-thirds of the time. Yeah,
pretty much. Essentially the few things that
gave Power Pack an edge over Halo were durability.
but also intellect, you know, when factoring
in Alex Powers' high intelligence. You know,
he was a member of the Future Foundation. Reed
Richards himself said he was around postgraduate
level intelligence at the age of 19. So despite
the fact that Power Pack also has Katie, who's
a young kid, who's, you know, not as brilliant,
when you average everything out, Power Pack
still had a slight edge in intelligence over
Halo. Which is fair, because I feel like a
teenager stealing a drug formula from a mobster
pretty dumb. It's not that smart of a teenager.
Makes sense. Is it kind of embarrassing though
to be eked out by the intelligence stat? Because
I feel like that would be pretty embarrassing,
especially from a group of kids. Well, I mean,
honestly, I kind of had to average out her intelligence
stat as well, considering that the article
within her is actually thousands of years old
and has amassed quite a bit of knowledge that
said she doesn't really have access to it and
she never really uses it. and the merged halo
combined persona in a majority of her depictions
has amnesia. So she doesn't really know anything,
unfortunately. Does she have amnesia currently
in the comics? From the last thing I read from
her, yeah, she's still kind of learning who
she is while living with Katana. She's very
much dependent on her. Okay, makes sense, makes
sense then. So this is a great win for Marvel.
I encourage a lot of listeners out there to
go check out Power Pack in Marvel Comics. Actually,
a lot of their best stories. do not take place
in the 616 main Marvel timeline, but rather
the more kid-targeted comics called Marvel Age.
That's its own continuity. But they're quite
accessible for kids, the Power Pack. As a matter
of fact, my daughter, who's one year old now,
when the time comes for her to start reading
comics and stuff and getting introduced to
Marvel, I think I'm going to start off with
Power Pack. And then from there, around age
seven or whatnot, I'll introduce her to Spidey
and the Fantastic Four. And then from there,
like around 11 or 12, probably get into more
of like the X-Men and the deeper themes and
stuff like that. Yeah, which is like the limit
for Marvel, like 11 and 12 year olds could
read X-Men. You know, DC has the real highbrow
stuff. So like when she's turning 16, totally
getting her sand man. You're not going to poison
my daughter's mind with it. That bullcrap.
I mean, Marvel has the Max line, so when Ella
becomes even older, you know, she could start
reading Max comics if she wants. I don't fucking
know. I don't even know if she'll be into comics,
but we'll see. I can introduce her to DC super
pets because that's pretty kid friendly. No!
Well, fine then. Geez. Not poisoning her mind,
I just said. Well, I guess that does it for
this duel. AJ 9K, help close this out. Thanks
for listening to Dynamic duel. Visit the show's
website at dynamicduel.com and follow us on
Instagram at dynamicduelpodcast. You can support
the show on Patreon at patreon.com slash dynamicduel
and joining a tier that works for you, or by
rating and reviewing Dynamic duel on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, Podchaser or on our website. Don't
forget to listen to the other shows in the Dynamite
Podcast Network, including Max Destruction,
Senjow World and Console Combat. Next week's
episode is going to come out right before the
4th of July. It's going to come out July 2nd.
So we're going to have a little 4th of July
themed episode for you guys, where we're going
to find out who to win in a fight between Uncle
Sam, who was like the personification of American
patriotism and Captain Britain, who is a hero
from the British Isles. I'm just glad that I
am on the side of America and you're a frigging
red coat. Yeah, I don't love that. But Captain
Britain is more awesome than Uncle Sam, who's
kind of a lame ass character, so yeah, I'm gonna
win this next one too. We'll see. But that
does it for this episode, we want to give a
big thanks to our executive producers Ken Johnson,
John Strosky, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Balcombe,
Mickey Mathageon, Brandon Nestergaard, Nathaniel
Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Austin Wazilowski, AJ Dunkerley,
Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Spies, Andrew
Shunk, Dean Maleski, Devin Davis, and Joseph
Kirsting for helping make this podcast possible.
We'll talk to you guys next week. Up up and
away, true believers.