This is a Dynamike Network podcast. Hey everyone,
Marvelous Joe here at the top of the episode.
With the approaching holiday season, we're officially
kicking off this year's holiday charity drive
in lead up to our charity dual episode in December,
which is gonna be Alfred Pennyworth versus
Edwin Jarvis. This year, all donations will
be going once again to Pop Culture Classroom,
a nonprofit organization that delivers high
quality, all inclusive educational resources
to school districts. teachers, and community
organizations using comics, graphic novels,
and related pop culture media. Their mission
is to inspire a love of learning, increase
literacy, celebrate diversity, and build community
through the tools of pop culture and the power
of self-expression. To donate to this wonderful
charity, visit our official store through dynamicduel.com
where you'll find two donation options. One
if you're Team DC, and one if you're Team Marvel.
Or you can go directly to dynamicduel.com slash
donate DC, one word, or dynamicduel.com slash
donatemarble, which are linked in our show notes.
We're making the charity drive a competitive
duel this year, except that the only stat is
which side can donate the most. Everyone who
donates will receive a digital poster featuring
original art of Alfred and Jarvis that's inspired
by New Yorker cartoons. One lucky random donor
will win a framed print of the Alfred vs Jarvis
art that we'll announce during that December
duel episode. Which fanbase will be the most
charitable? We'll keep everyone posted as to
which team is winning as donations come in
during these upcoming episodes. Thanks to everyone
who donates, and on with the show!
Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the superiority
between Marvel and DC by comparing their characters
in stat-based battle simulations. I'm Johnny
DC. And I'm his twin brother, Marvelous Joe.
And in this episode, we are going to pit the
DC villain of Mongol against the Marvel villain,
Annihilus. They're both intergalactic tyrants,
and we thought it would be a good matchup in
lead up to our review of the Marvels. Right,
yeah, Captain Marvel is a cosmic level hero,
so we're doing a duel with cosmic level bad
guys. Both of these characters are pretty interesting,
so I can't wait to tell you all about them
later on in this episode. Before that, we're
going to break down the comic book movie news
from the past week, of which there was one major
news item, and that was the first Echo official
trailer for the upcoming Disney Plus series.
As always, we list our segment times in our
episode description, so feel free to check out
the show notes if you want to skip ahead to
a particular topic. As our listeners may know,
our duel simulator is so advanced that it's
gained sentience, and has named itself the Artificial
Lifeform for Running Extensive Duels, just
a rather very intelligent simulator, 9000, or
Alfred Jarvis 9000. He has a quick message
for our listeners, so listen up. Why hello there.
Do you love listening and chatting about Marvel
and DC? Then become a part of the dynamic dual
community on Patreon, where you can choose
from three tiers. The dynamic two-o tier lets
you listen to this podcast without ads and
gives you access to its discord chat group,
where you can chat with Johnny DC and marvelous
Joe. The Fantastic Four tier gives you that
and more with two bonus episodes each month,
including bloopers and top ten shows where Johnny
and Joe count down your favorite Marvel and
DC subjects. The X-Force tier makes you an executive
producer of Dynamic Duel, where every month
you help the hosts choose what to review and
who to fight against each other. And finally,
the Dynamite Podcast Network tier allows aspiring
podcasters to create their own battle-focused
show using this Monte Carlo simulator.
Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast. Be sure guys to tune into the
Max Destruction podcast this week which is part
of the Dynomic
We're going to pick Roger Murtaugh from the
Lethal Weapon franchise against John McClane
from Die Hard. That'll be a good one. Also tune
into the Send Your World podcast this Thursday
to find out who would win in an anime battle
between Hashirama Senju from Naruto and William
Vangence from Black Clover. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com
or click in the link in our show notes to listen
to all the shows in the Dynamike Podcast Network.
But with that out of the way, quick! to the
No Prize! A No Prize is an award Marvel used
to give out to fans. Our version, the Dynamic
Dual No Prize, is a digital award we post on
Instagram and in our email newsletter for the
person that we feel gave the best answer to
our question of the week. For last week we
asked, what was your favorite Netflix Marvel
television series and why? And this was coming
off the news that the Daredevil born again series
has got a showrunner in Dario Scartapane who
was a writer on the Punisher Netflix series.
Yeah, it was pretty exciting news. We got quite
a few answers. So we'll break down all of the
honorable mentions before revealing this week's
no prize winner. Our first honorable mention
goes to Travis Herndon, who said, Hey guys,
Travis here. So my pick would have to be the
defenders. I think that show was a pretty good
series. kind of Avengers like having all the
street level heroes team up together to fight
a common foe. Oh, it makes me really hope that
maybe we might get another season or maybe
bring the defenders into the main MCU. So my
pick would definitely be defenders. Yeah. Great
answer, Travis. I actually really like the defenders.
For some reason it gets a lot of shit from
a lot of people, I think because Iron Fist wasn't
that smart in the series and there were some
plot elements like with the the dragons underneath
New York City and stuff that were kind of stupid.
But I really love the interactions between all
four of the defenders characters, including
Daredevil, Jessica Jones, Luke Cage and Iron
Fist. It was the best part of the show and
it kind of felt the most comic booky out of
all of the Marvel Netflix series. So I can
totally see why this could be somebody's favorite.
I mean, for me, the defenders was my second
least favorite Netflix Marvel series. mostly
because I think I had a villain problem, but
I can't deny the fact that it was cool to see
all the characters from these other shows that
we were watching come together, just like the
Avengers movie, you know, it had that same
appeal. For sure, yeah. I hope the Disney Plus
series carries forward the Defenders concept
in some way, shape or form for that platform.
Yeah, it would be really cool if they brought
back the actors for Luke Cage and Jessica Jones
specifically. And the Punisher. And Electra.
Just fucking everybody but Iron Fist. Our next
honorable mention goes to Anson Millard, who
said, Hey, it's Anson Millard. My favorite Marvel
Netflix show was Luke Cage. I feel like that
is the underdog pick for this. So Luke Cage,
I feel like had the best action scenes from
the standpoint of just having one overpowered
guy go against entire mobs of people. I also
love the music in there, bulletproof love. It
was awesome. It's cool that Method Man showed
up and just great villains, great show. Oh,
for sure. There was a lot to love about the
Luke Cage television series, especially season
two, which I was a big fan of. But Luke Cage
brought so many unique things to the table,
including the music. The action was really
awesome, although you kind of wonder why bad
guys even bother to bring guns to their fights
anymore, you know. And for like the Iron Fist
series, you wondered why nobody brought guns
to those fights. They were all martial artists.
But yeah, it was a great series and my culture
was just phenomenal in the role. It is an absolute
tragedy that story was not able to continue
into a season 3. Like I'm still dying to learn
what happened afterward. Right, yeah that was
a great cliffhanger ending for season 2. It
was so godfather! It was so good! Our next
honorable mention goes to Lizzie Dyer Arnie,
who said... Hey, it's Lizzie. 100%, I have
to say, my favorite Marvel Netflix show was
Daredevil. Seasons one and three were definitely
pure perfection. Season two wasn't as good with
the Defenders crossover, didn't like that.
But I mean, you have Matt Murdock. He's a blind
lawyer. He's got elevated super senses and
he's defending Hill's Kitchen. You got Marcy,
Foggy, Karen. They're the best side characters
you can ask for. If they're not in the new Disney
version, I'm really not interested. Yeah, this
is kind of the obvious answer, right? the common
answer, at least two other people gave the
answer of Daredevil because it was phenomenal.
And hopefully Disney Plus can carry forward
that greatness as much as they can with their
upcoming Born Again series. It sounds like
Disney is trying to recapture some of that previous
magic. Except of course when it comes to the
supporting cast, right? Because Karen and Foggy
are not returning and that's really a shame
because a big part of you know any superhero
is his supporting cast. for them to not be
in the upcoming Born Again series is really
a shame, especially since the series seems
at least to have been going heavily down the
road of a courtroom drama, and for Matt to
not have his firm partner there with him in
Foggy Nelson, it's kind of a shame. Well, I
heard the whole reason they're not going with
those actors specifically was because if they
did, they would need to pay the old Netflix
Daredevil show writers like some sort of creative
residuals. and they don't want to do that. That's
super lame. They're Disney. They have all the
money in the world. They should do it. I just
think they really hate Netflix. But oh, great
answer Lizzie, Nate Mantineo and Abner O'Tary
worthy to others who gave the answer of Daredevil
as well. So thanks to everyone who took the
time to visit our website and record an answer.
But the winner of this week's no prize is Braden
Johnston who said, hey, Braden J here. New
to the podcast, I've been loving every second
of it, but I'd say my favorite Marvel Netflix
series would have to be The Punisher. I discovered
it a few years ago, right after I had my daughter,
and so Frank's story really kinda hit home with
me there. And especially getting into season
two, that's where everything got amplified for
me. Just the story, the emotional beats, the
action, and everything just got way better after
that. I do feel that since the Punisher Netflix
series came out later, than the other shows,
like after The Defenders aired and everything
like that, the Punisher was often overlooked,
I think, both seasons. But I think that's really
a shame because both seasons were really well
done. I think Jon Bernthal was an incredible
Punisher and it's nice to see that there are
people out there that appreciate the show as
much as I do. It brought so much nuance to the
character of Frank Castle that I think a lot
of other adaptations, they kind of wrote him
off as like this really one note character,
but. to really explore the depth of the Punisher
is to make them so much more interesting. And
I think that was the true strength of the Punisher
Netflix television series. Absolutely, yeah,
I loved this series both seasons. I don't know
if we're gonna get another Punisher series
for Disney Plus, like we're doing for Daredevil,
but the Punisher was supposed to appear in
the Daredevil Born Again series, and we'll see
if the creative reboot changes that. I hope
it doesn't. Yeah, that would be a shame if we
lost the chance to see Jon Bernthal in the
role again. But great answer, Brayden Johnston,
you're the winner of this week's No Prize.
If you the listener want a shot at winning your
own No Prize, stay tuned to later on this episode
when we'll be asking another Question of the
Week. And now that that's done, on to the news!
This past week we got the first official trailer
for the Echo television series that's going
to come out on Disney Plus. Later on next year,
we thought maybe the show was going to come
out in November of this year but it's actually
coming out January 10th on Disney Plus and
on Hulu. The overall tone of the trailer surprised
me. I don't know what I was expecting. Honestly,
I was not expecting much from this Echo television
series but the best thing that I could say
about it is... that it really seems to be carrying
forward the vibe that was set in the Daredevil
Netflix series. I was really impressed with
what we saw here. I'm really hoping that the
trailer doesn't end up better than the show
itself, but at the very least, the trailer
got me hyped, which is what it's supposed to
do. I was also shocked by this trailer. This
show went from the bottom of my list to what
I'm interested in watching to the top for Marvel.
Yeah, I mean, because Echo wasn't all that compelling
in the Hawkeye television series, right? Right.
but to really explore her past with the Kingpin,
and you know, honestly, just to have the Kingpin
back, Vincent DiNardfeo's portrayal of the character
is so freaking impactful. Literally, you see
him just like, pounding this dude into the dumpster,
into the pavement in this trailer. It really
seems to be setting a new tone for what we get
from Marvel Studios and the maturity level,
and of course again, the tone. Yeah, absolutely.
I mean, I've been knocking the Kingpin. as
part of the MCU ever since we saw him in Hawkeye
because I thought Disney really screwed the
character over. But this trailer makes up for
all of that. I recant my blasphemy. He is amazing
as the character. Yo, on Hawkeye, he was a little
bit cartoony, right? Right. But that was just
kind of the vibe of the show. But here, the
vibe is much more keeping with the character
as we know him from previous seasons. And regarding
the whole vibe, it seems like Marvel is introducing
a new brand. for these type of character-driven,
grounded stories, that's gonna be called Marvel
Spotlight, which was the name of a comic book
title that Marvel used to produce to introduce
new characters or put a spotlight on lesser-known
characters within the comics. Yeah, this will
be Marvel Studios' first sub banner, which is
interesting, that it would debut with something
like Echo. Right, we've seen Marvel have a sub
banner before when it comes to film productions,
like with Punisher Warzone. and Ghost Rider
Spirit of Vengeance, those were under the Marvel
Knights banner. But that was abandoned. Usually
those productions were other studios. But now
that Marvel owns everything except for, you
know, Spider-Man, they've created their own
sub-brand in Marvel Spotlight, which I think
is pretty interesting. I don't know if it's
entirely necessary. Do you think it means that
Echo is not in the MCU? No, I just think people
don't have to worry about whether it is going
to be or not. Okay. Yeah, that makes sense.
Like it's not going to connect to any larger
story. It's just an interesting standalone
story. At the very least, I think it'll keep
this trend that we have among fans to try to
spot Easter eggs and connections to the larger
saga that's going on currently, the multiversal
saga or other television shows and stuff like
that. I think it just allows fans to just focus
on the story as kind of a standalone thing as
opposed to dissecting it to death. And thank
goodness, Oh look, Mephisto confirmed shit.
Yeah, break from that kind of over analysis
is something that I think would extremely benefit
the MCU as a whole. But regarding the trailer,
you know, it starts off with young Echo, Maya
Lopez, trying to order an ice cream from an
ice cream cart and the vendor is being a dick
to her because she's not able to speak given
that she's deaf. For his slight against this
little girl, Kingpin beats the shit out of
him. Maybe to death? We know that in the comics
and in the MCU continuity, Kingpin basically
raises this little girl as if she were his own
and he loves her. He sees a lot of himself
in Maya. I really love the effect they gave
for all of the impacts throughout this entire
trailer of like echoes. Like when the Kingpin
hits the guy selling the ice cream, the sound
of his punch repeats itself. Right, yeah, and
it actually transforms during the course of
the trailer. into more of a Native American
chant toward the end. I don't know if you caught
that, but that was pretty interesting. One of
the things I learned about the show is that
Echo is not gonna have the traditional powers
that she has from the comics in this show.
So if you listen to our question versus Echo
episode that we've done on this podcast, you'll
learn all about the backstory of Echo and what
her actual powers are, which are kind of like
Taskmaster. She's able to view a physical action
and then recreate it through her experienced
physical training. Now, do you think that's
because of Taskmaster and how we've already
seen her in the MCU in the Black Widow movie?
Yeah, I think it's possible that since Echo
and Taskmaster have almost the same powers that
the MCU would want to differentiate that. I
guess the abilities that Echo is going to have
in this show derive from her Native American
heritage, specifically the Choctaw tribe. I
think I'm pronouncing that right. And she basically
calls upon the spirits of her ancestors. which
give her certain abilities. Which is interesting,
I don't know, I understand why they may be changing
their powers. Honestly, I don't love that.
I'm kind of okay with Taskmaster and Echo having
similar abilities. There is a tendency though,
I find, for ethnically diverse characters to
draw their powers from their heritage, which
I don't think is always necessary. I think that's
overdone. I think it's far more interesting
for them to just have powers and not go too
overboard. Because honestly, okay. So I'm all
for inclusion. I'm the biggest proponent of
diversity in comics and television shows and
film, but transforming Echo's powers to be more
cultural like this is almost like changing
Daredevil's radar sense to be like the sight
of God or something because he's Catholic,
right? You don't always have to tie in the powers
into the character's identity. Sometimes it's
better just for the characters to have identity
and then deal with their own powers. Like Blue
Beetle, look at Blue Beetle. His Khajiitah scarab.
actually has nothing to do with his Mexican
heritage, but he's still a fascinating character.
Look at a character like Wolverine or a lot
of the X-Men actually, like Storm, Banshee,
all of these characters that are not so boxed
in with their abilities. Yeah, I mean, I agree
with what you've said, but I also don't mind
the Native American heritage thing. As long
as it's something I've never seen before, I
think I'm interested. If she did have the same
powers as Taskmaster, I'd be like, oh, redundant
character. You know, and I don't want Echo to
be a redundant character. That's a great point.
I mean, you are also coming from the perspective
of someone who's not really an Echo fan or
read any of the Echo comics. Exactly. So you
probably don't give a shit if they change her
too drastically like that. But all that being
said, you're right. If they do it well enough,
it could be fascinating and it could be really
cool to see and a great way to include Native
American cultural aspects. Right. Yeah. And
I'm not sure about what all of her different
powers are going to be. but it does look like
she has the power to kick ass, which is all
I need from the show, really. It was like way
more hardcore than I thought it was going to
be. Oh, it looks super violent. Yeah, you see
people getting straight up shot in the face
in this trailer, which I was not expecting.
One thing I wanted to touch on though, is that
they did reveal what Echo's superhero costume
looks like online. Oh, I did not see that.
Yeah, they revealed it at a Q&A session that
they did at the Chalk.Nation's annual Powwow
event. where they screen the first two episodes
of the show. It looks very much like, you know,
traditional Native American garb updated for
a modern era, kind of like what they did with
traditional African garb in the Black Panther
movie, how it was brought into the modern era.
Looks pretty cool. Oh, interesting. Honestly,
I would have just settled for the white poem
on the face, but this works too. It's a little
bit more colorful than I thought it would be,
especially given that the character of... Echo's
costume in the comics is mostly black and white,
you know? Right. We got the ever so slightest,
briefest of shots of Daredevil in this trailer.
It was kind of like a blink and you'll miss
it type thing, but it looked incredible. He's
like diving across this room or something like
that. And yeah, it looks fantastic. I can't
wait to see Daredevil in the show. But more
importantly than that, I love that they didn't
make that Daredevil cameo the highlight of this
trailer. They kept the focus. on the relationship
between Echo and Kingpin. And I think that's
where it needs to stay. I did blink and miss
it because I had no idea Daredevil was in the
trailer. Is he wearing his yellow suit or his
red suit? It's like black. It's really dark
in the room. It's hard to tell. Huh? Well,
it looks like I'm going to have to frame by
frame this shit now. Oh, yeah. Look at that.
Eh. What do you mean? Eh. Piece of shit. You
know, it's fucking awesome. I'll need to see
more. I can't wait to see more. Yeah. and we'll
see more on January 10th. It's only five episodes
that are all dropping at once, so we'll be reviewing
the show the following Tuesday. But speaking
of the Echo series and the Marvel Spotlight
banner, that brings us to our question of the
week.
Which not currently existing MCU character would
you like to see get their own mini series under
the Marvel Spotlight banner and why? Yeah, and
again, this has to be specifically a character
that we have not seen under a Marvel Studios
film or television series. Yeah, and we'll
include the Netflix characters in that too,
so none of the defenders or Punisher. Record
your answer at dynamicduel.com by clicking on
the red microphone button in the bottom right
hand corner of the screen, which will prompt
you to leave us a voicemail. Your message could
be up to 30 seconds long. And don't forget to
leave your name in case we include you on the
podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer and
award that person a dynamic dual no prize that
we'll post to Instagram and our email newsletter.
Be sure to answer before November 11th.
But I think that does it for all the news for
this episode. Now let's move on to the main
event where we find out who will win in a matchup
between the villain characters of Mongol and
Annihilus.
Okay, Mongul versus Annihilus. As we mentioned
earlier in the episode, both of these characters
are tyrannical, intergalactic villains. Mongul
is primarily a Superman and Green Lantern villain,
although he's gone up against other superheroes
before. Annihilus, if I'm not mistaken, is
primarily a Fantastic Four villain. Correct.
Yes, although he's posed quite the thorn in
the side of all of Marvel's cosmic level heroes,
including the Guardians of the Galaxy, Silver
Surfer, Nova, and whatnot. Right. I don't know
much about him other than that he's pretty
powerful. So I'm actually looking forward to
learning more about him. Really? Well, I'm
not looking forward to learning about Mongol
because he's DC and I don't give a shit. Well,
that's your fucking mistake is Mongols dope.
He's really cool. You'll see. I mean, he wasn't
that dope in the recent Warworld movie, the
animated one. He was kind of that's lame. Yeah,
that's he was actually really lame. He was done
much better in the Justice League cartoon.
And at least he has fucking been on the screen.
We have yet to see anything about Annihilus,
pretty sure. Annihilus has been in a cartoon,
I'm fairly certain. Well, it was shitty then,
because no one knows about it. To explain the
methodology behind your duels, let's go to
our sentient dual simulator, Alfred Jarvis 9000.
AJ9K, tell our listeners how you go about determining
a winner in our dual matchups. Yes, of course,
sir. The way I determine a winner between the
contestants is by running 1000 Monte Carlo simulations
using the characters statistics. A Monte Carlo
simulation is a probabilistic model used to
determine outcomes through random sampling.
In this case, I randomise the statistics along
a normal distribution as a way to simulate
the many variables that can occur during battle.
The stat parameters are based on the official
Marvel power grid from which the DC characters
statistics are extrapolated.
damage potential, versatility and perception
in order to create a more detailed and accurate
simulation. The results of the 1000 simulations
provide a percentage of wins for each character.
The contestant with the higher percentage is
declared the victor as they have a higher probability
to win any given battle. In an equitable pairing,
neither character should win 100% of the matches.
The comic book stories have shown that there's
even a way for Batman to defeat Superman, so
the confidence rate of my method falls in line
with the precedents that have been established
in the source material. My mathematical simulations
are without subjectivity or bias. Feats are
not the sole consideration, nor are fan votes
tabulated for determination of the winner.
Thanks AJ9K! Before we run the simulations though,
we like to break down each character's histories
and abilities before improvising a scenario
on how we imagine one of the 1000 simulations
would play out B for B. And I believe it's my
turn to go first with the Marvel character,
so let me go ahead and tell you all about Annihilus.
Many millennia ago, in the antimatter universe
known as the Negative Zone, a technologically
advanced species known as the Tianans traveled
throughout the dimension seeding life spores
across barren planets. A freak meteor collision
forced one of the Tianan spore ships to crash
onto a planet Arthros, where the crew died.
One of those spores evolved prematurely into
a small insectoid creature. Remarkably intelligent,
the creature struggled to survive, becoming
convinced that everything wanted to kill it
and that it must kill to survive. Eventually
the creature discovered the Tionan Starship
and learned how to use their advanced technology.
Over time, the creature grew in size and strength,
intent on eradicating any threat to its existence.
From the starship's warp drive, the insectoid
built the perfect weapon, the Cosmic Control
Rod, and from the remaining life spores, developed
an army of other insectoid creatures called
the Scavengers. He developed armor for himself,
becoming a paranoid death spot known as Annihilus,
ravaging neighboring planets just to protect
himself from the potential danger they could
pose to him. For Annihilus feared only one
thing, death. After developing a reputation
as one of the Negative Zone's most fearsome
and powerful Warlords, Annihilus encountered
the Fantastic Four for the first time. The
superhero team had traveled into the Negative
Zone when Mr. Fantastic detected the Cosmic
Control Rod as a source of anti-particles, which
they needed to treat invisible woman who was
having cosmic ray-related complications with
her pregnancy at the time. The team stole Annihilus'
weapon and escaped his wrath. though they returned
it after using it to go back home in the positive
matter universe. You can learn more about the
Fantastic Four in their duel episode against
the Justice Society. After conquering much of
the Negative Zone, Annihilus set his sights
on the Microverse and tried to invade Subatomica.
Though he was successful, he and his army were
eventually repelled. Annihilus briefly teamed
up with Mr. Fantastic when the hero was trapped
in the Negative
from taking over both positive and negative
dimensions. After Annihilus formed a truce
with fellow Negative Zone warlord Blastar, he
showed his new ally his newest and greatest
addition to his scavenger army, a robot created
by AIM called the Super Adaptoid. Suspicious
of Annihilus' plans, Blastar's wife sent out
a distress signal to the Avengers, who came
and defeated Annihilus, Blastar, and the Super
Adaptoid. For her actions, Annihilus killed
Blastar's wife, and Blastar in turn stole the
cosmic control rod. Without his weapon of choice,
Annihilus snuck onto Earth and took Mr. Fantastic
and Invisible Woman's son, Franklin, hostage,
forcing the Fantastic Four to go into the Negative
Zone and confront Blastar to get it back. Though
Annihilus planned for his army to invade Earth's
dimension through a portal in the
The Fantastic Four, alongside the Avengers,
were able to stop Annihilus. Later, he tried
to invade the realm of Asgard when it temporarily
drifted into the Negative Zone at a time when
its Bifrost Rainbow Bridge was shattered. Annihilus
was able to defeat every Asgardian warrior,
including Thor, but was ultimately defeated
by Odin. Unable to accept his defeat, Annihilus
kidnapped Odin in his sleep, and then lost in
a second battle with Thor. who then returned
Odin back to Asgard, which was now gone from
the Negative Zone. Eventually, Annihilus discovered
his old creators, the once thought lost to time
Tianans, though they were under the control
of another villain known as Brute. Teaming up
with Mr. Fantastic, Annihilus defeated the
Brute and freed the Tianans, though Mr. Fantastic
created a force field around their home planet
to protect the species from Annihilus trying
to conquer them. When a corporation called
the Gideon Trust breached the Negative Zone
to mine its resources, they also stole Annihilus'
Cosmic Control Rod. During his efforts to get
his weapon back, the rod was shattered, and
Annihilus was finally killed. However, upon
his death, his body released a pod containing
insectoid larva that was cloned from Annihilus
as part of his failsafe plan for death. The
larva grew, possessing all of Annihilus' memories
and intelligence. However, it was later discovered
that multiple cloned larvae had spawned from
the pod, forcing one of the Annihilus clones
to kill the rest. This surviving Annihilus rebuilt
the cosmic control rod and discovered a powerful
energy source known as the Opposing Force, which
was the negative zone equivalent to the Power
Cosmic, which is wielded by Silver Surfer and
Galactus, both of whom you can learn more about
in their respective dual episodes. After learning
that the positive matter universe was expanding
into the antimatter negative zone, Annihilus
felt that the positive matter universe was
now part of his domain. Using the opposing force,
he led his massive insect scavenger armada
through the energy surge that separated the
two universes and he led a full assault across
the cosmos that was called the Annihilation
Wave. Annihilus's armies devastated whole galaxies
and an untold number of worlds. He killed a
multitude of cosmic heroes, captured galactus
and all power cosmic wielding heroes, and laid
waste to entire alien empires and species.
It took the combined alliance of nearly every
living hero outside of earth to eventually
stop Annihilus and his wave. But when Nova finally
ripped Annihilus' organs from out of his throat,
Annihilus was merely reborn on a Kree planet
that was ceded to his invasion, and he grew
to his former self back in the negative zone.
Annihilus later killed the Human Torch after
the heroes sacrificed himself to keep the Warlord
from invading the positive matter universe
from a portal in the Baxter building. The Human
Torch was kept alive though using healing worms
that stitched together his body so that Annihilus
might get him to reopen the portal. But the
heroes stole the cosmic control rod and escaped
the negative zone back to Earth. Despite no
longer wielding his weapon, Annihilus proved
to be enough of a threat from his devastating
prior invasion to earn himself a seat on the
Galactic Council as a representative of the
Negative Zone, eventually getting his rod back
after a fight with the Fantastic Four. Later
Annihilus studied the Hulk and learned the secret
of his Gamma Transformation from Bruce Banner.
He used this knowledge to grow into a massive
giant, from there absorbing his entire dimension,
becoming an all-powerful entity in the Negative
Zone. It took the combined efforts of the Guardians
of the Galaxy, Thanos and the Shi'ar Imperial
Guard to stop him, where Adam Warlock devolved
Annihilus into a small bug and Thanos stomped
on him. You can learn more about the Guardians
and Thanos in their respective dual episodes.
Again, Annihilus was reborn in the Negative
Zone where he currently remains, having recently
gained a foothold in the Positive Matter universe
by invading a planet called Praxis II and transforming
it into Annihilation World, which was a new
bridge into the Negative Zone. That's his backstory.
Powers-wise, Annihilus is an evolved insectivoreid
with enhanced physical abilities including increased
strength able to lift 50 tons, increased speed
with flight, and an indestructible exoskeleton
that can withstand even a nova flame. He's
virtually immortal as his cosmic control rod
halts his aging, and he has a failsafe for
death involving resurrection via cloned larva.
His cosmic control rod can also fire massive
amounts of incredibly destructive energy, up
to 10 megatons. It can manipulate matter using
the opposing force and create portals within
and to and from the negative zone to travel
through or summon his scavengers or other creatures.
He's a gifted engineer and scientist, though
Annihilus's strategic thinking usually incorporates
some form of overwhelming force. His one weakness
is his mouth, as it's a way to get past his
exoskeleton. into his more vulnerable interior.
And that's Nihilus. I mean, I guess that's an
interesting backstory. I don't think it's as
interesting as Mongul's, I have to say. But
you know, it's good enough for Marvel. He's
basically as powerful as like a herald of Galactus,
but instead of wielding the power of cosmic,
you know, he wields the opposing force. Right,
yeah, it definitely seems like a powerful dude.
But I think Mongul's got him in this matchup.
Let me tell you all about Mongul. Little is
known about the early life of Mongul. other
than he's the disgraced ruler and former tyrant
of an unknown planet of billions, until an ancient
priest named Archimandite led a revolt that
overthrew Mongol's reign. Stripped of his power,
Mongol scoured the universe for a source of
power that granted him the strength to never
lose power again. Eventually, Mongol learned
of an artifact known as the Crystal Key that
could activate a planetary weapon known as
Warworld. The key was located in a vault on
the fourth planet of the Cygnus star system,
which was stored there by Martian Manhunter
at the behest of a deceased race of peaceful
aliens known as the Largus. After failing to
defeat Martian Manhunter to get the key, Mungo
learned of Superman, and he kidnapped low slain
Jimmy Olsen and Daily Planet reporter Steve
Lombardi in order to force Superman to fight
Martian Manhunter and get the key for him.
Which Superman did. You can learn more about
Superman in our Superman vs. Dr. Doom episode.
After Martian Manhunter rescued Superman's friends,
he and Superman fought Mongul together, though
Mongul was able to teleport himself and a ship
away as soon as he got his hands on the key.
After Mongul successfully activated Warworld,
the psychic link he now had over the planet
overwhelmed him when he attempted to destroy
Superman, and Mongul was forced to flee the
battle. Later, Mungoal was able to defeat Starman
on the planet Throneworld, a world capable
of destroying other planets, and took control
of its superweapon. Superman intervened by
rescuing Starman, however, and Mungoal was once
again forced to retreat. Desperate for revenge
against Superman, Mungoal infected the hero
with a parasitic psychic plant known as Black
Mercy on Superman's birthday that placed Superman
in a paralyzed dream state. where he dreamt
that he had grown up on the planet Krypton,
which had never exploded. Superman's mind rejected
the illusion, however, and he broke free of
the Black Mercy, before Mongul himself became
infected and trapped in a never-ending dream
of universal conquest. After the Crisis on
Infinite Earth storyline merged to DC's multiverse
and created a new continuity, Mongul was once
again in control of Warworld, with which he
conquered and enslaved entire star systems.
To distract and control the denizens of his
empire, Mongol hosted gladiatorial games on
Warworld that were fought by the strongest among
those he had enslaved. During a time when Superman
had exiled himself from Earth after killing
Zod, he was captured by Warworld, and Mongol
forced Superman to compete in the arena. Superman
rose amongst the gladiatorial ranks to Mongol's
disdain, and Mongol arranged a battle between
the hero and Warworld's fiercest warrior, an
alien known as Draga. when Superman defeated
Drago but refused to kill him, challenging
Mungo in rebellion instead. An enraged Mungo
attacked and nearly killed Superman before
the hero was teleported away by an alien cleric
with ties to Krypton that had been watching
the battle. Superman's act of defiance spurred
a rebellion on Warworld, and Drago was able
to defeat Mungo and take control of the giant
weapon after removing Mungo's crystal amulet
that he wore on his chest. Swearing revenge
and stealing a city-sized space cruiser, Mongul
fled Warworld, which was later taken over by
the villain Brainiac, who you can learn more
about in our Brainiac vs Ultron episode. Mongul
ended up on a small planet known as Paraton
V, which he was able to conquer easily due to
its technological inferiority. Mongul's starcraft,
however, became infected by the mind of Hank
Henshaw, who would later become Cyborg Superman,
and who managed to overpower Mongul. as its
ship was the most advanced technology accessible
on the planet. After Superman's death at the
hands of Doomsday, Mongol traveled to Earth
under Cyborg Superman's orders and used his
Starcraft to destroy Coast City, the home of
the Green Lantern, Hal Jordan, who you can learn
more about in our Green Lantern vs. Nova episode.
In place of Coast City, Mongol quickly constructed
a massive engine, which he named Engine City,
and gave it to Cyborg Superman, who had framed
another Superman imposter known as the Eradicator
over Coast City's destruction. With plans to
betray Cyborg Superman and destroy Metropolis
in an effort to create a second engine as part
of an overall plot to turn Earth into a new
war world, Mongol's plans were foiled by the
real Superman, who by this point had returned
from the dead. Though Mongol nearly succeeded
in killing Superman as Engine City was powered
by kryptonite gas, a rage-fueled Green Lantern
overpowered Mongol, who was imprisoned on Earth.
After escaping prison multiple times, Mungle
was transferred to a satellite prison orbiting
the moon, where he was forced to undergo experimental
mental reconditioning to pacify him. Mungle
fooled the scientists there into believing that
their methods were working, and when opportunity
struck, Mungle slaughtered everyone on board
and fled the solar system in a spacecraft.
Though he nearly died adrift in space after
his ship was randomly attacked, he was rescued
by the peaceful citizens of the planet Debstam
IV. which he quickly conquered. Unwilling to
be ruled over and succumbing to a fatal disease
that Mongol had unknowingly brought to the
planet, the citizens of Depstem IV sabotaged
all spacecrafts and committed suicide, trapping
Mongol on the planet with no one to rule over
save for two children, a son and daughter that
he had fathered that were immune to the disease.
Mongol was eventually teleported to Earth by
the demon Niron, who made an example of Mongol
by killing him in front of Earth's other villains.
Mongul's son, known as Mongul II, grew rapidly
and studied his father's legacy. After several
battles with the Justice League, Mongul and
his sister Mongal were teleported to their
home planet, where Mongul killed his sister.
During the Blackest Night event, Mongul II's
father returned as a Black Lantern and killed
all of the slaves that his son had acquired.
Escaping his father, Mongul II acquired Yellow
Lantern Rings by killing Yellow Lanterns, wearing
one ring on each finger of his right hand. Mongul
assumed control over the Sinestro Corps, which
he renamed the Mongul Corps after taking control
of Warworld and making it the Corps' new homeworld
base. Sinestro later confronted Mongul, however,
and, using a failsafe that Sinestro built into
each of the Yellow Lantern Rings, defeated Mongul
and retook control of the Corps. In post-Flashpoint
continuity, Mongul was now Mongul the 1791st,
and was revealed to be the descendant of a
long line of rulers within a race of alien conquerors
known as the War Zun, inhabitants of the ancient
and powerful Warworld Prime, which had been
created by the Old Gods. After assuming control
of Warworld Prime once again, dwarfing the other
Warworlds, Mongul
over his core of yellow lanterns. Though he
nearly succeeded, Sinestro turned Mongols hired
mercenaries against him, and later Mongul was
killed by his son, Mongul the 1792nd, who now
rules over Warworld. The powers-wise, Mongul
possesses vast strength and durability natural
to the war-zoon race, who live upon the harsh
environment of Warworld. The crystal amulet
embedded on his chest passed down from the very
first Mongol ruler, only increases his power
and allows him to emit powerful energy blasts
from his chest, eyes, or hands. Mongol also
possesses an array of technological trinkets
that allow him to teleport, shrink others into
small energy cubes, and mentally control Warworld,
a planet-sized weapon equipped with missiles,
energy cannons, and war machines that can conquer
and destroy other planets. Mongol is also a
strategic and scientific genius, having created
a genetically modified Black Mercy parasitic
plant to induce paralysis by physically bringing
about the hosts worst nightmares. And that's
Mongol. Why does his story seem like a rip off
of the movie Gladiator? Like why is DC so unoriginal?
Dude, I thought the same thing, but apparently
gladiators rip off of the Mongol story. It's
crazy, right? Somebody better sue Universal
Pictures is all I'm saying. That's also what
I'm thinking. Although who knows, next year
Universal may own Mongol, so they'd just be
suing themselves.
But now that we've got their histories and abilities
out of the way, let's speculate on how one
of the 1000 simulated matches will go. The winner
is determined by simulations, not the speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how this fight could
play out. Alfred Jarvis9000, what are the rules
of our speculation? Well, I should say there
are no rules, other than the characters have
no prior knowledge of the other going into the
fight. All they are aware of starting out is
that the other character is a threat that needs
to be eliminated. For the speculation, the
contestants will begin approximately 50 meters
apart in a non-descript environment that will
have no bearing on the match itself, as no environmental
statistics are considered in my simulations.
The contestants must earn victory on their own
merit. Alright then, let's get into it. Mongol
and Annihilus meet on the battlefield? Who goes
first? I'm going to say that Annihilus goes
first because he seems more maniacal than the
more like brooding Mongol. So Annihilus starts
off by blitzing Mongol, reaching him in less
than a second, and just flying into him and
tackling him to the ground. Okay, except that
Annihilus tackles nothing but air, cause Mongol
teleports out of the way, poof. And when Annihilus
stops to look for Mongol, that's when Mongol
reappears behind him, and with like a single
punch, just knocks Annihilus into the horizon,
to where Mongol teleports and is waiting for
him. All right, well. Okay, so Annihilus, you
know, he skids across the floor a few times
and then lands at the feet of Mongol again,
uh, looking up at him. But that's exactly where
Annihilus wants him. Because from the ground,
he's gonna fire a blast of cosmic energy from
his cosmic control rod right up at Mongol.
And the blast is so massive, it sends Mongol
literally into space, into the orbit of whatever
planet they're fighting on. And Mongol can't
fly, so he's like, Whoa! you know, spinning
around the world. But a Nihilus can fly and
he flies up to Mongol and just like lands this
massive uppercut into Mongol's big ass target
of a chin. Well, I wouldn't say that Mongol
can't fly. I think there's been some feats where
it's shown that he can, but it's extremely
rare. Mostly he's seen as like more of a leaper,
like the Hulk. But sure, yeah, he's in space
right now. And you know, he's definitely caught
off guard. but as he's tumbling through space,
that's when he summons War World into the planet's
orbit, which beams both him and Annihilus to
the planet's surface. So now this match is gonna
take place in War World's battle arena. Nice.
But I'm gonna say that if like, Mongol can summon
War World into this match, then Annihilus can
summon his Annihilation Wave. Okay? Okay. That's
only fair, right? So he's gonna open up this
portal into the negative zone using his Cosmic
Control Rod. and through it is gonna come this
entire fleet of insectivored ships and they
just arrive like a plague of locusts just blotting
out the stars with how dense their numbers are.
Okay that's fine you know Warworld is gonna
be busy blasting all these ships to smithereens
and meanwhile Mongol he's gonna fire his own
energy blast from his chest crystal which just
sends a Nihilus crashing into the edge of the
arena and Warworld citizens are like Maaagol.
Yeah, and those chants quickly turn into shouts
of, Oh my god, we're fucking dying! When the
Annihilation wave just starts nuking the shit
out of Warworld, just everything around the
battle arena and the whole planet is just getting
blasted to bits, there's devastation everywhere,
but you know, Annihilus doesn't care because
he's indestructible. And as the gladiatorial
arena's floor opens up from being split from
the destruction, Annihilus is gonna rush up
to Maagol. grab him and then slam him through
the planet's surface. Oh, you know who else
doesn't care about what's happening around
them? Mongol. Cause those nukes that are coming
from the annihilation wave ships aren't doing
shit besides revealing new layers of weaponry.
Like each Mongol ruler essentially created
a new layer of weaponized surface to Warworld
Prime. So we've got like almost 2000 more layers
to go here. So as Annihilus slams Mongol onto
the next surface, Mongol just kicks Annihilus
like miles away, and Annihilus in turn gets
slammed by a massive targeted missile that
just obliterates Annihilus along with like the
next three layers of Warworld's surface, like
leaving this giant crater. Oh yeah? Forcefield!
Damn it! So in the center of this crater that
Mongol just blasted in his own planet is Annihilus
surrounded and protected by this personal cosmic
energy forcefield. It protected him from the
blast. So he's fine and he's gonna fly up to
join the Annihilation Wave ships and he's gonna
board the greatest of their ships which is
called the Harvester of Sorrows. And that was
a ship that the Annihilation Wave used to destroy
planets and it literally uses the planet's energy
as fuel. So the Harvester ship is just gonna
send out this planet-sized energy blast that
consumes Warworld with Mongul on it. I mean
like maybe like a baby planet-sized energy blast
like World Prime. No! is pretty fucking huge.
Dude, the Annihilation Wave has destroyed plenty
of planets of all sizes, some that were multiple
times the size of Earth, so. Dude, big whoop,
Warworld can destroy entire suns. So it meets
this ship's energy blast with its own, and when
the beams collide, it's gonna generate this
massive explosion that destroys not only the
Harvester of Sorrows, but the entire annihilation
wave. And Annihilus, obviously. Okay, this has
to be like a massive explosion. If this explosion
is big enough to destroy the entire annihilation
wave, that explosion is also gonna destroy
Warworld too. Like there's no way around that.
So like in the midst of space, there's all
this debris from the planet and the ships and
there's bodies everywhere and devastation,
but surviving it all in the center of it is
Annihilus. The indestructible Annihilus just
floating in the middle of it all. Mongols vaporized.
Marvel wins. I don't know what makes you think
that Warworld would get annihilated by this.
Like, it's a fucking tank planet. Yeah, and
the Annihilation Wave is a big-ass armada. Okay,
well I mean, you're probably right that Mongol
wouldn't survive a blast that could also destroy
all of Warworld Prime, as ridiculous as that
is. So sure, Annihilus is floating out there,
you know, feeling victorious. Except that the
whole thing was a dream. What? When Mongol first
teleported behind Annihilus at the beginning
of this match, instead of punching Kim, he really
just infected Annihilus with the Black Mercy
parasitic plant, which paralyzed Annihilus and
gave him this delusion of this epic battle
in which he came out on top. But in reality,
While Annihilus is just standing there grinning
like an idiot lost in thought, that's when Mongol
is just going to reach down his giant ass mouth
and tear his spine out. Except that whole idea
is stupid and I hate it. I honestly forgot
entirely about the Black Mercy plant. But we'll
leave the scenario there. Either one of two
things happens depending on the results of this
match. Either the most epic battle of all time
happens where a whole planet and armada of ships
is with Annihilus standing victorious through
it all, or Mongol just made it all a dream with
a parasitic plant and then rips out Annihilus'
spine through his throat. That's the boring
way, mine is the cool way. Hopefully Annihilus
wins this and that epic battle really happened.
But let's go ahead and enter the character
stats and run the simulations and find out which
character is going to win. AJ9K, hit it! Inputting
data. Running calculations. Processing results.
Simulations complete. So stats wise, the two
characters were pretty even on a number of categories.
You know, they're both extremely durable, they
could both deal a ton of damage, and they both
have about equal range and intelligence. There
were a number of differences though. We said
that Annihilus was faster just through the
speed feats he has. Mongol is not quite as fast
as Annihilus, seemingly according to their
actions in the comics. Annihilus is also more
evasive. than Mongol considering that not only
can he fly, but he also can produce force fields
using his cosmic control rod. And it's not
like Mongol doesn't move again, he's sort of
like the Hulk in that regard, but he does sort
of enjoy also tanking a lot of shots. Yeah,
in place he's got a big old head and that thing's
not dodging anything. We did say Mongol was
stronger than the Nihilus, definitely for sure,
as well as a better fighter. Annihilus is kind
of just like this crazed maniac brawler guy,
but Mongol actually has a significant amount
of fight training and experience. Right. Exactly.
So considering all that, Jonathan, who is coming
out on top in this match? It's got to be Mongol.
Like, he's way stronger and, you know, he's
just as durable. It's got to be Mongol. This
guy could take on Superman. He could take on
Wonder Roman. There's no way in hell he can't
take on fucking Annihilus. Just this little
bug that can be squashed. Though it looks like
Instagram both agrees and disagrees with me
because it was a 50-50 split on who they thought
would come out on top in this match. And that's
pretty surprising because we got quite a number
of votes for this one, like around 30 or 40
or something like that. Yeah. So the fact that
it came out pretty even makes me think that
this was seemingly a pretty even matchup. Yeah,
it definitely looks like both characters have
their share of fans. Let's find out if this
was an even matchup by revealing the winner.
8g9k the results please. Here you are sir.
Alright the winner between the cosmic villains
of mongol and anialis is Anialis But it was
really close These guys went tit for tat Not
quite even But definitely measuring up to each
other Anialis only won 504 matches out of 1000
Holy shit! Barely squeaking over 50% at 50.4%
where Mongol won 496 matches at 49.6%. Holy
shit that is really close. These results have
got to be the closest to what our Instagram
followers thought it would be, that we've ever
done. Maybe, like it was interesting how the
characters weren't very similar stats-wise,
like they had a lot of differences and yet it
still came out as close as a coin toss. I'm
actually glad that it was close because both
characters I think are really cool. I think
both deserved to win. We should note that we
did not factor in Warworld itself or Annihilus's
army into these stat figures. Right, because
the characters have to win on their own merits.
That being said, Warworld is the ultimate weapon
and there's no reason to say why Mongol wouldn't
take advantage of using it. Same for Annihilus
with his annihilation wave especially against
a villain as powerful as Mongol. These guys
both have resources, they may as well use them,
you know? I think it makes for a better match
that way. Very true. But that does it for this
duel. Let us know what you thought about the
results by writing to us at dynamicduelpodcast
at gmail.com or by visiting us on Instagram
or X. You can find links to all of our accounts
by checking out our show notes or visiting our
website at dynamicduel.com. And on our site,
you can also find a link to our Patreon page
where you can join our dynamic 2-0 tier and
chat with us and fellow listeners. Our fantastic
4 tier, which gets you bonus content each month.
our X-Force tier that makes you an executive
producer of this podcast, or our newest tier
that lets you join our Dynamike Podcast Network.
If you can't join Patreon, you can still support
the show by signing up for our e-newsletter,
also at dynamicduel.com, so you'll never miss
an episode. Please don't forget to also visit
our website in order to leave donations for
Pop Culture Classroom, which will get you a
digital poster of our upcoming Charity Duel
episode in December, Alfred Pennyworth versus
Edwin Jarvis. Yeah, support a great cause guys,
and let's show them that dynamic dual fans care.
Next week is going to be a review episode.
We're going to review the upcoming Marvel Studios
movie, The Marvels. Jonathan, do you have any
predictions for that one? Yeah, I think it's
going to suck. All right. Well, Jonathan has
low expectations, which means that he's going
to be pleasantly surprised with the quality
of the film. We'll see and probably love it.
All right. But that does it for this episode.
We want to give a big thanks to our executive
producers, Ken Johnson, John Sturawski, Zachary
Hepburn, Dustin Belcombe, Miggy Mathenkean,
Brandon Estergard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yeaton,
Nick Ibbonto, Austin Wazilowski, AJ Dunkerley,
Scott Camacho, Adam Spies, and Andrew Schonk
for helping to make this podcast possible. And
we'll talk to you guys next week. Up up and
away, true believers.