This is a Dynamike Network podcast.
Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the superiority
between Marvel and DC by comparing their characters
and stat-based battle simulations. I'm Johnny
DC. And I'm his twin brother Marvelous Joe.
And in this episode, we are pitting the Doom
Patrol leader, Niles Calder, aka the Chief,
against the X-Men leader, Charles Xavier, aka
Professor X. Yeah, both of these guys are bound
to wheelchairs. They're both wicked smart.
And While one of them has powers and the other
one doesn't, the Chief is highly versatile
and a complete wild card. So I think it's going
to be a pretty good match. We said last week
that this episode was going to be Dorothy Spinner
vs. Moon Girl and Devil Dinosaur, but we're
actually going to punt that duel to later on
next month and we're going to do this one now.
Yeah, before the matchup we're going to break
down the comic book movie news from the past
week of which there was just one minor news
item. In regards to speculation around Gal
Gadot's involvement. in a potential Wonder Woman
movie. And we're also going to bring on Ken
Johnson, the host of the Max Destruction podcast,
to talk about his show. Yeah, as always, we
list our segment times in our episode description,
so feel free to check out our show notes if
you want to skip ahead to a particular topic.
As our listeners may know, our duel simulator
is so advanced that it's gained sentience, and
has named itself the Artificial Lifeform for
Running Extensive Duels, just a rather very
intelligent simulator, 9000. Or Alfred Jarvis
9000. Here's a quick message for our listeners,
so listen up. Why hello there. Do you love
listening and chatting about Marvel and DC?
Then become a part of the dynamic dual community
on Patreon, where you can choose from three
tiers. The dynamic 2-0 tier lets you listen
to this podcast without ads and gives you access
to its Discord chat group, where you can chat
with Johnny DC and Marvelous Joe. The fantastic
4 tier gives you that and more with two bonus
episodes each month, including bloopers and
top 10 shows where Johnny and Joe count down
your favourite Marvel and DC subjects. The X-Force
tier makes you an executive producer of Dynamic
Duel, where every month you help the host choose
what to review and who to fight against each
other. And finally, the Dynamite Podcast Network
tier allows aspiring podcasters to create their
own battle-focused show using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and consultation,
and get you simulation results to announce
on your show. Pitch the twins your show via
email at dynamicduelpodcast.gmail.com or by
reaching out to the Dynamite Podcast them on
social media. Check it out at patreon.com slash
dynamic duel. Pip pip cheerio. Thanks AJ 9k
and thanks to everyone who supports the podcast.
Be sure to tune into the Max Destruction podcast
tomorrow August 16th to listen to a review
of Robocop, the cult classic 1980s film. Can't
wait for that review. Also, anime fans should
check out Send Your World, a new battle podcast
featuring your favorite anime characters. In
the last episode, they found out who would win
between Asta from Black Clover and Meliotis
from Seven Deadly Sins. Tune in this Thursday
for the next episode drop. To listen to any
of the Dynamike Network podcasts, click on the
link in our show notes or visit dynamicpodcasts.com.
And with that out of the way, quick to the No
Prize! A No Prize is an award Marvel used to
give out to fans. Our version, the Dynamic Duel
No Prize, is a digital award we post on Instagram.
and in our email newsletter for the person that
we feel gave the best answer to our question
of the week. Last week we asked, besides Loki,
what other Disney Plus Marvel television series
that has come out do you most hope gets a season
2? And this is coming off of the trailer for
Loki season 2. We got quite a few answers, let's
go ahead and run down our honorable mentions
as well as the no prize winner. Our first honorable
mention goes to Travis Herndon, who said Hey
guys, Travis here. My pick would be a very controversial
pick, but I would say She-Hulk. I feel like
that show could get redeemed with a season two.
Maybe bring in some people who've done the
comics to write for She-Hulk, as well as maybe
bringing in one or two people who've done good
lawyer shows to really make it feel like a lawyer
show with a splash of Marvel heroism. I just
feel like She-Hulk can get a redemption. Yeah,
this is a great answer. that I didn't think
about because She-Hulk is, you know, probably
the worst Disney plus Marvel television show
to come out, in my opinion. But Tatiana Maslany
gave a great performance and the show's concept
has a lot of potential, especially if they lean
more into the like lawyer comedy drama case
of the week type format. Despite the fact how
much I disliked season one, I do think that
the show can be redeemed with the season two.
And that's what I want to see. Yeah, I mean,
as we've seen before, Kevin Feige is, you know,
not above self-correcting when he realizes
that he's made a mistake. Take Trevor Slattery,
for example. I love what they've done with
that character. And likewise, I don't think
She-Hulk, the series, is beyond redemption.
It needs to be redeemed, if anything. So great
answer, Travis. Our next honorable mention
goes to Rick McGrew from the RetroNomopod, who
said, Hey, guys, Rick from the RetroNomopod.
Yeah, I think Jeremy Renner. Taking up his mantle
as Hawkeye would what I'd want to see for a
second season. I like a ground-level hero I'd
like to see what other adventures Haley Steinfeld
would Get up to as Kate Bishop and kind of see
where the relationship evolves to from where
we left off So yeah season two of Hawkeye, I
think is the win Yeah, due to Jeremy Renner's
unfortunate accident that happened last year
It's likely that he wouldn't take a starring
action role within a Hawkeye season two, but
that's completely fine because they did a great
job of setting up the character's legacy in
Kate Bishop in Hawkeye season one. I think
we really need to see where the story goes from
there, and I'm surprised actually that a Hawkeye
season two hasn't been announced yet. Yeah,
same. I mean, considering that Jeremy Renner's
Hawkeye was one of the first main Avengers,
I would really hope to see that a subsequent
season would kind of establish a new Avengers
or sort of push in that direction. because
I think the Avengers team is something that's
sorely missing from the MCU right now that
people are interested in. For sure, yeah, and
Hawkeye season one was definitely like the
most Avengers-y feeling to it out of all the
Disney Plus shows. Great answer, Rick. Our
next honorable mention goes to Anson Millard,
who said, Hey guys, this is Anson Millard.
The easy answer for this is Moon Knight. It
was one of the best received Disney Plus shows.
I think it's the best set up to have a sequel.
in another season. We can finally see Mark
and Stephen work together with their combined
powers but there's also some room for some
drama between them because they like the same
girl can see some more stuff with Jake and
I would love if they tie more into the direct.
It sounds like Anson got cut off there but
I think he was gonna say he would like them
to take more in the direction of the comics.
That's only a guess. because while the Moon
Knight television series was good, it was largely
a departure from the source material. But he's
right. I wanna see where the Mark and Steven
relationship goes, especially with Scarlett
Scarab in the mix. And in the very last scene
of season one, we got introduced to Jake Lockley's
character, who I think can be explored too.
There's still a lot of mysteries within that
show that I think would be fun to see get addressed.
Yeah, it was also nice that the show had some
supernatural elements. I would actually like
to see Gael Garcia Bernal's werewolf by night
character making appearance on the show considering
that you know moon night first made an appearance
in his comic. That would be incredible. That
would be really cool. I'd like to see those
two team up even if it's just for an episode
or something. Just go on an adventure together?
Yeah. Like just steering the moon night show
in that more supernatural horror route would
be really cool. For sure. Great answer, Anson.
We want to give a quick shout out to Christopher
Manotti, Meggy Mathengian, and Jose Marcial
for taking the time to visit our website and
record an answer. But the winner of this week's
no prize is Colby Hentges, who said, Hey boys,
Colby Hentges. I'm going loose with the concept
of season two. What I want is an Elsa bloodstone
series coming out of the werewolf by night.
One shot. It could be a Buffy, the vampire slayer
style monster of the week show of just Elsa
hunting down different monsters every week.
It would be awesome. That's my answer. Hell
yeah, bro. This was a genius answer. Totally
sold me on this pitch. of having a Buffy the
Vampire Slayer take on the character of Elsa
Bloodstone who was first introduced in the
Werewolf by Night special presentation around
Halloween last year. This is fantastic, we
could see the origin of the monster hunters,
get more backstory on her father Ulysses and
the Bloodstone itself, and get introduced to
a lot of supernatural characters from the comics
incorporated into the MCU. Plus we could potentially
get more Manthing, who I think should be the
new Groot. He just- seems like a really fun,
cool character. Which is weird to say, but
it is what it is. And maybe we would even get
more Gal Garcia Bernal as werewolf by night.
He could just cameo in all the shows, including
Moon Knight. So yeah, out of these answers,
I would most want to see a Bloodstone series
for sure. So congrats to Colby Hentges for
winning this week's No Prize. If you, the listener,
want a shot at winning your own No Prize, stay
tuned to later on this episode when we'll be
asking another question of the week. And now
that that's done, on to the news.
Okay, a couple of weeks ago, Gal Gadot gave
an interview to ComicBook.com where she said
that she loved playing Wonder Woman and that
she heard from James Gunn and Peter Safran,
the heads of DC Studios, that they were going
to develop Wonder Woman 3 together. Not long
after that, she did another interview with Flant
Magazine where she explicitly said that she
was invited to a meeting with James Gunn and
Peter Safran and that they told her and she
said this was a quote. you're in the best hands,
we're going to develop Wonder Woman 3 with
you, we love you as Wonder Woman, you've got
nothing to worry about." This kind of caused
an uproar on the interwebs from people who either
loved the idea of Gal Gadot remaining as Wonder
Woman and another project happening in the new
Gunnverse, or just absolutely hated the idea
and wanted Wonder Woman Recast. We haven't really
heard anything from James Gunn regarding this
situation, which is strange considering, you
know, he'll go on to Twitter to debunk any
random rumor that appears on there. But we did
hear from Warner Brothers through a variety
article saying that basically Gal Gadot was
mistaken. There are no plans to proceed with
a Wonder Woman film with her involved at this
time. And there's no Wonder Woman film planned
at all, only the Paradise Lost prequel series
that kind of tells the story of the Amazons
prior to Wonder Woman. being born essentially.
Yeah, if you ask me, I think Gal Gadot was
trying to play to her fan base to force James
Gunn and Peter Safran's hand into keeping her
on as Wonder Woman in the new DCU. I think Gal
Gadot has a disease and it's called Liabetes.
And I stole that from a gift that I posted on
Discord. I don't think her intentions were
malevolent at all. You know, I think someone
asked her for an update and she just honestly
told them what she was told. I think James and
Peter absolutely told her that they're fans
of her as the character and that they would
like to develop a new Wonder Woman movie with
her. But saying you're going to develop a project
with someone does not mean that they're going
to star in that movie. We all know that Gal
Gadot is a huge Wonder Woman fan. It basically
helped make her career. But considering the
fact that this is a whole new fresh start,
it would be really confusing to me if Gal Gadot
continued in the role. I wouldn't hate it though
if she served as like an executive producer
maybe, something like that. She would still
be able to develop the story if she's truly
that passionate about the character. Yeah,
it would be like she was passing on the baton
to the next Wonder Woman in this new universe.
I think that she played the character well enough
that I would like to see her at least partially
involved, even if it's just an executive producer
title, in the new reboot. All in all, while
I do love Gal Gadot as Wonder Woman and think
she's perfect in the role, I don't think she's
the only one who's perfect in the role, or has
the potential to be perfect in the role. And
I'm excited to see what is in store for the
future of the character on the big screen.
Yeah, personally I'm hoping for a full on reboot
and recast, but that brings us to our question
of the week.
Who would you want to direct a Wonder Woman
reboot and why? Now we already asked you guys
who you would want to recast as Wonder Woman
if the role did get recast and we got some
great answers, but now we wanna hear about your
director choices. Record your answer at dynamicduel.com
by clicking on the red microphone button in
the bottom right-hand corner of the screen,
which will prompt you to leave us a voicemail.
Your message could be up to 30 seconds long
and don't forget to leave your name in case
we include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a Dynamic
Duel No prize that we'll post to Instagram
and our email newsletter. Be sure to answer
before August 19th. But that does it for all
the news for this episode. Let's go ahead and
bring on Ken Johnson, the host of Max Destruction,
a Dynamike Podcast Network show that pits your
favorite action heroes from movies and television
against each other. Yeah, I'll get him on the
line right now. Hey, Ken, glad to have you
back on the show since you were last on for
our 2004 Punisher review. How's it going? Great,
except you didn't have me back for Punisher
Warzone, which I took as a personal affront.
We had to call a quick audible on that one because
of Ray Stevenson's passing, but we did want
to have you on for that episode if that is any
consolation. It is. RIP, Ray. You guys did
a great job. I think it was well reviewed. It
was outstanding. I appreciate you guys. adding
me on for Punisher, that was definitely one
of my favorite things to do, uh, and really
kind of put me into where I am now. For those
who don't know, Ken is an executive producer
of Dynamic Duel. And as someone who has some
influence over what we do on this podcast,
he came to us essentially pitching a sister
show to ours, where he would use the Monte
Carlo simulator we use, but for action movie
star fights. And from that idea spawned not
only his show, Max Destruction, but the whole
Dynamike podcast network. So Ken, first off,
thank you for that. Between Max Destruction
and Send Your World, I think we're developing
a pretty neat collection of shows and Jonathan
and I love nothing more than taking credit
for things that we're only tangentially involved
in. 100% and it's my way of influencing from
the bottom. Yeah, Max Destruction has about
14 episodes right now. Your 15th episode is
coming out tomorrow. Your co-host is another
executive producer of the show, Dustin Balcom,
who reviewed Big Hero 6 with us. Ken, how aware
were you at the time when you selected Dustin
to do the show that you were going to be upstaged
to every turn? So it's a very interesting question
and I really appreciate you asking that because
we can finally settle the score. Dustin definitely
upstages me every time. He is the one that's
actually working all the little puppet strings
in the background. I'm not even really a person.
You guys have been talking to an AI program
this entire time that Dustin has created. You
know what? Honestly, it's been a blessing to
have Dustin as my co-host. Previous to this
podcast, of course, I had you call those tactics,
which the longest and worst issue I had with
that is finding a co-host that I could riff
with. It's so much fun to have somebody there
with you, either hyping you up, or trying to
shit on you at every turn, which is, I find
probably the most enjoyable about our podcasts.
And it's right up there with our deli guy, right?
It just spontaneously happened, and I'm so
glad Dustin is willing and able to keep up with
my shenanigans. Yeah, the deli guy is a fictional
character that pops up in every episode of Max
Destruction and is the brunt of a lot of the
collateral damage that happens in... their speculative
battles and it is awesome. But I had to prop
my boy Dustin up because he's part of Team Marvel
on our Discord. But you and Dustin have developed
quite a funny antagonistic relationship and
you guys have speculated on some incredible
fights like Jason Bourne versus James Bond,
Zoro versus Spartacus, Blade versus Riddick.
I have my own favorites so far, but what has
been your favorite episode to record? Oh my
gosh. Okay, so I'll give you my top two. My
first favorite really is Born vs Bond. As a
military professional and representing the United
States, I was glad really to bring home that
win. For America. Yeah, America, freedom, right?
The greatest episode I think I've had the most
fun with is probably one of the last ones we
did, which was Frank Dukes vs Nacho Libre.
I really loved that one. I knew from the moment
that I chose Nacho. I was free to just come
at it as ham-handed as I wanted to. And I have
such love for both characters that no matter
how it turned out, it didn't matter to me. Yeah,
I have the unfortunate distinction of running
the stats for Max Destruction. So all of the
episodes are spoiled for me. I always know
who's going to come out on top. But the speculations
that you and Dustin do are just fantastic.
I have to say I think my favorite episode so
far is the Crow versus Dean Winchester. just
learning about Dean, Manchester. I never watched
the show Supernatural, but it made me interested
in that show because it's like totally the type
of show that I would very much watch and enjoy.
And the crow is just awesome. I loved the fact
that you guys do these battles in environments,
because you essentially say, fuck dynamic duel
and they're not environment scenarios that
they come up with. The environments you guys
establish, like the church for that specific
match was. just so cool as part of the visualization
and the imagination of just thinking about
what was going on as you guys were describing
it. Yeah, my favorite episode I think has been
Jack Slater versus Dr. Smulder Bravestone, which
is essentially Last Action Hero versus Jumanji.
Largely for nostalgic reasons, I just really
have a fond nostalgia for the movie Last Action
Hero, which I remember seeing in theaters as
a kid. I also really liked Cameron Poe and
Axel Foley. I think the speculation on that
was top tier. As hosts, you and Dustin do a
great job of making these two very disparate
characters interact in a way that feels true
to how they would interact while staying true
to themselves and the movie worlds they came
from. So I think that's one of the best things
about your show. Yeah. Well, I appreciate it.
Obviously, the speculation you think would kind
of come easily. I can honestly say that was
the hardest thing to kind of get to. Like listening
to you guys is like, man, I don't know how
you guys think this is hard. You're just talking
up a video game between two characters, but
then, you know, taking these individuals that
you may or may not have a ton of understanding
with. Like you're taking these characters that
haven't been seen on the big screen, you know,
early 90s, sometimes 80s, and then trying to
apply them across the speculation and trying
to make it fun. So, you know, getting the stride
of tit for tat, you know, if I'm going to do
left, he's going to do right, but also not.
choreography, you know, trying not to set it
up prior to having it be spontaneous. And then
for me, always finding that way of putting
the nut shot on Dustin. And it doesn't matter
what character it is. I'm going to find a way
of doing it because I know he's expecting it.
And now I know the audience is expecting it
because I'm getting that feedback. So audience,
thank you. Keep it coming. It really drives
me to excellence, personas. of finding the way
of achieving that goal. For sure. My favorite
nut shot so far actually is when Zoro threw
his hat into Spartacus's balls. That was, I
think, the most creative so far. Really liked
that. Did not see it coming, so kudos. I even
loved the nacho one where he just kind of like
fell over and like hit it from the floor, yeah.
That was great. Speculating battles is almost
like an art form and you guys are doing so
much better than we did at the same stage in
your podcast. Jonathan and I always knew the
simulator could be used for something more than
just comics characters And as movie fans were
super glad you wanted to do an action movie
podcast as a fellow movie fan What are some
of your favorite action movies and can we expect
any of those to show up in future episodes?
So absolute favorite action movies. One of them
is the episode that just came out which is
Indiana Jones so Raiders of the Lost Ark and
Last Crusade are my absolute favorite movies
on earth. They really are. So Indiana Jones
is my favorite and I personally cannot wait
to see how that turns out against Jack Sparrow.
Terminator is definitely up there. So Terminator
2 is the greatest action movie on earth and
I would defy anybody to fight me on that one
and I will legitimately fight you, not Monte
Carlo simulated, but anywhere anytime we will
fight. The Terminator will definitely be showing
up. We're working on that. I really, really
enjoy noir films. Casablanca is not an action
movie per se, but I can't wait to pit like
Dick Tracy up against somebody. So that's going
to be fun as we roll out. So our first season
is only 20 episodes, guys. So after our first
season, we're gonna kind of rework things and
revisit and really take a look at these character
matchups that the audience has been putting
out. and by picking out the ones that we think
would work the best, those are going to be
episodes that will be coming up in season two
and so on. I can't wait to see what matches
you guys come up with in the future. I'm hoping
for Neo from The Matrix and Bruce Willis from
Die Hard. There's so many. Yeah, yeah. Well,
it was great to have you on as part of this
episode. Ken Max Destruction is an awesome show,
and we are super proud to have it as part of
the Dynamite Network listeners. If you love
action movies and you want to see who'd win
in a fight and are interested in hearing all
the creative ways Ken sneaks in a nut shot
into the speculations, listen to Max Destruction
anywhere you listen to podcasts or by visiting
dynamicpodcast.com. All right, Ken, thank you
so much for stopping by and I can't wait to
listen to more of your show and take care. Thanks,
guys. If you guys aren't following Max Destruction
on Instagram, be sure to do so. Ken's often
posting weekly audience match up ideas that
are pretty fun to participate Yeah, it's a really
fun show. Support a fellow Dynomic Network
podcast by subscribing to and following Max
Destruction.
But now let's get into the main event of this
episode, where we find out who's gonna win
in a battle between the Doom Patrol leader,
the Chief, and the X-Men leader, Professor
X.
Okay, the Chief versus Professor X, this is
definitely a mind over matter duel, which are
always pretty interesting to do. It's taken
us a while to determine who we would want to
pit against the Chief, because he doesn't really
have any powers. His superpower is essentially
that he's just really smart. But when it came
down to it, it was really hard not to do Professor
X, considering the fact that Professor X is
kind of inspired by the Chief. Yeah, and the
X-Men themselves were heavily inspired by Doom
Patrol. This duel of course is in lead up to
our 350th episode, which will be a team duel
between the Doom Patrol and the Guardians of
the Galaxy. Now, we all know Professor X is
like the foremost telepathic mind in the Marvel
universe, and a lot of people are probably wondering
why he's going up against the Chief, who seemingly
has no powers, but I think the people who read
Doom Patrol or watch the series and know all
about Niles Calder know that he has a contingency
for everything. That is basically his superpower.
He's so versatile. It's almost like he has every
superpower in like a one time use kind of situation.
That's the impression that I get. So I think
the stats will play out accordingly, and it
should be closer than I think a lot of people
would give the chief credit for. Yeah, anyone
doubting the chief, I think simply doesn't know
the chief. But we're going to rectify that
in this episode. But to explain the methodology
behind our duels, let's go to our sentient
dual simulator, Alfred Jarvis 9000, AJ 9K. Tell
our listeners how you go about determining
a winner in our dual matchups. Yes, of course,
sir. The way I determine a winner between the
contestants is by running 1,000 Monte Carlo
simulations using the characters' statistics.
A Monte Carlo simulation is a probabilistic
model used to determine outcomes through random
sampling. In this case, I randomize the statistics
along a normal distribution as a way to simulate
the many variables that can occur during battle.
The stat parameters are based on the official
Marvel power grid. from which the DC characters'
statistics are extrapolated. Additional stat
categories are included, such as range, damage
potential, versatility, and perception, in
order to create a more detailed and accurate
simulation. The results of the 1,000 simulations
provide a percentage of wins for each character.
The contestant with the higher percentage is
declared the victor. as they have a higher probability
to win any given battle. In an equitable pairing,
neither character should win 100% of the matches.
The comic book stories have shown that there's
even a way for Batman to defeat Superman, so
the confidence rate of my method falls in line
with the precedents that have been established
in the source material. My mathematical simulations
are without subjectivity or bias. Feats are
not the sole consideration, nor are fan votes
tabulated for determination of the winner. Thanks
AJ and IK. Before we run the simulations though,
we like to break down each character's histories
and abilities before improvising a scenario
on how we imagine one of the 1000 simulations
would play out beat for beat. And I believe
it's my turn to go first with the DC character's
backstory, so let me tell you all about Niles
Calder, aka The Chief. Niles Calder was born
with an aptitude for genius. He was a polymath
who excelled in his studies, particularly in
science and engineering. due to his obsession
with the gothic horror novel Frankenstein or
the Modern Prometheus written by Mary Shelley.
Fascinated by the concept of creating life,
Niles built incredible robots and, after obtaining
his doctorate, was given a grant by a mysterious
benefactor who had noticed his work. Niles
created a laboratory and after running experiments
and developing a ray that could reanimate dead
tissue, he traveled the world, learning from
other scientists and shamans the ways in which
to prolong life. While in India during the 1960s,
Niles made considerable progress on a life-extending
formula with the help of a wealthy mystic named
Ashok Desai, whose wife had died during childbirth.
Believing that the formula was nearly complete,
Ashok tested it on himself, and though it worked,
he also activated a latent metagen within him,
turning himself into a living portal to the
netherworld and driving him insane. Ashok's
daughter, Arani, feared her father and ran
away, living on the streets of Calcutta, where
she became deathly ill. Niles eventually found
Arani and married her, giving her the formula
on their wedding night in order to heal her
sickness. Concerned about the motivations behind
his mysterious benefactor, Niles left Arani
in the Himalayas to keep her safe. Niles soon
discovered that his benefactor was a man named
General Immortus. an evil and wealthy despot
and former Nazi who had lived for thousands
of years thanks to a magic potion that he had
lost the formula for and was counting on Niles
to recreate. When Niles refused to finish his
work for Immortus, the villain implanted a
bomb in Niles' chest, which could be detonated
remotely or if Niles attempted to remove it
while he was still alive. Forced to continue
his work, Niles instead orchestrated a plan
in which he manipulated Immortus into shooting
and killing him, stopping his heart. After
which, a surgical robot that Niles invented
removed the bullet and the bomb, and resuscitated
Niles back to life. The operation took longer
than planned, however, and as a result, Niles
was left a paraplegic without the use of his
legs. Initially distraught, Niles eventually
developed a theory that he called the Catastrophe
Curve. essentially believing that traumatic
events such as his own would force people to
adapt and emerge stronger and better than before.
Deciding he needed to stop General Immortus,
Niles saw others who had underwent debilitating
traumas to help him combat evil, eventually
putting together the Doom Patrol, which initially
consisted of Robot Man, Negative Man, and Elastigirl,
each of whom you could learn more about in
their respective duel episodes. against The
Thing, Cyclops, and Ms. Marvel respectively.
Having become wealthy by patenting several inventions,
Niles used scientific means to help each of
the Doom Patrol members overcome the accidents
that left them quote unquote freaks and develop
superhuman abilities as a result. Niles himself,
however, kept his motivations and even his
identity a secret from the team, revealing himself
only as the Chief. It wasn't until numerous
adventures later, during the Doom Patrol's third
battle against General Immortus, that Niles
was forced to explain his real name and backstory
to the team. Several years later, while battling
the villains General Zal and Madame Rouge, Niles
and the other Doom Patrol members decided to
sacrifice their lives in order to stop the villains
from blowing up the small town of Codsville,
Maine. You can learn more about this in our
Madame Rouge vs Mystique duel episode. Upon
hearing of Niles' death, Arani left Asia and
started her own Doom Patrol team to find Niles,
who she believed was still alive. Arani, whose
temperature-controlling metagene was activated
after Niles left her due to his formula, went
by the codename Celsius, and it was later revealed
that her hunch was correct. Niles had survived
the explosion thanks to a force field that
he had activated. after which he went into hiding
from General Immortus and began secretly working
for the US government. Arani died shortly after
Niles' existence was discovered, and Niles
rejoined the Doom Patrol, which reformed with
all new members including Dorothy Spinner and
Crazy Jane, the latter of whom you can learn
more about in our Crazy Jane vs Legion episode.
During the team's adventures, Niles had secretly
been working on his magnum opus, the ultimate
and cruelest implementation of his catastrophe
curve theory. After killing one new Doom Patrol
member known as Tempest for asking too many
questions, Niles was confronted by Robotman,
to whom Niles revealed that he was responsible
for the original Doom Patrol team's traumatic
accidents, along with several others who made
up the Doom Patrol's enemy team known as the
Brotherhood of Evil. Just before Niles could
enact his master plan to detonate a nanotech
bomb that would destroy half the world's population
and turn the rest into freaks, his head was
torn from his body by the Candlemaker, a creature
created from the mind of Dorothy Spinner. Dr.
William Magnus, who you can learn more about
in our Metal Men vs. Colossus episode, managed
to save Niles' head, however, and built a new
robotic body for him. while insisting that
Niles make up for his horrible actions. Wracked
with guilt, Niles removed his own head from
his robot body, after which he existed as a
disembodied head for some time. After rebuilding
the Doom Patrol and merging with one of its
new members, Niles died after entering the
Tree of Life. After the events of Infinite Crisis,
when Superboy Prime altered events within DC's
continuity, the original Doom Patrol, including
Niles Calder, emerged as a team once again,
and while its members were aware that Niles
was responsible for their accidents, they forgave
him. During the Blackest Night event, Arani
was resurrected as an evil black lantern zombie,
and used her powers to freeze and shatter Niles'
legs. After teleporting her and other black
lanterns to the Justice League's location for
them to deal with, Niles set to work on creating
a new body for himself. successfully forming
one from Kryptonian cells allowing him to gain
the powers of Superman. After turning on his
team, he was defeated by the Doom Patrol and
his comatose body was placed in storage. In
post-Flashpoint continuity, Niles Caulder created
a Doom Patrol team consisting of its original
members and Element Woman. After the team learned
from Lex Luthor that Niles caused the traumatic
accidents that turned them into superhumans,
the team disbanded. Niles was able to reform
the team eventually, but they fired him once
they realized he was using them for his own
selfish purposes once again. And that's Niles
Colder's history. Powers-wise, the Chief has
a genius level intellect and is a world-renowned
expert in the fields of robotics, engineering,
chemistry, physics, biology, and many others.
He's developed an array of machines, devices,
and formulas, including Robot Man's body, the
radiation-containing bandages of Negative Man,
a life ray that brings the recently dead back
to life, nanobots that can rearrange matter
itself, an elixir that extends one's lifespan,
and forcefield and portal generators from his
wheelchair. He also packs a gun, so break yourself.
Niles Calder has always been a fascinating character
to me. I think he's one of DC's most interesting
characters, actually. largely informed by my
viewing of the Doom Patrol television series,
but to actually hear the comic book series,
I'm all the more intrigued. It was really interesting
how he ended up in a wheelchair, but I think
it's weird how writers made him go from a guy
who was testing out the catastrophe theory into
like a super villain who wanted to destroy
half the world. I feel like that was a pretty
large leap there.
Don't self pity yourself even though like this
horrible thing happened to you. You can turn
that into something greater. They took that
to its extreme where he believed that catastrophe
was necessary to sort of evolve humanity. And
so he was going to be the arbiter of that.
Delusions of grandeur. You know what though,
Professor X has some dark shit in his backstory
too. Let me go ahead and tell you all about
that right now. Now Charles Xavier was born
in New York City to Sharon and Brian Xavier.
renowned nuclear physics researcher operating
in New Mexico. As a genetic mutant, Charles
began manifesting the earliest signs of his
latent psychic potential while still in the
womb as he recognized his twin as a malignant
presence. Though his sister Cassandra tried
to kill Charles as a fetus, he was able to
defend himself with his telepathic ability,
causing Cassandra to apparently be stillborn.
When Charles was nine years old, his father
Brian died in an accident at the research facility
and his mother Sharon married a Dr. Kurt Marco.
The three moved into Sharon's family estate
in Westchester, New York, where Charles met
his new stepbrother, Cain Marco. Charles' new
stepfather Dr. Kurt Marco was abusive, however,
and relentlessly beat his wife Sharon and his
son Cain, who in turn bullied Charles. The young
Charles not only endured torment at the hands
of his stepbrother, but as his telepathic abilities
began growing in power, he also experienced
Kane's and his mom Sharon's abuse firsthand.
Ultimately, the abuse proved to be too much
for Sharon, and she succumbed to alcoholism.
Shortly after, Dr. Kurt Marco died in a fire
inside their mansion home, leaving Charles and
Kane as orphans. Fortunately, Charles had a
gifted academic mind and was able to graduate
high school and attend Bard College, graduating
with a degree in biology at age 18, by that
point having lost all of his hair. He then
went overseas to Oxford University for his postgraduate
studies, earning master degrees in genetics
and biophysics. There, he met fellow student
Moir McTaggart, and the two developed a romantic
relationship. After college, Charles decided
to join the military, where he excelled in
search and rescue missions through the use of
his telepathic powers. Charles then traveled
the world, ending up working at an Israeli hospital
for Holocaust survivors, where he first encountered
a fellow mutant named Eric Lencher, whom you
can learn more about in our Sinestro vs. Magneto
duel episode. The two men often debated on how
the evolving human race would affect mankind.
While Eric foresaw war and death, Having suffered
his whole life for being different, Charles,
more idealistic, hoped for a future of peace
and acceptance between humans and mutants.
Later, after encountering a destructive, power-hungry
mutant called the Shadow King in Egypt, Charles
realized that the existence of malevolent mutants
would mean he would ultimately have to fight
to protect his cause and convince the human
race of a peaceful coexistence. He then traveled
to the Himalayan mountains, where he encountered
an alien named Lucifer, who was scouting the
planet in preparation for a future invasion.
To prevent any interference, the alien dropped
a massive stone block on Charles' legs, crippling
him. While recovering in Bombay, India, Charles
began working on a device called Cerebro that
would amplify his telepathic abilities and
help him find other mutants. He began psychically
reaching out to young mutants in an effort
to help them control including a young Jean
Grey, whom you can learn more about in our
Raven vs. Phoenix episode. Charles then traveled
back to New York and attended Columbia University,
where he received a PhD in anthropology and
a medical doctorate in psychiatry, before transforming
his family estate in Westchester into an institute
for young mutants. It was there he would teach,
protect, and guide students in the use of their
burgeoning abilities, instilling in them his
dream of human and mutant peace. Charles' initial
students consisted of Cyclops, Jean Grey, Beast,
Archangel, and Iceman, and he called them the
X-Men for their extra abilities. You can learn
more about the team in our Titans vs X-Men team
duel episode. In their first field mission,
the X-Men fought Charles' old friend Eric, now
known as Magneto, who had assembled his own
group, the Brotherhood of Mutants, to enforce
mutant superiority. Over the years, the X-Men
protected humanity from threats such as the
Juggernaut, who was Charles' step-brother,
Cain Marco, now imbued with the power of the
magical crimson bands of Scytoric, a mystic
entity. Charles also directed his team against
the Sentinels, who were mutant hunting robots,
and the Savage Land Mutates, who were experiments
from an Antarctic jungle. Though Charles and
the X-Men saved the Earth time and again, they
never won humanity's respect, and mankind's
fear of mutants only grew. With his reputation
preceding him, Charles joined an elite secret
group of the planet's most influential figures
called the Illuminati, which included Iron
Man, the Submariner, Dr. Strange, Mr. Fantastic,
and Black Bolt, and the group would prevent
sensitive global catastrophes in secret. Eventually,
the X-Men came across Krakoa, a sentient island
that captured the team, forcing Charles to recruit
a new band of mutants to rescue them, including
Storm, Wolverine, Colossus, and Nightcrawler.
As his group of students grew, Charles received
a telepathic message from LaLondra, the princess
of the Shi'ar alien race who sought his help.
Charles and LaLondra fell in love, and after
a mission that seemingly killed most of the
X-Men, he moved to space to live with the Shi'ar
as LaLondra's consort. Charles later returned
to Earth and recruited another young team called
the New Mutants. Around this time he learned
that he had a son named David with a woman he
met in Israel. the young man suffered from
severe psychic trauma and would later be known
as the Mutant Legion. Eventually, the missing
X-Men returned and Charles led the team to fight
Magneto on his orbital asteroid base. During
that fight, Charles mentally shut down Magneto's
mind, which caused the evil portion of the
villain's psyche to implant itself in Charles'
brain. This evil presence, combined with Charles'
vast telepathic power, eventually manifested
into a dark psychic entity called Onslaught,
which took a majority of Earth's heroes to defeat
and nearly destroyed the world. Remorseful
for his part in Onslaught's creation, Charles
turned himself over to government authorities,
who then attempted to use Charles' powers against
mutant kind. Rescued by the X-Men, Charles
helped the team fight the ancient mutant apocalypse,
but faced a more personal psychic threat when
his twin sister Cassandra Cassandra Nova was
revealed to have survived from the womb as
a psychic presence and took over Charles' body.
She exposed Charles as a mutant to the world
and caused the obliteration of the entire mutant
population living on the island of Genosha.
Eventually Jean Grey was able to use Cerebro
to help constitute Charles' mind within his
own body, pushing Cassandra Nova out. Charles
used the publicity surrounding his mutant status
to create the X Corporation,
that would provide resources to mutants in need.
All was not well however, as it was later revealed
that Charles had kept secrets from the X-Men.
Back when the X-Men were captured by the sentient
island of Krakoa, Xavier had recruited a new
team to rescue them, but they perished in the
attempt. Xavier also kept secret that the danger
room was powered by a sentient Shi'ar artificial
intelligence that he had suppressed. The AI
eventually broke free and attacked the X-Men.
After a time, Xavier was able to make peace
with the Danger Room, and he sought redemption
alongside the mutant Gambit in their mission
to stop the evil geneticist, Mr. Sinister.
At one point, Cyclops, who had amassed the power
of the Phoenix Force and had become Dark Phoenix,
killed Charles. With him dead, the villainous
Red Skull harvested Charles' brain and used
it to imbue himself with telepathic powers,
turning himself into the Red Onslaught. After
the Red Onslaught was defeated, it was revealed
that Charles' mind had been abducted by the
Shadow King to fight in a never-ending battle
on the Astral Plane, which is a psychic plane
of existence. The X-Men found Charles and rescued
him from the Astral Plane, with X-Men member
Phantom X donating his body for Charles' mind
to inhabit. Shortly after, Charles implemented
a plan he had been working on with former love
interest
He developed a system in which all mutants could
live in peace and be resurrected through a
process that used a combination of mutant abilities.
Charles sent telepathic invitations to all
mutants, helping to turn Kakoa into an influential
world power, and finally finding a worthy compromise
between his ideals and those of his old friend
Magneto. And that's his backstory. Powers-wise,
Professor X possesses vast psionic abilities
and is regarded as having the most powerful
mind on Earth. With his psychic powers, he can
perform a variety of telepathic effects including
mind reading, mind control, mind erasure, mind
transference, thought casting, illusion casting,
psychic cloaking, psychic shielding, psychic
pain, and psychic astral projection, all at
a range of up to 250 miles or 400 kilometers.
He has a genius level IQ and is the world's
foremost authority on genetics and mutation.
and is an expert in nearly every field of mental
and life sciences, as well as an expert strategist
and diplomat. He is also gifted in engineering,
having created Cerebro, which amplifies his
abilities to a global range and has become
mobile in its latest versions. Prior to his
paralysis, Professor X was a proficient hand-to-hand
fighter, having received combat training from
his time in the military. His weaknesses include
telepathic shielding, such as Magneto's helmet.
and the paralysis of his legs. To offset this
latter weakness though, he rides a hoverchair
invented by the mutant Forge who incorporated
Shiar technology and is controlled via mental
command. And that's Professor X. I totally
forgot about Onslaught. Would we ever do a duel
with Onslaught? The entity itself doesn't have
a huge history on its own, but I guess I could
go into greater detail of the story of Onslaught.
if and when that time came. Okay, cool.
Well, now that we've got their histories and
abilities out of the way, let's speculate on
how one of the 1000 simulated matches will go.
The winner is determined by simulations, not
this speculation, but it's fun to imagine how
this fight could play out. Alfred Jarvis9000,
what are the rules of our speculation? Well,
I should say there are no rules, other than
the characters have no prior knowledge of the
other going into the fight. All they are aware
of starting out... is that the other character
is a threat that needs to be eliminated. For
the speculation, the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the
match itself, as no environmental statistics
are considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. Alright
then let's get into it. The Chief and Professor
X meet on the battlefield. Who goes first?
the chief's mind and learning all about this
guy, who he is, what he can do. OK, I was prepared
for this, though. OK, because I'm thinking like
the chief's brain is a vast labyrinth of knowledge
and experiences that would make like most men's
heads just explode if they ever got a peek.
So, OK, if Professor X ever got a mental glimpse
into that mind, like at the very least, he'd
be so shocked by the breath. of information
and atrocities and just dark thoughts within
the chief's mind. He'd just be like, holy crap.
Right. So that's going to leave the chief at
least a few seconds to pull out his gun and
just shoot Professor X like right in the bald
dome. That is quite the assumption right there.
And I'm guessing a lot of your strategy actually
hinged on Professor X being shocked by Niles
Calder's brain. Yes. You know what? I actually
believe that would happen. I think that Niles
Calder has a really. crazy ass mind judging
by all the crazy ass adventures the Doom Patrol
have been on. So sure, if the Chief needed
to buy himself a second, this is where he buys
it. But also, like then again, Professor X
has dealt with like a lot of disturbed minds
also. So I don't think he's quite as stunned
by the Chief's brain as he thinks he is. I think
he's able to actually avoid the Chief's gunshot
by using mind control at the last second to
throw off his firing can. Okay, that just means
that the bullet's just gonna... hit his hover
chair then instead of his head. And you know,
that's gonna make the hover chair malfunction
and just go haywire. So Professor X, he's essentially
writing a mechanical bull at this point and
he's gonna be too distracted to perform any
psychic attacks. You can't do that to a man
in a wheelchair. What the hell's going on here?
Just did, it just did. Okay, so if Professor
X's hover chair is like flying around, Professor
X. is gonna mentally steer it as best he can
to crash into the chief's wheelchair, just
murderballing the dude. Do you know what murderball
is? Like people know what murderball is, right?
Yeah, I know. It was a documentary about the
US men's paraplegic rugby team. Right. And
in that movie they just knock the shit out of
each other, pushing other wheelchair guys to
the ground. That's what happens here, the chief
is knocked over in his wheelchair. Okay, so
I didn't mention this in my bio, but... The
Chief can walk. What? He doesn't actually need
his wheelchair. Why? He cured himself of his
paralysis a long time ago. He just used the
wheelchair to avoid suspicion and garner sympathy.
Oh my God. What a fucking prick. Yeah, yeah.
That's what Robotman said essentially as well.
So the Chief, you know, he just dives back
toward his wheelchair. and he's going to activate
a button that actually transforms the wheelchair
into this like robotic exoskeleton suit kind
of like robot man and wearing that exo suit
he's going to leap onto professor x's hover
chair and just yank him right out of it and
just like fling him to the ground this dude
sucks but i'm going to say that before the
chief can even lay a hand on the professor x
is going to start erasing the chief's mind
right including his knowledge of how this exosuit
even works. So the chief's not going to be
able to do anything. His mind is just going
to go blank. But like the chief has worked
with psychics on the patrol like Mento before.
So he'd most likely be able to realize if his
mind is being erased. And I'm going to say,
like, once he notices that without hesitation,
real quick, he's just going to whip out the
squirt gun from his jacket and he's going to
spray this anti-medicine. formula onto Professor
X that's gonna erase his mutant powers. Meta-humans
aren't the same thing as mutants. They're basically
the same thing. Chief made a formula that can
erase powers? Well, I mean, he made a formula
that could trigger Meta-Genes and extend life,
so sure, yeah, he could reverse engineer that
to remove Meta-Gene powers as well. The dude's
smart. Like, I'm calling bullshit. I feel like
your speculation hinges on a lot of assumptions.
You don't think Chief would be prepared living
in a world with metahumans to be able to disable
them? I guess he's created so many superpowered
beings it's not out of the realm of possibility
that he has means to depower them. But before
this depowering formula fully kicks into effect,
Professor X, he's gonna reach into the trunk
of his hoverchair and pull out a mobile Cerebro
device, and he's gonna put it on, it's gonna
amplify his power so that before his psychic
abilities vanish, he still has enough psychic
juice to make Chief's mind explode from a telepathic
blast. Force field. Boom. The blast doesn't
reach the Chief because he activates a force
field that includes psychic shielding. All right.
The Chief's then going to launch a capsule
of nanobots from his exosuit at Professor X
and that's just going to disassemble his body
at the molecular level. Essentially, it looks
like he dissolved Professor X with acid. Okay,
sure. Whatever. All right. But if you remember
earlier in this duel, Professor X erased part
of the chief's mind, right? And the dark malevolent
side of the chief combined with Professor X's
psychic power. So now in place of Professor
X is Onslaught. Way to go. And now the chief
is a fuck like a million times over because
Onslaught is going to tear through his mind
and just obliterate it like a boot crushing
an ant. And no force field is going to hold
onslaught back. Match over. So the chief is
dead? Yeah, the chief's dead. Onslaught just
ripped his mind a new butthole. OK, I mean,
jokes on you, though, because once the chief's
heart stops beating, it triggers his exosuit
to emit a life ray, which brings the recently
dead back to life. And once he's back, that's
when he activates a portal to the D creator,
which is this giant eyeball in the sky that
lays its sights right on Onslaught and just
de-creates him. I mean, Niles too, probably.
But Onslaught first, so the Chief wins. Well,
I remember the de-creator from the show. Yeah,
that. That's way more powerful than Onslaught.
I don't think so, but it doesn't matter because
from the very beginning this whole match actually
took place in the Astral Plane, where Professor
X took Chief's mind to play out as like a psychic
illusion this whole match to And now that Professor
X knows what the chief would do and like his
curiosity has been satiated. He's just going
to leave the chief in this comatose state where
he believes that he's been decreated by the
Decreator. How did I know you were going to
go there? It's all an illusion. It was all a
dream. I say it all really did happen and Professor
X was dissolved and onslaught was decreated.
You can't just go back to the beginning of
the match and be like, oh, it never happened.
Yes, I can, because that is one of Professor
X's powers. Haters gonna hate, and mind manipulators
gonna manipulate. So we'll go ahead and leave
the match there and input these characters'
stats and find out which scenario actually
happens when we come back with a winner. AG9000,
take it away. Inputting data, running calculations,
processing results, simulations complete. Okay,
as we predicted, these characters have fairly
different stats. As we mentioned, Professor
X is very one note, and the chief is... quite
versatile. In fact, that was the chief's highest
stat, the versatility. That makes sense because
the chief has a contingency for everything,
right? But Professor X was off the charts in
terms of damage level, considering the guy can
render, you know, like an entire town inert
just by shutting down everybody's minds. And
his range was also ridiculously high considering
he can stretch his mind out to a radius of 250
miles and extend that even further with Cerebro.
Right. We did say though that the chief was
smarter, he had a higher intellect, and he
was more evasive, thanks to the fact that he
utilizes force fields. Yeah, I had a real hard
time conceding even the notion that the chief
is smarter than Professor X. But then you gotta
kinda consider the chief at the same level as
Mr. Fantastic Reed Richards. Yes, Professor
X is a brilliant genius. A large part of that
though has to do with his psychic faculties,
not necessarily his book smarts. Professor X
is the foremost authority on genetics and mutation,
but Reed Richards and the chief can like invent
teleportation devices. So Professor X was lower
in the intelligence stat, but he was much higher
in the perception stat where we accounted for
his telepathic abilities, including mind reading.
Yeah, the perception stat is where the two
characters had the largest discrepancy when
it came to stats. So taking all of this into
consideration. Who do you think came out on
top? Professor X. Gotta go with the main mind
here. As smart as Chief is, he's just not as
powerful. And not only do I think that, a vast
majority of people think that, because according
to our Instagram poll that we put out there,
86% of our Instagram followers think that Professor
X is gonna win. That's a big margin. I guarantee
you though, that is just because of the X-Men
cartoons and the movies. People just love the
X-Men. So of course they're gonna vote for an
X-Man. Yeah, people like the X-Men because
they're more popular than the Doom Patrol because
Marvel's better. So I agree with you. Yes.
Well, let's see how misplaced your confidence
is. AJ 9K, the results, please. Hey, you are,
sir. The winner of the matchup between the Doom
Patrol's chief and the X-Men's Professor X
is. Professor X, you damn right it is. By 60.8.
percent. Professor X won 608 of the 1000 simulated
matches, whereas the Chief only won 392. You
know, that's actually closer than I thought
it was going to be. For as careful as I was
not to underestimate Niles Calder, I still
did in the fact that he got a few more wins
than I thought he would. I mean, you made a
believer out of me. When you first mentioned
this match, I didn't think it was going to
be that great because I figured Professor X
would win. So this isn't really a surprise
to me. But when I started delving more into
the character and was like, hey, maybe he could
pull this off. I really got hopeful and I regret
that now cause I feel bad. Good. Actually,
when you were going into the chief's backstory
and you were talking about how he gave himself
Superman powers and stuff like that, I'm like,
oh no, I made a horrible suggestion, but you
know, I feel really happy about how this all
turned out. Yeah, I mean, the chief has no
powers, but he has tremendous potential. In
the end, though, I guess that can overcome
just the vast sheer might of Professor X, which
sucks. I mean, for you, yeah, not for Marvel
fans. As it turns out, Professor X has a greater
mind. Marvel fans have the greater minds. Wait,
what? Yeah. Yep. You didn't know that? Makes
sense because you're a DC fan that you wouldn't
know something. I can't say no, I didn't know
that because. Whatever. That does it for this
duel. Let us know what you thought about the
results by writing to us at dynamic duel podcast
at gmail.com or by visiting us on Instagram
or Twitter X. You can find links to all of
our accounts by checking out our show notes
or visiting our website at dynamic duel.com.
And on our site, you could also find a link
to our Patreon page where you could join our
dynamic two-o tier and chat with us and fellow
listeners, our fantastic four tier, which gets
you bonus content each month. our ex-force tier
that makes you an executive producer of this
podcast, or our newest tier that lets you join
our Dynamike Podcast Network. If you can't
join Patreon, you can still support this show
by signing up for our e-newsletter also at
dynamicduel.com. Or you could also rate the
show on Apple podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser,
or on our website. Yeah, let us know what you
think. Next week we are going to review Blue
Beetle that comes out this week. Get pumped!
I'm not that pumped. Well, you're dumb, so
it makes sense. Everyone else, super stoked.
Hopefully, you guys got to turn out for this
movie. Like we cannot have another DC box office
bomb like the Flash. It's definitely gonna
happen, man. I'm sorry. We'll find out, I guess.
I'm gonna go see it. I'm taking my whole family
to go see it. I encourage you guys to do the
same. But that does it for this episode. We
wanna give a big thanks to our executive producers,
Ken Johnson, John Snorosky, Zachary Hepburn,
Dustin Balcom, Mickey Mathengian, Brendan Esfregard,
Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Nick Abonto,
Austin Wyslowski, AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho,
and Adam Spees for helping make this podcast
possible. And we'll talk to you guys next week.
Up up and away, true believers. I can read
your mind. And right now you are thinking that
I can't read minds.