This is a Dynamike Network podcast.
Welcome to the dynamic duel podcast a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC By comparing
their characters in stat-based battle simulations
I'm Marvelous Joe and I'm his twin brother Johnny
DC and in this episode We're going to find
out who to win in a fight between the Superman
villain Livewire and the Black Panther villain
claw essentially These are two energy beings
one composed of electricity and one composed
of sound So, yeah, we're gonna find out who
wins between electricity and sound, essentially.
You had no idea who's gonna win, so we can't
wait to find out the answer later on in this
episode. Before that, we're gonna break down
the latest comic book movie news to come out
this past week, of which there was one major
news item. According to Jeff Snyder, renowned
Hollywood journalist, Deborah Anwalt and Elden
Henson will be returning as their characters
of Karen Page and Foggy Nelson in Daredevil
Born Again. It's great news! As always, we
list our segment times in our episode description,
so feel free to check out the show notes if
you want to skip ahead to a particular topic.
Our artificially intelligent dual simulator,
AJ-9K, has a quick message for our listeners,
so listen up. Why hello there. Do you love
listening and chatting about Marvel and DC?
Then become a part of the dynamic dual community
on Patreon, where you can choose from three
tiers. The dynamic 2-0 tier lets you listen
to this podcast without ads and gives you access
to its Discord chat group, where you can chat
with Johnny DC and Marvelous Joe. The fantastic
four tier gives you that and more with two
bonus episodes each month, including bloopers
and top 10 shows where Johnny and Joe count
down your favorite Marvel and DC subjects. The
X-Force tier makes you an executive producer
of Dynamic Duel, where every month you help
the hosts choose what to review and who to
fight against each other. And finally, the Dynamike
Podcast Network tier allows aspiring podcasters
to create their own battle-focused show using
this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe
will help you develop your show, provide graphic
support and consultation, and get you simulation
results to announce on your show. Pitch the
twins your show via email at dyna or by reaching
out to them on social media. Check it out at
patreon.com slash dynamicduel. Pip pip cheerio!
Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast. Be sure to tune in to the Max
Destruction Podcast guys, part of the Dynamike
Podcast Network which last week found out who
would win in a fight between Severus Snape from
Harry Potter and Wong from Doctor Strange.
This week I'll actually be guesting on Ken's
show as we find out who would win between Michael
Keaton's Batman from the 1989 Batman and Matt
Salinger's Captain America from the 1990 Captain
America film. That's right. Max Destruction
is doing a Marvel vs. DC episode, and if you
want to find out who'd win between Batman and
Captain America, at least those versions of
the characters, listen to his show Wednesday,
January 15th. Meanwhile, on the Sandro World
podcast, host Zachary Hepburn speculates on
fights between your favorite anime characters.
This week, we'll find out who would win between
Killer B from Naruto against Blackstar from
And in the newest show in the Dynamite Podcast
Network, Console Combat, hosts John and Dean
find out who would win in fights between your
favorite video game characters. In yesterday's
episode, they speculated on who would win between
Cervantes from Soul Calibur and Scorpion from
Mortal Kombat. So be sure to check that out.
Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link
in our show notes to listen to all of the shows
in the Dynamite Podcast Network. But with that
out of the way, quick to the no prize. A no
prize is an award Marvel used to give out to
fans. Our version, the Dynamic Dual No Prize,
is a digital award we post on Instagram and
in our email newsletter for the person that
we feel gave the best answer to our question
of the week. Last week's question we asked,
who would you cast as the sentry in the MCU's
Thunderbolts film? And that's coming off of
the news that Steven Yeun has departed that
role for that movie. You got a lot of great
answers. Let's go ahead and run down our honorable
mentions as well as the no prize winner. Our
first honorable mention goes to Scott Camacho,
who said, I'm going to go ahead and state the
obvious and say Henry Cavill. I mean, he's
worked with Superman. So, you know, he has the
goody two shoes parts of Sentry. And for the
void, his work with the Witcher and being a
villain in Mission Impossible, I think he has
the acting chops and the star power to pull
that character off. So I've heard this answer
before and I've always hated it. But now who
we know that Henry Cavill is not returning
to the role of Superman. Sure. Why not make
him the century? I actually think that would
be really cool. And I would love to see the
actor again in a superhero role. Absolutely.
I mean, the guy is very superhero esque in his
appearance. I think he'd be a fantastic century.
The character is often seen as an analog to
DC's Superman. So, yeah, if he played Superman
for DC, let's have him play the analog for Marvel.
I think he'd be a great get. It would also
be like the ultimate troll from Marvel 2 Warner
Brothers. Exactly, exactly. I'm surprised actually
Jonathan you're going along with this because
I think it's a great idea. Well this would
be punishment for not hashtag restoring the
Snyderverse. WB gets what's coming to them.
Great answer Scott Camacho. Our next honorable
mention goes to his twin brother, Gil Camacho.
Who said? Hey guys, Gilimacho here. I know a
lot of people are probably thinking Henry Cavill
should be a good recruit for Sentry. just so
we can punch a gut to DC. But since we both
have Luke and Chris Hemsworth, I think it should
be Liam Hemsworth. All right, guys, thank you.
Yeah, why not round out the Hemsworth brother
trio and get Liam Hemsworth in the role as
the Sentry. Now, some people may balk at the
idea of casting both brothers in the MCU, but
there's precedent given that Luke plays the
thespian version of Thor in Thor Ragnarok and
Love and Thunder. But also, the Sentry kinda
looks like Thor in the comic books. You know,
they're both like big buff dudes with long blonde
hair. Although Liam Hemsworth does look kinda
weird with long light colored hair. Have you
seen him as the Witcher? It's weird! No. Hahaha.
I don't think it's a bad option. I think it's
a pretty solid option. I think it could work,
yeah. Great answer, Gil. Our final honorable
mention goes to Matt Estes, who said... Hey
guys, Matt Estes here. Hey, I think Alexander
Ludwig. From Vikings, he played Bjorn Ironside,
would be a great pick for this entry. He's got
the look and he's got the acting chops. Yeah,
offhand, I didn't remember who Alexander Ludwig
was until I looked him up, but I totally recognize
him as the main villain of the first Hunger
Games movie, and from Vikings. The guy looks
the part of this entry to a T. He has some big
roles under his belt, and also, I don't think
he'll cost Marvel a dime. Yeah, honestly, there
are a lot of actors from the Vikings series
that can play superhero roles. I'm still waiting
for Katherine Winnick to join DC in some kind
of role. She needs to be there. She's awesome.
Yeah, I remember when she was the front runner
on my wishlist to play Captain Marvel. But great
answer, Matt Estes. We want to give a quick
shout out to Mitchell Smoothie, Cornelius Robinson,
and Corey Wooten for taking the time to visit
our website and record your answers. But the
winner of this week's Snow Prize is... John
Spees. and Ryan McMullen, who both gave the
same answer. Let's hear both of them. Hey guys,
John Speas here. My pick for the century would
be Alexander Skarsgård. I know his father's
already been in the MCU, but Alexander is tall.
We know he can get fit from his time as Tarzan,
and he's got that Swedish blonde hair that I
think would work really, really well. So he
is my pick, Alexander Skarsgård. Hey guys, it's
Ryan McMullen here. Hi. choice for the Sentry
would be Alexander Skarsgard because that guy's
got the look, right? He could definitely be
the Sentry. Nobody else hands down is him. Yeah,
both of these are great answers. Not only does
Alexander Skarsgard have the look though, he
also has the intensity, I believe, for the
role, which would be required to play a mentally
unstable character like the Sentry. Oh sure,
yeah, did you see him in the Northman? That
was a great role for him. No, but I saw the
trailer for Infinity Pool because I was too
afraid to watch the movie and holy shit, this
guy could act. Yeah, he's a leading man. I have
no doubt that he would make the perfect century
and I think a lot of fans would be super excited
to see him in the role because he is to a T
the perfect century. It needs to happen. You
know, I did see him in recently that I thought
he was really good in the final season of Succession.
He was incredible in that role. like really
menacing and like really intelligent. So yeah,
that's the perfect way to describe the century.
If Kevin Feige cast Alexander Skarsgard in the
role of the century like tomorrow, I guarantee
you MCU stock would go up. Fans would be all
over that. Absolutely, yeah. It would save
the box office. Do it Kevin Feige, do it for
the fans. So congrats to John Spees and Ryan
McMullen. John is a long time friend of the
show. You know, him and his brother Adam have
guessed it on. this podcast on numerous occasions.
They recently ended their nostalgic movie podcast,
The Blast From Our Past, and we are super sad
to see it gone. And Ryan McMullen, I think
this is the first time we've heard from you.
Way to crush it out of the gate. Absolutely.
If you, the listener, want a shot at winning
your own no prize, stay tuned to later on this
episode when we'll be asking another Question
of the Week. And now that that's done, on to
the news.
Alright this past week we got some awesome news
in regards to the Disney Plus upcoming television
show Daredevil Born Again. Now we learned like
a couple months ago that the entire series
is being retooled under the new showrunner Dario
Scartapin and with that news Jeff Snyder is
reporting via his blog The Insnyder that Deborah
Ann Wall and Elden Hansen will be reprising
their roles as Karen Page and Foggy Nelson in
the upcoming Daredevil season. Fantastic. Yeah,
it's super exciting because previously we had
heard the exact opposite of that, that they
weren't returning because then Disney would
have had to have paid the old Netflix writers
as like creators of the show. Yeah, something
weird like that. But I'm glad that Skardepain
realized that Foggy Nelson and Karen Page were
a huge part of the appeal from the Netflix
series. The chemistry between those three cast
members was spot on and a big part of what
made the show enjoyable. Yeah, totally. I really
hope that this means that The Netflix series
is made canon in the MCU. That would be fantastic.
Well, interestingly enough, if you go onto
the Disney Plus Marvel Hub page, the Netflix
series have been added to the official Marvel
timeline in their menu. A what? Yeah, so it
looks like those shows are actually being treated
as canon now. Wait, even Iron Fist? Even Iron
Fist. Whoa. Now, of course, that doesn't guarantee
that the actors will be. cast the same in future
appearances. But we know that a lot are returning,
including Charlie Cox, now Deborah Anwalt, Elden
Hansen, Jon Bernthal will be returning as the
Punisher, as it's expected that he will still
retain his cameo on the Daredevil born again
series. And there are also rumors that Kristen
Ritter will be returning as Jessica Jones in
a cameo. So lots to look forward to. Super excited
with the new direction that Dario Scartapin
has taken this series. and really bringing Marvel
fans what they want. The series doesn't currently
have a premiere date yet, but it's expected
to come out in 2025. Can't wait for that. Of
course, if you want your immediate Daredevil
fix, you can see him for approximately 90 seconds
as he cameos in the Echo television show. I
haven't seen that yet. Is it really only 90
seconds? Yeah, it's only for one fight scene.
What a rip off. I guess if you really want
your Daredevil fix, just rewatch the Netflix
series. There you go. But speaking of Karen
Page and Foggy Nelson returning to the show,
that brings us to our question of the week.
What other character from the Daredevil Netflix
series do you most hope returns for Disney
Plus's Daredevil born again show and why? Record
your answer at dynamicduel.com by clicking
on the red microphone button in the bottom right
hand corner of the screen, which will prompt
you to leave us a voicemail. Your message could
be up to 30 seconds long. And don't forget
to leave your name in case we include you on
the podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer
and award that person a dynamic duel no prize.
that we'll post to Instagram and our email
newsletter. Be sure to answer before January
17th, because next weekend is our birthday,
and we're recording the next episode a little
early.
But I think that does it for all the news for
this episode, so let's go ahead and get into
our main event, where we find out who'd win
between the villain characters of Livewire
and Claw.
Alright, Livewire versus Claw, as I mentioned
at the top of this episode, these are two energy
beings, one of them being made out of electricity
and one of them being made out of sound. I'm
a little bit nervous about how this speculation
is going to go considering that these two characters
don't really have a physical essence that can
be permanently harmed, I think. Yeah, how does
one energy form damage another energy form?
I have no idea. We'll find out. We'll figure
something out. Of course, Livewire is a Superman
villain who was first introduced in the Superman,
the animated series back in the 90s. She was
an original character that has kind of stuck
around in the comics. Yeah, kind of like Harley
Quinn. Yeah, yeah. Whereas Klaw has been a
primary villain for Black Panther since his
first iteration. He was portrayed by Andy Serkis
in the Black Panther movie as well as Avengers
Age of Ultron. Yeah, but the character is pretty
different in the comics as far as I'm aware.
Yeah, he is like... Klaue in the movies was
an arms dealer whose hand was severed by Ultron,
whereas in the comics, Klaue is more of a scientist
whose hand was actually taken by T'Challa himself.
But we'll learn more about the character shortly.
Before that, to explain the methodology behind
our duels, let's go to our sentient duel simulator,
Alfred Jarvis 9000. AJ9K, tell our listeners
how you go about determining a winner in our
duel matchups. Yes, of course, sir. The way
I determine a winner between the contestants
is by running 1000 Monte Carlo simulations using
the characters statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation
is a probabilistic model used to determine outcomes
through random sampling. In this case, I randomise
the statistics along a normal distribution as
a way to simulate the many variables that can
occur during battle. The stat parameters are
based on the official Marvel power grid from
which the DC characters statistics are extrapolated.
Additional stat categories are included such
as range, damage potential, versatility and
perception in order to create a more detailed
and accurate simulation. The results of the
1000 simulations provide a percentage of wins
for each character. The contestant with the
higher percentage is declared the victor as
they have a higher probability to win any given
battle. In an equitable pairing, neither character
should win 100% of the matches. The comic book
stories have shown that there's even a way
for Batman to defeat Superman. So the confidence
rate of my method falls in line with the precedents
that have been established in the source material.
My mathematical simulations are without subjectivity
or bias. Feats are not the sole consideration,
nor are fan votes tabulated for determination
of the winner. Thanks AJ9K. Before we run the
simulations though, we like to break down each
character's histories and abilities before improvising
a scenario on how we imagine one of the 1000
simulations would play out beat for beat. And
I believe it's my turn to go first with the
DC character. So let me tell you all about Livewire.
Metropolis's radio shock jock DJ, Leslie Willis,
made a name for herself bashing Superman, claiming
that he only saved people for attention seeking
and less than altruistic reasons. At the height
of her popularity, the owner of the radio station,
Miguel Sendoza, decided to switch to a country
music format and he fired Leslie, in part because
his wife had been saved by Superman a week prior.
and he didn't appreciate Leslie's success.
Unbeknownst to Miguel, Leslie was a metahuman
capable of absorbing and redirecting electromagnetic
waves, and after electrocuting her producer,
Leslie went to the roof of the radio station's
building and climbed its antenna in an attempt
to disrupt the signal coming from it. She was
struck by lightning on the tower, however, and
her nervous system, unable to absorb that level
of electricity. was converted into pure electrical
energy. Thrilled by her transformation and
overcome by power, Leslie decided to attack
Superman while he was searching for Lois Lane,
who had been kidnapped by Leslie's brother.
Initially overwhelmed by Leslie's power, Superman
managed to defeat her by seeding a cloud with
ice particles, transforming it into a storm
cloud that generated a lightning bolt that shorted
Leslie's body, just in time to save Lois. You
can learn more about Superman in our Superman
vs. Dr. Doom episode. Leslie was later kidnapped,
along with many other metahumans, by an alien
known as the Auctioneer, who captured and sold
unique beings across the universe. After successfully
shorting the power source to her containment
field, Leslie was able to escape and help Earth's
heroes such as Superman and Mr. Terrific. defeat
the Auctioneer by taking over his ship's communication
systems, and she was able to broadcast their
victory to Earth. After having been seen partnered
with the heroes, Leslie decided to turn over
a new leaf and agreed to be studied by Star
Labs. Her power levels fluctuated over time
as her entire body began converting to energy,
which slowly caused her to become mentally
unbalanced. She escaped Star Labs and took hostages
in Las Vegas. demanding a ransom of all the
money in the town. Jimmy Olsen happened to be
in Las Vegas at the time, and after he summoned
Superman and he and Leslie fought, Superman
managed to get Leslie into a containment suit
that he wore during a time in the 90s when he
himself was also an electrical energy being.
I remember that electric blue Superman, yeah.
The containment suit instantly helped regulate
Leslie's energy and her sanity was restored.
Soon after, Leslie became a member of the Superman
of America, a team Superman put together after
traveling the United States and realizing he
can't be everywhere all the time. In post-Flashpoint
continuity, Leslie was given a new origin.
No longer a radio shock jock, but a streaming
personality and vlogger made famous for her
makeup tutorials and pranks. For one of her
pranks, Leslie broke into Metropolis's main
power station and took control of the with the
intention of turning off all of its power except
for one illuminated, obscene message that could
be seen from space. Superman interrupted the
stream, however, and Leslie accidentally electrocuted
herself with enough electricity to power Metropolis.
Blaming Superman for what had happened to her,
she fought him a number of times before Batman
created an energy-diffusion prison for her on
Stryker's Island. A cult managed to siphon
her out of prison, however, and Batgirl was
forced to bring her down with her father Commissioner
Gordon when he was Batman for a time. And that's
Livewire's brief history. She hasn't been around
for a long time. Powers-wise, Livewire is a
being of pure electromagnetic energy, making
her immune to most physical attacks. She can
absorb, store, and project electrical energy
strong enough to affect Superman, though high-voltage
attacks do use up a substantial amount of her
energy. and forces her to recharge by absorbing
additional electrical energy elsewhere. She
is able to phase through most solid matter and
can travel along power lines or other forms
of circuitry. She could also imbue machines
and devices with her own electrical energy
to take control of them. She can naturally emit
radio waves, and she can charge objects with
electromagnetic energy to make them magnetic.
and cannot affect insulated objects. That's
LiveWire. I like how her origin was updated
from a shock jock, which is what it was from
the cartoon, if I remember correctly, to an
influencer. Yeah, a wannabe influencer, essentially.
Yeah, that's pretty great. I didn't know she
was a technopath, though. I didn't know she
could control other electronic devices. Yes.
I guess that makes sense. Yeah, she does that
pretty frequently with TV screens, or just
screens of any kind, really. Okay. She like
invades their systems and then like she can
speak to people through screens. It's pretty
cool. Yeah, this is gonna be a difficult fight
because let me tell you about Klaue's history
and powers. Ulysses Klaue was born in Belgium,
the son of Fritz Klaue, a former Hydra Colonel
who in World War II joined Baron Strucker in
an attempted invasion of the African nation
of Wakanda in order to learn its secrets. The
Klaue family had a history with the as Ulysses'
great-great-great grandfather had a run-in
with the Wakandans in the 1800s and never returned
home to tell about it. Fritz, his father, was
slightly luckier as he was able to barely escape
Wakanda with his life. Returning home to Belgium,
Fritz raised Ulysses with tales of the formidable
African nation and instilled in his son an
intense hatred for Wakanda and its leader, the
Black Panther. You can learn more about the
Black Panther in his dual episode against Black
Manta. Something of a science prodigy, Ulysses
studied physics as a young adult, specializing
in the field of applied sonics at the Technical
University of Delft in the Netherlands. There,
he designed a sound transducer able to convert
the vibrational waves of sound into physical
mass. However, the device would require vibranium
in order to function, vibranium being a rare
metal found only in the nation of Wakanda that
can absorb kinetic energy. Eager to get his
hands on the metal? Ulysses enlisted a group
of mercenaries and fashioned a sonic blaster.
He and the mercenaries journeyed to the Wakandan
border, where they were confronted by its then-king
and Black Panther, T'Chaka. When the king was
overpowered by Ulysses' sonic blaster, 13-year-old
Prince T'Challa jumped in the fight to help.
As Ulysses fired his weapon on the young prince,
T'Chaka leapt in the way of the blast and was
killed, protecting his son. In retaliation,
Wakandan warrior Zuri impaled Ulysses right
arm with a spear, causing him to drop his sonic
blaster. Young T'Challa then picked it up and
used it to blow off Ulysses hand and force the
villain to retreat. In the end, Ulysses did
obtain a small sample of vibranium, but more
importantly, earned an enemy for life in Prince
T'Challa, who would grow up to become the new
king of Wakanda and the Black Panther. Ulysses
spent the next few years building his sound
transducer that could convert sound waves into
solid form and equipping it into a prosthetic
device to replace his missing right hand. He
attempted to invade Wakanda again, this time
getting at the source of all vibranium called
the Great Mound, and bombarded Wakanda with
a horde of sound energy creature constructs,
which Ulysses referred to as Echoes. However,
Black Panther was able to track the source
of these Echoes to Ulysses' secret lab which
he blew up, seemingly killing Ulysses. As it
turned out, however, the villain's consciousness
survived as his body was transformed by his
transducer into a being made entirely out of
sound, now able to shape and control vibrational
forces at will. With his new abilities, he set
his sights on the Fantastic Four and Mr. Fantastic's
inventions. Though Ulysses was able to trap
the team in a force field, the heroes consulted
with Black Panther, who sent them some vibranium
knuckle guards that Mr. Fantastic used to defeat
the villain. As it turned out, vibranium was
one of Ulysses' only weaknesses due to its
vibration absorbing properties that would render
his powers inert. Ulysses was imprisoned, but
was freed by Ultron, who recruited him into
his Masters of Evil super villain team. The
group took on the Avengers, but were defeated
in battle with Ulysses falling to his rival,
the Black Panther. His sound form was too powerful
to be subdued by conventional means, however,
and Ulysses to set his sights on an isotope
variation of Wakandan vibranium called Antarctic
Vibranium, which was found only in the Savage
Land, a hidden tropical region in Antarctica
located well below sea level. Unlike Wakandan
vibranium which absorbs vibrations, Antarctic
vibranium emanates vibrations. Ulysses was thwarted
in his attempt to obtain it by the jungle hero
of the Savage Land known as Khazar. who caused
the villain to attune the Antarctic Vibranium
at such a frequency as to open a portal to a
different vibratory plane of reality, where
Ulysses became stuck. Eventually, though, he
found his way back home via the Nexus of All
Realities, a portal to all dimensions that you
can learn more about in our Swamp Thing vs
Man Thing dual episode. Ulysses suffered his
quickest and most embarrassing defeat at the
hands of the mutant Dazzler, whose whole ability
is to convert sound into light energy. She
absorbed his sound essence only to expel it
later in a fight with Galactus, the world devourer.
Ulysses' consciousness then found itself living
inside of Galactus' machinery for a time until
he was discovered by Dr. Doom during the Secret
Wars event where heroes were pit against villains
in a cosmic experiment on a planet called Battleworld.
After returning to Earth, Ulysses became a
member of the Frightful Four, alongside the
Wizard, Hydro Man and Titania, and the team
was successful in transforming the Fantastic
Four's thing from his rocky form into his human
form as Ben Grimm, thus rendering the hero powerless.
Though the Frightful Four were able to capture
the remaining Fantastic Four, it was the human
Ben Grimm who freed his teammates and saved
the day, resulting in Ulysses being imprisoned
by Mr. Fantastic in a special vacuum containment
unit. An echo construct of Ulysses himself managed
to evade apprehension, however. and captured
the hero Daredevil in an effort to use his superior
senses to locate his original self via a specially
built antenna. Daredevil destroyed the Echo's
antenna device though, which destroyed the
Echo itself. The real Ulysses would be freed
by the frightful Four, which included the new
member Carnage, whom you can learn more about
in our Lobo vs Carnage dual episode. Due to
the symbiote's insanity and weakness to Sonics,
Ulysses kept Carnage in check to keep the team
safe. Carnage turned on the team, however, and
stabbed Ulysses with a vibranium spear that
caused him to detonate and disperse beyond reconstitution.
With his final act, Ulysses used the last of
his power to summon a bolt of sound energy that
separated Carnage from his host. Though he
was believed to be dead, Ulysses was later found
as a prisoner of the international peacekeeping
agency, SHIELD, apparently having reconstituted.
That's his backstory. Powers-wise, Claws abilities
stem from his Soundwave body. which his consciousness
can vibrate at a frequency to produce a solid
form. In fact, he can manipulate all ambient
sound in his vicinity for a variety of effects,
including creating other solid sound constructs
called echoes, project waves or beams of concussive
force, and create deafening or debilitating
tones. By manipulating the frequency of his
own sonic state, he can render himself highly
durable, with increased strength able to lift
around 10 tons, and even more when supported
by additional vibrational force, or he can
render himself intangible. Either way, he is
virtually immortal and resistant to physical
attack. He is a gifted technical engineer and
scientist in the branch of physics that studies
sound. His only weakness is vibranium, which
absorbs sound, or a vacuum in which he would
dissipate. And that's Klaue. I'm not gonna lie,
Klaue is a pretty cool villain. Yeah, he's
kind of like a red lantern, although more like
a red green lantern because red lanterns do
they even produce constructs? I thought it was
just like lava. They can, they can. Although
I do think it's dumb that his friggin weakness
is the primary weapon of his rival. That's
like Superman going up against kryptonite man.
Yeah, Clair really needs to find a better enemy
than the guy who is best equipped to kill him.
Exactly. I think you'd be a much more successful
villain if he stopped going against the Black
Panther. Definitely not the Dazzler either.
That was funny.
Now that we got the characters' histories and
abilities out of the way, let's speculate on
how one of the 1000 simulated matches will go.
The winner is determined by his simulations,
not the speculation, but it's fun to imagine
how the fight can play out. AJ9K, what are
the rules of our speculation? Well, I should
say there are no rules, other than the characters
have no prior knowledge of the other going into
the fight. All they are aware of starting out
is that the other character is a threat that
needs to be eliminated. For the speculation...
The contestants will begin approximately 50
meters apart in a nondescript environment that
will have no bearing on the match itself, as
no environmental statistics are considered
in my simulations. The contestants must earn
victory on their own merit. Alright then, let's
get into it. Livewire and Claw meet on the battlefield.
Who goes first? I'm gonna say Livewire goes
first because electricity moves faster than
sound, I'm pretty sure. Yeah. So... She's gonna
start by firing a lightning bolt right at Claw's
face, which no way he's fast enough to dodge
that. Uh, well, I mean, like, if she moves her
hand and fires the lightning bolt with lightning
speed, you're probably right. Uh, he wouldn't
be able to dodge it, so he gets hit in the
face, but you forget his physical form isn't
normal. It's just vibrational forces that are
rendered solid. So, like, he probably gets blasted
onto his back, and he's probably a little stunned.
but he's not like seriously injured, right?
And you know what follows lightning? That's
right, thunder. And as soon as the thunder clap
follows her lightning bolt, which is like immediately,
the thunder is gonna empower claw and he's gonna
convert the sound of the thunder into a construct
of like a herd of giant stampeding elephants.
And those elephants are just gonna trample
Livewire. Interesting, okay. But actually, Livewire,
she's just gonna convert her body into electricity
and zip between the elephants and then like
zap herself right into Claw's sonic device
that he has on his hand. And she's going to
short that sucker. So now Claw can't use it
to project sound anymore. Oh, really? Yeah.
You think it would be that easy? That's cute.
Again, Claw is made of essentially kinetic sound
energy, including his sonic blaster. It's not
actually technology. Well, why the fuck does
it look like it is then? Like, why would he
just give himself a normal hand? Excuse me.
Something as bad as does it need a reason?
Yes. The answer is no. You know, he has a hand
blaster on his hand because it's just that
much cooler when he kills you with it. That's
why. Oh, my gosh. OK. So live wire. She dives
into his sonic blaster hand, which is essentially
just pure kinetic energy. So she gets thrown
out of it, I guess. But now she knows what she's
dealing with, at least more or less. And she's
going to generate an electromagnetic energy
dome around Klaut to contain him. Okay. Well,
I'm going to say this electricity dome is probably
making a noise, like this low level electric
hum sound, right? So Klaue's gonna tap into
that electrical hum and amplify it so that
it turns into this debilitating, piercing noise
that just penetrates the energy field and hurts
Livewire's ears so bad that she like drops the
energy field. And then Klaue is gonna shoot
this massive, concussive energy beam from a
sonic blaster at Livewire and it's gonna slam
into her like a freight train and cause her
body to disperse. I was going to call bullshit
on that, like, piercing sound attack you just
did, but I guess she is still able to hear
things. Yeah, yeah. I guess it would work. OK,
so you fired this beam at her and say her body
was dispersed. You think it was a dispersal,
but it was intentional to dodge the beam and
livewire reforms, like essentially teleporting
right behind Klawe, where she's going to grab
him by the back of the neck and just electrocute
him. at the source fatality style dude sonic
form I don't know what you don't get about that
yes solid sonic form it would have no effect
on him like the sound does not conduct electricity
so she's gonna try to electrocute him he just
goes intangible to escape her grasp and then
he's gonna shoot a massive shock wave into
the ground beneath live wire like shaking the
ground and breaking it up and he's gonna lift
these massive boulders using vibrational forces
into the air and then slam them down onto her
just Burying live wire like deep into the ground
like 20 or 30 feet in the ground He buries
live wire and that grounds her right? I'm no
scientist But I think at that point her electrical
energy form would be grounded and would like
disperse into the earth and she would lose
Her form so she'd be gone Essentially so match
over you just got scienced. Oh, too can sense
of this game bitch Let's say when she's grabbing
him by the neck, that electric charge was actually
to convert his sound form into an electric current,
just like a microphone, so that she could transmit
his body into space as radio waves. So she wins.
What is that? How microphones work? You don't
know how microphones work. Yeah, man. They like
use magnets or some shit to like turn sound
into an electric signal and live It's like a
living electromagnet. So in your face. Magnets,
how do they work? Ha ha ha. But like, you need
some kind of like antenna or something to broadcast
the signal. Like she would need some kind of
technology. She can't do that on her own. No,
actually, she can. That's one of her abilities
that I said she had. She's actually even done
her own Sonic attacks before by bombarding people
who could hear radio waves like Superman or
the Flash's children. Oh. Well, good on you
for conveniently leaving that out of your bio.
I just said I mentioned it. I wasn't paying
attention to you. Also, radio waves are not
the same thing as actual sound. So I think you're
full of crap. That's not technically a sonic
attack. I don't know what you're talking about.
No, but a microphone will convert sound into
a radio wave. And again, she just blasts them
out into space to drift forever. That's stupid.
But we could leave the match there. I say she
gets buried underground. and you say that Klaue
gets blasted into the sky as radio waves. Yeah,
no sound in space. Yeah, in space, no one can
hear Klaue scream. We'll go ahead and leave
the match there. We'll run the stats on these
characters and find out which of these scenarios
happens when we come back with a winner. AG9K,
hit it. Inputting data, running calculations,
processing results, simulations complete. All
right. I was really nervous prior to the match,
trying to figure out how these two energy beings
would hurt each other, live wire being electrical
energy, claw being essentially kinetic energy.
I don't know if we found a great solution. We
had to get really sciencey at the end there
with our speculation. And probably 99% of that
is bullshit because you and I are not scientists
and we have no idea what the hell we're talking
about. But it was a speculation. Yeah, yeah,
it was. Technically, when it came to figuring
out their stats, for the most part, they were
going pretty tit for tat, I would say. Like
Livewire is definitely faster than Claw. Yeah,
but Claw is stronger and smarter. We said they
were about the same when it came to evasiveness
considering they both can go intangible, although
have a kind of semi-tangible form that allows
them to get punched in the face by the good
guys. They're both really destructive. Their
damage potential is really high. They're also
both really versatile characters. Yeah, given
that they could use their powers for a variety
of effects, like Livewire even has Technopathy
and Klaue can create constructs, including duplicates
of himself and stuff like that. So a lot of
back and forth, but also a lot of like equity
between their abilities. For the most part,
there was fighting skill. We said that while
Klaue was an experienced fighter, Livewire
basically had no training whatsoever. And there
was nothing in my research to indicate that
she did. She's very much a projectile based
attacker. Very rarely does it come down to
fisticuffs. So basically taking all of these
stats into account, Joseph, who do you think
came out on top? I think Mr. Ulysses Kla is
coming out on top of this one. Although no
one on Instagram agrees with me. Well, actually
I should say 72% of the people who took our
poll don't agree with me, but it's fine to be
wrong. They can be wrong. I'm actually a little
bit surprised that LiveWire came out that high.
I think just. Maybe a lot of people are thinking
about the MCU version of Klaue and thinking
that there's no way that he would be able to
defeat someone made out of lightning. That's
my guess. That's probably a really good guess.
Well, let's find out who won. AJ9K, the results
please. Hey, Yuasa. The winner of the matchup
between Livewire and Klaue is... fucking Klaue.
Yeah! And it wasn't even Um, he won 693 of
the 1000 matches or 69.3% compared to Livewire
winning only 30.7. Okay, so Claude wins around
two-thirds of the time. And honestly, like this
baffles the shit out of me. Like I know the
discrepancy in the fighting stat is pretty drastic,
but damn, I thought I totally had you when
it came to like our speculation. and I came
out of that really confident that Livewire
would win, but apparently not. Well, it's hard
to think of an instance in which this fight
would come down to hand-to-hand combat, right?
Right, exactly. But you would have to assume
that fighting skill would play at least a small
portion of some of the matches, and when you
run a thousand simulations, it was enough of
an influence to give Claude the ultimate victory.
It also just baffles me that sound can beat
lightning energy. That's... I cannot comprehend
that. but it's also hard to comprehend lightning
energy beating sound too, right? No, not for
me. I totally see it. But that does it for this
duel. Let us know what you guys thought about
the results by writing to us at dyna or by visiting
us on Instagram or Twitter. You can find links
to all of our accounts by checking out our show
notes or visiting our website at dynamicduel.com.
And on our site, you could also find a link
to our Patreon page where you could join our
Dynamic 2.0 tier and chat with us and fellow
listeners, our fantastic 4 tier. which gets
you bonus content each month, our X-Force tier
that makes you an executive producer of this
podcast, or our newest tier that lets you join
our Dynamike podcast network. If you can't
join Patreon, you can still support the show
by signing up for our e-newsletter also at
dynamicduel.com, so you'll never miss an episode.
Next week, we're going to be reviewing the
latest DC animated film that has been released,
Crisis on Infinite Earths, part one. Yeah,
I haven't seen it yet, but I'm starting to hear
good things, so I'm cautiously optimistic.
We'll see. But that does it for this episode,
we want to give a big thanks to our executive
producers Ken Johnson, John Sturawski, Zachary
Hepburn, Dustin Belcombe, Miggie Mathingian,
Brandon Estergard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yeaton,
Nick Abonto, Austin Wieselowski, AJ Dunkerley,
Scott Camacho, Adam Spies, Andrew Schunk, and
Dean Molesky for helping make this podcast
possible. And we'll talk to you guys next week.
Up, up, and away, true believers. It's electric.
Wookie wookie wookie.