This is a DynaMic Network podcast. Hey guys,
Marvelous Joe at the top of the episode to
remind you that in the months of November and
December, Dynamic Duel is donating 10% of the
proceeds from our store to Stand Up to Cancer.
So support our show, support a great cause
by going to dynamicduel.com and clicking on
the store button where you can buy a whole
bunch of new cool products. Jonathan, what do
we got for them that's new? We got hoodies,
we got posters, shoes. water bottles, even a
2025 calendar for you guys. Yeah, there's a
whole lot of holiday shopping you could do on
the website. So again, be sure to visit dynamicduel.com,
click the store button and check out all the
dynamic duel stuff we have to offer. Thanks
guys and on with the show.
Hi, welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Marvelous Joe. And I'm his twin brother,
Johnny DC. And in this episode, we're going
to review some lame ass show on Max called The
Penguin, I guess? So you know when Joseph is
talking about a DC show, if he calls it lame,
it means it's actually the exact opposite of
that. It was everything I wanted it to be. It
was fantastic, a masterpiece, and it basically
restored my faith in DC after the disaster that
was Joker 2. Well, don't give away the farm
on this intro, man. Like, you gotta tease what's
coming up later on this episode. I'm just letting
the people know it's good. Okay, but, like,
was it really good, though? You guys have to
stay tuned to find out. Before we get into the
review, we're gonna break down last week's
comic book movie news, including the trailer
that Marvel Studios released for What If Season
3, and actually, that's all the news. As usual,
No DC news. As always, we list our segment
times in our episode description, so feel free
to check out the show notes if you want to
skip ahead to a particular topic. Our artificially
intelligent duel simulator AJ9K has a quick
message for our listeners, so listen up. Why
hello there, do you want even more from this
podcast? Then become a part of the dynamic duel
community on Patreon, where you can choose
from three tiers. The dynamic two-oh tier gives
you access to our Discord chat server. The
fantastic four tier gives you two bonus episodes
each month, and the X-Force tier makes you
an executive producer of this show. Lastly,
The Diner Mike podcast network tier lets you
create your own podcast using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and consultation,
and get you simulation results. Pitch the twins
your ideas via email at dynamicduelpodcast at
gmail.com. Check it out at patreon.com slash
dynamicduel. Pip pip cheerio. Thanks, H3N1K,
and thanks to everyone who supports the podcast.
Guys, be sure to tune into the other shows on
the DynaMic Podcast Network this week, including
Max Destruction, which pits your favorite action
heroes from film and television against each
other. This week, hosts Scotty and Gilly are
finding out who would win in a fight between
Bugs Bunny and Roger Rabbit. On the Senjoworld
podcast, host Zachary Hepburn speculates on
fights between fan favorite anime and manga
characters. Zach is currently traveling abroad,
so the show is momentarily on a brief hiatus.
And on the Console Combat Podcast, hosts John
and Dean simulate battles between popular video
game characters. In yesterday's episode, they
found out who would win between Emil8239 from
Halo and Grayfox from Metal Gear Solid. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our
show notes to listen to all of the shows in
the DynaMic Podcast Network. But with that
out of the way, quick to the no prize! A no-prize
is an award that Marvel used to give out to
fans. Our version, the Dynamic Duel No Prize,
is a digital award that we post on Instagram
for the person that we feel gave the best answer
to our question of the week. Last week we asked,
what would you say is the best Marvel or DC
film to watch on Valentine's Day with your significant
other, and why? And this is coming off the
news that Captain America Brave New World is
coming out on Valentine's Day for 2025, and
Jonathan and I were arguing on whether or not
it would be a good date movie. We got a number
of answers, so let's break down this week's
honorable mentions before revealing the no-prize
winner. Our first honorable mention goes to
Baideer Bangura, who said, Hi, Dinami Dool.
My answer to the question of the week would
be Batman Returns. I think the great chemistry
between Michelle Pfeiffer. Michael Keaton is
palpable. I think that the storyline is amazing.
I think the imagery and the scenery, the neo-noir
scenery in the movie is really great as well.
So great storyline, great feelings, great emotions.
I think with some good food you would have
a great Valentine's Day. Take care. Yeah I would
definitely say out of all of these superhero
films in existence, the romantic relationship
between the lead characters, Batman and Catwoman,
has Like you could cut it with a knife. It's
a nice little romantic game of cat and flying
mouse that they have going on there. Exactly.
Now, Bydeer mentioned that you could pair it
with good food for a great Valentine's Day too.
Jonathan, what meal would you pair with Batman
Returns? Oh dude, easy. Pussy. Ha!
I was gonna say something like, I don't know,
some kind of dessert that resembles mistletoe
or something like that because there's the line
in the movie where he's like, mistletoe can
be deadly if you eat it and she's like, a kiss
can be deadlier if you mean it. But I think
you have the winner answer right there. Let's
go ahead and move on. Our next honorable mention
goes to Travis Herndon, who said? What's up,
dynamic dudes? Travis here. Shout out to my
evil twin. So, my answer would have to be Into
the Spider-Verse. I mean, one. Who doesn't
love Spider-Man? Two, who doesn't love animated
movies? It's a sick-ass movie to watch with
your significant other and come on, I'm pretty
sure most of us got our significant other by
pulling the hand on the shoulder, eyebrow rate,
saying hey, two of them. It's a sick-ass movie
to watch with your significant other on a Valentine's
Day, so come on. Yeah, Into the Spider-Verse,
I don't think had a whole lot of romantic elements.
I think across the Spider-Verse really played
up on the Miles Morales, Gwen Stacy relationship.
pretty well in a way that I think would be
appealing to both sexes. But yeah, the first
movie had the iconic line from Uncle Aaron,
where to get a girl, you put your hand on their
shoulder and you go, hey, which is absolutely
how I got my wife. Not really. But that's the
way I like to think of it in my head. What?
Jonathan, let's hear your best. Hey, hey, girl.
What's up? All right. I'm pretty sure you didn't
get your wife that way. I did not. Now that
I think about it, a lot of the Spider-Man movies
would probably make great date night movies
because, you know, like the original Sam Raimi
trilogy really focused on the Mary Jane relationship.
There was the Gwen Stacy relationship and of
course the new trilogy with MJ. They're all
good. So great answer Travis. Our next honorable
mention goes to Colby Hentges. Who said? Hey
boys, Colby Hentges. The best Marvel or DC
film to watch with my wife on Valentine's Day
is DC's Justice League. Weed and cut or Snyder
cut, it doesn't matter because I can give my
wife the attention she needs without missing
anything important because nothing important
happens in those movies. Weed and cut, hot
garbage. Snyder cut, hot garbage. They both
smell like new teeth. And Jonathan, I think
we agree on this answer, right? We agree on
Justice League, but definitely not Zack Snyder's
Justice League. That was far superior to the
theatrical version of the film, which yeah,
it doesn't even need to exist. So why even watch
it? If you're busy doing other things. That's
fair. So great answer, Colby. We want to give
a quick shout out to Jose Marcial, who basically
gave the answer of any Marvel movie along the
same lines as Colby Hentges's Justice League
answer. Great answer, Jose. But the winners
of this week's no prize are two people, actually.
Waldo and Mason Thompson, who gave the same
answer. Let's hear Waldo's. Hey, guys, Waldo
here. Um, I guess I'd have to go with either
of the Wonder Woman. the first one more. You
know, it's heavily involved with her story with
Steve Trevor, not just how they met, but how
they're growing, becoming part of each other's
world. And then at the end with his sacrifice,
which is also reflected at the end of the second
one with her sacrifice of him. If you're trying
to win over a lady friend, The best way to do
so is through a classic love story, as we see
in the first Wonder Woman film in particular,
that also features a strong female protagonist.
Yeah, it's definitely one of the more romantic
superhero movies out there, I think. The relationship
between Diana Prince and Steve Trevor is pretty
well developed and also pretty tragic at the
end. This tale of these lovers coming together
and then being torn apart and then, you know,
they get reunited in the sequel. It's all good
Valentine's Day stuff. Yeah, and I would agree
the best that the genre has to offer. Actually,
if I were to give my answer to this question,
obviously it would be Deadpool, because nothing
brings a couple together, like laughing together.
Ryan Reynolds and Miranda Baccarin were great
in the first movie, and I believe the film
came out around Valentine's Day to begin with,
so yeah, that was the correct answer. Well,
honestly, horror films have actually been shown
to bring couples together more than any other
genre, so Plop and Constantine. Plop? There
had to be a better verb choice there than plop.
I said what I said. Alright, congrats again
to Waldo and Mason Thompson for winning this
week's No Praise, guys. If you, the listener,
want a shot at winning your own no prize, stay
tuned to later on this episode when we'll be
asking another question of the week. And now
that that's done, on to the news!
Alright, this past week we got the official
trailer for season 3 of Marvel Animation's
What If series. It's gonna be the third and
final season of this series, and I gotta say
I'm gonna be sad to see it go because I enjoyed
both seasons 1 and season 2. Season 2 a little
bit more than season 1. I thought season 2 took
a more anthological approach to the story,
didn't have to worry as much about setting up
the Guardians of the Multiverse like season
1 did. So... I really appreciated it running
with the what if concept a little bit smoother
than season one. Yeah, I agree. Season two was
a lot better than season one. But that's sort
of why I'm scared about this upcoming season
because it seems like this one will also have
like an overarching narrative between stories.
Possibly. If they're ending it. If they're
ending it, yeah, then we're probably going to
have a couple episodes dealing with the rest
of the Watchers besides Watu. We see the group
of Watchers. towards the end of this trailer
talking about how like this is the end. So I
don't know how many of these episodes are going
to be dedicated to that. Hopefully not many,
but it looks like we have quite a good selection
of anthological episodes to choose from, including
a Western version of Shang-Chi. We have a fucking
Gundam Avengers, including Captain America Gundam,
a Shang-Chi Gundam, a Moon Knight Gundam, which
was really cool to see Moon Knight play with
the rest of the Avengers. in this series and
plus he had a really cool looking Gundam. We
saw Photon there, we saw the Red Guardian and
Melina Vostokov there. That episode is going
to be freaking amazing, it's going to blow
my mind. There's also a like Red Guardian and
Winter Soldier team up episode in what looks
to take place back in the days of the USSR.
Most interesting, it looks like we're going
to get a revisit to the world of the Eternals
because we see like Icarus and some of the
other Eternals characters. There was a shot
that we got here of Arashem that looked very
similar to the end shot of the live action film
that came out. So it'll be really cool to see
like how they may approach the Eternals characters
from a different angle in the series. It seems
like they're stepping a little bit further outside
the boundaries of just the live action Marvel
Studios films to touch on things like the television
shows such as Moon Night and even X-Men 97
which was the big reveal at the end of this
trailer. We get a what-if episode where the
X-Men are interplayed with the greater MCU cast
as we see Storm being the goddess of thunder.
And she's voiced by Alison Sealy-Smith, who
did the voice of the character in the X-Men
90s cartoon and X-Men 97. And it was freaking
epic to hear, I think. Yeah, everything looked
cool. I think I'm still baffled though as to
why they would want to end the show. Yeah.
Because I feel like it's a concept that never
really needs to end, you know? I'm wondering
if it's because... The storyline from the what
if shows maybe leads into something like secret
war and it's going to like collapse the multiverse
perhaps. I don't know. Well, the show can only
really last as long as the multiverse lasts,
right? And it seems like, yeah, they are wrapping
things up in the multiversal saga with Avengers
Doomsday coming out in a couple years and then
Avengers Secret Wars the year after that. So
you figure you still got two more solid years
of what if shows to do though. I would agree.
I would definitely agree. So you agree that
Marvel's dumb? Not in the sense that they're
not smart, just more in the sense that they
could keep the show running. So maybe shut your
mouth. Yeah, but they won't because they're
dumb. Okay, I got you. I read you. Hey, Jonathan,
when is DC coming out with a multiversal series
that's this good, huh? Oh, that's right. They
don't have an established universe to begin
with, so okay, okay. You don't gotta say it
like it is, Marge. I'm really looking forward
to what if season 3, the stories that they're
looking to tell here and of course the animation
is always quality and just how epic the show
can be I think bodes well for what is bound
to be a truly awe-inspiring finale. The season
is debuting on December 22nd, just a few days
before Christmas and then we're going to get
one episode a day through the rest of the year
ending on December 30th I assume. until the
new year. That said, it still will count towards
this year's Brothers Awards. Yep, that's correct.
So look forward to our review of that later
guys. But that brings us to our question of
the week.
What has been your favorite animated Marvel
or DC project of all time and why? We're talking
television shows. We're talking films, both
theatrical and direct to video, the works.
So record your answer at dynamicduel.com by
clicking on the red microphone button in the
bottom right hand corner of the screen, which
will prompt you to leave us a voicemail. Your
message could be up to 30 seconds long and don't
forget to leave your name in case we include
you on the podcast. We'll pick our favorite
answer and award that person a dynamic duel
no prize that we'll post to Instagram. Be sure
to answer before November 23rd.
So that does it for all the news for this episode,
so let's go ahead and get into our main event
where we review the HBO and DC television series,
The Penguin.
Okay, The Penguin is a spin-off series of the
2022 film The Batman, written and directed
by Matt Reeves. Reeves also served as an executive
producer for this show, which was created by
Lauren LeFranc. It's a limited, 8-episode HBO
Max series that tells the story of how Oswald
Cobblepot, the Penguin, played masterfully by
Colin Farrell, rises to power in Gotham City's
criminal underworld after the Riddler destroyed
most of the city at the end of the Batman movie.
Now I loved the Batman film. We gave it 5 out
of 5 stars in a review and while I was looking
forward to this show, I clearly wasn't looking
forward to it enough because it somehow managed
to exceed my expectations and deliver a devastating
masterwork spinoff in what continues to be
my favorite Batman universe on screen. If you
haven't seen The Penguin yet, do not ruin the
show for yourself by continuing to listen to
this spoiler review. Stop here, watch the show.
then come back. It's only eight episodes. Forget
and take a sick day at work and just binge
the whole thing because I guarantee you, it's
extremely hard not to watch the next episode
once you've started. Yeah, if you listen to
this review without watching the television
series, how dare you? How dare you do that to
yourself? Go watch the show, then come back
and listen to the spoiler review because it
is fucking phenomenal. It's such a damn good
show and you don't wanna ruin it for yourself.
No. In fact, I liked it more than I liked the
Batman. I did not think that we should have
given the Batman five stars. I think we should
have given it four and a half stars. But this
series is better than the Batman. You know,
this series actually reminded me a lot of the
Daredevil shows from Netflix that we love.
We gave season three of that five stars just
for its like gritty realism and hard boiled
edge. This had a lot of that. But set in the
Batman world, which makes it instantly better,
instantly worse. I agree with you on the other
points. The show was actually so good after
I finished it all, I pulled up Daredevil season
3 just to feel better about myself and remind
myself that yeah, Marvel is still capable of
pulling off this type of crime drama. Paired
with, I will add superhero action, which this
series didn't have a whole lot of. It really
wasn't part of the superhero genre. Yeah, true.
That said... There are a lot of people who
expect a lot of action from their comic book
stories, but I still think that even if you're
a fan of hardcore action, there's a lot to love
about this show. Now, I wasn't able to watch
the whole series in one go, but man, did I want
to because the pacing and tension and plot
of the series had to be hooked from the first
episode. Yeah, I think I immediately texted
you after the first episode ended and I told
you that this is probably going to be a five
star show. just with how good the first episode
was and that you need to see it immediately.
Yeah, you actually sent me that right as I was
starting the show and I was like, oh damn,
it's gonna be so good, I can't wait. I mean,
yeah, the show is right up my alley. Like some
of my favorite movies of all time are things
like The Departed, Drive. So I didn't know
quite to expect going into The Penguin, but
coming out of it, I loved it. I was happy for
you. I was proud of you that you finally got
a win as a DC fan. Hey, thanks. Yeah, I was
happy for myself as well. Cause as I've mentioned,
The Joker 2's failure shook me to my core,
and the Penguin really, really helped. Now,
I mentioned that the pacing and plot of the
series were phenomenal. That's not to say that
there weren't slow or even unnecessary moments
during the course of the show, but there were
very, very few, because just about every scene
contributes to the further development and realization
of these very real characters that exist in
this gritty, realistic, hard-boiled Gotham City
setting. that was established in the movie
and is expanded upon in this series. The world
building here is incredible and it showcases
the type of Gotham City that I've always wanted
to see and even believed it would be like as
a reader of the comics. It's not as fantastical
or even as mundane as prior movies have depicted
it. It meets this perfect neo-noir sweet spot
that you believe could develop characters like
Batman or as we see in this show. a deformed
mob boss like the Penguin. It reminded me a
lot of the video game Batman Arkham City, because
in that game it had just suffered a devastating
earthquake that kind of destroyed sections of
the city, and it was almost like they used
that as inspiration for the show, which I loved,
because that game was fantastic. So it was
No Man's Land. Exactly, right. Now regarding
the Penguin, you know, he's always been something
of a joke character, this fat, monocle-wearing
sideshow freak that no one would believe. could
hold his own in a fight especially against Batman,
but in Matt Reeves universe, he is what he
always should have been, the last remnant of
a mafia that controlled and corrupted Gotham
City for generations. He works very well within
that framework, allowing for a truly epic rise
to power storyline within the gangster crime
genre, a genre that's rife with themes of power,
legacy, and redemption, as well as examinations
of morality and ambition. We see examples of
this in other epic gangster dramas such as The
Godfather, Goodfellas, Scarface, where characters
are driven by their desire for dominance and
respect only to find that their pursuit of
power often leads to their undoing. In The Penguin,
this theme is amplified by Oz's deep-seated
narcissism and unresolved guilt, which shapes
his actions and decisions throughout the series.
His journey reflects the tragic truth that,
in a world where power is everything, True
redemption is rarely achieved because power
corrupts, and those who seek it often lose
what little humanity they have left along the
way. Yeah, if the Batman movie was kind of
an adaptation of sorts of the long Halloween
storyline from the comics where we see basically
the criminal underworld in Gotham City get supplanted
by costumed supervillains... then I see the
Penguin series as kind of like an interesting
look at the transition between those two periods.
Between the crime family and mob boss period
and the supervillain period. Oh yeah, for sure.
Actually, this series borrowed quite a bit from
the long Halloween sequel, Dark Victory, in
which Sophia Falcone was one of the primary
villains. Oh, interesting. Okay, okay. Yeah.
Now, one of the things I like most about comic
book adaptations as a comic reader is that
I get the opportunity to watch fate unravel
as it were. Most people know that the Penguin
is a Batman villain, but if you're not a comic
book reader, you may not be aware of some of
the darker aspects of this character, like how
Oswald killed his brothers when he was a child
in the comics. Some people try to go into films
and shows knowing as little as possible, but
I actually live for the dramatic irony of watching
how adaptations unfold and how characters on
screen become like the characters on the page.
Sometimes they don't, which is often disappointing,
and sometimes a modern adaptation will improve
upon what was on the page, and I'd argue that's
definitely the case for the Penguin series.
Not only has the Penguin been made much more
frightening and interesting to me at least in
this show, but so have minor comic characters
like Sofia Falcone. What would you say to people
who may look at this series and say that this
is more like the Penguin in name only considering
his name is Oz Cobb, not Oswald Cobblepot,
and he's more of a ruthless thug as opposed
to like a aristocrat? I would tell them that,
you know, this is an adaptation of that. I actually
like the twist that he didn't grow up as an
aristocrat and that he grew up actually really
poor. That's more interesting to me character
wise. and that he's someone who aspires to climb
the social hierarchy rather than already being
at the top. It's a better journey for the character.
I agree. I mean, by this point, I'm pretty
much demanding that James Gunn fold Matt Reeves'
universe into the upcoming DCU because there
is zero way the Penguin can be done better.
Zero. Like, why would you even want to try?
Don't. Yeah, it's kind of a shame, like the
whole state of the DC cinematic universe, where
you have, you know, James Gunn's thing going,
but you also have these elseworld stories from
one offs that filmmakers wanted to tell, like
the Joker, like the Penguin. But it's also
disparate that it almost makes it feel meaningless.
And I don't want that. Like, I want this world
for the Batman to continue. I want to see so
much more and explore it like to its fullest.
And I feel like with other film adaptations
of Batman. like the upcoming Brave and the
Bold, we're not going to get the opportunity
for that. Yeah, you're just going to have these
competing versions. And not only competing versions,
competing Matt Reeves versions, because James
Gunn has actually enlisted Matt Reeves into
helping him develop the Batman side of the
DCU, like the upcoming Arkham series that's
rumored. Which makes zero sense to me. Well,
considering the success of this HBO series,
maybe you're gonna get your wish. Maybe James
Gunn will realize that this is the best play
for developing his DCU. Dude, yes, please.
Hashtag incorporate the Reevesverse. We need
to get that trending, people. Now I'm biased
because I love psychologically heavy morality
tales, but this show in my opinion is exactly
what the comic book genre needs right now to
overcome superhero fatigue. Just fresh and
profound takes on characters. that audiences
are already familiar with. I agree, totally.
The best way for superhero stories to stay relevant
is by constantly mixing it up, right? You want
different genres thrown in there and you want
quality stories. Luckily, The Penguin has both
of those things going for it. Yeah, it's the
perfect example of that. The story is incredible,
the characters are interesting as hell, but
speaking of them, let's move on to our character
breakdown. Starting with Oswald Cobb, aka The
Penguin. Now he of course is played by Colin
Farrell in what is to date the magnum opus of
his career, in my opinion. He's completely
unrecognizable in the role and his performance
seems to come across just so naturally for
him. It's like a very technical performance,
but it's played as if another actor is method
acting. I don't know if there's ever been a
greater performance in any adapted comic book
work. I think he even tops Heath Ledger's Joker.
Wow, that's pretty high praise. I mean, do
you disagree? I would put them on the same level.
You're right, they're both highly technical
performances. I do think that Colin Farrell
has the added benefit of the substantial amount
of makeup that he's wearing as a means to help
transform his look and his character. Oh, 100%.
I was talking to my wife about the Penguin's
casting with Colin Farrell and how initially
Warner Brothers wanted Jonah Hill to play the
Penguin, but he wanted to be the Riddler and
because of that dispute he just left the project
altogether. But holy cow, what a boon that
was because we would have never gotten Colin
Farrell as the Penguin if that did not happen.
Yeah, I just cannot see Jonah Hill in this show,
but there's no touching Colin Farrell in this
performance. Absolutely not, yeah. Now, the
Penguin in the comics is unique among Batman
villains in that he's not insane, just unbelievably
prideful and narcissistic and vengeful. And
I love that this version of the character manages
to stay true to all of that while also being
fairly unique. You know, like we mentioned earlier,
Oz didn't grow up rich like in the comics,
and that serves as one of his motivations in
this universe, to help bring his mom out of
poverty and become a symbol for his community
as someone to be admired and relied upon. He
has this romanticized, almost Robin Hood-esque
view of being a mafia don, and wants to be
one. but is continually diminished and overlooked
by others due to his physical handicap and
scarred face, which he takes great offense to.
He considers the name Penguin to be very offensive
and disrespectful, and he'll straight up murder
or betray anyone to prove his worth, even impulsively,
as he did several times throughout the show,
such as with his brothers, Alberto, and even
Vic. That said, his character delves into morally
grey area, often doing bad things for seemingly
the greater good, or so we believe. Ultimately,
his narcissistic need for attention and control
culminates in the almost poetic tragedy of the
Penguin, finally attaining his lifelong goal
of becoming the head of Gotham's criminal underworld,
but at the cost of all of his relationships,
having killed Vic, essentially imprisoning his
mother, and forcing his lover, Eve, who betrayed
him, to role play as his mother in this demeaning
and twisted fantasy. I got the impression that
the relationship between Eve and Oz was always
somewhat of a role-playing type relationship.
I got the impression that was not the first
time that she had done that. Really? I didn't
get that. Although I guess I would have put
it past him. It was legitimately horrifying
seeing his mother cry in the hospital bed looking
out on the city as a vegetable trapped in her
body and having Oz interpret her tear as her
being happy for him. Yeah. Yeah, that was really
hard to watch, especially considering the fact
that we knew that's the last thing she wanted.
She wanted Oz to kill her over her ending up
like that. The fact that he twisted that into
something where he just kind of ignored her
pain, knowing the promise that he had made
to her, feeling like he had given her what she
wanted, is incredibly selfish of him, but also
right in line with the character. The fact that
he killed people who didn't deserve to die
like Vic. and left people alive who he promised
to kill is very malevolent. Yeah, what was
your reaction to him killing Vic in the final
episode, rationalizing it as Vic being too
much like family and therefore being a vulnerability
to him in his rise to power? I figured from
the very first episode that Vic was not going
to make it to the end of the series. I figured
he was living on borrowed time, essentially.
I was surprised that it happened when it happened
and the way that it happened. It was very, very
heartbreaking, but also not surprising considering
the fact that Oswald's own family, his mother,
had just betrayed him. You know, telling him
that she hated him and stuff like that. So yeah,
I see where he was coming from about how family
is not a good thing to have. I remember that
scene took me completely by surprise because
I was thinking at the time, now this is kind
of a slow scene, and then all of a sudden he
just fucking crushes his throat. And it was
kind of disturbing in the way that it snuck
up on me. Yeah, it was very disturbing. Honestly.
I know this probably won't be the case and
I kinda hope it isn't, but maybe Vic will come
back. Maybe Vic will come back as Victor Zazz
instead of Victor Aguilar. I actually hope that
happens because I think Vic was too good of
a character to just let go like that. I understand
the poetic nature of it, but I also, yeah,
like you don't want to see the character go
away. But speaking of Victor Aguilar, he was
played by Renzi Feliz. I'm still heartbroken
by what happened to Vic. He was hands down
the most likable character on the show, thanks
in large part to Renzi's very real and very
sympathetic performance. Yeah, I liked him ever
since The Runaway Show. He played Alex Wilder
in that show, so he's a really talented actor
who's now done both Marvel and DC work. But
his better stuff is for DC, as is most actors
who do both. Tell that to Jared Leto. That's
a horrible example. Now Victor was a tremendously
effective audience surrogate. You know, he
was this smart, if not naive orphaned boy who
just didn't want to die. Who eventually, like
a lot of the characters on the show, fell for
the promises that Oz made and he even began
to champion his ideals. You got the sense that
even though Vic became Oz's right-hand man,
he was adopting only Oz's good traits about
loyalty, fairness, and success. Vic felt shame
and guilt when he was forced to do bad things,
and ultimately his loyalty was rewarded with
a harsh death at the hands of a man unwilling
to share anything, power, respect, and even
a human connection. I loved how human Victor
was, you know? He made mistakes. He failed
to put the jewels in John Vede's car. He let
his girl go on the bus. He gave away a chance
at happiness in that regard. Right. Yeah. Oof.
That's super sad in hindsight. The stutter
was a pretty humanizing aspect as well. For
sure. Yeah, it was something that even Oswald
recognized. I think it was the main reason he
kind of took him on as his surrogate. I think
Rezzy Feliz did as well with his stutter acting
as someone like someone like Charlie Cox does
with his blind acting. It was just entirely
convincing and obviously well researched and
informed. And I definitely commend him for that.
Yeah, 100 percent. I didn't feel forced or
anything like that. And it was always interesting
to see when it didn't pop up, like when he
was really passionate about something. That
was cool to see. Like he had his own arc in
regards to his stutter. Moving on to Sofia Falcone,
aka Sofia Gigante, aka The Hangman. She was
played by Kristen Malotti. Now like Colin Farrell's
performance, Kristen thoroughly embodied the
role of Sofia in a very profound performance.
I only know Kristen from her comedic work on
How I Met Your Mother. So I didn't even know
she was capable of top tier acting like this.
And holy shit, where's this woman's Emmy? Like,
why even bother holding any kind of award ceremony?
Just give it to her. She was intense, man. Even
from the first episode, I was just scared as
shit of her. Yeah, when she was talking to Oz
as he was being tortured, naked on that chair
with the wire in his armpit, I was like, oh,
damn. Oh, this scene is wild. Her performance,
actually the entire cast's performances. matched
the quality of the writing, which was phenomenal,
especially for the character of Sofia. Her arc
is rooted in vengeance and a desire to reclaim
her father's empire, which she was promised
by him before he betrayed her. Her path somewhat
mirrors the penguins and how her desire to restore
her family's honor and legacy drives her to
make horrific choices. She wants to prove she's
worthy of the throne, but in doing so, she
becomes just as corrupt as the men who denied
her. Her journey is one of tragic self-destruction,
showing how even the best intentions can be
swallowed up by the desire for power. And as
she works to reclaim her birthright from the
dismissive men in her family, she ultimately
becomes the one thing she was accused of being
and never wanted to be, which was a mass murderer.
And while she's horrifying, she's also very
sympathetic because the show does a great job
of showing everything she's been through, all
the unjust trauma. But in the end, she comes
back full circle into the hell that created
the monster that she is. Yeah, back in Arkham,
which is unfortunate. She never really should
have gone back. I think the one misstep that
she had and therefore it kind of felt like the
show had was when she didn't kill Oswald when
she had the opportunity to. Instead, trying
to play this weird humiliation game between
him and his mother, you know. that just seemed
like unnecessary on her part. And she kind
of paid the price for that. She was kind of
twisted about it. You know, she had the benefit
of having a psychiatrist for a lover of sorts.
So she kind of ran with that. I could see where
she was coming from because the character was
pretty twisted and she just wanted to make
him suffer before killing him. But yeah, like
I said, I think those actions were in character
for her. I really loved the play throughout
the whole series between, you know, Sophia
being an ally of Kawalpats and then an enemy
and then an ally. and the shifting power balances
that were fluctuating throughout the episodes.
It was just really well crafted and kept me
hooked. I didn't actually think she was going
to be the main bad of the series. I thought
that was going to be Carmine Falcone or even
Alberto Falcone. I actually thought there was
going to be a reveal probably towards the end
of the season where Alberto was the real Hank
man and not his father and his father was just
covering for his son. Sort of in the same way
that Alberto was revealed to be the holiday
killer in The Long Halloween. That would have
been interesting, yeah. Yeah, I thought so.
I would have liked to have seen the actor get
more screen time. But I also don't hate the
fact that Sophia was the hangman because she
was the hangman in the comics. I think honestly
this entire cast is gonna sweep the Yemis next
year, at least for the Drama Awards. Yeah, you
better fucking hope that Agatha Alalong is
nominated as a comedy, because you are screwed.
It obviously is. I think both Agatha Alalong
and the Penguin are gonna win a lot of awards
next year. I hope so. I don't actually watch
a lot of television just doing this podcast
that isn't Marvel or DC related, especially
recently, but I have a hard time imagining something
could be better than The Penguin. And when
it wins, it'll just help solidify the superhero
genre's place in the larger film and television
landscape. Yeah, if Watchmen hadn't done that
already, hopefully The Penguin will. But let's
move on to our story highlights.
Where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
DynaMic Podcast Network presents Console Combat,
where video game legends brawl every Monday.
Comic Book Titans smash every Tuesday. Max Destruction,
where TV and action heroes battle every Wednesday.
And Sendro World, where anime champions clash
every Thursday. Join us as we speculate on
the matches and armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge victorious.
Visit dynamicpodcast.com where we settle the
debate and settle the score.
Episode 1 was titled After Hours. One week after
the assassination of Carmine Falcone and the
destruction of Gotham City Sea Wall by the Riddler,
Oswald Cobb is caught by Alberto Falcone, Carmine's
son and heir apparent as he recovers a stash
of Falcone's valuables from the Iceberg Lounge.
After Alberto reveals plans to revolutionize
the Falcone drug operation, he ridicules Oz's
aspirations to become a powerful mobster. and
Oz impulsively shoots Alberto dead. Oz attempts
to dispose of Alberto's body and threatens a
group of juvenile delinquents who are attempting
to steal the rooms from his car. He spares Victor
Aguilar after forcing him to help dispose of
Alberto's body, and hearing him stutter, ultimately
recruits him as his driver. Oz learns that
the Falcons plan to assume control of his drug
ring, while Alberto's sister, Sophia Falcone,
newly released from Arkham Asylum, suspects
Oz is responsible for Alberto's disappearance.
Oz's plans to skip town are discouraged by his
dementia-stricken mother, Frances, after which
Oz visits Falcone's rival, Salvatore Maroney,
in Blackgate Prison, offering to bring the
drug operation back into Maroney's control.
Maroney is reluctant, but reconsideres after
Oz returns to him a ring he'd taken off of Alberto
that Carmine had taken from Maroney.
but is distracted by the sudden recovery of
Alberto's body, staged by Vic to implicate
Moroni's crew. Oz is released and begins plotting
with Vic to take control of the Falcone crime
family. Fantastic first episode, I was totally
hooked from the get-go. I was super shocked
when basically in the first scene, the Penguin
killed Alberto Falcone, and it was just a series
of shocking twists and turns from then on out.
Oh, absolutely, I started watching. this show
in my living room. And right when that scene
happened, I basically yelled, oh shit. And
then I was forced to go watch in the bedroom.
I guess my one question about this episode,
which seemed like a plot hole, was did Oz know
that he was going to get captured by Sophia
and taken to the Falcon Mansion? No, I don't
believe he did. We do know that Vic kind of
screwed up the plan. He was supposed to send
the Falcons Alberto's decapitated head. He
just couldn't figure out how to do that exactly.
Yeah, I definitely don't think it was Oswald's
plan to get tortured. So the initial plan was
just to crash the car into the mansion and
just leave it at that. I just happened to be
lucky enough to be saved by Vicks timing. I
mean, the guy was cut up pretty bad. I think
timing wise, the penguin would have rather
had it come earlier. Man, the wire in the armpit.
I never would have thought of that. I've never
seen anything like that in my entire life. And
I hope I don't again. I squirmed in my chair
for sure. Looking at that method of torture.
This whole episode had such great tension.
Like even when he was getting tortured and they
found one of the kids who was stealing his
rims and he was basically like, no, the guy's
lying. It's like, oh my gosh, dude, really?
There's no way you're getting out of this. Only
for Victor to come through in that moment.
Though I rate that Oz framed him, Moroni continues
their partnership by allowing Oz to help with
a Falcon drop shipment that is subsequently
taken by Moroni's crew. Carmine's brother,
Luca, arrives to assume leadership of the crime
family. Meanwhile, Sofia suffers PTSD from
Alberto's death and becomes increasingly unhinged,
convinced someone in the family is a mole for
Moroni. She bribes a drug addicted GCPD detective,
Marcus Wise, investigate the heist and Wise
kidnaps Ervod, one of Moroni's henchmen, from
the hospital. Moroni's wife, Nadia, assigns
Oz to retrieve Ervod before the Felcones get
him to talk. During Alberto's funeral, Oz assigns
Vic to plant evidence to frame Felcone underboss
Johnny Viti for Alberto's murder while he reaches
Ervod to have him implicate Viti. However, Vic
is caught trying to plant the evidence and
barely escapes. forcing Oz to murder Ervad instead
with a switchblade, which he then plants on
Sofia's personal enforcer, Castillo, to frame
him as the mole. Luca executes Castillo, denying
Sofia's demand that she do so to avenge Alberto,
and orders her out of the family business.
Oz makes Vic dig a grave for Ervad and Castillo,
threatening to kill him if he fails again.
He then meets with Sofia, who proposes a partnership
to wipe out the Falcone family hierarchy, so
she may take control. Solid second episode.
I really love how the end of it sets up the
stakes of the show and that Penguin and Sophia
are gonna join forces to bring down the Falcone
crime family. I thought that was a great initial
setup, of course, that kind of gets unraveled,
but yeah, everything that happened in this episode,
I thought was a great continuation of the first.
Now, did Oz initially intend to plant the knife
on Viti or was he always planning on framing
Sophia's bodyguard? I initially thought he was
going to plant it on John Viti, but I think
it was actually really smart of him to do it
on Castillo considering that no one would have
probably believed that John Viti would betray
the family considering he was second in command.
And Oz wanted to utilize the leverage that he
still had on Viti later on. Makes sense, yeah.
Did you crap your pants like I did when Vic
got caught planting the jewels in John Viti's
car? No, I went to the bathroom like a regular
person. Okay, but you still had to shit yourself?
Yes. OK. I totally thought Vic was going to
die in that moment. Everything that happened
in this episode was just so unpredictable, which
is one of the reasons that I loved it. Actually,
this whole show was pretty much unpredictable.
Well, it made Oz a good protagonist despite
all of his malevolence because he was so adaptable
and able to roll with things. And it was always
interesting in seeing what ways he managed to
survive episode to episode despite all the
shit he was pulling. Oh absolutely, yeah. Moving
on to episode 3, titled Bliss. In flashbacks,
Vic is left orphaned after the Sea Wall explosion
drowns his family. In the present, Sofia introduces
Oz to a new drug that was used on her and other
inmates at Arkham, which Oz names Bliss. Together
they make a pitch to the Triads to help distribute
the Bliss across the city, but they refuse
to do business with the pair unless they gain
the support of John Vede. Oz and Sofia blackmail
Viti for his support by threatening to expose
his sexual affair with Luca's wife, after which
the triads agree to enter into business with
Oz and Sofia. Meanwhile, Vic is torn by his
desire to leave Gotham with his girlfriend in
pursuit of a better life, or staying with Oz
to potentially become rich and powerful, while
also fearing that Oz will kill him if he tries
to flee. When Oz learns of Vic's intentions,
though angry, Oz allows Vic to leave. Vic ultimately
chooses Oz over his girlfriend however, and
returns only to find Oz and Sophia held at
gunpoint by the Morones, who have realized Oz's
duplicity. Before a hitman can execute Oz,
Vic crashes Oz's car into him and the two escape,
leaving Sophia abandoned to her fate with the
Morones. Now all of this happened really fast
I thought, which was exciting. Oz playing like
triple agent between the Falcons. and Moroni's
and Sofia's own little thing. I didn't think
it was going to unravel as quickly as it did.
Yeah, and it was so climactic that I almost
was wondering where the show could possibly
go from there. Oh, same. It just felt like
everything that the story had been building
towards in that moment just came crashing down.
And then the series, you know, became about
Sofia and the Moroni's teaming up to go up
against Oz. But yeah, I was basically on the
edge of my seat at the end of this episode.
And the start of the episode, like seeing the
seawall crash into Vic's home and seeing his
family die and experiencing the attack that
the Riddler did on the city was the stuff from
nightmares. Oh, literally. It was so tragic
and real feeling. I literally have nightmares
about tidal waves. So that was very, very horrifying
when I saw that. And just seeing Vic's expression
as well, like you cannot be more sympathetic
towards that guy. He lost everything. blame
Batman for Vicks and his family's death. Okay.
If he was smart enough, if he was a good enough
detective to know what a fucking carpet tool
was, none of that would have happened. Wow.
You know what? Victor probably would have blamed
Batman too. Now we've compared the show to
genre greats like the Godfather, Scarface, but
it also reminds me a lot of like the Sopranos
and Breaking Bad, especially when we get a look
drugs that they're growing on freaking mushrooms
instead of like blue meth crystals like in Breaking
Bad it's red crystals which was really interesting
to see it was like something new I'd never seen
before the way they were doing that and to
have the backstory of it come from like Arkham
medication that was brilliant. Moving on to
episode four titled Chentani. In flashbacks
Sophia learns from a reporter that Carmine
is suspected of being the hangman. a serial
killer who strangled and hanged numerous women
in a similar manner as she had witnessed her
own mother die when Sofia was a child. Desperate
for answers, Sofia meets with the reporter privately.
Oz alerts Carmine to that, who retaliates by
framing Sofia for the murders and having her
committed to Arkham Asylum, horrifying both
Alberto and Oz. Though she's initially only
to be confined for six months, Carmine pulls
strings to extend her stay to over a decade
until his death. She is constantly mocked by
the inmates, while her doctor, Ventress, subjects
her to electroshock therapy. Ventress' associate,
Dr. Julian Rush, eventually realizes that Sofia
is innocent and quits. The mental and physical
strain leads Sofia into a breakdown, and she
murders her cellmate, Magpie. In the present,
Sofia is rescued by Rush, and Sofia, having
learned from Nadia that Oz murdered Alberto,
concludes that no one can be trusted. That night
she unleashes a gas in the Felcone mansion
that wipes out the Felcone family hierarchy
including Luca. She spares Gia, her cousin's
young daughter, and Viti whom she holds at gunpoint.
This is a pretty good flashback episode. Arkham
looks absolutely horrifying and I really like
how they kept up the continuity from the Batman
film and how the institution was presented.
Yeah, it looks like they used the same set
for sure. I agree. Absolutely horrifying. This
is another nightmarish situation where you're
just trapped in a mental institution and over
medicated so that you can't escape or do anything
or no one will believe you. It's very much believable
that something like that, along with the electroshock
therapy, would drive Sophia insane. It was neat
how Magpie was in this episode, who is a Batman
villain. She's like a thief, right? Right, yeah.
Although I will say that the actress kinda
turned in a CW performance for an HBO show.
Uh, yeah, that's fair. Although I'm not- I'm
not quite sure what else I would have expected
from her. It was very like Harley Quinn-lite,
I would say. And speaking of Batman villains,
did you see that fans spotted a scarecrow mask
and glove inside Julian Rush's office? Wait,
what? No? Yeah, there are screenshots you can
see of it online. Okay, I need to see that now.
It's not necessarily an implication that Julian
was the scarecrow. It may just been that he
was treating Jonathan Crane while in Arkham.
Oh snap, look at that. Oh man, I cannot wait
to see Matt Reeves version of Scarecrow. That's
gonna be awesome. If that happens. Oh, they're
freaking teasing that it's gonna happen. Who
do you want to be the main villain of the Batman
2? I keep hearing rumors that it's going to
be Mr. Freeze and that his whole thing is going
to be a new drug in Gotham City that freezes
people. I didn't hate the interpretation, but
I also wouldn't hate if they went with someone
like the Scarecrow who's a little bit more grounded
I would say than even Mr. Freeze. I just think
Mr. Freeze needs to be done justice on screen.
We've already had a good version of Scarecrow.
I want to see Clayface be the bad guy and as
opposed to being like a muck monster guy he's
just like a serial killer in the same vein of
what we got earlier this year in Batman the
Kid Crusader. I would totally love that. I would
accept that, absolutely. Moving on to episode
five
as ransom in exchange for the Bliss shipment
stolen by Nadia. At the same time, Oz has Vic
look after Francis. During the trade, a guard
bribed by Oz tries to assassinate Moroni in
Blackgate, while Oz kills Taj and Nadia by setting
both on fire while exchanging the hostage for
the drugs. The fire activates chemical extinguishing
sprays that destroys most of the Bliss, while
Moroni survives the attempt on his life and
escapes prison. Meanwhile, Gia is sent to a
children's home. and Sofia tortures Viti until
he decides to support her bid to be the family
head. Joined by Rush, who has fallen in love
with her, Sofia rebrands the family under her
mother's maiden name, Gigante, and earns the
loyalty of the crew by making an appeal to
shared oppression under the former Mafia heads.
When Viti objects to her plans, Sofia executes
him. She and a grieving Moroni later form an
alliance to kill Oz. Elsewhere, Oz, after learning
of Moroni's escape and losing the support of
his lover Eve, is berated by his mother for
forcing her to hide in a condemned apartment
in the no-mans land area of Gotham known as
Crown Point, where Oz and Francis used to live.
Oz remembers an abandoned underground railway
nearby, showing it to Vic and declaring it their
new base of operations to regrow the Bliss.
The scene where the Penguin straight up sets
the mother and son on fire was so hardcore.
Yeah, I kind of saw it coming a mile away though,
because I was like, what else would he be dripping
wet with? Right. Would it make sense for it
to be anything else but something combustible?
It made me think of the scene from Luke Cage,
which I think was like a better emulation scene
in terms of how impactful and frightening it
was. But this one was also pretty up there.
Oz definitely executed some pretty interesting
plans on his road to power. I love how they
incorporated the underground trolley system
of Gotham into the show. because the character
of the Penguin has usually been associated with
like the sewers. You know, you take a look
at something like Batman Returns and how, you
know, he was basically abandoned there as a
baby. But instead of growing up in the sewers
like that, in this show, not only did they
have him build his criminal underworld from
there, but it was also like the true origin
of the character because it was the location
of where he first killed his brothers. Yeah,
I thought it was definitely an homage to Batman
returns having them work out of the tunnels
underground. But it was weird in that made him
feel more like the Danny DeVito version of
the character, as opposed to the comic book
version of the character. And they're pulling
for multiple inspirations. I thought it was
fine. I thought it was cool. To me, the penguin
will always be the guy operating from the penthouse
floor of the iceberg lounge building more than
the guy operating out of the underground sewer
system. I think he's at home in both worlds,
honestly. I think the show showed that. Episode
6 was titled Gold Summit. Oz has managed to
regrow his drug empire significantly, reproducing
and distributing the Bliss via the city's abandoned
underground trolley system. Sophia and the Moronis
kill several Bliss dealers as a warning, leading
Oz to decide to give away Bliss for free to
raise demand across all other gang territories.
Vic is confronted by Squid, a drug dealer from
his neighborhood, who asks Vic to let him join
the operation. Vic attempts to pay him off,
but when Squid threatens to expose Vic and
Oz unless he gets a meeting with Oz, Vic shoots
him dead and flees. Frances's condition deteriorates
further and she has Oz promise to kill her if
she becomes severely ill. Oz threatens the
corrupt councilman Sebastian Haiti to restore
electricity to Crown Point and sets a meeting
with the heads of the other gangs, who he convinces
to work together against the Gigantes and Morones.
Sophia and Sel break into Oz's apartment to
find leverage against him, and Sophia discovers
a photo of Eve. Sophia visits Eve, threatening
to kill her to get to Oz, but Eve gives up
his location after Sophia reveals Oz was aware
of the true identity of the Hanged Man who
targeted prostitutes. Francis and Vic dance
to music after power is restored to Crown Point,
just as Sophia enters their home with a crowbar.
Can you remind me where any of the prostitute
characters in this show also in the Batman movie
with Selena Kyle? I don't believe so. They
mentioned the 44 below and some of them working
down there, but I don't remember their faces
from the movie. One of the most heartbreaking
moments of the series is not only when Oswald
has to pull his mother out of the freezing cold
bathtub, but also when Vic is forced to shoot
his childhood, not quite friend, but acquaintance.
I thought those are two very powerful moments
from the series and they both happened in this
episode. You know, one is this very dark moment
between a mother and son about euthanasia, and
the other one sort of signals Vic's descent
into possibly being bad. Why do you think Vic
chose to live the life of a criminal as opposed
to going with his girlfriend to California?
I think Oz is incredibly persuasive. You saw
that with him talking with the other gang members.
I think Vic truly believed. the promise that
the Penguin could give him a life better than
one he had ever known with his family in Crown
Point. It's things like that make me feel less
sympathy for the character of Vic and his fate
at the end of the show when you just see him
make some truly bad decisions in regards to
life in general. Well, I definitely think him
not going with his girlfriend when Oz essentially
let him was a huge mistake. I'm not sure that
killing Squid... was a mistake because it was
something that had to be done in part for his
own self-defense. Squid was an abusive and
unpredictable element that definitely needed
to be eliminated for Oz's and Vic's empire
to succeed. Moving on to episode 7 titled Top
Hat. In a flashback, Oz is resentful of the
attention that his mother gives to his brothers
Jack and Benny. After a game of hide and seek
in the sewer tunnels, Oz leaves his brothers
trapped inside an overflowing sewer tunnel
where they drown. In the present, Oz returns
to his apartment and finds an injured Vic,
who reveals that Sofia has kidnapped Francis.
Vic escapes right before Moroni arrives with
his men, who find and beat Oz before forcing
him to take them to his underground lair. Oz
and his men stage an ambush and Moroni dies
of a heart attack while fighting Oz. Meanwhile-
Sophia has Rush interrogate Francis about Oz's
weaknesses and visits Gia after learning that
she intends to cooperate with the police. Disillusioned
after seeing the pain she has caused Gia, Sophia
considers accepting Oz's ultimatum to trade
Francis for his bliss supply, but Rush convinces
her to go through with her desire to see Oz
suffer. During the trade, Sophia instead sends
in a bomb that destroys Oz's underground base
and kills his entire crew. Oz survives and
resurfaces only to be knocked out by Detective
Wise. There aren't a lot of funny moments in
this show, but I definitely thought one of them
was when Moroni had a heart attack while fighting
Oz, which shouldn't be funny because heart attacks
aren't funny. But that was just so absurd how
that happened. And even Oz was like, what the
fuck? Yeah, he was adamant that he won fair
and square during their fight, even though he
basically lucked out. I thought it was really
cool how Oz developed a loyalty amongst the
people working underground with him, so much
so that he had his own army to fight back against
the Morones when they came down there. Killing
the lights and everything, I thought was just
a really cool strategy that helped them win.
What did you think about the flashback to Oz's
childhood in that he was basically a kid murderer
at the time who showed no remorse? I initially
thought that he was naive enough to not fully
recognize his own actions. But then I think
later on it became clear that his actual intent
was to kill his brothers. Yeah, I'm with you.
I thought initially he didn't realize what
he had done. But later on in the series you
kind of realize that there's something not
quite right with this kid. And maybe he did
it as an act of impulsive rage for his brothers
utilizing his handicap against him. And that
he couldn't get down to where they were. But
that makes him sound insane. And yet adult Oswald
doesn't- seem that insane. Like he's evil,
but he's not necessarily crazy. He's malicious
and vengeful and narcissistic. Those can be
seen as mental illnesses of a degree, but ultimately
when you take a look at the history of the
comics, yeah, he does kill his brothers as a
kid for largely the same reasons because they
made fun of him. Sociopathy, I guess you could
describe it. Yeah, exactly. Although in this
case, I think part of him was just looking out
for his mother. You know, he saw how hard of
a time she was having, and he didn't want her
to be burdened by two other brothers. And you
know, he was selfish. He wanted all of her attention
for himself. So it's interesting how a character
like the Penguin throughout the whole show is
kind of playing two different games, one that
benefits him and the one that, you know, benefits
his family. That's sort of what's somewhat
endearing about the character. You know, like
what kind of guy would threaten a councilman
to turn on the lights for the community that
he was living in. What kind of guy wants to
foster this helpful relationship with his community?
Well, the kind of guy who relies on the community
to run his criminal enterprise. That's fair.
Moving on to the final episode, episode 8,
titled A Great or Little Thing. Using EMDR therapy,
Rush learns that Francis already knew about
Oz drowning his brothers and tried to have him
killed by the gangster Rex Calabrese. but Oz's
manipulative promises as a child convinced her
not to go through with it. Oz is brought to
Sophia, who threatens to cut off Francis' finger
unless Oz confesses to his mom the truth that
he killed his brothers. Oz refuses to admit
his actions even as Rush tortures Francis,
causing her to disown him before suffering a
stroke. Oz manages to escape, killing Wise,
and getting Francis to the hospital. Meanwhile,
the local bosses abandon Oz for Sophia, puts
out a bounty for Oz as she prepares to leave
Gotham. While Oz forms an alliance with Councilman
Hady, Vic arranges for the bosses to be murdered
by their deputies, who help Oz abduct Sophia.
Instead of killing her, Oz has his new police
contacts return her to Arkham. Oz and Vic visit
Francis to celebrate only to learn that she
entered a vegetative state, causing Oz to break
down. Later that night, Vic tells Oz that he
views him as family, which Oz reciprocates
before murdering Vic, saying that families make
people weak. Meanwhile, Rush, who has returned
to Arkham to care for Sophia, hands her a letter
from her half-sister, Selina Kyle. Oz takes
the vegetative Francis to a new penthouse suite
where he dances with Eve dressed as Francis
as the bat signal shines in the sky. I loved
this final episode. I thought it was a solid
ending to the season and potentially series
as a whole. I'm not sure if we're gonna get
a second season of this. But yeah, everything
that happened here, from Oz being unwilling
to admit that he killed his brothers to his
mom, even though she already knew, to the Penguin's
very own Don Corleone-type moment in which all
of the heads of the different gangs are killed
at the same time. It was all so freaking great.
Yeah, that was a great twist, along with getting
Sophia Falcone put back into Arkham. I totally
thought he was gonna kill her. And... It was
a great bit of writing leading up to her apparent
demise that had you convinced that he was going
to kill her. He gave her a fate worse than death,
right? He put her exactly where she did not
want to end up again. Although I have to imagine
Rush would probably help her escape. Yeah,
most likely. I wonder what the letter said that
Selina Kyle wrote her. Yeah, I'm wondering
the same thing. I'm actually thinking that we're
going to see Sophia Falcone show up again in
the Batman sequel, maybe alongside Catwoman.
And if that's the case, I wonder what storyline
they're adapting. I imagine we're going to see
the Penguin again and Sophia again. And yeah,
that makes me really curious, you're right,
as to what they will be doing with the story,
whatever they do. I'm here for it because I
loved this show. Again, I can't wait to see
more of this universe. I hope it keeps going
on and on and that James Gunn decides to make
it a part of his main universe overall with
this season. Its outstanding performances and
epic brutal storyline made The Limited Series
a crime thriller of the highest caliber and
a masterpiece within the genre I felt. I'm giving
it 5 out of 5 stars, just like The Batman,
a fresh rating on Rotten Tomatoes. Yeah, I'm
not sure if you're referring to it as a masterpiece
within the crime genre or within the superhero
genre, but honestly it doesn't matter because
I think that term applies to both. Not only
is it a great entry into superhero media in
general, but I 100% think that the show holds
up among the greatest crime dramas ever made.
Like it's right up there with The Godfather,
The Departed and things like that. I'm not
sure if it's up there with The Godfather, but
I would say it's definitely up there with like
The Sopranos. And you know, holding this season
up against any season of Breaking Bad, I think
it's competitive. I would love to see more seasons.
I don't think we're going to get them. But
I could follow this Penguin story all the way
to the end, for sure. I think one of the best
things that I can say about the show is that
I was at a restaurant the other day and the
bartender lady who was middle-aged, she looked
like to be in her fifties or something like
that, she just brought up out of the blue with
some people sitting at the bar how great this
show was. And it just stood out to me as being
something that had tremendous crossover appeal
in terms of its audience and demographic. I
heard that the show has done really well. and
I hope that's the case. And I hope it brings
a lot of new audiences to the genre. Yeah,
I think it doesn't hurt that it was propped
up as an HBO original that comes with a lot
of clout, right? I've actually had coworkers
come up to me asking me if I had seen The Penguin,
which I hadn't yet. And they're like, oh, you're
going to love it. It's so good. I thought it
was really good. And that just got me even more
excited to start watching it. Yeah, I'm sure
they agree with your five star rating. I agree
with your five star rating. I'll say it's still
not better than Daredevil season three. but
I'll say it's probably the best television
series that DC has ever produced. Even better
than Watchmen? I think it was better than Watchmen.
Holy cow, maybe, maybe. I know it was better
than Agatha all along, that's for sure. Barely.
Like I said in our last episode, they're entirely
different shows. I think Marvel could absolutely
produce a series like The Penguin with no issues,
but can DC produce a series about a magic coven
of witches at the same quality as Marvel Television
did with that show? I don't think so. They
don't need to make lame shows like that, because
they make cool shows like The Penguin. OK,
yeah. But that does it for this review. AJ9K
help close this out.
or by rating and reviewing dynamic duel on Apple
podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser, or on our website.
Don't forget to listen to the other shows in
the DynaMic podcast network, including Max
Destruction, Senjou World, and Console Combat.
In our next episode, we will be doing a duel
as a tie-in to this review of the Penguin between
another street level Gotham villain character,
Black Mask, against Marvel's Madam Mask. Yeah,
two grounded criminal characters within Marvel
and DC that don't have powers but they do have
badass masks should be interesting to see how
that plays out. So mask off bro, let's go! Me
and you! But that is it for this episode, we
want to give a big thanks to our executive producers
Ken Johnson, John Storosky, Zachary Hepburn,
Dustin Belcombe, Miggy Mantagian, Brendan Estergard,
Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Austin Waselowski,
AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam
Spies, Andrew Schunk. Dean Molesky, Kevin Davis,
Joseph Kirsting, Josh Leiner, and our newest
executive producer, Mike Williams. Thanks for
helping make this podcast possible guys, we'll
talk to you all next week. Up, up and away,
true believers.