This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
And welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Marvelous Joe. And I'm his twin brother
Johnny DC. And guys, this is the episode where
we find out who'd win in a fight between the
Red Lantern Atrocitus and the Juggernaut. Holy
shitballs, this is going to be an awesome episode.
I cannot believe it has taken us until year,
what is this, eight, nine, to get to a Juggernaut
duel. Shame on us. It's a crime for sure. Yeah,
Juggernaut is one of the most powerful Marvel
characters out there. And I don't think Atrocitus
has a chance in hell of winning this duel. I
mean, the guy punches strong. What else is
there? Oh, you'll find out. later on as we get
into the characters' backstories, and then
we'll run their stats in a thousand simulations
to come out with a definitive winner. Before
that, we're going to break down the latest comic
book movie news that came out this past week,
which we got a lot of. There was the new Captain
America Brave New World official teaser, we
got the Agatha All Along teaser trailer, as
well as the Watchmen Chapter 1 Red Band trailer.
A lot to talk about, but as always, we list
our segment times in our episode description,
so feel free to check out the show notes if
you want to skip ahead to a particular topic.
Our artificially intelligent duel simulator
AJ 9k has a quick message for our listeners.
So listen up. Why hello there, do you want even
more from this podcast? Then become a part
of the dynamic duel community on Patreon, where
you can choose from three tiers. The dynamic
two-oh tier gives you access to our Discord
chat server. The fantastic four tier gives
you two bonus episodes each month, and the X-Force
tier makes you an executive producer of this
show. Lastly, The DynaMic Podcast Network tier
lets you create your own podcast using this
Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe will help
you develop your show, provide graphic support
and consultation, and get you simulation results.
Pitch the twins your ideas via email at dynamicduelpodcast
at gmail.com. Check it out at patreon.com slash
dynamicduel. Pip pip cheerio. Thanks AJ and
N1K and thanks to everyone who supports the
podcast. Guys, be sure to tune into the other
shows on the DynaMic Podcast Network this week.
including Max Destruction, which pits your
favorite action heroes from film and television
against each other. This week, hosts Ken and
Scottie are pitting Schwarzenegger's Conan the
Barbarian against King Leonidas from 300. I
know we said that last week, but in their last
episode they actually reviewed Conan the Barbarian.
On the Senjoworld podcast, hosts Zachary Hepburn
speculates on fights between fan favorite anime
and manga characters. The show is currently
on a season hiatus, but it's coming back in
a few weeks. So this is the perfect time to
catch up on Send Your World's 40 episode library.
And on the Console Combat podcast, hosts John
and Dean find out who would win in fights between
popular video game characters. In yesterday's
episode, they found out who would win in a
battle between Codsworth from Fallout 4 and
Clap Trap from Borderlands. So it was like
a BattleBots episode. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com
or click the link in our show notes to listen
to all of the shows in the DynaMic Podcast
Network. But with that out of the way, quick
to the no prize. A no prize is an award Marvel
used to give out to fans. Our version, the
dynamic duel no prize, is a digital award that
we post on Instagram for the person that we
feel gave the best answer to our question of
the week. Last week we asked you guys, what
other Marvel or DC character would you like
to see get a cultural re-imagining for a one-off
special? And this was coming off of the Batman
Ninja versus Yakuza League teaser trailer that
we got. the week prior, we were saying what
other kind of concepts you guys could come
up with that was similar to Batman Ninja. And
we got a lot of great answers. Like all of
them were great. It was really hard to pick
the honorable mentions and winner this week.
But the first honorable mention goes to Travis
Herndon, who said, What's up, Donn and Medoos.
Travis here. Shout out to my twins. So my answer
had to be Spider-Man, but with an African style
makeover. You can even go for a more mystical
route with him that instead of like a regular
spider total, it could be a Nazi, the spider
from African mythology. I mean, that would
be cool, like a mystical Spider-Man. Like imagine
that kind of Spider-Man teaming up with Black
Panther. So that's my answer, African Spider-Man.
This was such an awesome answer. African Spider-Man,
of course, there's the African deity and Nazi,
the spider. So it totally makes sense that
there would be an African Spider-Man and, you
know, his stories could take place. in early
Africa and it works so well for the character,
especially since Anansi is always depicted
as kind of like a trickster, jokey kind of god.
But the answer is too good because it's already
actually been done in Marvel Comics. The very
first Spider-Man in the Marvel 616 universe
was actually named Anansi and he was in Africa.
Yeah, that blew my mind. I loved this answer
so much. I totally thought we were going to
give it the win until you were like, this is
actually already a thing. I was like, what?
And maybe Travis Herndon subliminally already
knew that, and maybe that's why he gave it as
his answer. But yeah, great answer. Our next
honorable mention goes to Cat Stevenson, who
said. Hi guys, it's Cat, first time caller,
long time listener. I think it would be really
cool to set Hawkeye in a wild Western setting.
I know it's one of the weirder things, but I
think a Sheriff Hawkeye thing would be really
intriguing to watch, and I think it'd be super
fun. It'd be a good movie, different animation
styles, and I would till to see a bow and arrow
duel scene. That would be epic. Alright guys,
hope you have a good day. Bye bye. This is a
really fun answer. I think having Hawkeye set
in the days of the Old West using his bow and
arrow instead of gun slinging... fight villains
as like the sheriff of this old west town. That's
perfect. I could totally picture it in my head.
Like maybe he was trained by Native Americans
at the time and the use of the bow and arrow
and he just prefers to use that and he's like
shooting down the barrels of bad guys guns
as they're like set to draw and everything like
that. It would be fantastic. Yeah, seeing like
a high noon type duel and the dirt roads of
the old west with a bow and arrow would be
wild. Wild west. And they could probably name
the movie Wild West. And then they have like
a giant spider in it. And Nazi. Oh, my God,
it's all it all makes sense. It's coming full
circle. Great answer, cat. Our next honorable
mention goes to Colby Hentges, who said, Hey,
boys, Colby Hentges, I'd like to see Dr. Strange
get a Celtic reimagining, less occult and mysticism,
more nature and druid kind of vibes. That's
what I want. That would be cool. Like have
an old medieval style version of Dr. Strange.
Just reimagine him in that time period, probably
set around Ireland or Scotland or something
like that, the old Celtic region, and have
a more of a, yeah, Druid nature bound type of
spell caster. I think that works pretty well
for the master of the mystic arts. I'm actually
not too familiar with Druid shamanism and how
it compares to something like occultism. So
I'd actually be really interested to see that.
Well, it's like a lot of animal and plants.
control, like nature control type stuff, right?
Gotcha. That'd be totally cool to see. And I
would love to see it like in that, like book
of Kells, Wolfwalkers type animation style.
That'd be really cool. Oh, hell yeah. Yeah,
that's really cool. That's a great idea. Great
answer, Colby. We want to give a special shout
out to Micky Matangian who suggested the idea
of a Filipino flash, which was a great concept.
I think we were just looking for more of a hook
there. Also shout out to Cyrus Moore who said
he wanted to see stories about green lanterns
throughout American history, dating back to
the Revolutionary War. which was just a little
bit more broad of a concept than we were looking
for. But that does sound pretty cool too. Yeah,
I really liked both of those answers. But the
winner of this week's no prize is Joseph Kirsting,
who said. Hi, it's Joseph Kirsting. The character
I think is green arrow in ancient Greece. I
think you see him grow up under the rifle king.
Maybe a son of Apollo get banished by an evil
king. Him. fight his way back in a classic
hero quest and overthrow the evil king and become
a vigilante king hybrid and then it'd be pretty
cool. Yeah, ancient Greek myths are heavily
influential when it comes to heroic storytelling
in comics in particular. It would be really
cool to see Oliver Queen among the pantheon
of heroes that include like Hercules and Perseus
and Jason. His old school approach really works
within that world, because you could also explain
his trick arrows as being divine or mythic
in some way. Yeah, given to him by Apollo or
Artemis or something like that, fantastic.
Yeah, that would be really cool. The way Joseph
described the story that he would wanna see,
it sounds a lot like Perseus, and that's fine
with me. I think if you could retell some of
these ancient stories with superhero characters,
I think that'd be actually a pretty cool interpretation.
That actually would be really cool. I would
read a series about that for sure. So great
answer, Joseph. You win this week's No Prize.
If you the listener want a shot at winning
your own No Prize, stay tuned to later on in
this episode when we'll be asking another question
of the week. And now that that's done, on to
the news.
Alright, this past week we got our first official
teaser trailer for the upcoming Captain America
Brave New World movie that's coming out on Valentine's
Day in 2025. I was really shocked when this
trailer came out because I wasn't expecting
it to come out, but it makes sense considering
that they're starting to do fan screenings for
Deadpool and Wolverine and this teaser is almost
certainly playing before that movie. And I'm
here for it. I think my big takeaway from watching
the trailer was that it perfectly captures the
vibe of the Captain America spy espionage thriller
section of the Marvel Cinematic Universe. That
tone was established in films like Captain
America The Winter Soldier, Captain America
Civil War, and of course the Falcon and the
Winter Soldier Disney Plus television series.
It's my favorite pocket of the MCU, I think,
and this trailer gets me super pumped to revisit
that tone for these Marvel films. Yeah, it
totally gives off vibes of Winter Soldier for
me. I really didn't want to like this trailer
because you know Falcon and the Winter Soldier
I thought was okay. It had some great action
scenes, but I can't say I was really looking
forward to seeing this film in particular.
Now I cannot wait to see this. It looks like
it's going to be everything that I hope the
MCU returns to. It just looks like it's going
to be really badass. For sure. Yeah, I mean
if you watched Falcon and the Winter Soldier,
that show did have a villain problem with Flag
Smasher. But we got to see Falcon go up against
the likes of Batroc the Leaper, which was really
badass, and the Tunisia flight scene was probably
one of the most incredible action scenes out
of any Marvel movie or show. Actually, I think
it'll be hard to top in this movie, but considering
we see Captain America going up against like
other fighter jets in a similar vibe to the
first Iron Man movie, they might just be able
to accomplish beating the Tunisia flight scene.
Yeah, I don't know if they're going to be able
to, but it looks like they're trying really
damn hard. You know, with the second wingman,
his sidekick, the new Falcon, I forget his
name. Yeah, Joaquin Torres. That's going to
be cool. And also looks like they're doing
a callback to Eternals because there's been
a lot of speculation that whole flight action
scene takes place around Tiamat, the celestial
that was coming out of Earth's core. Yeah,
the big rumors that that's where Adamantium
is going to come from. I don't know if that's
been confirmed or not, but that would be pretty
cool as a tie into the future X-Men franchise.
Yeah, for sure. Now, the teaser trailer starts
with Sam Wilson meeting with President Thunderbolt
Ross, formerly General Thunderbolt Ross, who
was played by William Hurt, who unfortunately
passed away prior to this movie filming. Harrison
Ford, we've talked about this recasting before.
I think he's an inspired choice to replace William
Hurt.
caliber and credibility with fans show up in
a Marvel film. I'm really excited to see Harrison
Ford in this role, especially since one of the
most exciting things about this trailer came
from one of the end tags of the Red Hulk appearance.
Yeah, that was a fantastic way to end this
trailer. I got pumped up. Like the Hulk is my
favorite Marvel character. I honestly don't
know too much about the Red Hulk. I know that
the angrier he gets, the hotter he gets, not
like sexually. But like heat wise, yeah, the
angrier he gets, the more he emits heat radiation.
Okay, cool. Yeah. Uh, we need to get duel with
him in here soon, I think, or maybe closer
to the actual drop date of this film, but I'm
looking forward to that too. For sure. Yeah.
I think one of the coolest things about this
whole trailer too, was this initial setup,
this conversation between Sam Wilson and Thunderbolt
Ross and the premise that Ross wants to make
Captain America a figure in the military once
again.
It's also interesting because they already have
US Agent working for them, so why would they
need Captain America? That's a great point.
Probably because US Agent sucks. Yeah, fuck
that guy! Although, he'll be showing up in the
Thunderbolts movie, so he might be able to
redeem himself there. As will Thunderbolt Ross,
apparently. We get some pretty good shots of
Giancarlo Esposito's character. We don't quite
know who he's going to be playing, but the
rumor is that he's going to play a former SHIELD
agent named G.W. Bridge. who's actually a good
guy. The vibes that he gives off during this
trailer is that he looks kind of sinister,
but that could also be translated as badass
as fuck. It was interesting to see Isaiah Bradley
here who was in the Falcon and the Winter television
show. He was another super soldier, the first
black super soldier, and he tries to assassinate
President Ross. Yeah, not gonna lie, this trailer
definitely hit a little bit differently after
Trump's assassination attempt. It's a dark
reminder of what the world is actually like.
For sure. You know, there's actually a lot
of shit going on in the real world that's affecting
this movie and actually even the Falcon and
the Winter Soldier because that show originally
had a plot dealing with a global virus. And
now you have this movie with an attempted assassination
and also all the shit that's going on in Israel
and Gaza right now. As a matter of fact, that
geopolitical situation has forced Marvel to
drop the moniker of Sabra from Shir Haas who
plays the character in this movie. I believe
the change that they're going with is that Ruth
Bat Sarraf is going to be a former black widow
as opposed to the Israeli hero. Can life stop
imitating art, please? For real, right? Hopefully
nothing else drastic happens like the White
House doesn't get destroyed or something like
that. Yeah, if it's destroyed by like a red
hulk especially, I'm gonna be like, nope. We
do get a slight glimpse of the back of the leader's
head, Samuel Stearns played by Tim Blake Nelson,
and we hear his voice in this trailer too, actually.
Who knows what part the leader is going to
play in this movie. If he's the one who's maybe
mind-controlling Isaiah Bradley because he
does have the power of telepathy in the comics,
maybe he has something to do with transforming
President Ross into the Red Hulk. That would
make sense. But however it plays out, I'm super
here for this movie, man. I cannot wait to see
it. Yeah, I'm really looking forward to the
leader as a villain because we've been waiting
for him ever since the second film within the
MCU, The Incredible Hulk. Right, yeah, they've
been sitting on the character for a while,
so hopefully it's all worth the wait. Hopefully
this movie is better than the Falcon and the
Winter Soldier television series, which we thought
was mostly okay. But that brings us to our
question of the week.
What has been your favorite Disney Plus original
series from Marvel Studios so far?
Record your answer at dynamicduel.com by clicking
on the red microphone button in the bottom
right hand corner of the screen, which will
prompt you to leave us a voicemail. Your message
could be up to 30 seconds long, and don't forget
to leave your name in case we include you on
the podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer
and award that person a Dynamic Duel No Prize
that we'll post to Instagram. Be sure to answer
before July 20th. And speaking of Disney Plus
originals, this past week we also got our first
teaser trailer for Agatha All Along season
one. I also was not expecting this trailer.
I don't even know what I was expecting from
this show. I thought maybe it was gonna be quirky
and silly, similar to the early episodes of
the WandaVision television series, but I was
kind of blown away by this trailer, honestly.
Were you surprised, Jonathan? Dude, I was so
confused at the start of it. Like, it's a long
setup, right? Making you feel like you're in
some sort of dark police procedural. Yeah,
I mean, It heavily evokes the television series
called The Killing, which is a fantastic television
series. Actually, this series appears to be
evoking a lot of thriller and horror based
series, including The Killing, including, you
know, like even The Exorcist. There's a whole
lot to enjoy here. And I'm actually really looking
forward to the show after not really anticipating
it at all. I think it'll be a good time around
the Halloween season. Yeah, I agree. This is
definitely a show that I don't think anyone
asked for. I mean, Agatha Harkness. getting
her own television series. That's kind of crazy.
But I was really glad to see that this show
is invoking like a lot of different horror genre
tropes in the same way that WandaVision did
with classic television. I think it makes it
a worthy successor of WandaVision in that regard.
Yeah, Agatha Harkness is not a popular Marvel
character for sure, definitely nobody asked
for this series, but she does inhabit this very
specific corner of the Marvel Universe, specifically
witchcraft. You know, if you're talking about
witches, outside of the Scarlet Witch, Agatha
Harkness is like the biggest player in the game.
And it seems like they have an interesting
story to tell here where we see that Agatha
was trapped in Wanda's spell. And since the
Scarlet Witch died in the Multiverse of Badness,
there's no way for her to get out. So we have
this other witch, Rio, played by Aubrey Plaza,
kind of snap her out of the spell and see if
she can get her magic back, it looks like. Although
I'm not entirely sure Aubrey Plaza is a good
guy or a bad guy here. She really comes across
as the same character that she played in the
Legion television series, which is far and away
one of my favorite Marvel television series
ever. But in that show, she played Lenny, who
was once possessed by the Shadow King. And
I don't know if it's just Aubrey Plaza's demeanor
or cadence or something like that, but she
always comes across as a little kind of sinister.
I totally get those vibes as well. If they
have any sort of multiversal aspect to the show,
it would be nice to get a callback to Lenny,
because Aubrey Plaza was just incredible in
the Legion television series. But here she
plays a witch alongside Agatha. Agatha is going
to walk the Witch's Road, which is apparently
a trial to get her magic powers back. And so
she assembles this coven of covenless witches,
which looks like a lot of fun. Apparently this
includes Billy Maximoff, who is the son of
Wanda. I don't know who the actor is. I've never
seen him in anything. I've seen a lot of people
praised his performance in Heartstopper. So
hopefully that translates to this show. No,
he's not actually Billy yet, right? Well, he's
credited, I believe, as just teen, but I think
it's gonna be revealed that he is Billy. Okay.
A.K.A. Wiccan, a member of the Young Avengers.
I wonder if we'll run into Speed as well this
series. His brother? Yeah, that would be fantastic.
I don't know if he fits. within the story that
they're trying to tell here about witches and
magic, but it feels not right to see one brother
and not the other. I think it's fantastic that
Marvel appears to be going full on horror with
this, you know, we did get a glimpse of that
with the werewolf by night special, but it looks
like they're taking that even further here
with some truly scary seeming moments in the
teaser. Yeah, for real, at one point I was
like, what the fuck is this, the conjuring?
The show debuts on September 18th, I believe
the first two episodes are going to come out
on that day, then each episode is going to
come out weekly into November. and we'll definitely
be reviewing it once all the episodes come
out. So look forward to that, but also look
forward to our upcoming review of Watchmen
Chapter 1 for which a Red Band trailer was dropped
this past week. Now I don't have too much to
say about the trailer other than it looks incredibly
faithful to the source material as we've talked
about the teaser trailer that they did for parts
1 and 2. It looks like it's just the comic
book panels in animated form. Actually watching
this trailer made me really appreciate how
faithful Zack Snyder was to the source material
when it came to framing his shots from the
comic. Yeah, I think the last time we talked
about this project, I mentioned how this animated
Watchmen series of films just seems redundant,
especially when you have Zack Snyder's version
out there. I still feel the same way. And in
fact, I actually like a lot of the line deliveries
and voices given by the actors from Zack Snyder's
live-action film like Billy Crudup's voice
as Dr. Manhattan was way better than Dr. Manhattan's
voice in this trailer and for this upcoming
movie. Yeah, I won't disagree with that I thought
Billy Crudup's performance and voice performance
specifically was phenomenal in the Watchmen
movie and some of the lines from this trailer
Kind of felt like they were trying to imitate
the same delivery that they made in the live-action
film Such as like maybe this was a political
killing things like that. Yeah, Jeffrey Dean
Morgan's delivery of the comedians line, what
are you kidding, we're saving them from themselves,
was like a lot more cocky and nuanced than this
voice actor who just seems like angry in one
note. So even after this trailer, I feel like
I'm less excited for it. Really? Yeah. I like
the look of it. I'm glad that it exists in the
sense that more people are going to be exposed.
to the Watchmen story. Maybe people that would
never have picked up the comic, which you know
is hailed as maybe one of the best examples
of comic books as a medium. But also, the Watchmen
storyline, I think, also translates to different
mediums pretty well. Well, in that regard,
I think I would have rather had something like
a Watchmen video game or something like that
than this rehash of the Watchmen story, because
the Watchmen story never changes, right? I
feel like there are so many other projects that
DC could have done. besides this considering
we got already a pretty faithful adaptation
of this story, we could have got something
like, I don't know, a Hawkman animated film
or something like that. And that just seems
like it would have been a better use of their
resources. I know Watchmen is a brand and everything
like that, but I think telling the same story
over and over is just a missed opportunity
on DC's part, which is why I appreciated so
much what Damon Lindelof did with the Watchmen
HBO television series. Oh, just like adding
to that universe? Yeah. Yeah, he did a fantastic
job with that. I did notice that Paramount was
one of the studios responsible for this animated
film. They of course helped produce the live
action film made by Zack Snyder along with
Warner Brothers and I'm wondering if this maybe
is a push in some way for Paramount to make
money. I know that the studio is being sold
currently and this may be like an easy cash
grab considering the fact as we've learned since
the last time we reviewed the teaser trailer
for this, Watchmen is apparently DC Comics best
selling published work. Like by far, year after
year. More than like the Dark Knight or something
like that? Something bad? Yeah, oh yeah, absolutely,
totally. That's weird. I mean, is it, it's a
really good piece of work. Of course the trailer
was red banned for this film because it's gonna
have nudity in it. In the trailer, it even
shows Dr. Manhattan's schlong, which is gonna
be weird to see animated. I wonder what kind
of floppy effects that are gonna give it. Yeah,
it was pretty floppy in the live action movie.
Not that I was paying too much attention, but
yeah, not that you were stepping frame by frame.
But yeah, it looks incredibly faithful. From
the looks of it, the film may go up to the
fearful symmetry chapter within Watchmen, which
I know was the halfway mark of the book. And
then part two will carry on the story from there.
Exactly. So like the prison sequences, the
breakout, all the squid stuff. That won't be
until next year. Chapter 1, of course, is being
released on August 13th, so we're just a month
away from reviewing it. Along with everything
else that's being released around that time,
geez. For real. Disney and Warner Bros. decided
to release everything all at once this summer.
It's ridiculous.
But I think that does it for all the news for
this episode, so let's go ahead and get into
our main event where we find out who would win
in a fight between the Red Lantern Atrocitus
and Juggernaut.
Alright, Atrocitus versus Juggernaut. These
are two extreme powerhouses from Marvel in
DC, both wielding Crimson energies as it were.
You know, Atrocitus with his red lantern ring
and Juggernaut with the Crimson Bands of Sidorak.
That was like a Doctor Strange thing, wasn't
it? Yes, he has a spell called the Crimson Bands
of Sidorak which he uses to ensnare people.
Now he invokes the same entity that the Juggernaut
is a champion of. but no, the bands that the
Juggernaut wields are what provide him his armor.
It's not like he can summon an ensnaring spell
or anything like that. All right, so these are
like bracelets? Yeah, pretty much. Okay, so
it's like the tough guy wearing red jewelry
duel. Exactly. Another tiny between these characters
is that they're both magically powered. I know
that the Juggernaut is, but I'm not so sure
about Atrocitus. Yeah, Atrocitus is like a shaman,
you could say. So their powers sort of come
from magic in a way. Should be interesting,
but to explain the methodology behind our duels,
let's go to our sentient duel simulator Alfred
Jarvis9000. AJ9K tell our listeners how you
go about determining a winner in our duel matchups.
Yes, of course sir. The way I determine a winner
between the contestants is by running 1000 Monte
Carlo simulations using the characters statistics.
A Monte Carlo simulation is a probabilistic
model used to determine outcomes through random
sampling. In this case, I randomized the statistics
along a normal distribution. as a way to simulate
the many variables that can occur during battle.
The stat parameters are based on the official
Marvel power grid from which the DC characters'
statistics are extrapolated. Additional stat
categories are included such as range, damage
potential, versatility and perception in order
to create a more detailed and accurate simulation.
The results of the 1000 simulations provide
a percentage of wins for each character. The
contestant with the higher percentage is declared
the victor as they have a higher probability
to win any given battle. In an equitable pairing,
neither character should win 100% of the matches.
The comic book stories have shown that there's
even a way for Batman to defeat Superman, so
the confidence rate of my method falls in line
with the precedents that have been established
in the source material. My mathematical simulations
are without subjectivity or bias. Feats are
not the sole consideration, nor are fan votes
tabulated for determination of the winner. Thanks
AJ9K! Before we run the simulations though,
we like to break down each character's histories
and abilities before improvising a scenario
on how we imagine one of the 1000 simulations
would play out beat for beat. And it's my turn
to go first this episode with the Marvel characters'
backstories, so let me go ahead and tell you
all about Juggernaut. Kane Marco was born to
Marjorie and Dr. Kurt Marco, who was a nuclear
physicist from Berkeley, California. Kane's
mother died when he was three years old, leaving
him in the hands of his abusive father. A troubled
child, Kane was sent to multiple boarding schools,
all of which he was expelled from. When one
of his father's colleagues, Dr. Brian Xavier,
died in an accident at his research facility,
Dr. Kurt married Xavier's widower, Sharon,
and he and Kane moved into her family estate
in Westchester, New York, along with her young
son, Charles Xavier. Having a new family didn't
end Dr. Kurt's abusive behavior, who continued
to beat Kane and his new wife, though he spared
Charles, whom he seemed to prefer over his
own son. Kane hated Charles for this, and he
began bullying his stepbrother relentlessly.
What he didn't know though was that Charles
was developing psychic abilities stemming from
a genetic mutation, and was already experiencing
the mental and emotional turmoil that Kane
and his mom were going through. You can learn
more about this in our Chief vs. Professor
X duel episode. Ultimately, the abuse proved
to be too much for Sharon, and she succumbed
to alcoholism. Shortly after, Dr. Kurt Marco
died in a fire inside their mansion's home,
leaving Charles and Kane as orphans. While Charles
would use his gifted academic mind to graduate
high school early and earn multiple degrees
at home and abroad, Kane was pulled into the
military. While serving on a mission in Asia,
Kain deserted his unit as they came under heavy
fire. Cowardly trying to navigate through the
jungle brush, he happened upon the lost secret
temple of Citorok, a powerful mystic deity.
Within, Kain happened upon the crimson gem
of Citorok, which looked like a giant glowing
ruby. Planning to steal it, Kain grabbed the
gem and upon contact was bombarded with mystical
energies that destroyed the temple and buried
Kain in the rubble. He emerged, transformed
with crimson armor, and seemingly limitless
strength becoming the Juggernaut. With his mind
set on vengeance for the injustices of his
past, Kane sought out his stepbrother Charles
who at this point had become Professor X, the
leader of the X-Men, which he formed to defend
his dream of peaceful, mutant, and human coexistence.
You can learn more about the X-Men in their
team duel against the Titans. Kane's new helmet
protected him from Professor X's psychic attacks,
and the entire X-Men team was able to defeat
him. were unable to stop his newfound might.
It took assistance from the Human Torch of
the Fantastic Four to melt off Kane's helmet
so that Professor X could stop his stepbrother
by placing him into a coma. The Professor locked
Kane in the mansion's basement, where he attempted
to remove the powers of the Juggernaut with
some assistance from Doctor Strange. Eventually,
Kane came out of his coma and attacked the X-Men
again, who used the Gem of Sidorak to send
Kane to the deity's dimension known as the Crimson.
Cosmos. Kane eventually made his way back to
Earth's dimension and went on to battle other
heroes such as the Hulk, before meeting and
forming a criminal partnership with a mutant
named Black Tom Cassidy, and soon the pair
became the world's most wanted criminals. After
fighting Thor, the Norse God of Thunder, Kane
found himself hurled into space, where he overthrew
a small planet and became its ruler. Black
Tom Cassidy made a deal for access to a teleportation
machine, which he used to get Kane back to
Earth. Upon his return, Kane searched for and
rediscovered his Crimson Gem of Sidorak to
reclaim his power source, which mystically bonded
to his body. Not long after, the powerful psychic
entity known as Onslaught emerged, a manifestation
of the combined psyches of Magneto and Professor
X. Shocked to learn that Onslaught was partly
his stepbrother, Kane fought the entity, who
ripped the Crimson Gem from Kane's body and
trapped him inside of it. Kane eventually was
able to free himself only by destroying a corrupt
aspect of Sidorak himself, a battle that would
later strip him of most of his power. Humbled,
Kane finally reconciled with his stepbrother
Professor X and joined the X-Men, coming to
understand the mutant plight despite not being
a mutant himself. His old partner in crime,
Black Tom Cassidy, then formed a new Brotherhood
of Mutants, which Kane joined as a double agent
for the X-Men, and later joined the British
mutant team known as Excalibur, which you can
learn more about in our Uncle Sam versus Captain
Britain duel. Kane was among the X-Men who tried
to protect Professor X from the Hulk's wrath,
who had returned to Earth after being exiled
into space by a secret group of influential
heroes called the Illuminati. Still unable to
access the full power of Sidorak, Kane lost
his fight with the Hulk. However, Sidorak then
appeared before Kane to tell him that the Crimson
Gem was meant to be used for selfish, not heroic
purposes. Agreeing to the Deity's terms, Cain
was restored to his full strength and once again
fought the Hulk, a battle which ended with
the Hulk using Cain's momentum against him and
fleeing the encounter. Cain ended up abandoning
Sidorak's power, instead choosing to wield the
Hammer of Kurth to become a member of the Worthy,
a group loyal to the Norse god of fear known
as the Serpent. Eventually, Thor defeated the
serpent and Cain lost his hammer. Without the
blessing of Sidorak, he was now entirely powerless.
Retiring to a farm in Utah, Cain tried to live
peacefully, but soon heard Sidorak's gem calling
out to him as he started looking for a new champion
for the Mystic Deity. Cain heeded the call,
but only to the gem first in order to destroy
it. He had to take on the power instead of
eradicating it, however. to keep the gem's power
out of the hands of a villain known as the
Living Monolith. Becoming Cidorak's champion
once again, Kain tried to collect a 20 million
dollar bounty on Deadpool's head, though the
merc buried Juggernaut with a cement truck,
buying him enough time to escape. During a confrontation
with the former New Mutants member Magic, Kain
was condemned to her nether realm of Limbo,
where he was cut off from Cidorak's power.
Kain had to sacrifice his armor to get back
home. where he once again sought out the Crimson
Gem and regained his abilities. You can learn
more about Magic in her duel episode against
Deadman. Though Kane sought to become a citizen
of the mutant island nation of Krakoa, Professor
X had to initially deny his stepbrothers request
since Kane was not a mutant. However, due to
his history as a member of the X-Men, Krakoa's
leading council put Kane's citizenship up for
a vote, and he was able to join his former teammates
on the island. Kane became a member of one
of Krakoa's defensive forces based out of a
pocket reality contained in Professor X's son
Legion's psyche, a team known as the Legionaries.
You can learn more about Legion and Krakoa
in their respective duels against Crazy Jane
and Danny the Street. And that's the Juggernaut's
backstory. Powers-wise, Juggernaut is bonded
to the Crimson Bands of Cidorak, granting him
immense levels of mystic power. This includes
vastly enhanced strength, able to lift in excess
of 100 tons. He is fully invulnerable to damage
due to a mystic personal force field around
his body, which he can extend to increase his
area of protection. Juggernaut's personal inertia
keeps him moving in any direction he chooses,
making him able to smash through any obstacle
and rendering him virtually unstoppable. With
enough time and distance, Juggernaut can reach
speeds approaching Mach 1. He is only susceptible
to high-level mental or magical attacks, and
if he is ever injured, the powers of Sidorak
allow him to regeneratively heal. He also has
military hand-to-hand combat training, and finally
with the bands, he is self-sustaining, having
no need for food, water, or air. Hey, sounds
like a better version of Rhino. That's not
a incorrect statement for sure. Yeah, they both
specialize basically in charging their enemies,
and I gotta tell you, there's no way that Atrocitus
is gonna stop the Juggernaut because you can't
stop this motherfucker. Holy shit balls. Is
what the Juggernaut is gonna be saying. when
Atrocitus kicks his ass. Let me tell you all
about the Red Lantern Atrocitus. Now in DC
comics, the Guardians of the Universe are a
race of beings who are among the first intelligent
beings in the universe. In order to bring order
and peace to the universe, the Guardians settled
on the planet Oa near the center of existence,
from which they directed a peacekeeping army
of androids known as Manhunters. The Manhunter's
programming eventually became corrupted however,
punishing beings over trivial matters and eventually
coming to the conclusion that because organic
life could not be perfect, they would exterminate
all of it to achieve true order within the
universe. Out of 3,600 sectors in the universe
that the Manhunters were charged with protecting,
they began their universal genocide in Sector
666, where a being named Altos watched as Furtah,
daughter Atreca, and son Limey were murdered
by the androids. Although the Guardians were
able to decommission the Manhunters before more
sectors were entirely annihilated, Altos was
one of only five beings in the entire sector
to survive the genocide. Together, they formed
a terrorist cabal known as the Five Inversions
that was dedicated to destroying the Guardians
from Oa and all that served them. With Altos,
now known as Atrocitus, as their leader, the
Five Inversions performed an alien occult ritual
that allowed them to see into the future. Prophesying,
among other things, the Blankest Night event
when Necron, the embodiment of death, would
usher in the death of all life in the universe.
After setting up a home base on the planet
Yismalt, the Five Inversions conquered three
entire galaxies, establishing a dominion known
as the Empire of Tears, with magic and occultism
integrated into everyday life. Looking to quell
the Inversion's terrorism and replace the Empire
of Tears' chaotic magic use with scientific
order, the Guardians used their new universal
peacekeepers, the Green Lantern Corps, to overthrow
the Empire and imprison the five Inversions
on Yosmalt. The five prisoners were periodically
visited by the Green Lantern named Avan Sur,
who became obsessed with their prophecy of
the Blackest Night. When Aben freed Atrocitus
in order to guide him to the source of the
prophetic Black on Earth, Atrocitus escaped,
fatally injuring Aben and beginning a rampage
on Earth. After performing rituals to track
down William Hand, the one prophesied to herald
the Blackest Knight, Atrocitus was attacked
and defeated by Sinestro and the rookie Green
Lantern, Hal Jordan. Both of whom you can learn
more about in our Sinestro vs Magneto, and
Green Lantern vs. Nova duel episodes. Sinistro
returned Atrocitus to Yismalt, where Atrocitus
vowed revenge against Sinistro and prophesied
that Sinistro's home planet of Korugar would
fall into chaos. This prophecy eventually resulted
in Sinistro defecting from the Green Lantern
Corps and starting his own Sinistro Corps, who
went to war with the Guardians. It was at this
time that Atrocitus forged the first Red Lantern
power battery, powered by rage, in much the
same way that Green Lanterns and Yellow Lanterns
were powered by Willpower and Fear, respectively.
He killed the other four Inversions, using their
blood to create a Red Central Power Battery
and Red Brains, which were sent to wrathful
beings across the universe, primarily those
who had been wronged by the Sinestro Corps,
including the former Green Lantern Lyra. The
Red Lanterns ambushed the Green Lanterns after
they had defeated Sinestro, capturing him and
retreating to Yasmalt. There, Atrocitus had
Sinestro crucified to a red lantern symbol,
attempting to use his blood to expand his new
red rings for his core, with the goal of destroying
Kor'gar, the Sinestro core, and the Green Lantern
core. Before he could, however, Sinestro was
rescued by his core members alongside Hal Jordan
and a couple of blue lanterns in a massive
battle on Yosmalt, forcing Atrocitus to retreat
to the dark side of the planet. where he performed
a ritual to locate the Blue Lantern's homeworld,
as they too were now the subject of his wrath.
During the Blackest Night event, Black Power
Rings arrived on Yosemalt and reanimated Lyra
as well as the other foreign versions, one of
which ripped out Atrocitus' heart, though he
survived since Red Lantern Blood was pumped
by their red rings once they obtained them.
Later on Akara, Atrocitus attempted to steal
the sole orange lantern Larkfleeza's power
battery, but was thwarted by members of the
other colored core. Hal Jordan, Sinestro, the
blue lantern Saint Walker, the violent lantern
Carol Ferris, as well as Indigo One. Atrocitus
was taken to the planet Riot, where he agreed
to help fight the Black Lanterns, despite vowing
to kill the Guardians afterward. After tracking
the Black Lantern's central power battery to
Earth, the core leaders combined their lights
to form the white light of creation, who have
failed to destroy the battery. During an attack
by a Black Lantern Spectre, Atrocitus sensed
its true nature as an entity of divine wrath
and attempted to capture him to use his rage
as a power source. His attempt failed, however,
and Atrocitus received a warning from the Spectre
about the true rage entity of the emotional
spectrum, a being known as the Butcher. After
Necron and the Black Lanterns were defeated,
Atrocitus returned to Earth and used the blood
of several criminals to perform a ritual to
locate the emotional spectrum entities, including
the Butcher, though his actions sparked a confrontation
with Hal, Carol, and Sinestro. Atrocitus had
hired Lobo earlier to attack them, however,
in a ploy to gain the other's trust. His plan
worked, and Atrocitus managed to locate the
Butcher, which, with reluctant he managed to
imprison his power battery to use as an energy
source for his rings to create constructs.
Though the Spectre tried to stop him, he found
himself unable as he realized Atrocitus' cause
was a quote-unquote, Holy One. You can learn
more about the Spectre in his duel against
Galactus. The Butcher was, however, eventually
freed from Atrocitus' lantern by the villain,
Corona, a former guardian of the universe who
was responsible for unleashing evil and chaos
on the world, near the beginning of time. After
using the Butcher to defeat Atrocitus and several
other lanterns, Chrona retreated to the planet
Riot, and though Atrocitus and the others managed
to track him there, they initially only found
the Book of Black, which revealed that it was
Chrona all along who had corrupted the Manhunter's
programming. The lanterns became trapped within
the book, but were eventually freed by the Green
Lantern Kyle Raynor. of the opportunity to
kill Krona in revenge, as Hal Jordan had done
it while Atrocitus was trapped, Krona's corpse
was delivered to Atrocitus on his smalt to do
with as he saw fit. With the ultimate cause
for his rage avenged, Atrocitus feared losing
control over the Red Lanterns as his rage dimmed.
Performing a blood ritual using Krona's innards,
Atrocitus made a new vow to punish the guilty
across the universe to maintain order. and he
promoted one of his Red Lanterns, Bleese, to
be his right hand, restoring her sanity as the
Red Lantern rings drive its bearers mad with
rage. Bleese, however, almost immediately attempted
a revolt, and on top of that, Krona's corpse
went missing, leading Atrocitus to fear that
Krona had resurrected somehow. In reality,
a being named Abyssmas, which was one of Atrocitus'
early attempts at creating life through necromancy,
stole Krona's corpse and ate it, imbuing him
with great power. Although Atrocitus was injured
in the battle against Abyssmas, he was saved
by Jon Mour, the new Red Lantern of Earth.
When another Lantern of Earth, Kyle Raynor,
attempted to harness the power of the Seven
Core, Atrocitus agreed to train Kyle in harnessing
rage and the use of a Red Lantern Ring. Shortly
after, Atrocitus was confronted by a powerful
entity known as the First Lantern, an alternate
reality in which his former self, Altos, did
not lose his family to the Manhunters, but
instead rose to power as a wrathful dictator
within his sector, going so far as to killing
his own wife and later being killed by his own
son. Atrocitus rejected this reality and joined
a campaign to destroy the first lantern with
the other core, which also resulted in him
and Sinestro killing the last of the Guardians
of the Universe. Stripped of his Red Ring by
the Green Lantern, Guy Gardner, who became the
new leader of the Red Lanterns, Atrocitus merged
with the Butcher, but was stripped of the entity
by Kyle Raynor. After attempting to create
hundreds more rings and ring bearers on Earth,
Guy Gardner destroyed all of the new rings,
as well as Atrocitus, seemingly. Atrocitus emerged
later on, however, and regained leadership
over the Red Lantern. with whom he began enacting
the prophecy of the Red Dawn on Earth, as the
planet and its beings were the new source of
his rage. And that's Atrocitus so far. Powers-wise,
the Red Lantern Atrocitus is an alien of the
planet Yismalt with greater longevity, physical
strength, and durability than humans, as well
as having sharp claws on his hands. He is an
accomplished necromancer and shaman of blood
magic, allowing him to see into the and create
objects such as red lantern batteries and rings.
Upon bearing the red ring, Atrocitus' blood
was replaced by a lava-like red plasma, so intent
it's capable of burning through and corroding
other forms of energy. He can project this plasma
from his mouth or ring, and he is one of the
few red lanterns capable of creating energy-based
constructs of anything he can imagine. He's
also one of the few red lanterns in possession
of his full mental faculty, and and not consumed
by a debilitating sense of rage. And that's
Atrocitus. So it looks like another similarity
between the two characters is that sometimes
they've occasionally flirted with the idea
of being heroes. Uh, yeah, you could say that.
He's definitely teamed up with, you know, quote-unquote
good Lantern Cores, kind of the same way that
the Juggernaut has teamed up with the X-Men.
He's a misunderstood anti-hero, I guess you
could say. I would not describe Juggernaut
as that. He's more of like a selfish dickhead
who sometimes gets wise. And Atrocitus is going
to get wise during this matchup because he's
going to find out what happens when an unstoppable
force meets an immovable object. Is Atrocitus
the unstoppable force or the immovable object?
No, obviously Juggernaut is both. Okay.
Where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
Dynomic Podcast Network presents Console Combat,
where video game legends brawl every Monday.
Dynamic Duel, where comic book titans smash
every Tuesday. Max Destruction, where the world
is at its limit. TV and action heroes battle
every Wednesday, and Sendro World, where anime
champions clash every Thursday. Join us as we
speculate on the matches and armed with the
power of mathematical simulations, discover
who will emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
But now that we've got their histories and abilities
out of the way, let's speculate on how one
of the 1000 simulated matches will go. The winner
is determined by simulations, not this speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how this fight could
play out. AJ9K, what are the rules of our speculation?
Well, I should say there are no rules, other
than the characters have no prior knowledge
of the other going into the fight. All they
are aware of starting out... is that the other
character is a threat that needs to be eliminated.
For the speculation, the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the
match itself, as no environmental statistics
are considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. Alright
then let's get into it. Atrocitus and Juggernaut
meet on the battlefield. Who goes first? I'm
going to say Atrocitus goes first, because
he's just like really angry. way more angry
than Juggernaut. So he'll start off by aiming
his ring at Juggernaut and just napalming the
guy with like a stream of hot plasma that's
just gonna melt his armor off. No, Juggernaut's
force field is gonna stop that. It's not even
gonna touch Juggernaut. And Juggernaut's gonna
be like, "'Don't you know who I am? "'I'm the
Juggernaut, bitch.'" I had to say that. And
Juggernaut's gonna charge forward and he slams
into Atrocitus, just turning him. into a red
smear. Quickest match ever. Okay, so let me
get this straight. Human torch can melt his
armor, but atrocitas can't? No, I mean to clarify,
the human torch melted the rivets that held
Juggernaut's helmet in place, not his armor,
and that was like his first comic book appearance.
I mean like since then, he's grown more powerful
and developed the force field thing. Okay, but
Atrocitus' plasma can destroy other forms of
energy, like forcefield energy. No, no, Juggernaut's
forcefield, it's not like just simple energy.
It's magic energy sourced from one of the most
powerful elder mystic deities. Like Atrocitus
is not more powerful than Sidorak, and like
neither are any of the lanterns for that matter.
So I don't think Atrocitus' energy is actually
strong enough to burn through Juggernaut's
forcefield. Okay, fine. Atrocitus gets slammed
into but you know, he's not a smear because
he threw up a wall construct at the last second
So what juggernaut plows right through the
wall and he's this unstoppable force now, right?
No, but like Atrocitus was knocked out of the
way of the juggernaut by the wall debris is
what I'm saying And you know Atrocitus he's
an accomplished shaman and he's probably gonna
recognize The mystic nature of juggernaut's
powers by this point. So while juggernaut you
know, continues to charge in the same direction,
Atrocitus is just gonna vomit plasma blood on
the floor in a circle around him. What is it?
What does the circle of plasma blood do? You're
gonna find out. You're gonna learn today. Okay.
Well Juggernaut, meanwhile, he's gonna make
a long ass U-turn and he's gonna double back
to charge Atrocitus again. But this time, you
know, he's built up enough speed so he's going
like 200 miles per hour. And like, for sure
when he plows it to Atrocitus, he's gonna turn
him into a skid mark. Except that like in the
time it takes for Juggernaut to do this long
ass U-turn, Atrocitus used his blood to create
a blood magic sigil around him. And when Juggernaut
steps into that sigil, he gets frozen in place.
You virtually can't stop him though. Like there's
also a mystic force powering Juggernaut's inertia.
So you're just talking about magic versus magic.
Okay, okay, well, let's say instead of freezing
him in place, the blood sigil just makes him
run in place like a like a frictionless surface
or like a hamster wheel. Interesting. I'll
allow it. And from the sigil, Atrocitus is then
going to channel a tornado made of pure blood
that just lifts Juggernaut into the air. And
now that he's in the air and can't like run
or charge or do fucking anything that he can
do. Atrocitus is going to create this giant
mace that he's going to swing in the air and
knock Juggernaut to the horizon. No, but like,
so a force generated against Juggernaut is the
same thing as Juggernaut directing a force
against the object. So basically Juggernaut
is just going to no sell being hit by this
red energy mace. It's just going to shatter
around him as he's like running midair being
lifted up by this blood tornado. And then. Juggernaut's
gonna clap his hands, which is gonna be like
this massive thunder clap that generates a gust
of wind that's gonna dissipate Atrocitus' blood
tornado. And Juggernaut's gonna fall to the
ground, you know, outside of the blood sigil,
and he's gonna stomp the ground, which is gonna
kick up this massive ass boulder that he catches
and just hurls at Atrocitus, just smashing into
him. Except that this boulder is caught midair
by like a giant... set of claws like talons.
It's an energy construct that just crushes
the boulder in its grasp before moving over
to Juggernaut and gripping him by his helmet
like a crane game and bringing him over to Atrocitus
who uses the claws to pry off the Juggernaut's
helmet, at which point he's going to carve a
symbol into Juggernaut's forehead that allows
Atrocitus to take control of him, like mentally.
And that's one of the Juggernauts just going
to punch his own head off. and end this match.
Well, okay, if the Talons pick up and bring
Juggernaut over to Atrocitus, then they're generating
inertia for Juggernaut in Atrocitus's direction,
right? So like, Atrocitus doesn't have any time
to pry off Juggernaut's helmet or carve anything
into his head because Juggernaut's just gonna
keep fucking flying toward Atrocitus, you know,
fist first, and he's just gonna punch off Atrocitus's
head clean off instead of his own. Hey, hey,
you can't. You can't do that thing. I did the
head thing. I say Juggernaut misses and punches
Atrocitus through the chest. And surprise, Atrocitus
doesn't even need a heart to live. Well, he
probably has other organs in his chest, right?
Like lungs or something like that. Does he
need lungs to breathe? Because those are gone,
too, with this hole in his chest. He's an alien.
Like, you don't know where his lungs are. All
right. Well, then Juggernaut turns Atrocitus
around and then rips out his ass lungs. OK.
Same thing.
The disrespect, no way Atrocitus is gonna let
this happen to him. He would just get so pissed
off. He's already full of rage and he saw this
coming. So it didn't happen because he divined
the future before this match and saw Juggernaut
would try shit like that. And so it doesn't
work. Like Juggernaut just ends up under his
control. End of match that never happened.
All right, we'll go ahead and leave it there.
Either Atrocitus manages to pry off Juggernaut's
helmet. and carve a magic symbol in his forehead
that makes him take over Juggernaut's mind
and cause him to punch his head off. Or Juggernaut
rips out Atrocities' heart and or butt lungs.
Well it's not the heart. I hate to say it's
the butt lungs. We'll just say internal organs.
We'll just go with that. Okay. There we go.
We'll go ahead and leave the match there. We're
going to input the character's stats, run a
thousand simulations, and come back with a
winner. AJ9K, hit it! inputting data, running
calculations, processing results, simulations
complete. All right, this is a pretty interesting
match up. The characters were semi-similar
in terms of their stats, although we did give
the edge in things like durability and strength,
obviously, to Juggernaut. Yeah, there was no
surprise there. Also no surprise we gave the
edge in terms of versatility, range, and evasiveness
to Atrocitus because Juggernaut never evades.
Yeah, that's true. We also gave the speed advantage
to Atrocitus because Juggernaut really has
to accelerate to those high speeds that he can
run at. Whereas Atrocitus, you know, he's damn
fast. We gave a slight fighting edge to Juggernaut
considering that he has a lot of experience
as a brawler and also has some military combat
training. Whereas Atrocitus was a... whereas
Atrocitus was a psychologist prior to joining
the five inversions. And we all know that psychologists
don't know how to fight. I'm just saying like
he doesn't have much fight training. He's very
much a brawler, but I don't know how formal
that is. Of course this means that Atrocitus'
background gives him the edge in intelligence.
We also said that he had the edge in perception,
being that he can divine the future. So taking
all these stats into account, Jonathan, who
do you think is going to take home the dub?
I'm pretty sure it's gonna be atrocities. They
were almost tit-for-tat when it came to the
different stats But I feel like the stats were
atrocities came out ahead in he came out far
ahead in and I think most people would agree
Our Instagram followers in the poll that we
did voted 73% in favor of Atrocities winning
which surprised me not gonna lie. I mean, it's
the motherfucking juggernaut. You can't stop
him I don't see how you can vote against him,
but let's see if they're right AG9K the results
please. Here you are sir. Alright the winner
between Atrocitus and Juggernaut is... Atrocitus.
Of course it is! Of course it is! I guess you
can stop this motherfucker cause Atrocitus
laid the beat down on Juggernaut winning 827
of the simulated matches over Juggernaut's
measly 173 wins. Shit yeah, eighty two point
seven percent over seventeen point three percent
is no joke Juggernaut just didn't have you know
a lot of the stuff that atrocities excelled
in like range versatility and speed Durability
and strength alone weren't able to help him
overcome. I mean really statistically juggernaut
is not that Impressive of a specimen. He's
kind of a one-trick pony in that You know, he
smashes things and he punches things and he
does that stuff really well, but there's not
much more he can do. Yeah, he's sort of like
the ultimate when it comes to like smashing
and punching things, right? Yeah. But yeah,
it definitely didn't help him when it came up
against a character as versatile as a lantern.
So does that mean that this was a mismatch?
Absolutely. Yeah. I mean, I liked the idea
of it at the time, because, you know, again,
all the different correlations that we found
between them. regards to like red energy and
they're just both angry thematically the match
works but statistically it could have been worse
almost and we definitely can't blame the executive
producers on this one because it was my idea
for a matchup i perhaps overestimated the juggernaut's
ability to go up against red lantern so that's
my bad and once again you underestimate the
awesomeness of dc and now you're learning your
lesson I definitely overestimate the cheater-ness,
the overpowered-ness of DC quite often. I tend
not to think that the characters are as bullshit
as they are, but apparently I'm wrong. It's
a fucking lantern character! How did you not
see this coming? Because it's the fucking juggernaut,
bitch! That's why. Pride, that's what it is.
You're too proud of your Marvel characters.
Well, pride cometh before the fall, and now
you know. Well, my fist cometh before your fall.
Next time I see you. simply because I'm mad
about this match. So yeah, next time I see you
in person, Jonathan, just be ready. You're
gonna get punched. Okay, and like atrocities,
before you even reach me, I'm just gonna vomit
all over you.
That's gross. So have fun. Come at me. Well,
that does it for this duel guys. H-U-9K help
close this out. Thanks for listening to Dynamic
duel. Visit the show's website at dynamicduel.com
and follow us on Instagram at dynamicduelpodcast.
You can support the show on Patreon at patreon.com
slash dynamicduel and joining a tier that works
for you, or by rating and reviewing Dynamic
duel on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser or
on our website. Don't forget to listen to the
other shows in the DynaMic Podcast Network,
including Max Destruction, Senjow World and
Console Combat. In our next episode, we will
be reviewing Justice League Crisis on Infinite
Earths Part 3. This, of course, is the supposed
final film in the 10 film Tomorrowverse series.
I'm gonna say right now I don't think you can
match the conclusion that was Justice League
Dark Apocalypse War, but I'm hoping that Part
3 is at least better than Part 2. Yeah, same,
same. But that does it for this episode, we
want to give a big thanks to our executive
producers, Ken Johnson, John Strosky, Zachary
Hepburn, Dustin Balcombe, Mickey Mathagean,
Brandon Essergard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yeaton,
Austin Wazilowski, AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho,
Gil Camacho, Adam Spies, Andrew Shunk, Dean
Maleski, Devin Davis, and Joseph Kirstink for
helping make this podcast possible. We'll talk
to you guys next week. Up up and away, true
believers.