This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
Hi and welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast,
a weekly show where we review superhero films
and debate the superiority between Marvel and
DC by comparing their characters and stat-based
battle simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe. And I'm
his twin brother Johnny DC. And in this episode,
we are going to find out who'd win in a fight
between the two Native American characters
of Black Condor and Warpath. Warpath being a
member of the X-Men, actually X-Force, and
this is kind of a tie into our previous episode
which was a review of X-Men 97. But it's also
a lead up to our future team duel episode of
Outsiders vs X-Force, which is going to be
in September. So look forward to learning more
about X-Force and the Outsiders throughout
these upcoming months. Before we input the character
stats and run simulations to find out which
character would win in a fight. we're gonna
break down the latest comic book movie news
to come out this past week. Of which there was
just one news item, we learned about who the
writers are gonna be for the upcoming Lanterns
DCU television series. As always, we list our
segment times in our episode description, so
feel free to check out the show notes if you
wanna skip ahead to a particular topic. Our
artificially intelligent duel simulator, AJ-9K,
has a quick message for our listeners, so listen
up. Why hello there. Do you love listening
and chatting about Marvel and DC? Then become
a part of the dynamic duel community on Patreon,
where you can choose from three tiers. The dynamic
two-o tier lets you listen to this podcast
without ads and gives you access to its discord
chat group, where you can chat with Johnny
DC and Marvellous Joe. The Fantastic Four tier
gives you that and more with two bonus episodes
each month, including bloopers and top ten shows
where Johnny and Joe count down your favourite
Marvel and DC subjects. The X-Force tier makes
you an executive producer of Dynamic Duel,
where every month you help the hosts choose
what to review and who to fight against each
other. And finally, the Dynamite Podcast Network
tier allows aspiring podcasters to create their
own battle-focused show using this Monte Carlo
simulator.
Thanks AJ9K, and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast. Be sure to tune into the shows
on the DynaMic Podcast Network this week, including
Max Destruction, which pits your favorite action
heroes from film and television against each
other. Hosts Ken and Scotty are returning this
week for the show's third season premiere, this
time pitting Starro the Conqueror from the
Suicide Squad against Legendary's King Kong.
On the Senjou World podcast, host Zachary Hepburn
speculates on fights between fan favorite anime
and manga characters. This Thursday for the
show's season finale, we'll learn who will win
between Rimuro Tempest from That Time I Got
Reincarnated as a Slime vs. Yateng Jujji aka
Rau from Reim Monster. And on the Console Combat
Podcast, hosts John and Dean find out who would
win in fights between popular video game characters.
In yesterday's episode, they reviewed the 2007
film Hitman. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or click
the link in our show notes to listen to all
of the shows in the Dynamite Podcast Network.
But with that out of the way, quick to the no
prize. A no prize is an award Marvel used to
give out to fans. Our version, the dynamic duel
no prize, is a digital award we post on Instagram
for the person that we feel gave the best answer
to our question of the week. Last week's question
was, who's your favorite robot superhero or
villain from Marvel or DC and why? And this
is coming off of the news that the upcoming
Vision series from Marvel Television will be
coming out in 2026. We got four answers, so
let's break down this week's honorable mentions
before revealing the no prize winner. Our first
honorable mention goes to Abner O'Terry. Who
said? Hey guys, what's up? It's Abner O'Terry.
And my answer is obviously Robot from The Doom
Patrol because, uh, he's awesome. You can't
get better than a punk-rocking robot. He's
the best. What the fuuuuck? It's Robotman! But
I agree, he's awesome. He's probably my favorite
personal robot character as well. I still remember
when I was first becoming a DC fan, I had gotten
my first cell phone and I said Robotman. as
my wallpaper, because I just like the idea
of carrying Robotman around. Is he a punk rock
robot or is he more, you know, heavy metal?
Heavy metal for sure. Great answer Abner. Our
next honorable mention goes to Miggy Matangian,
who said, Hey, what's up guys? This is Miggy
and my favorite robot superhero. Does it count
as a superhero? It's more of a sidekick. I guess
that counts. It's Geetz. Booster Gold's like
robotic sidekick from the 25th century. He's
just like very sarcastic and a lot smarter
than Booster Gold. So it's just a funny like
relationship between the two of them. Yeah,
excited to see him in the live action show.
Wonder who they'll get to voice him. To the
sweat drips down my balls. All these bitches
call. Ah, skeet skeet, motherfucker. Ah, skeet
skeet. How dare you disrespect skeet's name?
Mickey's right. He's a pretty cool robot. He's
a great foil and companion to Booster Gold because
I think. of how they play up on the fact that
he knows more than Booster Gold, who is often
depicted as kind of dumb. Miggie was wondering
who will voice Skeets in the upcoming Booster
Gold television series. What do you think?
Honestly, I think you could get away with doing
a voice actor that I think you need a celebrity
voice. And in that regard, I don't think you
could do better than Billy West, who did the
voice of Skeets the Robot for the Justice League
Unlimited animated show. Yeah, Billy West is
fantastic. He does the voice of Fry in Futurama.
and literally dozens of other voices. There's
no time to throw up. He's the red M&M. Yeah,
yeah, there you go. Maybe one day we'll get
around to doing a duel with Skeets. Who knows?
Ah, Skeet, Skeet. Let's go to move on to the
next answer given by Christopher Manotti who
said. Hi guys, Christopher Manotti. As a DC
fan, I have to say Red Tornado. I really like
this character. He's not your typical kind
of robot that shoots lasers and hacks into stuff.
His power is literally generating tornadoes.
I think that's pretty cool. I also think his
character is really interesting. I especially
liked in the Young Justice show when you find
out that he built another body for himself
so that he could experience humanity. Really
cool. Yeah, Red Tornado I would say is probably
one of the most powerful androids out there.
He has a very complicated backstory, you know,
coming from the Tornado Tyrant, which was...
a literal tornado villain from the planet ran.
If you guys aren't familiar with him, we did
a duel between him and Sandman, which was pretty
cool, I thought. It's interesting to have a
robot character who is so elemental. He's very
bound to the earth and very natural in that
regard, considering he's basically a sentient
tornado. But also, he's like the pinnacle of
technology. So there's an interesting dichotomy
to that character. Yeah, for sure. Great answer,
Christopher. But the winner of this week's
Snow Prize is... Travis Herndon who said,
Well, you're talented in your opinion, but you're
gonna get throat chopped from me if you're
saying that. And I will second that throat chop.
Yeah, anybody who hates on Baymax is lying
to themselves and deserve to be throat chopped.
I don't know if I would consider Baymax to
be as iconic as the Terminator or R2-D2, but,
you know, I think he's probably a class just
under that. Okay, Mr. Robot Popularity Expert,
I don't know what the fuck you're talking about.
Baymax is awesome. He's one of the more unique
robots out there and it's- really interesting
considering that he is also a superhero and
a healthcare robot. There's a dichotomy to
him as well. And he has a one of a kind personality.
Like what are you talking about man? He's all
the way up there in terms of the upper echelon
of pop culture robots. And he's a Marvel character.
So bonus points. Yeah, I figured we were going
to give the win to the one person who didn't
respond with a DC answer. That's right. Honestly,
I just don't want to get throat chopped. Well,
too bad. It's gonna happen. Great answer Travis,
you win this week's no prize. If you the listener
won a shot at winning your own no prize, stay
tuned till later on this episode when we'll
be asking another question of the week. And
now that that's done, on to the news!
Okay, so last week DC Studios CEO James Gunn
confirmed on Instagram that the Lanterns showrunners
would be Damon Lindelof from Watchmen and Lost
Fame and Chris Mundy, the showrunner of Ozark
and former writer for shows like Criminal Minds,
Cold Case, Bloodline, and True Detective. Which,
it's funny that the show has always been pitched
as True Detective in space and they actually
got a writer from True Detective to work on
the show. I've never seen Ozark, but I hear
that it's really good. I have seen Watchmen
by Damon Lindelof, and that's essentially,
in my opinion, the greatest television series
for Marvel or DC that has ever been made. The
thing won so many Emmys, it won a freaking Peabody,
it doesn't get better than this writing duo.
I'm not gonna lie, I'm kinda insane with jealous
rage right now at these like God tier showrunners
for this show. It's gonna be incredible. I think.
David Lindelof did a fantastic job with the
Watchmen series. The way that he brought that
story into the modern era in a sequel series
was exceptionally done. And I think with these
guys working on the show, DC fans really have
nothing to worry about. Oh no, this has like
easily become with this news, like my most
anticipated project from the upcoming DCU. This
show is going to be so high brow, like Game
of Thrones quality, I suspect. It sounds like
it's going to be way better than what Greg
Berlanti was coming up with. Don't get me wrong,
shows like Arrow and The Flash were good, but
they're no The Leftovers, they're no Watchmen,
they're no Ozark from what I've heard. What's
really cool though is that they're not only
showrunning the series, but Chris Mundy, Damon
Lindelof, and acclaimed comic book writer Tom
King also wrote the pilot script and the show's
Bible. Which if you're not familiar with that,
it's basically the entire background, history,
and premise of the show. So it sounds like they're
really in charge of DC's like cosmic universe
as it were. And that's amazing. Sounds like
Green Lantern is finally, finally going to
get his due. Not on this big screen, I guess,
but you know, at least on a screen that's non-animated.
Well, the cool thing is that it's going to tie
into the movies that we will see on the big
screen. It'll take place in the same universe.
Super, super excited by this news. It sounds
like it's going to be so much more prestige
than I thought it would be. We don't have a
release date for this show yet. Considering
the writing talent, I'm sure the show is gonna
be very, very expensive. So it'll probably be
a while before we get it. Maybe 2026, I'm guessing.
I can't wait for it. And I'm really looking
forward to finding out like who's gonna be
the lead characters. Is it gonna be Hal Jordan,
John Stewart, Guy Gardner? We don't know yet.
But that brings us to our question of the week.
Who is your favorite Green Lantern? And why?
Record your answer at dynamicduel.com by clicking
on the red microphone button in the bottom right
hand corner of the screen, which will prompt
you to leave us a voicemail. Your message could
be up to 30 seconds long, and don't forget
to leave your name in case we include you on
the podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer
and award that person a Dynamic Duel No Prize
that we'll post to Instagram. Be sure to answer
before June 8th.
But I think that does it for all the news for
this episode. So let's go ahead and get into
our main event, where we find out who would
win in a fight between Black Condor and Warpath.
Alright, Black Condor versus Warpath. These
are two Native American superheroes going head
to head and lead up to our upcoming team duel
coming out in a few months of Outsiders versus
X-Force. Now, Warpath, you guys may know from
the comics, if you read the comics, but if
you are more familiar with just the movies,
he was in X-Men Days of Future Past. He was
part of the future X-Men team that was basically
getting slaughtered by the Sentinels. Yeah,
and we've never seen Black Condor in live action.
Though he was in some animated films, direct
to video film about the Rey, a DC character,
and of course he'll be featured in the upcoming
Crisis on Infinite Earths Part 3 film. Only
one version of the character has been Native
American though, right? Yes, yeah. There's been
four different versions of Black Condor. I'm
going with the Native American Navajo version
because he seems to be not only the most popular
because he's been in different media. but also
he is the current mainstream version of the
character in DC's Prime Continuity. The character
of Black Condor though didn't actually start
off as a DC Comics character. He was a part
of Quality Comics, which was eventually purchased
by DC Comics. Black Condor is a creation of
Will Eisner, actually. Oh, fascinating. What
other characters are from Quality? Uncle Sam,
Phantom Lady, Doll Man, The Ray, basically
all of the Freedom Fighters. Oh, interesting.
Well, I'm glad you're going with the Navajo
version. It's cool to get all this representation
from the Native American tribes because Warpath
is Apache. And then we also have Forge, who's
Cheyenne. And then you have Echo, who's Choctaw
in the MCU. But in the comics, she's from the
Blackfoot tribe. Oh, and then you have like
Khori from What If, who's part of the Mohawk
tribe. Yeah, Black Condor can take all of them
on. OK, OK. Come at me, bro. He's not even going
to be able to take on Warpath. So nice tray.
Okay, to explain the methodology behind our
duels, let's go to our sentient duel simulator,
Alfred Jarvis 9000. AJ9K, tell our listeners
how you go about determining a winner in our
duel matchups. Yes, of course, sir. The way
I determine a winner between the contestants
is by running 1000 Monte Carlo simulations using
the characters statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation
is a probabilistic model used to determine outcomes
through random sampling. In this case, I randomize
the statistics along a as a way to simulate
the many variables that can occur during battle.
The stat parameters are based on the official
Marvel power grid from which the DC characters'
statistics are extrapolated. Additional stat
categories are included such as range, damage
potential, versatility and perception in order
to create a more detailed and accurate simulation.
The results of the 1000 simulations provide
a percentage of wins for each character. The
contestant with the higher percentage is declared
the victor as they have a higher probability
to win any given battle. In an equitable pairing,
neither character should win 100% of the matches.
The comic book stories have shown that there's
even a way for Batman to defeat Superman, so
the confidence rate of my method falls in line
with the precedents that have been established
in the source material. My mathematical simulations
are without subjectivity or bias. Feats are
not the sole consideration, nor are fan votes
tabulated for determination of the winner.
Thanks, Adrien NK! Before we run the simulations
though, we like to break down each character's
histories and abilities before improvising a
scenario on how we imagine one of the 1000
simulations would play out beat for beat. And
it's my turn to go first with the Marvel characters
backstory, so let me tell you guys all about
the X-Man Warpath. James Proudstar was born
to Neil and Maria Proudstar on the Apache Native
American Reservation in Camp Verde, Arizona.
James idolized his older brother John Proudstar,
who was a skilled athlete and decorated United
States Marine. Upon John's return from military
duty back to the reservation, James witnessed
his brother's mutant ability manifest for the
first time when he saved the life of a little
girl by wrestling a charging bison to the ground.
John was soon discovered by Professor X using
Cerebro and was recruited into the latest iteration
of the X-Men team, taking on the codename Thunderbird.
Alongside new recruits such as Storm, Wolverine,
Nightcrawler, Colossus, Sunfire, and Banshee,
Jon helped rescue the original X-Men members
from the Sentient Island nation of Krakoa.
You can learn more about the X-Men, Inner Titans
vs X-Men team duel, and more about Krakoa in
its duel against Danny the Street. In Jon's
next X-Men mission, he prevented the evil Count
Nefaria from escaping in a small aircraft by
jumping onto it and smashing it mid-air until
it exploded. It was an act that bravely, but
unfortunately, sacrificed his life for the
team. James was devastated upon learning of
his older brother John's death and blamed the
X-Men. Although John was to be buried with military
honors, James stole his brother's body and
gave him a traditional Apache warrior funeral,
in that moment swearing vengeance on Professor
X and manifesting his own mutant abilities,
the very same as his brother's. James was approached
by and joined the Hellions. which was a rival
mutant team to the X-Men, led by the Hellfire
Club's White Queen, Emma Frost, whom you can
learn more about in her duel against Poison
Ivy. James took on the codename Thunderbird
to honor his brother's memory, and went on
to fight the X-Men out of vengeance, but learned
in the course of their battle that Professor
X was not responsible for John's death, and
that John died as a true hero and warrior.
James declined an invitation to join the New
Mutants and returned to the reservation with
his vendetta abandoned. Many years later, while
on a trip to New York, James was approached
by the mutant Cable, who wanted to recruit him
onto his strike force team called X-Force.
Though James initially declined, he returned
home to the reservation to find everyone slaughtered,
and joined the X-Force under the new code name
Warpath in an effort to discover who the killer
was. During his tenure on the team, he developed
his powers to increase his mutant-enhanced
strength and senses, and began a relationship
with fellow X-Force member Siren, the daughter
of Banshee. Eventually, James learned who murdered
his people at the reservation. It was Cable's
clone from the future named Strife, who at the
time was dead. James was soon killed and journeyed
into hell itself to seek revenge against Strife,
fighting him alongside the X-Force who were
brought into the realm by Valkyrie to save James'
soul. In the end, X-Force won, returning James
back to life. You can learn more about Cable
in his duel against Booster Gold. Soon after,
James and the rest of the X-Force found themselves
caught in a vibranium bomb explosion that seemingly
killed the group. In reality, they survived
the attack and clandestinely prevented an alien
invasion. During that time, James' powers began
to fluctuate. temporarily giving him the power
to fly, and also removing his ability to speak
at one point. However, eventually, his powers
returned to normal. After the Scarlet Witch
was driven mad and used her reality-warping
powers to remove the abilities of mutants around
the world, James was fortunate enough to retain
his abilities and joined a new iteration of
X-Force where he was gifted vibranium knives
by Storm and Black Panther. The new team was
tasked with completing missions deemed too
secret or extreme for the main X-Men to handle.
One of X-Force missions was to defeat a horde
of resurrected mutants turned evil by the Black
Queen, Selene. One of the revived mutants being
James' brother, John. James had to kill his
brother in an act of mercy and ended up killing
Selene by stabbing her in the chest with her
own dagger, freeing the souls of the resurrected
mutants she was controlling. James then left
X-Force to later join the X-Men on their new
island base of Utopia off the coast of San Francisco.
James was later captured by the secret government
project called Weapon X for experimentation.
However, he was rescued alongside other captives
by a future version of Wolverine, and the group
took on the name Weapon X, serving as a mutant
rescue squad. While on the team, James developed
a romantic relationship with the mutant Domino.
However, he left when Old Man Logan stepped
down from leadership and Sabertooth took over
to turn the team into a mercenary squad. You
can learn more about Wolverine, Domino, and
Sabertooth in their respective duels against
Hawkman, Harley Quinn, and Killer Croc respectively.
James joined the majority of Earth's mutants
in creating their new mutant nation on the
sentient island of Krakoa. There, he joined
former new mutants members including Mirage,
Magic, and Wolfsbane, in helping train young
mutants living on the island on how to control
their new powers. While there, James' brother
John was able to be resurrected as Professor
X, Magneto, and the other heads of Krakoa had
developed a system of mutant resurrection using
a combination of mutant powers including mass
generation, reality warping, time manipulation,
and genetic and psychic archiving. Though initially
fearing to meet his brother out of fear that
he had somehow failed to live up to him, James
and John finally reunited and left Krakoa to
return to the reservation together. After Krakoa
was attacked by the anti-mutant terrorist organization
Orcus, James and John's Apache Reservation became
a makeshift mutant refugee camp. And that's
Warpath's backstory. Powers-wise, Warpath has
an enhanced mutant physiology that grants him
increased strength, able to lift a maximum of
75 tons, increased speed, able to run 100 miles
per hour, Nearing Vulnerability and Increased
Agility. In the event he is injured, he has
an increased healing speed. Warpath also has
enhanced senses, including hearing, smelling,
and seeing at great distances, and night vision.
He also has some mystic senses, allowing him
to perceive supernatural energies. Warpath is
a highly skilled hand-to-hand fighter and wields
two large daggers made out of vibranium. Finally,
while he was able to fly for a period of time
when his powers were temporarily in It seems
as if he is sometimes still able to tap into
that power. It's unclear, but it's an ability
that's rarely used at best. So for the purposes
of the speculation and the simulations, I'm
gonna treat his flight power as more like a
vast leaping ability, which seems more true
to the spirit of the character. If he is a
flyer, he's not a skilled or practiced one.
And those are his powers. Yeah, I'm not gonna
lie, that character is not as interesting as
Black Condor. What are you talking about? You
don't like the brother aspect with Warpath and
his brother Thunderbird? Not really. Well,
you are just a horrible brother then. How about
that? Sure, but I think you'll get what I'm
talking about when I go over Black Condor's
backstory, which actually begins in the Golden
Age of Comics. Now, when archaeologist Richard
Gray and his wife were killed by bandits during
an expedition in Mongolia, their orphaned son,
Richard Gray Jr. was raised by an unusually
intelligent race of Condors, from whom the young
Richard seemingly learned to fly, though it
was later revealed that his powers derived from
his metahuman abilities of telepathy and telekinesis.
As Richard grew into a young man- Seriously,
raised by Condors? That's a better backstory.
That's a freaking fantastic golden age origin.
Does not get more golden age than that. Now
as Richard grew into a young man- A hermit named
Father Pierre found and educated Richard, teaching
him survival skills and worldly knowledge. After
Father Pierre's death, Richard became the costumed
adventurer Black Condor, designing a black outfit
with glider wings to resemble the birds that
had saved his life. After tracking down and
killing the Mongolian bandits that murdered
his parents, Richard traveled to America, where
he assumed the identity of Senator Thomas Wright.
his doppelganger, after Richard failed to stop
a plot to assassinate the senator. After some
time fighting crooked politicians, Richard joined
the Freedom Fighters during World War II, led
by the personified spirit of America known as
Uncle Sam, which later became part of a larger
team known as the All-Star Squadron, which fought
the Nazis in Europe. The Freedom Fighters eventually
ended up in an alternate universe known as Earth-X,
where the Axis powers successfully conquered
the world. After two and a half decades of fighting
the Nazis, Richard and the Freedom Fighters
were eventually able to end the war with help
from the Justice Society and the Justice League
of America, teams you can learn more about in
their team duels against the Fantastic Four
and Avengers respectively. Though Richard traveled
to the main DC universe, Earth-1, to continue
his superhero career as the Black Condor, he
eventually returned to Earth-X to help rebuild
the war-torn world that had become his home.
A new black condor emerged years later, named
Ryan Kendall. For over 200 years, the Kendall
family and their associates, known as the Society
of the Golden Wing, had pursued the dream of
creating a flying man. Initially, their methods
were harmless, but as their obsession grew,
so did the macabre nature of their experiments.
By the early 20th century, their attempts had
become brutal and inhumane, and they continued
to fail. By the 1960s, The society turned to
mutation, irradiating the womb of Ryan's mother
to ensure her child would be born with tailored
genetic mutations. The child, Ryan, grew up
isolated under the care of his grandfather,
Creighton Kendall, the Golden Wing Society's
leader. For 20 years, Ryan underwent various
chemical, radioactive, and physical treatments,
and on his 21st birthday, the final and most
significant treatment left him in a coma instead
of achieving the society's desired outcome.
Ryan was sent to a special care facility, an
asylum for the society's failed subjects, where
for two years while in a coma, he was fully
aware of his surroundings and learned about
the true twisted nature of the society. Upon
awakening, feeling betrayed and violated, Ryan
fled and eventually settled in New Jersey's
Pine Barrens, living as a hermit. There he befriended
a park ranger named Ned David Smith, who was
a Delaware Native American who helped Ryan adjust
to life outside of isolation. Ned suggested
the name Black Condor, reflecting Ryan's dark
and predatory nature. Although reclusive and
reluctant to embrace the role of a hero, Ryan,
as the Black Condor, had an instinctive, heroic
nature, fighting alongside other superheroes
such as Hawkman and eventually joining a new
incarnation of the Freedom Fighters. Ryan was
later killed by Sinestro alongside other freedom
fighters when they were ambushed by the secret
society of supervillains. Though Ryan would
return briefly as a black lantern during the
Blackest Night event, a Navajo man named John
Trujillo would later claim the black condor
mantle after he was gifted elemental powers
from the Mesoamerican deity Tokadol, also known
as the Spider Woman, whose webbing holds the
fabric of the universe together. He was not
his tribe's first to bear the Black Condor
title, as nearly 150 years earlier, U.S. Colonel
Kit Carson raided a Navajo stronghold within
the Arizona canyons, forcing its citizens to
march 300 miles east for a resettlement in
what was known as the Long Walk. Many Navajo
died along the way, and their bodies were feasted
upon by Black Condors, or vultures. Those who
survived believed the Black Condors were rescuing
the souls of those who died to return them to
the Arizona canyons. When the Navajo eventually
did return to the canyons, they faced attacks
from cattlemen who wanted to steal their land.
When a young man begged to coddle for help,
like she did with John Trujillo, she imbued
him with the powers of the Black Condor to protect
his people. John fought alongside the Freedom
Fighters in his first mission, and continues
as a member of the team in DC's Prime continuity.
With the re-emergence of the multiverse, the
Nazi-controlled Earth-X returned, along with
a new version of the Freedom Fighters to combat
them with a new black condor named Marcus Robbins.
Born to contemporary black slaves working in
a Detroit industrial complex who dreamed they
could fly away from their indentured servitude.
After Marcus and his father secretly built
a prototype of mechanical wings, and the Nazis
found out about it, Marcus's father forced
him to fly away to save himself while his parents
were taken and never seen again. Marcus became
a legend among the Detroit workers known as
the Black Condor, and after joining the Freedom
Fighters, Marcus returned to Detroit and led
a revolt among the black community there against
the Nazis. For this duel, I'll be going with
the current Prime Universe version of Black
Condor, John Trujillo. in part because the executive
producers felt that version was the best one
to compete against Warpath. Powers-wise, most
versions of Black Condor have had low-level
telekinesis, which not only enabled them to
fly, but also emit telekinetic bursts. Since
John Trujillo is divinely empowered rather than
a metahuman, his power manifests as aerokinesis.
allowing him to manipulate the wind so that
he can fly at great speeds using his biological
wings and create gales or whirlwinds. John also
draws power from the earth, granting him increased
strength and durability. He's also a trained
warrior. That's Black Condor. Uh, yeah, none
of those origins were better than Warpaths.
Come on! None of them? Brotherly love, man.
Oh my gosh. Brotherly love. is not a greater
story than overcoming Native American oppression
and slavery. I'm sorry. Well, I'm not going
to argue against that, but also you're still
a bad brother. Also, I learned something today.
I guess a condor is a vulture. Yeah, I never
knew that. I actually learned that today too.
Total mind blow.
Where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
DynaMic Podcast Network presents Console Combat,
where video game legends brawl every Monday.
Comic Book Titans smash every Tuesday. Max Destruction,
where TV and action heroes battle every Wednesday.
And Sendro World, where anime champions clash
every Thursday. Join us as we speculate on
the matches and armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge victorious.
Visit dynamicpodcast.com where we settle the
debate and settle the score.
But now that we got their histories and abilities
out of the way, let's speculate on how one
of the 1000 simulated matches will go. The winner
is determined by simulations, not the speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how this fight could
play out. AJ9K, what are the rules of our speculation?
Well, I should say there are no rules, other
than the characters have no prior knowledge
of the other going into the fight. All they
are aware of starting out is that the other
character is a threat that needs to be eliminated.
The contestants will begin approximately 50
meters apart in a nondescript environment that
will have no bearing on the match itself, as
no environmental statistics are considered in
my simulations. The contestants must earn victory
on their own merit." Alright, then let's get
into it. Black Condor and Warpath meet on the
battlefield. Who goes first? I'm gonna say that
Warpath goes first, because he's better. He's
like, he just has a better name. Like Warpath.
That's badass. Black Condor... You know, like
vultures, they just wait around, you know? So
Warpath's going first. They're symbols of death.
Like you're walking around and you see a vulture.
Yeah, you're going to be freaked out. Warpath
is going to show how freaked out he is by entreating
his vibranium daggers from behind his back.
And he's just going to charge at Black Condor
like a bison, like 100 miles per hour. And
he's going to jam both of his knives right into
Black Condor's chest. You don't think Black
Condor sees Warpath charging at him with those
knives? Like. What is he a joke to you? Obviously
Black Condor sees Warpath charging at him at
a hundred miles per hour. Like it would only
take Warpath literally a second to cover a 50
meter distance at that speed. A hundred miles
per hour, is that supposed to be fast? By the
time Warpath gets to within say like 10 meters
of Black Condor, Black Condor is just gonna
spread his wings and trap Warpath in this tornado
that he generated. And that's gonna launch him
just spinning high into the air, at which point.
Black Condor, he's just gonna fly up and plow
right into Warpath at full speed with his fists.
Is that even gonna hurt Warpath? Like how strong
is Black Condor? Dude, Black Condor, not only
can he, you know, fly really fast to like increase
the impact of this blow, but he's also strong
enough to like crack force fields. Okay. I don't
even know how to quantify that, but we'll say
that Black Condor flies up, punches Warpath,
Warpath gets rocked higher up into the air.
But Warpath's a badass, he doesn't care. He's
gonna recover from the punch and he's gonna
skydive back down toward Black Condor, straightening
his body for a high-speed dive. And he's just
gonna tackle Black Condor out of the air, slamming
him right into the ground and jamming his daggers
right into his kidneys. Actually, Black Condor,
he's pretty maneuverable in the air, so I'm
gonna say he just shifts out of the way a little
bit from Warpath's dive and Warpath's just
gonna fall to his death. Oh shit! I mean, no,
no. Warpath's gonna land on the ground into
the superhero landing pose. You know, like one
fist on the ground while kneeling like a badass,
and he's immediately gonna stand up and chucks
one of his knives like a bullet right at Black
Condor ripping through one of his wings and
forcing him to like spiral down and crash into
the ground. Damn! Okay, that was a good move.
I mean, he wouldn't crash because like he could
just generate a gust of wind beneath him before
he hits the ground. So that's what he's going
to do here. And now that Black Condor is on
the ground, he's going to summon up a wind
that's going to lift debris generated from Warpath's
superhero landing. And he's going to use those
stones to just pummel Warpath like hailstones.
That would not hurt Warpath at all in the slightest.
He just smacks those pebbles away like they're
annoying flies or something like that. And
that's when he hurls his second knife right
at Black Condor's face. Just whack sticks right
in there headshot. OK, except that the knife
is blown with the wind gust down right into
the ground at Black Condor's feet, allowing
him to pick up the knife. And that's when Black
Condor is going to use the wind like a vacuum
on Warpath and just like suck him in towards
him and stick him with his own knife. Um, I.
I guess that a vibranium knife would be able
to pierce Warpath. Yeah, it would. But they're
up close and personal now, and Warpath is gonna
grab Black Condor's wrists and force him to
pull the knife out of him, like, I don't know,
say his shoulder or whatever. And that's when
Warpath's healing factor is gonna kick in.
It's just gonna seal that wound right up. Good
as new. I totally forgot that he has a healing
factor. As Warpath is holding onto Black Condor's
wrists... He's gonna headbutt him right in
the face, which is gonna cause Black Condor
to stumble back a step and he's gonna drop
the knife. And that is when Warpath follows
up with a flying dropkick straight to Black
Condor's jaw, laying the fool out cold. Because
there's no way he's durable enough to take
a hit like that. Dude, Black Condor is as durable
and strong as the ground he stands on. So yeah,
he could take it. And while Warpath's on the
ground. Before he can get up from his drop
kick, Black Condor is just gonna pin him down
onto the ground with this mighty wind that's
also gonna pull the arrow from Warpath's lungs.
That's gonna suffocate him and end this fight.
So match over. No, Warpath can just hold his
breath. He just holds his breath for a minute.
He's fine and he's gonna summon the strength
to reach out and grab his knife that Black
Condor dropped. And you know, since all this
wind is pushing him down, Warpath is gonna
punch the ground really hard. creating this
like small tremor that causes Black Condor
to lose his bearings long enough for Warpath
to at least get to his knees from where he
just uppercut slashes Black Condor up the middle,
you know, slicing him right in two. That's
how you match over. Lose his bearings? Black
Condor is like really graceful, like a bird.
But I guess we'll leave it there. Either Black
Condor suffocates Warpath by pulling the air
from his lungs. or Warpath slices Black Condor,
scrote to throat with one of his knives. And
then he scalps him, because that's what the
Apache did. I think they did that, yeah. Wow.
But we'll find out which of these scenarios
happens by inputting the character stats and
then running a thousand simulations and coming
back with a winner. AG9K, hit it! Inputting
data, running calculations, processing results,
simulations complete. All right, I like this
matchup. This was an idea by the executive producers.
I believe Devin Davis submitted this idea for
a duel match and it was not one that I had in
consideration. I was thinking like other strong
guys to go up against Warpath since he's essentially
X-Force's or one of X-Force's resident muscle
men. But really I didn't know anything about
Black Condor. I didn't know how strong Black
Condor was. All he knew was that he had wings
that could allow him to fly. Honestly, I didn't
know much about Black Condor either. He's a
pretty obscure character. But you know, he
gets his name dropped every once in a while.
I definitely like this John Trujillo version
more than the others, I would say. I've been
looking forward to getting him into a duel
at some point. I did like this matchup. Yeah,
it was closer than I would have thought, too,
considering, you know, the slightly different
power sets where Black Condor had a little
bit more in terms of speed and evasiveness because
of his flight. Warpath was a little bit higher
in terms of durability and strength. They kind
of evened each other out in a lot of areas.
Warpath also had higher perception due to his
enhanced senses, but Black Condor had higher
marks on range because he could create gusts
of wind that cover entire city blocks. Yeah,
neither character were very versatile and they
also matched up pretty evenly when it came
to things like fighting skill and damage level.
With all that in consideration, who do you
think's taking the win on this one, Jonathan?
It's gotta be Black Condor. I mean, he has
almost everything going for him that Warpath
does in terms of strength and durability. but
he has the added bonus of being able to fly
and control the wind. I put up the Instagram
poll very, very late, like right before we began
recording this episode. Usually I do a day
before. Right now, the poll is sitting at 50
in terms of who people think will win. So that
doesn't help. No, I'm actually surprised that
Black Condor has that many votes, though, considering
I feel like Warpath is the more popular character.
Is he, though? I feel like most people know
who Thunderbird is, if they know him at all,
because he's fairly obscure as well. When you
say Warpath, I'm like, who? Thunderbird's brother.
Well, like there was a version of Thunderbird
in the Gifted series as well, which was a spinoff
from the X-Men on Fox. The one that no one
watched? Yeah, the one that I didn't even watch.
Okay. Well, Instagram polls aside, let's go
ahead and get the results and find out who won.
AG9K, the results please. Hey, Yuasa. Alright,
the winner between Black Condor and Warpath
is... Warpath. Fuck! Sucks to suck! Warpath
beat Black Condor 539 times out of a thousand
matches, meaning Black Condor only won 461,
so Warpath wins 53.9% and Black Condor only
wins 46.1% of the time. What the hell? gave
him the win. I thought Black Condor was coming
out on top here. Well, the biggest disparity
between the two characters was in two stats.
One of them was durability, which Warpath was
higher in, and the other one was range, which
Black Condor was higher in. But then Warpath
eked out a small victory when it came to perception
and strength. Stupid enhanced senses. I feel
like Black Condor should have enhanced senses.
Like, it makes sense for the character to have
that. He just hasn't had enough appearances
in the comics for them to establish that. Yeah,
well the comics have established that between
Warpath's enhanced reflexes and senses, it
makes him an absolute marksman with his throwing
knives. And you know, considering how fast
he can throw, I just don't think that Black
Hunter would stand a chance. Warpath is just
too strong and too much of a badass and too
cool and too powerful and too awesome and too
just good in general. Holy shit, why don't you
marry him already?
Nah, I'm good. You say Warpath is cool, but
like, I just remember him getting his ass beat
in Days of Future Past. Yeah, by those future
Sentinels. Like a lame ass. Black Houndour
would not have gone down that quick. Yeah, you
probably would have flown away or something.
Like a coward. Bitch, you don't know his life.
I mean, except for the fact that you literally
just told me his life, so there you go. Dang
it. But that does it for this duel guys, let
us know what you thought about the results by
writing to us at dyna or by visiting us on
Instagram, which you can find a link to in our
show notes or by going to our website at dynamicduel.com.
And on our site, you could also find a link
to our Patreon page where you could join our
dynamic duo tier and chat with us and fellow
listeners, our fantastic four tier, which gets
you bonus content each month, our X force tier.
that makes you an executive producer of this
podcast or our highest tier that lets you join
our DynaMic Podcast Network. Please don't
forget to rate the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify,
Podchaser, or on our website. Our next episode
is going to go back to the nostalgic era of
the mid-90s superhero cartoons. We recently
just got done reviewing X-Men 97, which brought
us back to the old X-Men the animated series.
Now we're going to journey back on the DC side
of things with a review of Batman Mask of the
Phantasm. Yeah, it's a great movie, I never
had the opportunity to see it in theaters,
but I'm glad we're finally getting around to
reviewing it. It's a classic. But that does
it for this episode, we want to give a big thanks
to our executive producers Ken Johnson, Jon
Storowski, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Belcombe,
Miggy Matangian, Brandon Estergard, Nathaniel
Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Austin Wiselowski, AJ Dunkerley,
Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho. Adam Spies, Andrew
Shunk, Dean Molesky, and Devin Davis for helping
make this podcast possible. We'll talk to you
guys next week. Up up and away, true believers.