This is a DynaMic Network podcast. Hey guys,
Marvelous Joe at the top of the episode here
to let you know that for the months of November
and December, Jonathan and I will be donating
10% of the proceeds that we earn on our Dynamic
duel store to the charity Stand Up to Cancer.
So for your holiday shopping this year, go to
our website, dynamicduel.com, click on the
store button, and check out the wide offering
of products that we have available for you
guys. from apparel to accessories and even stickers.
The week before and after Black Friday, we
will be providing you guys a 10% off discount
code. And if you're a patron of ours, right
away we'll be giving you 15% off anything in
the store for the next two months. Also make
sure to check back each week as we will be updating
our store with new and exciting products for
you guys to explore and enjoy. Again, for the
months of November and December, we'll be donating
10% of our proceeds to Stand Up to Cancer. So
support the podcast, support A Great Cause,
and get some cool merch for yourself, your friends,
or your family this holiday season. On with
the show.
Hi, welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Marvelous Joe. And I'm his twin brother
Johnny DC. And this is a big episode. In tie-in
to our previous review of Venom the Last Dance,
we are going to be finding out who would win
in a fight between White Lantern, Kyle Rayner,
and Null, the eldritch god of darkness. This
is going to be a really fun episode because
basically, Null's going to wipe the floor with
White Lantern and it's going to be enjoyable
for me to witness that. So both of these characters
are insanely powerful, but if you think Null
is more powerful than the White Lantern Kylo
Renner, I don't know what to say. Cocaine's
a hell of a drug. Well, we'll find out later
on this episode, guys. Really excited for it.
Before we get into the duel though, we're going
to break down the latest comic book movie news
to come out this past week. including just
one news item actually. It was the new release
dates that were announced in the Marvel Studios
2025 look ahead sizzle reel. Yeah, there was
some DC casting news announcements but it was
really for unrecognizable actors in lesser roles.
So it was hard to get excited about. I find
it hard to get excited about most DC things.
So I totally see where you're coming from.
You are sassy this episode. I think it almost
come from some like insecurity they're having
about the matchup later on. It's gotta be. Nah,
I just had a lot of sugar this morning, so.
Halloween candy. Yeah, exactly. As always guys,
we list our segment times in our episode description,
so feel free to check out the show notes if
you wanna skip ahead to a particular topic.
Our artificially intelligent duel simulator,
AJ9K, has a quick message for our listeners,
so listen up. Why hello there, do you want even
more from this podcast? Then become a part
of the dynamic duel community on Patreon, where
you can choose from three tiers. The dynamic
two-o tier gives you access to our Discord chat
server. The fantastic four tier gives you two
bonus episodes each month, and the X-Force tier
makes you an executive producer of this show.
Lastly, The Diner Mike podcast network tier
lets you create your own podcast using this
Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe will help
you develop your show, provide graphic support
and consultation, and get you simulation results.
Pitch the twins your ideas via email at dynamicduelpodcast
at gmail.com. Check it out at patreon.com slash
dynamicduel. Pip pip cheerio. Thanks, AJ and
IK. Thanks to everyone who supports the podcast.
Guys. Be sure to tune into the other shows
on the DynaMic Podcast Network this week, including
Max Destruction, which pits your favorite action
heroes from film and television against each
other. This week, hosts Scotty and Gilly are
determining the winner between Mickey Mouse
and SpongeBob SquarePants. On the Send Your
World podcast, host Zachary Hepburn speculates
on fights between fan favorite anime and manga
characters. Zach is traveling abroad for the
next couple of weeks, so the show is currently
on a brief hiatus. And on the Console Combat
podcast hosts John and Dean simulate battles
between popular video game characters. In yesterday's
episode, they found out who would win in a
fight between Scud the disposable assassin and
IG-88 from Star Wars Battlefront 2. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com
or click the link in our show notes to listen
to all of the shows in the DynaMic Podcast
Network. But with that out of the way, quick
to the no prize. A no prize is an award Marvel
used to give out to fans. Our version, the Dynamic
duel No Prize, is a digital award we post on
Instagram for the person that we feel gave the
best answer to our question of the week. Last
week we asked you guys to give us your best
30 second film pitch for the MCU Blade movie
because we got news that the film was removed
from Marvel's schedule and we had to figure,
you know, it's gotta be easier than what they're
making it to crack a Blade script for the movie.
We got quite a number of answers, but we're
going to break down this week's honorable mentions
before revealing the no prize winner. Our first
honorable mention goes to Colby Hentges, who
said, Hey boys, Colby Hentges. Since Marvel
likes to get cheeky with the punctuation lately,
the new Blade movie will be Blade, Ebony. It'll
be Blade teaching the new Black Knight, Dane
Whitman, how to use the Ebony Blade he found
at the end of the Eternals. The Black Knight
will be the young loose cannon. Blades getting
too old for this shit, Whitman. It'll be a
lethal weapon with vampires. But who do we get
to play the Joe Pesci part? Yeah, this is a
pretty good idea. The only appearance we've
gotten of Mahershala Ali as the Blade character,
if you can call it an appearance because it
was just his voice, was in the end credit scene
of the Eternals movie in which we hear Blade
addressing Dane Whitman, the Black Knight,
about his ebony blade. So we know that those
two have met in the Marvel Cinematic Universe
I like to think that's not a plot thread that
Marvel would just leave hanging. Now the Black
Knight wields a blade in the comic books called
the Ebony Blade, which is a vampiric blade
of sorts. You could describe it that way, and
I'm pretty sure that's why Blade showed up
in The Eternals even, but Dane Whitman's sword
is a magical, powerful sword that grants him
bloodlust that he constantly has to fight against.
Yeah, I really like the idea of a lethal weapon
vampire movie. I think that's fantastic. As
for who would be cast in the Joe Pesci role?
I nominate Joe Pesci. Yeah, just cast Joe Pesci.
He's still around. Great answer, Colby. Our
next honorable mention goes to Mason Thompson,
who said, OK, you could involve. Sorry if I'm
saying this super fast. You can involve the
werewolf by night in the swamp thing to kind
of continue on from the short film. And Blade
has to hunt them down to see things. They're
involved with the vampires. You have the vampires
be like a tribe. So that way, they're they
haven't been in MCU because they're like hidden.
And so he hunts them down. He realizes they're
not a part of that. And then they came up or
something like that. Like he thinks they're
part of the vampire tribe. And then, yeah. So
Mason Thompson made sure to call back and let
us know that he meant Man-Thing and not Swamp-Thing,
since Swamp-Thing is a DC character. But yeah,
both Werewolf by Night and Man-Thing were in
the Werewolf by Night Disney Plus special presentation
that came out a few Halloweens ago. So the characters
are established and yeah, it would be neat
for Blade to interact within the supernatural
world that special set up and go after them
thinking that they're, you know, evil creatures,
but it turns out it was just a mix up and then
they all joined together to fight an evil vampire
tribe. I like it. It has shades of like underworld
to it, but underworld is just a cool concept.
Like vampires versus werewolves. Is it currently
being done right now? And so it's ripe for the
picking. Yeah, I didn't think of it that way,
but that would be cool. Essentially, it seems
like Mason Thompson is pitching a Midnight
Suns movie that just stars the character of
Blade, which I have no problem with. So we're
going to answer Mason. Our next honorable mention
goes to Travis Bailey, who said,
Hey, Travis Bailey, shout out to my good friend.
All right. So look, Contessa goes to Old Man
Hawkeye. I need that rolling out. Right. I'm
putting together a team. We got a threat Lilith
out of Idaho. she's producing demons somehow,
we gonna go there we gonna shut her down. They
get there, they meet up with Elsa Bloodstone
thinking that she's Lilith, she ain't that
but she whoops the ass, alright? But, ass comes
off, I'm not roaming I'm playing, and the big
bad at the end, the scarlet witch. Okay he went
through that really quick, but basically Travis's
pitch is having the Contessa hire Hawkeye as
Ronin to go after Lilith during which they
encounter Elsa They find out it's not. She teams
up with Ronin, who turns out to be Blade, against
the final bad guy who turns out to be Scarlet
Witch. So there's a lot of elements going on
there. I would probably nix the Scarlet Witch
thing at the end and just have the actual bad
guy be Lilith, the mother of demons, or actually
there's another Lilith who's like the daughter
of Dracula. So you might want to go that route.
But we've been introduced to Elsa Bloodstone
in the MCU in the Werewolf by Night special
presentation. And she was fantastic in that
short film. and she managed to get a hold of
the Bloodstone within that story, which we
know is a war against vampires. Elsa Bloodstone
would be a great partner for Mahershala Ali's
Blade. Yeah, but how do you feel about him as
Ronin? There have been a lot of different characters
to portray the Ronin identity over the years.
Basically, Ronin is kind of a persona for superheroes
who have to go undercover. You know, Echo's
been Ronin, Hot Guy's been Ronin. I could totally
see Blade as Ronin. Though I would probably
want that reveal to happen sooner rather than
later. That way you don't have a Blade movie
where Blade rarely shows up. You know, we don't
want to think it's Hot Guy the whole time. Honestly,
if we're nixing the Scarlet Witch thing, yeah,
also just nix the Ronin thing. Just have Blade
be recruited to go fight Lilith. I like it.
Sold. Yeah, decent concept overall. So thanks
Travis Bailey for your answer. We want to give
a quick shout out to Daniel Alonso, as well
as Travis Herndon, who pitched the idea of
a Blade and Ghost Rider team up against Blackout
and Mephisto in Vegas idea, which I thought
was pretty good, but it was more of a demon
movie than a vampire movie. So it didn't get
an honorable mention, but I still liked it.
But the winner of this week's snow prize is
Mike Williams. Who said? Mike Williams here.
Blade movie scripts, maybe Blade versus Morbius.
And somehow Spider-Man comes along and convinces
them they need to be on the same team. Probably
never get made, but we can wish upon it. Enjoy
your show, and as always, make mine Marvel.
Peace. Yeah, if any Blade movie was to get made
in an ideal world where the rise to these characters
wasn't all jumbled, we would get a Blade versus
Morbius film, right? That would be awesome.
And... They would fight against each other and
then end up teaming up to go up against a larger
vampire threat such as Dracula, Deacon Frost,
someone like that. I think that would be the
best case scenario for a Blade movie. Unfortunately,
out of all the ideas that were listed here,
this is least likely to happen because Sony
owns the rights to Morbius. Yeah, but that
said, Sony has also lent Spider-Man to the MCU
before, so why not another character like Morbius?
Well, they might offer that deal with Marvel
as a way to extend their Spider-Man contract,
so who knows? Maybe it's not out of the realm
of possibility. I would like to see it happen.
In fact, I think if you got like a Blade movie
with Morbius and Elsa Bloodstone as like his
sidekicks, that would be the ultimate best case
scenario. I think honestly, if Sony wants to
get even more in Kevin and Faggy's good graces,
they would offer something like that. For sure.
So great answer, Mike Williams. You win this
week's No Prize. If you, the listener, want
a shot at winning your own No Prize, stay tuned
to later on this episode when we'll be asking
another question of the week. And now that that's
done. On to the news!
Alright, this past week we got a look ahead
sizzle reel video from Marvel Studios that
details their upcoming projects on Disney+.
And we got a lot of new release dates that
we previously didn't know before. Basically
a reveal of what's coming out later this year
and in 2025. There's a lot of great stuff, a
lot of new footage that was introduced within
the sizzle reel, including a look at Daredevil
Born Again, where we got to see the fucking
kick-ass action that's going to be in the show.
It looks... Like it's going to continue carrying
the torch that the show had on Netflix in terms
of its just gritty, hardcore, rough and tumble
action fights. We got to see Daredevil fighting
characters like Muse and The Punisher. It all
looks so damn fantastic and I really can't wait
for this show to come out. We previously already
got a release date for Daredevil Born Again,
but it reiterated that the show will be debuting
on March 4th, 2025. Yeah, I cannot wait. Everything
that comes out for the show just gets me excited
for it. It's going to be awesome. The next show
we got to look at was Your Friendly Neighborhood
Spider-Man, which is an animated series that's
coming out on Disney+. It takes place in kind
of an alternate timeline wherein we get a look
at Peter Parker's early days as the web-slinging
hero where he doesn't quite have his costume
nailed down yet, but What was interesting was
that it was revealed that Peter Parker's mentor
in this timeline is Norman Osborn, not Tony
Stark. So we're going to see how that influence
affects him as a character. That's weird. I
didn't know it was an alternate timeline. Why
would they do that? I don't know. Initially,
the premise of the show was going to be a look
at Peter Parker's origin because we never really
got that in the MCU. He was already established
in the Captain America Civil War movie. as
a full-fledged superhero when he was recruited
by Tony Stark. And I thought we were going
to get to see his early adventures as the hero,
how he decided to become the hero and everything
like that. But just knowing that this isn't
like sacred timeline Peter Parker kind of bums
me out. I don't even want to see it now. I know
this has kind of become my least anticipated
show for 2025, but we will be reviewing it.
It actually is going to debut on the Disney
Plus television platform on January 29th. So
pretty soon here, actually. The animation looks
pretty good, I'll give it that. It looks like
straight out of a Steve Ditko comic, but the
3D element is pretty nice, considering it's
computer animated. Not quite stylistic on the
same level as the Spider-Verse, but like really
no animation can even approach that franchise.
I'm pretty sure Peter Parker kills a kid by
slamming a brick into his head. Well, we will
find out if that kid deserved it or not. Whoa.
But moving on to Ironheart, we learned that
that- live action series is going to debut on
Disney Plus on June 24th. So during the summertime.
But we got a cool look at Riri Williams suit
as she's building it. It looks pretty damn
badass. And we also got to look at the hood
within the sizzle reel, which if you didn't
see the leaked D23 footage, this is probably
your first looks at these characters. I wasn't
excited for this show at all. But I got to say,
the footage from it looks really damn good.
Yeah, it looks pretty compelling, honestly.
I'm not a huge fan of Dominique Thorn's Riri
Williams because she didn't impress me in Black
Panther Wakanda forever, but this show does
look pretty dang good. Next up in the sizzle
reel was What If Season 3, which is coming
like really fucking soon. I had no idea earlier,
but this show is actually debuting this year
on December 22nd with a new episode coming out
each day after it debuts. So we're probably
going to get this show in its entirety before
the start of the new year. We got some pretty
cool shots, like a Western type tale. There
was a fucking Transformers version of Captain
America, which I am like super excited by. That'll
be really cool. I mean, the What If series
is just pretty damn good, especially season
two. I really like season two of What If. I
thought it was better than season one. So I'm
really looking forward to season three and
seeing what they do there. Yeah, it looks like
What If is getting its first spin-off series
in Marvel Zombies. Right, yeah, we got our first
look at that show, which is gonna be TVMA on
the Disney Plus platform. We got a brief look
at the Marvel Zombies universe in the first
season of What If, but they're gonna continue
that story within this Marvel Zombies animated
series, which is gonna come out in time for
Halloween next year in October 2025. The animation
looks spot on. There's a shot here where we
see a bunch of people falling off a building,
and it reminds me a lot of World War Z and...
I'm super pumped for this show. I gotta tell
you. I think the biggest surprise out of this
sizzle reel that came out was our first look
at Wonder Man, which is a television show starring
Yahya Abdul-Mateen II, who is no stranger to
comic book shows and movies. Here he is playing
Simon Williams, who is the character of Wonder
Man, the superhero who's also an actor. And
it looks like the television shows is really
leaning into that aspect of the character and
kind of sending up, you know, Hollywood tropes
and things like that. It kind of seems like
he is a guy who has superpowers, who is auditioning
for a role called Wonder Man, and through the
course of the show he actually becomes that
hero. We see him being mentored by Trevor Slattery,
who is played by Ben Kingsley, who infamously
was the guy behind the Mandarin in Iron Man
3, and was great comedic relief in the Shang-Chi
film. I'm not a huge fan of Trevor Slattery.
I'll just never forgive what Iron Man 3 did
with the character of the Mandarin, but... since
Shang-Chi was able to kind of salvage that
character and that concept. It's kind of interesting
to see what's going on with Wonder Man. And
honestly, I'm curious. It has piqued my curiosity,
we'll say. I feel like Trevor Slattery was
redeemed in Shang-Chi, especially because the
real Amandarin ended up being way cooler than
anything Iron Man 3 could have imagined. I don't
love the idea that he's acting as a character
called Wonder Man. The whole thing is just kind
of confusing, but Honestly, Trevor Slattery
was the most interesting thing about this footage
to me. Yeah, that show is not going to come
out, though, until next December. So around
Christmas time, 2025. The next show that we
got a look at in the sizzle reel is Eyes of
Wakanda, which looks like an amazing, amazing
animated series where we get a look at the Black
Panthers of the past in Wakanda's history.
The animation style, I think, is what stood
out most to me in that. It's not like the What
If series or anything else that Disney has produced
for Marvel Studios. It looks a little bit more
stylized and Pixar-y. I guess the best way to
describe it so far is that it kind of reminds
me of The Clone Wars. Yeah, yeah, I thought
the same thing. But like with a whole lot more
money put into its budget. Aizu Wakanda is going
to come out in August of next year. Can't wait
to see more on that show. Yeah, I'm really intrigued
by it. Honestly, I think for a lot of these
shows... I kept repeating myself saying that
I am super pumped to see it, but it's true.
You know, there's a lot of good stuff here coming
out from Marvel at the end of this year and
throughout 2025. So this trailer just got me
super pumped, totally aboard the hype train
for what's coming out on Disney plus. And I
know that like Marvel said that they were going
to start winding down the quantity of their
projects and really focus on the quality, but
it seems like we quite have not reached that
point because there's a shit tongue coming
out in 2025. Man. Speaking of all the shit that's
coming out, that brings us to our question
of the week.
I didn't mean like shit, I was like, stuff.
It was a lot of stuff. Yeah, a lot of shit.
Oh God. Out of Marvel Television's upcoming
projects revealed in the sizzle reel, which
one gets you the most excited and why? Yeah,
I'm particularly interested in the projects
that you weren't as excited in until you saw
the sizzle reel and then it got you like super
pumped. So record your answer at dynamicduel.com
by clicking on the red microphone button in
the bottom right hand corner of the screen,
which will prompt you to leave us a voicemail.
Your message could be up to 30 seconds long
and don't forget to leave your name in case
we include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer and award that person a Dynamic
Duel No Prize that we'll post to Instagram.
Be sure to answer before November 9th.
But I think that does it for all the news for
this episode, so let's go ahead and get into
our main event where we find out who would win
in a fight between the White Lantern, Kyle
Raynor versus Null.
Alright, White Lantern vs. Null. Now these two
characters are heavy hitters, if I do say so
myself. Basically they're on the same level
as like Lactis and Spectre. This is that kind
of matchup. These guys are just off the charts.
Yeah, White Lantern, Kyle Raynor, is the culmination
of all the different multicolored energies of
light in the universe, and Null is a primordial
deity, really, of darkness. They both have...
really badass weapons. Kyle Rayner wields the
White Lantern Power Ring, Null wields All Black
the Necro Sword, and each of them can use their
weapons to produce constructs out of their respective
element of light or darkness. I'm really excited
to be doing a duel episode with Kyle Rayner.
He was the Green Lantern that was around when
I first started reading comic books, so he's
near and dear to my heart. He's known as being
the most creative of the Green Lanterns. Yeah,
we've done a lot of Green Lantern episodes
so far, like against Nova, against Beta Ray
Bill, against Quasar, but this will be the
toughest battle yet for a Green Lantern. I just
don't see how you stand a chance, that being
said, I don't know a lot about White Lantern,
so let's go ahead and break down the characters'
histories and abilities. But first, to explain
the methodology behind our duels, let's go
to our sentient duel simulator Alfred Jarvis
9000. AJ9K, tell our listeners how you go about
determining a winner in our duel matchups. Yes,
of course, sir. The way I determine a winner
between the contestants is by running 1,000
Monte Carlo simulations using the characters'
statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation is a probabilistic
model used to determine outcomes through random
sampling. In this case, I randomise the statistics
along a normal distribution as a way to simulate
the many variables that can occur during battle.
The stat parameters are based on the official
Marvel power grid from which the DC characters'
statistics are extrapolated. Additional stat
categories are included such as range, damage
potential, versatility and perception in order
to create a more detailed and accurate simulation.
The results of the 1000 simulations provide
a percentage of wins for each character. The
contestant with the higher percentage is declared
the victor as they have a higher probability
to win any given battle. In an equitable pairing,
neither character should win 100% of the matches.
The comic book stories have shown that there's
even a way for Batman to defeat Superman. So
the confidence rate of my method falls in line
with the precedents that have been established
in the source material. My mathematical simulations
are without subjectivity or bias. Feats are
not the sole consideration, nor are fan votes
tabulated for determination of the winner. Thanks
AJ9K! Before we run the simulations though,
we like to break down each character's histories
and abilities, before improvising a scenario
on how we imagine one of the 1000 simulations
would play out beat for beat. And I think it's
my turn to go first with the Marvel characters'
backstory, so let me go ahead and tell you
all about Null. In a cosmic cycle of death and
rebirth, the Marvel universe expands from a
cosmic singularity over billions of years until
it collapses in on itself to give birth to
a new reality. Null, the primordial god of darkness,
was born of the void in the aftermath of the
Marvel Multiverse's sixth iteration. Null drifted
through eternity, untouched by purpose, until
the Celestials intruded, igniting the seventh
iteration of existence with their Light of
Creation. This light, destined to shape a new
universe, pierced Null's realm of darkness,
forcing him from solitude. With a hatred of
this invading brightness, Null resisted when
the Celestials offered him a cosmic role to
serve as the counterpart to the Beyonders,
known as the King in Black. he waged war upon
the Celestials with his power over the Primordial
Void, determined to reclaim his kingdom of darkness.
In his defiance against the Celestials, Null
crafted the first symbiote weapon, All Black,
the Necro Sword, forged from his living Abyss.
With it, he decapitated the Celestial, causing
the other space gods to retaliate, casting
him and the slain Celestial's severed head into
the void. Isolated but undeterred, Null repurposed
the Celestial's head into a forge, using its
cosmic energies to empower his Necro Sword
further and create his Symbiote Armor. In his
own likeness, Null began manifesting life from
the darkness itself, experimenting with symbiotic
creatures and forming a hive mind that connected
each creation to his own dark essence. With
his symbiote army at his command, Null clad
himself in his symbiotic armor and set forth
on a genocidal crusade. destroying planets,
extinguishing stars, and slaughtering any god
or creature that dared to dwell in the light.
For eons, Null's dark empire grew, and his legend
spread through the cosmos as a figure of terror.
His conquest drew the attention of a time-displaced
Silver Surfer, who attempted to free a world
under Null's oppressive rule. The two clashed
in an intense battle, with Null successfully
infecting the weakened surfer with a symbiote,
making him his Void Knight. Despite the setback,
the Silver Surfer was freed by Ego the Living
Planet and used the last of his power cosmic
to conjure a star, the blinding force of which
hurled Null across the cosmos, temporarily
halting his rampage. Null recovered quickly,
however, and resumed his campaign against the
light undeterred by the setbacks. As his terror
continued, Null encountered an army of gods
empowered by the light of the Enigma Force and
clad in shining golden armor. Null slaughtered
the entire army, save for one who struck a blow
through Null's head as Null impaled the Light
God through the chest. Wounded, Null was discovered
by Gore, an alien mortal who stole All Black
the Necro Sword, claiming it as his own. While
Null could have pursued the weapon, he instead
allowed Gore to wield the All Black, recognizing
the mortal's vengeful heart as a mirror of
his own hatred for the Light. As Null recovered
from his battle with the Light Gods, he observed
Ghor's bloody rampage across the stars and took
satisfaction in the devastation wrought by
his former blade, knowing that his influence
had once again seeped into the cosmos, spreading
death in his stead. Null's reign resumed and
endured until an ill-fated invasion of Earth
during the Middle Ages. One of his most terrifying
creations, a symbiote dragon named Grendel,
arrived on the planet attempting to subjugate
its people. However, the young thunder god
Thor rose to defend Earth, striking down the
Grendel with a lightning-charged blow. Thor's
divine lightning energy shattered Null's connection
to his entire symbiote hive, scattering his
creations across the universe and fracturing
his control over them. Free from Null's influence,
the symbiotes began bonding with new hosts,
discovering the beauty and honor in light and
life.
binding him within a prison formed from their
own bodies, an artificial planet they called
Klintar, which translates to cage in their language.
Though locked away, Null's dark will was not
yet broken. In the centuries that followed,
he subtly influenced symbiote hosts and sent
visions to the Church of the New Darkness, a
cult composed of the few who still remembered
and revered his legend from the Middle Ages.
His presence began to stir when the international
espionage organization, SHIELD, unearthed the
remnants of Grendel in modern times, using
its symbiote essence to create super-soldiers
during the Vietnam War, including one commander,
Rex Strickland, who was codenamed Tyrannosaurus
Rex. SHIELD's project reawakened Null's psychic
link to the symbiotes, allowing him to exert
control over some of the soldiers, sparking
conflict with a new generation of heroes, including
Eddie Brock, the host of the Venom symbiote.
whom you can learn more about in our Clayface
vs Venom duel episode. Brock's battle with
the Grendel and subsequent entanglement with
Null's cult followers only strengthened the
symbiote god's hold over his long-lost creations.
Through a twisted ritual involving Carnage,
Null's followers resurrected Cletus Kasady,
granting him godlike power with Null's influence.
Together, Carnage and Null sought to collect
parts of the Codex, which was a residuel trace
of the hive mind left by symbiotes in their
former hosts. By gathering the Codex, they
hope to break the bonds of Klintar and release
Null once more. You can learn more about Carnage
in his duel against Lobo. Carnage's bloody rampage
for the Codex brought Null ever closer to freedom,
culminating in a showdown with Venom that left
Null completely reawakened. Breaking free of
Klintar, he reassembled its fragmented symbiotes
into a horde of dragons and set off on a new
campaign of terror, determined to claim Earth
and crush the light it represented. After reclaiming
All Black the Necro Sword, he cut a path of
destruction across the cosmos, resuming his
cosmic slaughter, conquering countless planets,
and even corrupting and assimilating his celestial
gods into his army. Arriving in Earth's orbit,
Null set his sights on its mightiest heroes,
brutally ripping the sentry in half and incorporating
the dark energy of the hero's void persona
into himself. covering Earth in a sphere of
living darkness, Null imprisoned or corrupted
heroes in a massive offensive, seeking out Eddie
Brock's young son, Dylan. Before the child
was born, Dylan was influenced in the womb by
the codex of Anne Wang, his mother, who had
once bonded with the Venom symbiote as She-Venom,
granting the child powers capable of countering
Null and the symbiotes. Though Thor tried to
stop Null by using his divine lightning as
he had Null himself proved too powerful and
unleashed his full might by sending his symbiote
controlled celestials into battle, overpowering
the Thunder God. At the height of Null's invasion,
the Silver Surfer came to Earth to help fight
his former foe, yet he was also overpowered.
When Null seemed lost, Eddie Brock and Venom
were chosen as the avatar of the Enigma Force,
temporarily becoming the hero known as Captain
Universe. Empowered by this opposite force,
Venom gained the cosmic power to confront Null
directly. In that confrontation, Brock formed
a battle axe merged from Thor's hammer Mjolnir
and the Silver Surfer's surfboard and launched
an assault that stripped Null of his symbiotic
armor, leaving him vulnerable. With Null weakened,
Venom carried the Dark Lord of the Abyss into
the sun, using the Unipower to destroy him
in an eruption of light. With Null's death,
the symbiote hive mind found liberation and
Venom was renamed the new King in Black. guiding
the symbiotes toward a new legacy of protection
instead of conquest. In his final words, Null
cursed Venom, insisting that his darkness would
one day return, and in fact, his consciousness
lived on, hidden as a codex within the symbiote
hive-mite. Powers-wise, Null, as a primordial
entity of darkness, has power beyond most other
Marvel characters. He can generate and manipulate
the eldritch void that he calls the Living
Abyss. With it, he can control a parasitic darkness
that can enslave beings as powerful as Celestials
and the Silver Surfer. From it, he can also
create living creatures of darkness, primarily
dragons and symbiotes, some of which, like Grendel,
are powerful enough to destroy whole cities.
Noel can also use the Living Gebess to create
weapons and armor, such as his nearly indestructible
symbiote armor that he can reshape on his body
to form things like a helmet, or a cape, or
a pair of dragon wings. He used the darkness
to forge All Black the Necro Sword, which was
strong enough to kill a host of god-like beings,
including decapitating a Celestial, whose cosmic
power he infused into the sword. All Black can
fire dark energy, create dark tendrils, and
even shape-shift its form. Null is immensely
strong, with beyond class 100 level strength,
he is durable enough to withstand Celestial
attacks, and has a regenerative healing factor
derived from his living abyss. He can fly at
orbital speeds using his wings or a dragon
mount, and he is an expert combatant with billions
of years of fighting experience and an expert
strategist with eons of accumulated knowledge.
And that's null. So what you're telling me
is that his weakness is light. What I'm telling
you is that even though his weakness is light,
he has extinguished stars, he has killed light
gods, and he will straight up murder Kyle Rayner's
ass and put him in a fridge. Just like his girlfriend.
Too soon, too soon! No, Null sounds pretty
cool. I didn't know his Necro Sword was imbued
with cosmic energy. That's wild. Yeah, with
the energy of a Celestial. What's the cooler
sword? The Necro Sword or Excelsior? Oh, Hulkling
Sword? Yeah. By far, the Necro Sword. By far.
Yeah. Okay. It's not even a question. I saw
what Gorr did with the Necro Sword. I didn't
see what Gorr did with the Necro Sword. I thought
Hela had the Necro Sword essentially in the
MCU. No. Oh, if we're talking about the MCU,
Gore wielded the all-black Necro Sword, but
it was very different from how it is in the
comics. You're right, Hela's abilities in Thor
Ragnarok more closely matched the power of
the Necro Sword. Still not as cool as wielding
a power ring, especially a white one. Ooh,
jewelry. All right. But like the coolest jewelry.
You'll learn. You're going to learn today.
Let me tell you all about the White Lantern
Kyle Raynor. At the beginning of the multiverse,
when light and life first emerged, the life
entity was born and was the source of emotional
entities, Aion, Parallax, Predator, Ophidian,
Butcher, Adara, and Proselyte. After battling
the forces of Death and the Black, the entity
went into hibernation within Earth to regain
its strength, with the earliest sentient race,
that would eventually be known as the Guardians
of the Universe, hiding its existence to protect
it. Hundreds of millions of years later, Kyle
Rayner was raised by a single mother, Mara Rayner,
in Los Angeles, California, as his father,
Gabriel Vasquez, was a CIA agent who was forced
to abandon his family due to his line of work.
Despite the lack of a father figure, Kyle channeled
his energy into art, eventually pursuing a
career as a graphic artist. Though his creative
nature set him apart, he struggled financially.
One random night, however, Kyle's life changed
forever when he was approached by a small blue
alien named Gantlet, who was a guardian of the
universe from the planet Oa and a founder of
the Green Lantern Corps Universal Peacekeeping
Force. Gantlet was the last of the Owens after
the Green Lantern Corps' destruction, and was
on a mission to bestow the final remaining
power ring to a new bearer. Without explanation,
Gantlet handed Kyle the ring before vanishing.
Kyle tried on the ring, which instantly transformed
his clothing into the standard Green Lantern
uniform. Realizing he'd been given incredible
powers, yet unsure what to do, Kyle showed
the ring to his photographer girlfriend Alex
DeWitt, who encouraged him to become a superhero
and change his uniform into one more creative
to set him apart from prior Green Lanterns.
Before long, Kyle helped Superman defeat Mongol,
both sharing surprise at Kyle's ring's ability
to affect the color yellow. a known flaw in
prior Green Lantern rings. You can learn more
about Superman and Mongol in their respective
duels against Dr. Doom and Nihilus. As Kyle
continued to train and learn more about his
new powers, tragedy struck when he returned
home one day to find Alex murdered and her body
gruesomely stuffed into a refrigerator by the
villain Major Force. Enraged and grief-stricken,
Kyle confronted Major Force, who had operated
under a shadow a Green Lantern power battery,
capable of recharging a Green Lantern ring.
After recovering the battery and recharging
his ring, Kyle chose not to kill Major Force,
despite his rage, as he knew Alex would have
wanted him to make the heroic decision, and
he was inspired to fully embrace his role as
a hero and a Green Lantern. Over time, Kyle
became known throughout the superhero community,
forging friendships with other heroes like
Connor Hawk, Wally West, and Donna Troy. the
latter two of whom you can learn more about
in their duels against Speedball and She-Hulk.
After joining the Justice League, Kyle eventually
encountered Hal Jordan, his Green Lantern predecessor
and destroyer of the Green Lantern Corps, who
had become a nigh-omnipotent villain known as
Parallax. When Parallax attempted to reshape
time and reality, Kyle was forced to sacrifice
the planet Oa to stop him. Upon Kyle's return
to Earth, he settled in New York City, where
he became friends with the former Green Lantern,
Guy Gardner, and he met Jade, the daughter of
another former Green Lantern, Ellen Scott,
who you can learn more about in our Green Lantern
vs Iceman duel. As Kyle's romantic relationship
with Jade developed, he faced new enemies such
as Fatality, Sonar, Nero, and Oblivion, the
latter of which was a manifestation of his own
inner turmoil and fears. Upon realizing the
nature of Oblivion, Kyle confronted and overcame
this dark aspect of himself, allowing him to
tap into his full power potential and transform
into Ion, a being of near limitless power.
As Ion, Kyle was able to cure the former Green
Lantern Jon Stewart's paralysis, and even restore
the planet Oa and the Guardians of the Universe.
In a selfless act, Kyle sacrificed the last
of his omnipotence to reignite Oa's central
power battery, allowing for the recreation
of the Green Lantern core and earning him the
honorary title of Torchbearer. in recognition
of his dedication to the Green Lantern mission
and legacy. When Kyle was led to believe that
Major Force killed his mother, Mara, Kyle decapitated
the villain before flinging his head into space.
Fearing he had become a danger to those he loved,
Kyle left Earth and ventured into the cosmos,
where he discovered Hell Jordan's body and unearthed
the truth behind Hell's actions, that Hell
had been possessed by Parallax. a powerful parasitic
entity representing fear, which had driven
him to madness and destruction. Armed with this
revelation, Kyle returned Hell's body to Earth
and helped exercise Parallax from Hal, successfully
restoring Hal as a Green Lantern. You can learn
more about Hal in our Green Lantern vs Nova
episode. It was later revealed that Sinestro
was the one responsible for Mara's death in
an effort to break Kyle's will so that he could
serve as the new host for Parallax. Though Kyle
became Parallax for a time, he was able to
break free of the Entity's control with the
help from Held Jordan, and he was later inducted
into the Green Lantern Corps' Honor Guard, where
he developed a relationship with Sinestro's
daughter and fellow Green Lantern, Sora Nick
Natu. During the events of Blackest Night when
the dead across the universe were resurrected
as Black Lanterns, Kyle sacrificed his life
to protect his fellow Green Lanterns. As Black
Rings attempted to turn Kyle into a Black Lantern,
members of the Indigo Tribe and Star Sapphires
intervened and managed to bring Kyle back to
life. After facing a resurrected Black Lantern
version of his former lover, Alyx, Kyle and
the other Green Lanterns managed to repel the
Black Lantern army and defeat its leader, Necron,
the personification of death, when Sinestro
managed to awaken and bond with the life entity
within the Earth. becoming a white lantern.
You can learn more about Sinestro in our Sinestro
vs Magneto duel episode. When a rogue Owen known
as Corona trapped Parallax within the Green
Lantern's central power battery, allowing him
to take control of the Green Lantern core,
Kyle became a blue lantern for a time. In the
altered reality following Flashpoint, Kyle
was chosen to wield power rings from each color
of the emotional spectrum, including red rage,
orange avarice, yellow fear, and Green Willpower,
Blue Hope, Indigo Compassion, and Violet Love,
resulting in his transformation into a White
Lantern. With each ring, Kyle underwent intensive
training, mastering the abilities of each color,
a journey that eventually led him to wield
the White Light of Life, enabling him to tap
into every emotion and power associated with
the spectrum. As a White Lantern, Kyle faced
unprecedented threats, including the rise of
the Third Army. a force created by the Guardians
to replace the Green Lantern Corps. With the
Third Army's ability to infect and transform
others into soulless soldiers for the Guardians,
Kyle worked alongside other Lanterns to destroy
the Third Army and stop the Guardians. During
this period, Kyle became instrumental in the
battle against Relic, a scientist from a previous
universe who sought to drain the emotional spectrum's
energy, believing that its depletion was inevitable.
Kyle and other lanterns attempted to stop Relic,
but his knowledge of the Spectrum's mechanics
made him a formidable opponent. Relic's attack
led Kyle to confront the Source Wall, a boundary
at the edge of the universe. In a final bid
to stop Relic, Kyle passed through the Source
Wall, a feat that no one had survived, and one
that restored each of the emotional entities.
Although the universe believed him dead, Kyle
eventually re-emerged from the other side,
forever changed by the experience and equipped
with new cosmic insights. Upon his return,
Kyle's powers as a White Lantern grew, allowing
him to wield life energy at an unparalleled
level. His unique role drew the attention of
the new gods, led by Highfather, who sought
to harness the life equation now within Kyle
to create a weapon that would kill Darkseid.
Highfather manipulated Kyle in an attempt to
forcefully sever his connection to the Kyle
resisted, however, and ultimately joined forces
with other lanterns and allies to prevent Highfather's
plans, as it would have resulted in the deaths
of billions. Realizing that his power could
easily become a target, Kyle made the difficult
decision to distribute the White Light among
a select group, forming a small, white lantern
core dedicated to safeguarding life. Kyle's
duties as a white lantern extended beyond traditional
heroics. He used his power to heal and rebuild
worlds devastated by conflict, guiding civilizations
in need, and providing them with the means
to prosper. His new status also introduced him
to beings across the universe who sought the
White Lantern's influence, from the Guardians
to cosmic entities intrigued by his ability
to channel life itself. This journey taught
Kyle a new level of responsibility as he grappled
with the implications of holding the life equation
and the ethical dilemmas it posed. Balancing
the interests of various cosmic powers, Kyle
carefully navigated his position as a force
of creation, ensuring that his actions served
the greater good. After helping the Omega Men
overthrow the tyrannical rulers of the Vegas
system, Kyle was summoned by some of his Owen
allies to help resurrect Hal Jordan, who had
died. Successfully doing so, Kyle then attempted
to resurrect the entirety of the Blue Lantern
and Kyle returned to being a Green Lantern once
again. But for this match, Kyle will luckily
be in full-on White Lantern mode, as he's one
of the few beings in existence capable of wielding
each color of the emotional power spectrum in
DC Comics. These capabilities include indestructible
construct generation, allowing Kyle to manifest
anything he can imagine in any solid color
he chooses except for black. He could also detect
and instill emotions in others as well as fly,
teleport himself and others across the universe,
see others' memories, and heal himself and
others even from fatal wounds. And unlike other
power rings, his ring requires no charge as
long as he's cultivating life with it. And that's
Kylo Renner. Well, trust me, Kylo Renner will
not be cultivating any sort of life while in
battle against Null, the King in Black. All
he's going to be doing is fighting, so I feel
like he's just going to run out of energy eventually.
Yeah, no, that's not going to happen. Especially
when Kylo Renner is just going to make short
work of Vel. Oh, you think so, huh? I do, in
fact. Well, let's find out then. All right.
Come at me, bro.
Where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
Dynomic Podcast Network presents... Console
Combat, where video game legends brawl every
Monday. Dynamic Duel, where comic book titans
smash every Tuesday. Max Destruction, where
the world is at its limit. The Dynomic Podcast
Network presents... TV and action heroes battle
every Wednesday, and Sendro World, where anime
champions clash every Thursday. Join us as
we speculate on the matches and armed with the
power of mathematical simulations, discover
who will emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
Now that we've got their histories and abilities
out of the way, let's speculate on how one
of the 1000 simulated matches will go. The winner
is determined by simulations, not this speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how this fight could
play out. AJ9K, what are the rules of our speculation?
Well, I should say there are no rules, other
than the characters have no prior knowledge
of the other going into the fight. All they
are aware of starting out is that the other
character is a threat that needs to be eliminated.
For the speculation, the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a non-descript
environment that will have no bearing on the
match itself, as no environmental statistics
are considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. Alright
then let's get into it. White Lantern and Null
meet on the battlefield. Who goes first? I'm
going to say that Kyle starts off, you know,
he's going to see Null's Necro Sword, and in
response he's going to create like a giant...
futuristic lightsaber version of the Buster
Sword, you know, Cloud's weapon from Final
Fantasy. Basically just a big ass lightsaber.
Alright, uh, Null's gonna see this and like,
he's gonna tell White Lantern that he's gonna
slit his throat and choke out the stars with
his blood. And Kyle's gonna be like, okay, not
a Star Wars fan, I guess. More of a Star Trek
guy, apparently. And that's when he's gonna
lift his giant lightsaber sword straight into
the air and just slash downward towards Null.
It's gonna emit this vertical wave of pure
light energy that's gonna slash Null right in
half. No, because White Lantern's massively
telegraphing with his big-ass sword swinging
downward and everything, so Null's gonna be
ready. He's gonna unleash a giant symbiote dragon
that serves as a shield to protect him. The
wave of light is gonna evaporate the dragon
from existence, but as it does that, we see
Null riding another symbiote dragon like a steed,
and he's just gonna charge full on White Lantern,
and charging along with Null and his dragon
are gonna be like a hundred symbiote tendrils,
okay? And each one of those tendrils has a mouth
at the end with sharp teeth. Basically, they
just like pass over White Lantern like a cavalry
running over a foot and they just devour him
to small bits as they pass. So I just imagine
this as him like riding like a black wave of
like ink and teeth. Yeah, pretty much. That's
kind of cool. But I'm going to say when Kyle
sees Noel charging, get him like a Lancer. He's
going to create a massive energy cannon in
the shape of like a lion mech robot that shoots
light energy from its mouth. And he's going
to blast Noel and his dragon. with this white
hot energy beam. And alongside Kyle are gonna
be four other mech lions, which are focused
on shooting down all of the individuel symbiote
tendrils. So, all right, the lion cannon destroys
the symbiote dragon, but Null's gonna leap
off of it in time to avoid the blast himself.
And from the symbiote armor, he's gonna sprout
giant dragon wings of his own, and he's gonna
just continue on swooping in. and ramming his
necro sword through White Lantern, impaling
him like Vlad the Impaler. Uh, alright, so,
Kyle, I guess he gets impaled through his chest,
but that's when a spinning energy saw blade
just comes down and slices the necro sword blade
off, like, at the hilt. And while it spins
through the air around Null, just carving chunks
of his armor off, Kyle's gonna pull the necro
blade out of his chest, and just overload it
with white light until it vanishes. and then
he's gonna heal his chest wound while Null is
still distracted by the saw blade. Okay, it
would take an insanely powerful attack to break
the Necro Sword, okay? Because it's not only
supremely powerful, it's also imbued with the
power of a Celestial. Yeah, and? I guess I'll
allow it since White Lantern seems pretty powerful
with his light-based attacks, but like, that
wouldn't even matter because Null has... created
a new all-black necro sword before. And maybe
this one's not quite as powerful, but it's not
like the sword is the source of his living
abyss powers. So while White Lantern is healing,
Null is just gonna conjure a new sword from
the hilt of his old one, and then create like
a giant clawed symbiote hand that like swats
the energy saw blade away and snatches up White
Lantern in its grasp, just crushing him to
death in like this Iron Maiden pointy. grip?
Well, not really, because as the Iron Maiden
grip tightens, you know, Kyle's light aura is
going to solidify and expand into this protective
sphere. And as Kyle's pushing back against the
darkness, that's when he's going to yell, let's
go Voltron force. And that's when his five lion
mecha's that he created transform around him
into a giant mecha robot. I figured that was
His giant mecha is gonna slam his palm down
onto Null and just splatter him everywhere.
No, cause when the giant Voltron robot slams
his hand down, it's gonna slam onto a giant
spike. Like this spire that Null has erupted
from the ground beside him. And from the spire
is gonna leak this black symbiotic ooze that
rushes all over the Voltron bot, just taking
it over and transforming Voltron into like
this giant- Horned demon monster type thing
and the living abyss is also gonna seep into
white lanterns control room area Inside the
robot and take him over to just enslaving white
lantern to the will of null and making him his
new Void knight just like null did with the
silver surfer. So this match is over No, no,
cuz let's say as the giant mecha is being taken
over That's when the mecha is white light turns
bright indigo and its energy instills within
Null this very strong sense of compassion, causing
him to, you know, summon the darkness back
to him. So while Null is having this very sensitive
moment, that's when Kyle expands a white dwarf
star within Null's head, obliterating him and
his symbiote armor into nothingness. Wow. Okay.
Well, anyone who's ever tried to... Psychically
or empathically affect null they're just exposed
to the void that is his essence essentially
it doesn't go well for them They basically
become catatonic So I'm gonna say that's what
happens to white lantern when he tries to manipulate
nulls emotions But it's not like Kyle's mind
is connected to his you know empathic powers
his emotional influence powers Okay, like even
if white lantern was successful in killing
null with a white dwarf star inside his head
Kyle was assimilated, even if briefly, which
means that he's now part of the Symbiote Hivemind
as a codex that Null's consciousness can still
have influence over even after his quote unquote
death. So like White Lantern thinks he's won,
but suddenly Kyle's white ring turns black with
like a red spiral on it and he becomes a black
lantern under Null's control. So Null still
wins no matter what. Null's dead, Kyle is alive,
and you think Null wins? Yes, because at the
end, Null's consciousness is in his ring controlling
him. Pretty sure that's not how this works.
Null's dead, Kyle's alive, match over. I think
what you mean to say is that no matter what
happens, Null wins either way. Either White
Lantern becomes assimilated, or he dies, or
he comes under Null's control, so yeah. So
many ways for Null to win this, you're screwed.
Well let's take it to the stats then. Sure!
Alright, yeah let's input them, run the simulations,
and get the results. AG9K, hit it! Inputting
data. Running calculations. Processing results.
Simulations complete. This was a damn good
match you guys. Man their stats were just so
freaking powerful. I don't see how any other
character would be able to go up against these
guys. Both White Lantern and Null statistically
were maxed out. in their durability, their strength,
their damage level, their range. We did say
that White Lantern was a little bit faster because
he can essentially teleport across the entire
universe, whereas Null has to, you know, like
travel through the universe. Yeah, we also
said that White Lantern was slightly more versatile
than Null because the guy's, you know, a freaking
White Lantern. Yeah, he does have control over
the entire spectrum, you know. whereas Null
sticks to his living abyss and darkness motif,
so he doesn't have quite as many tricks up
his sleeve. But we did say that Null was more
intelligent than Kyle and a better fighter.
But Kyle rated higher when it came to evasiveness
because he's more prone to creating force fields.
The interesting stat here I thought was perception,
because White Lantern has the ability to detect
emotions across the universe and hone in on
them and stuff like that. But Null is also
connected to his symbiotes around the universe.
So he can kind of like manifest an avatar of
himself through those beings that he's created.
But also through the symbiote Hivemind, anyone
who's come into contact with the symbiote, a
copy of their brain is basically uploaded to
the Hivemind as a codex. So he has access to
all that information as well. Which is wild.
Honestly, both of these characters are really
cool. Like, I feel like the White Lantern Ring
is the ultimate weapon in DC. and the Necro
Sword is like the ultimate weapon in Marvel.
Again, really close matchup. I would say that
the Necro Sword is probably secondary to the
Infinity Gauntlet, which is the ultimate weapon
in Marvel and would totally stomp all over
a white lantern ring, but that's neither here
nor there. It's also cheating. I'm talking
about like a real weapon, not like a cheater's
weapon. Okay, okay. Oh, I could do anything,
ah. Considering all these stats, Jonathan, who
do you think is gonna be the winner of this
match? Well, White Lantern for sure. The stats
are really close, but I think he'll come out
on top. Now, Instagram disagrees with me. The
poll is fresh. Like it definitely hasn't hit
the full 24 hours, but it looks like Null has
a pretty strong lead at the start with a 62%
favorability amongst our Instagram poll takers.
Well, let's see if they're right. I think they're
right. AG9K, the results, please. Hey, Yuasa.
OK, the winner between White Lantern, and Null,
the king in black, is... White's Lantern. Yes!
What? Yes! Really? Who is this guy? Uh, motherfucking
Kyle Rayner, my boy. I don't know what this
shit is, but uh, White Lantern won 522 matches
out of the 1000 simulations, whereas Null only
won 478. In the end, really, It was White Lantern's
versatility, his speed, and the fact that Null
is vulnerable to light-based attacks that really
put him over the edge. Even though Null has
proven to be extremely resilient against things
like the Power Cosmic and Thor's lightning,
it's those things that do him in. That's right!
That's right! So proud of my boy Kyle, he's
been my boy since the 90s. Null is just new
and lame, and this podcast proves it. Null is
definitely one of the better new characters
that Marvel has produced over the past decade
or so. Definitely the best villain. I hope
people who are new to the character at least
got that impression through his backstory and
his powers and everything like that. He really
didn't deserve to go down like this to some
punk-ass kid named Kyle. I mean, really? I just
feel like Cartman right now. I just want to
be like, shut up, Kyle! You shut your mouth,
fatass! Null is definitely not a Cartman. He's
like one of the skinniest characters out there.
He's like Slenderman but with long hair. Kinda,
and you know, just badass powers and shit. Anyway,
that is it for this duel guys. Let's get this
over with. AJ9K, help close this out. Thanks
for listening to Dynamic duel. Visit the show's
website at dynamicduel.com and follow us on
Instagram at dynamicduelpodcast. You can support
the show on Patreon at patreon.com slash dynamicduel
and joining a tier that works for you, or by
rating and reviewing Dynamic duel on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, Podchaser or on our website. Don't
forget to listen to the other shows in the DynaMic
Podcast Network, including Max Destruction,
Senjow World and Console Combat. Our next episode
is going to be a good one. We're going to review
Agatha all along season one. I actually haven't
started watching the show. I wanted to wait
to binge it. So it'd be fresh in my mind as
I was reviewing it. But I have been waiting
on pins and needles to start this thing. I cannot
wait. I can wait. I haven't started it either,
but I'm not looking forward to the show at all.
I heard it's really good. Sure, we'll find
out. Oh, you're going to find out. Yeah. You're
going to fuck around and find out. I don't
know what that means. But yeah, with that for
this episode, we want to give a big thanks
to our executive producers Ken Johnson, John
Swarovski, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Balcom,
Miggy Mattinghien, Brandon Essergard, Nathaniel
Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Austin Wazilovski, AJ
Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam
Spies, Andrew Shunk, Dean Maleski, Devin Davis,
Joseph Kirsting, and Josh Schleiner for helping
make this podcast possible. We'll talk to you
guys next week. Up up and away, true believers.
live together in perfect harmony, side by side
on my piano keyboard. Oh lord, why don't we?