you
A weekly show where we review superhero films
and debate the superiority between Marvel and
DC by comparing their characters in stat-based
Battle simulations. I'm Johnny DC and I'm his
twin brother Marvelous Joe and in this episode
We are reviewing venom which just came out
last week It's kind of a controversial movie
among for sure for sure among the general public
maybe not necessarily fans I think for the most
part fans really liked it. Yeah, but either
way, I'm super excited to talk about it I did
not hate it, surprisingly. I thought I would
because of all the comparisons to like Catwoman
and stuff like that. Oh, that was fucking bullshit.
Yeah, Lady Gaga fans. I blame them. Screw whoever
said that. But before we get into that, just
a reminder, this is our 92nd episode. We are
counting down to our 100th episode, which will
happen in early December, I believe, and we
have a big surprise. Can't talk about it yet,
but only eight more episodes to go after this.
Yep. It's going by fast. In this episode, we'll
be breaking down the news from the past week.
A lot of news. Yeah, a ton of news. Yeah, because
of New York Comic-Con. Yeah, and a lot of them
are videos. There's the Aquaman Extended video.
There's the Spider-Man Into the Spider-Verse
Official Trailer 2. We're going to be talking
about Rosie Perez being cast in Birds of Prey.
I think that's like the one non-video news
item. There's two trailers for Daredevil Season
3. A Titans final trailer. And then a Harley
Quinn animated series first look. So... Yeah,
a ton of stuff to go over and break down. The
news itself could almost be the entire episode.
But yeah, after that, we'll get into the Venom
review. Just real quick. Usually we save this
for the end of the episode, but right now we
are trying to get to 200 ratings specifically
on iTunes because Rotten Tomatoes has recently
changed their standards for what qualifies as
a Rotten Tomatoes approved critic, which includes
podcasts now. All we need is 200 ratings and
we meet all of the criteria. So we've been
trying to get there and we have been getting
ratings, but a few people have also been generous
enough to give us reviews. So we just wanted
to give them a quick shout out. Yeah, we super
appreciate it. Thank you very much to Dnick290,
Badewalker, JazzPee, LilChef118, and LarryNuki.
I think that's how you pronounce that. Thanks
to all of you for your generosity. Yeah, you
guys say fantastic things. I don't deserve it,
but you don't deserve it. I do. Neither do
you. Thanks again. Yeah, if you guys could help
us out with reaching 200 ratings on iTunes,
please do so. And if you want to give a review
as well, that would be fantastic. So this Thursday
on Patreon, we will be releasing bonus content
for our patrons in the form of our secret project
that we've been working on for the past month
that the general public doesn't have access
to yet. But it'll be like the second episode
of that. So patrons look forward to that this
Thursday. If you want to join our Patreon, go
ahead and go to patreon.com slash dynamic duel.
And for just two bucks a month, you get access
to weekly bonus content, which is awesome.
So check that out for sure. One of our main
goals for the Patreon account is to reach 25
patrons, at which point we will be printing
out physical copies of the dynamic duel no
prize that we award each week to a listener
that gives our favorite answer to the question
of the week. And speaking of no prizes, it's
no prize time. So a No Prize is an award that
Marvel used to give out up until the 90s to
fans. Our version, the Dynamic Duel No Prize,
is a digital award that we post on social media
that I personally draw for those who we feel
gave the best answer to our question of the
week. Last week's question was, who would you
have cast as Huntress and Black Canary? This
of course stemming from the news that those
two roles have been cast in Birds of Prey. Right.
So this was a tough one. Yeah, a lot of great
answers, a lot of great half answers, I guess.
Yes. With almost every answer that we received,
I really, really liked one of those answers
and really kind of didn't really care for the
other one. Ultimately, I awarded the no prize
to two people who sort of gave my two favorite
actresses for the individual roles. But yeah,
for Black Canary and for Huntress. Yeah, yeah,
yeah. Honorable mention goes to Ariana Quadra
for her answer of Diane Kruger as Black Canary
and Rosario Dawson as Huntress, which was fantastic
choices. Like, I totally loved Diane Kruger
ever since Troy. And Rosario Dawson? Total badass.
They may have been aged out of the parts by
this point now, though. They're both in their
early 40s, late 30s, I think. Yeah, it'd be
hard to carry a franchise with them. But yeah,
honorable mention also goes to Joel Seagrave,
who gave the answer of Tatiana Maslany. She's
the orphan black actress for Black Canary and
Eliza Dushku as Huntress. Yeah, that was a great
answer. I can see both of those actresses in
those roles. I can see Tatiana Maslany playing
Huntress as well as Black Canary. She could
do so many roles. Yeah, I guess that's what
she's known for. Yeah, another honorable mention
goes to John and Adam Spies, who gave the answers
of Natalie Dormer as Black Canary and Marie
Evgaropoulos as Huntress. They actually gave
this answer in their own podcast, Blast From
Our Past podcast. which we guest starred on,
when they sent us their answer, they were like,
just the podcast is our answer. So we put it
in this list. Yeah, that was a fun episode.
In that episode, we talked about the Batman
animated series 90s cartoon show, as well as
the X-Men 90s cartoon show. So definitely check
that out if you get a chance, if you're a fan
of those shows, because their podcast is just
awesome. It's a great podcast. Again, it's
called The Blast from Our Past Podcast. Yeah,
but to move on to the winners of the NOAH Prize,
we are giving it to Jacob Bell. who gave the
answer Blake Lively for Black Canary and Liv
Tyler as Huntress. That's great right there.
It is. Blake Lively as Black Canary, that was
always my dream cast. Liv Tyler is probably
a little bit too like- Well, she's like a decade
older than Blake Lively. Yeah. And she's always
been very low energy, very soft spoken. I don't
quite see her as being like the fierce Helena
Bertinelli from the comics. And then we're
also giving the no prize to Mia Moraes. who
gave the answer Trisha Paytas as Black Canary.
I don't know who that is. Which, but the answer
of Lily Collins as Huntress was fantastic.
I love Lily Collins. She's great. She would
make a fantastic Huntress. Great answer. Yeah.
So yeah, congrats to Jacob Bell and Mia Marius.
You guys both get the Dynamic Duel No Prize
for this week. If you wanna win a Dynamic Duel
No Prize, go ahead and listen to later on this
episode when we ask you guys another question
of the week. With that out of the way, onto
the news.
So late last week Warner Brothers unveiled an
extended video. It's five minutes long of Aquaman
footage. Yeah, that was crazy when I saw that.
I was like, wow, what's happening here? Yeah,
this whole trailer literally, literally left
me with tears in my eyes. It's so beautiful.
Oh my God. So fantastic. The action looks amazing.
That's the thing that blew me away. The action
and just the cinematography is so bright, so
colorful, so amazing. These set pieces. I just
want to go there. Right? Like I can't believe
someone imagined some of these places, some
of these like set designs. It's just phenomenal.
It's great. For both of these trailers for
Aquaman, I just am blown away by how expensive
the movie feels. It feels huge. The production
value on this must've been astronomical. Like
a $300 movie. I mean, what? What? $300 million
movie. Seriously, seriously, so much money,
every frame. Yeah, it starts off with Jason
Momoa, Arthur Curry, sort of like, talking about
his origin, I guess, his parents. It's interesting,
the first shot is actually of a snow globe of
a lighthouse sitting on top of an H.P. Lovecraft
book, which we know James Wan is a big horror
fan and H.P. Lovecraft deals with underwater
monsters and stuff like that, so that was a
good call out. But we get to see, basically,
it's the love story between his mom, Queen Atlanta,
and his father, Tom Curry. they're in love,
but she has to leave. And then, you know, we
see Aquaman, you know, grown up and he's lifting
us up a submarine. But then the extended video
really gets into the meat of what it is. And
it's really like two action set pieces. I don't
even want to say action, because the first
one is, it's more like an Indiana Jones exploratory
kind of piece. They're in the desert. They
find these lost remains of Atlantis, which is
kind of cool. I'm guessing it's like one of
the cities of Atlantis. And that's why the Atlanteans
don't live there anymore. Or like the city
moved at some point or something. Yeah, maybe,
I mean. Arthur Curry doesn't say that as they're
walking up the sand dune. He's like, you know,
there's no way Atlantis was this far inland.
But yeah, just makes you wonder like what happened
to Atlantis? What happened to the city? It's
a strange line. It's a strange scene. It looks
cool. It looks really, really cool, just like
this ancient city. And even Jason Momoa can
help himself just being Jason Momoa. It's badass.
He's a little bombastic. He is. He is. It's
it's not in keeping with the character of Arthur
Curry that I know from the comics. Yeah. Well,
what is that character? He's a little more
bland. He's a little more generic. He doesn't.
He's not bombastic. I wouldn't describe him
as that. It's true. But in that regard, I think
that Jason Momoa is perhaps adding some depth
to the character that didn't exist prior. You
look at characters like Iron Man, who prior
to the Iron Man movie was a little bit of the
same, you know, he wasn't defined through his
humor. Right. He wasn't like a smart ass. Right.
He was heavily defined as a character by his
alcoholism and a straightforward attitude. But
it wasn't until Robert Downey Jr.'s portrayal,
which was at the time to me a little bit unfamiliar
in regards to the character, but it totally
came to define Tony Stark going forward from
there, which I came to appreciate because it
did add depth. Now we know Tony Stark as the
eccentric billionaire. Yeah, Jason Momoa definitely
isn't selling a regal Aquaman. He's definitely
more of a guy who just grew up in the normal
world. So I don't... I don't mind it. Perhaps
drinks heavily or something, you know. Yeah,
he does. We know that from the Justice League
film. But it will be interesting if he does
eventually become closer to the Aquaman that
we all know and love from the comics towards
the end of the film, that will be his character
arc. To go from this guy who is the opposite
of royalty and go into a more mature character.
Yeah, yeah. In this scene, they activate this
Atlantean machine in kind of a funny way where
she takes a sweat and he's like, we could have
just peed on it. I laughed at that. But it's,
you know, it's a good thing that her hand didn't
like move south lower and just like extract
the urine from his groin. There's probably
a lot more there in his bladder. You probably
maybe, yeah. But the machine activates like
a hologram and it's I think it's King Atlin,
the first King of Atlantis who actually sank
Atlantis. And he's talking about his trident.
So now we know sort of like the story they're
looking for this trident. And we haven't really
got that in previous trailers. Right. And they're
trying to find it, I assume, before Orm can
find it. Right, yeah, I think so. But as he's
talking about Atlantis, we get these really
great scenes just looking at ancient Atlantis
and underwater Atlantis. Yeah, it's amazing.
It almost looks like Asgard on steroids. Oh
yeah. It's insane. It is insane. There's so
much detail, so much detail in every frame.
It's ridiculous. Once he starts talking about
the Trident and it has the power of Atlantis.
Once that the hologram is done, she like breaks
the key. And then he's like, shouldn't we have
at least written the message down? It was kind
of another funny scene. He's like, blah, blah.
Tried it. But then, you know, we get some more
like quick cuts of different scenes, but it
really leads into Black Manta and some like
Atlantean soldiers against Mara and Arthur.
Yeah. Which is pretty cool. Black Manta. Such
a badass. He looks so flippin cool. Yeah, I'm
glad we pit him against Black Panther. I know,
I know. In our duel episode. It was such a
good matchup. I'm really glad we did it. Arthur,
you know, he definitely seems to be holding
his own, like, doing like this flip kick against
Black Manta, which was kind of cool. He's a
fighter. Yeah, definitely. Mera is on the run,
running across the rooftops as these soldiers
are just like tearing straight through walls.
It's pretty cool. The camera work is pretty
amazing. The camera work is the most impressive
thing about this action scene. I've never seen
camera work quite as kinetic as this. where
it's like darting through windows and stuff
like that and really tracking along with the
action in a way that's impossible to do physically,
but somehow they pull it off. It's movie making
magic. It is for sure, for sure. It's something
that you can't do in comics, right? Right. And
it just brings so much energy to the scene.
But you know, that ends with one of the soldiers
getting shot on Mara. And then we get more
action scenes throughout the rest of the video
of Oram and Arthur Curry fighting underwater.
That looks really cool. That's gonna be a highlight
of the movie, I feel like. We also get a lot
of the underwater battle scenes between the
sharks versus the alligators versus the seahorses
and stuff like that. Yeah, and Nicole Kidman
being a badass with her trident. Yeah, I didn't
know she was gonna have an action scene in this
movie. No, I didn't know either. Looks like
she's protecting her family. Maybe they find
out that she's living with this family at some
point. Yeah. And that's why she has to leave,
I'm guessing. Yeah. I think so. They definitely
de-aged her for this. I'm wondering what role
she's going to serve later on in the film.
Not sure. But we get to see more of the trench
and more of that really, really cool scene
of him like carrying a flare down into the water.
Those monsters look awesome. And then it ends
with this pretty cool line of like Atlantis
has always had a king. Mer is talking to Arthur.
This was a great moment. Yeah. And she's like,
we need something more. And Arthur's like,
well, what's greater than a king? She's like
a hero. And then it's the coolest shot ever.
It's well timed with the music and the moment.
It is super well timed. It's just like this
powerful cathartic moment of Aquaman just like
stepping out of this waterfall with the trident
in his classic costume, hair's all wet, just
pins his trident to the ground. So badass.
Oh, so great. I'm wondering if the movie can
actually live up to this moment from the trailer,
because it's a lot of elements that work together
to create this magical moment. It will, it
absolutely will. Okay. It will. I have so much
faith in James Wan. I can't wait for this film.
He should be commended for creating what looks
to be just a magical movie that presents a
lot of things that we have never seen before
in film. In regards to the action, in regards
to this world that he's creating, it looks on
par with something like Avatar. Oh yeah. It's
awesome. I think out of all of its competition
for its opening weekend, it's going to come
out with the top spot. It's facing fierce competition
from Bumblebee, from Mary Poppins, from Sherlock.
Homes and Watson. Homes and Watson, yeah. And
then that entitled Deadpool Christmas special
thing. Right. Yeah. We're not exactly sure if
that's just a PG-13 of Deadpool 2 or not. I
mean, I'm beginning to think it's not going
to be just that. Right. That's probably the
one I'm most concerned about. Uh huh. Um, this
all kind of brings us to our question of the
week.
So of the four other major films opening in
the same timeframe as Aquaman, including Bumblebee,
Mary Poppins, Holmes and Watson, and the untitled
Deadpool Christmas special, tell us why you
think Aquaman has the best shot at winning the
weekend box office, or why not? Yeah, it's
a little nerve wracking. It is. With all those
movies competing against each other. They're
just gonna consume each other, and I hope that
Aquaman's box office doesn't suffer as a result.
Again, I do think it'll win the weekend, but
if it doesn't, I'm kind of curious which one
will take it over. Does this trailer make you
nervous for Deadpool? No, I don't care if Deadpool
makes money or not because we already have Deadpool
2. So it's kind of more like a joke Christmas
special kind of thing, I think. So I don't think
it was made necessarily to make money but more
to facilitate the brand of Deadpool. I wish
they weren't doing it, I hate them. But yeah,
post your answer to our Instagram, Twitter,
Facebook, or email us at dyna and we will pick
our favorite answer and draw that person a dynamic
dual no prize that we'll post to social media.
Moving on from Aquaman into Spider-Man, we got
the official second trailer for Spider-Man
into the Spider-Verse. And I think this is the
best trailer for this movie by far. They've
all been really impressive. But this one was
a great way to sell the movie to general audiences
who weren't still quite clear on what the concept
is. Because it's Peter Parker that introduces
the film and he kind of gives us narration.
and you get short clips of animated scenes
that resemble the Sam Raimi films where he's
talking about like, you know who I am, I've
saved the world, you know, and we see him stopping
the train from Spider-Man 2 and just like the
car through the window. Yeah, it's very familiar
and I think that's a great lead in to what
is going to be a more unfamiliar universe for
most moviegoers. It seems kind of like a Deadpool
version of Spider-Man and that like he's self-aware.
He knows he's a comic book, you know, like
he did a Christmas album. Yeah, and the comic
book and he has a cereal and a so-so popsicle.
That was hilarious because I've had that popsicle
and that's the one with like the gum eyes that
are on it. They have other Marvel versions of
it, but yeah, that was a shitty looking popsicle.
It looked like it was photographed on like a
plastic plate or something. It's funny. But
yeah, it transitions from there into the Miles
Morales Ultimate Universe and we get a rehash
of the scene where he tells his dad, I love
you, which pays off later on in this trailer
where He tells his dad he loves him again while
in the Spider-Man costume. Right, and the dad's
like, what? Wait, what? It looks like the Kingpin
and some other supervillains are trying to
open a dimensional gateway, and that's what
brings Spider-Man through to this world. So
that was the Kingpin. Yes. And it's voiced by
Leif Schreiber. Oh, that's cool. Yeah. It's
a pretty good Kingpin voice, I think. I like
the character design on all these guys, but
he looks particularly menacing here. But Kingpin
does. He does. He does. And so Spider-Man comes
into the Ultimate Universe and basically tells
Miles, like, I'm from this normal universe
and you're from this like weird dinky universe
using french fries as metaphors. But he trains
Miles on how to be Spider-Man. And in the process,
we introduced to all these other characters
that are going to be in the movie. They're pretty
cool at the introductions. Yeah, I like the
introductions. Gwen Stacy with like the drums,
I was like, yeah, it was like really getting
into the trailer. Yeah, we've seen her in those
Aspen trees before, but yeah, like. Her universe
is very pink. She's a musician in her universe.
She plays the drums. She's in a band. This
is the universe where Gwen Stacy was bit by
the radioactive spider instead of Peter Parker.
We also get introductions to Spider-Man War
voiced by Nick Cage. It's a really quick introduction.
Yeah, it's a really quick introduction. It looks
pretty cool though. And we also see Spider
who is Penny Parker who controls the spider
robot. So that's pretty cool. I wasn't expecting
to see her, but her art style, the art style
in each of these characters. is pretty spot
on for the universe that they come from. Yeah.
Like Penny Parker, she looks like an anime
character. Right, right. And Peter Parker looks
like a Looney Tunes character. He looks almost
exactly like Porky Pig. And John Mulaney's voice
is just fantastic. It's fantastic, it's great,
yeah. I like how Peter Parker's like, this can't
get any weirder. And he's like, it can get
weirder. I have no idea why his hand is wet
though, or his body is wet. Right. After that
we get... Just kinda like quick flashes about
what the rest of the movie is about. It looks
like Kingpin is teaming up with enemies like
Tombstone and the Scorpion to fight the Spider-Man.
It's a different take on Scorpion. Is that like
the ultimate version? Yeah, it is. Green Goblin's
in it too and it's the ultimate version of him
as well. We see Prowler as well, I think. Yeah,
Prowler. All great designs, I think. I still
just love the animation of this whole thing.
Is it like a little... choppy again so it looks
like almost like it's stop motion or something
like that. Yeah, lower frame rate. Right, exactly.
It brings a lot of charm to it. Yeah, definitely.
The last thing is Miles and Peter and Spider-Man
Noir and Peter Porker and all those guys, they're
I guess hiding in Miles' room where Gonky is,
or Gonk, I don't know how to pronounce his
name, but it's his best friend and he's reading
a Spider-Man comic book it looks like and they're
trying to remain hidden by sticking to the walls
as like a singular spider. Right. Spider-Hem
blows the cover by saying, do animals talk in
this universe? Cause I don't want to freak
him out. That was hilarious. It was pretty good.
I really liked that joke. And all, every time
I see new marketing for this movie, I get more
and more excited for it. Especially that final
shot where like Miles Morales takes that opening
scene and really makes it his own. Where Peter
Parker was standing on that gargoyle looking
over New York City. This time it's Miles Morales
and he kind of stamps his own mark on it. Yeah,
he's literally putting his own mark on it.
Yeah, it's- I mean, it's vandalism, but it's
still badass. It's a bumper sticker. No one's-
who's gonna complain? No one's gonna see it.
I've been more excited for this than like any
other Marvel movie, I think, in a really long
time. Really? Yeah, I don't know why. Just
because of its artistic style? I think so. Yeah,
it's really cool. It's certainly more styled
than other animated Marvel and DC films that
have come out recently, such as like Lego Batman.
Oh, yeah. Or Teen Titans Go or something like
that. Yeah. So in other news, Rosie Perez has
been cast as Renee Montoya in the Birds of Prey
film, which in one sense is kind of perfect
casting. She's a little bit older. She is. That's
the other sense. It was a definite surprise
to me. I thought they would go for someone younger,
for someone who, you know, could carry a franchise
for many years to come. Right. Well, in the
comics, the question is... Victor Sage and
he is the mentor to Renee Montoya who comes
the second question. So it looks like in this
Birds of Prey movie, they're kind of swapping
that in that it seems like Renee Montoya is
going to be the mentor character to perhaps
some of these younger super heroines. I don't
know honestly, if that's the case. She may just
be a cop. She may just be a Gotham city police
officer, which I could totally see her selling,
you know? Oh, so you don't think we'll see
her as the question? I'm starting to have doubts
because of this casting. If it was a younger
casting, I think maybe you would have, you know,
like a pretty solid journey from her being
a detective to being the question. But I think
this may be a smaller role than I initially
thought. OK. Yeah. Because, you know, they need
some kind of face for the police force in Gotham
City in general. So why not have it be Renee
Montoya? That makes the question may not factor
into this at all. Which is kind of a shame.
I do like the character of the question. Yeah.
I mean, it still leaves room for Victor Sage
to be the question, but it kind of maybe puts
the character of René Montoya in a position
in the cinematic realm, at least of never being,
never being the question. Yeah. It leaves both
options open-ended. Yeah. Yeah, it does. You
know, I remember her from films like Do the
Right Thing, White Men Can't Jump. I don't
think I ever saw that full movie. She was in
Planetable Express. It was the last thing I
saw. She was. Yeah. She was a cop in that, wasn't
she? Yeah, she was. Yeah. Maybe that's what
I'm thinking. She's going to be a pretty badass
detective. But yeah, again, it was it was just
a big surprise to me. I wasn't quite sure how
I felt about it initially, but quite the diverse
cast that they have going here now. Yeah, for
sure. For sure. She's of course joining Journey
Smollett Bell and Mary Elizabeth Winstead. and
Margot Robbie in the film. We don't know who
is going to play Black Mask yet. And we don't
know who's going to play Cassandra Cain yet.
That'll be interesting. Yeah. Yeah, definitely.
I'm looking forward to seeing what else they
could do with this. I don't have 100% confidence
in the project yet, I would say. But, you know,
I'm just waiting for more information. We have
rumors of what the story is going to be. And
that sounds like a bad-ass story. Right. But
hopefully Cathy Young can pull it off, the
director. Right, right. Alright, moving on to
the first trailers for Daredevil Season 3.
They're a little bit late coming considering
that the third season actually debuts in just
like a week actually. Right. Yeah. But I think
that's why they gave us two right away. We
got two Daredevil Season 3 trailers. The first
one is more about Matt Murdock and we see him
kind of out from under the rubble that he was
stuck under from the Defenders television show.
Yeah. Can you believe that it's actually been
that long since we've had a Daredevil season?
Yeah, since like last year. Since season two,
no, two years ago. What? Since season two,
we've had two seasons of Luke Cage, two Iron
Fist seasons, a Defenders and a Jessica Jones.
That's true. Yeah, it's been a while. But it's
good to have him back, especially with the
Kingpin back. Heck yeah. In this trailer, we
see that Kingpin strikes a deal and he's able
to get released on parole, it looks like, from
prison. And he's out to seek revenge against
Matt Murdock and just... make his life a living
hell. So it seems to be at least partially
adapting the Born Again storyline in which the
Kingpin knows Daredevil's secret identity and
you can listen to more about that in our Daredevil
versus Nightwing dual episode that we did a
few months ago. And I'm not missing anything
right? Like Kingpin doesn't currently know
Matt Murdock's identity. Like he'll learn it
in this season. Well at the end of Daredevil
season two it seemed like he was this close
to figuring it all out. He was following a
paper trail. that would have revealed that Matt
Murdock was Daredevil. Cause that was his kind
of project while he was in prison, just passing
time, was trying to figure out who this guy
is. The action looks spectacular in this trailer.
It looks like we have another hallway fight
this time that takes place in the prison. And
I heard that it's just amazing from people
who have seen the first few episodes of the
show so far. Both trailers are really intense.
Yeah, they are. Really intense. Matt's back
to wearing his black outfit from the initial
season one. I think the reason he's wearing
the black costume is because as we see at the
end of this trailer, there's a new guy who's
wearing the Daredevil costume and he's being
a villain basically. So I think in order to
distinguish himself from that evil Daredevil,
Matt has taken on his old costume so that he
doesn't get confused by the authorities or
from other people. I don't know if that's the
case because he's wearing his black costume
before he even meets the new Daredevil. But
we don't necessarily know the chronology of
events here. It could be that this new Daredevil
has been Daredevil for quite some time at this
point. True, maybe. So it is cool though, I
mean, they're heavily implying that this new
Daredevil is Bullseye, just the way he's throwing
things and how accurate he is at throwing and
marksmanship and stuff like that. And he has
a gun at the very end of the trailer. It's
kind of like a callback to like the famous Daredevil
comic book cover where he's like pointing a
gun. Oh, right. Yeah. It was like no more Mr.
Nice Guy or something like that. Something
like that. Yeah. Part of Frank Miller's run.
It is very reminiscent of that. And Wilson
Bethel looks pretty cool in the mask, I think.
At one point, he was in the running to play
Captain America. He was like in the top three
contenders to play Captain America. Oh, really?
Oh, I'm still glad that Chris Evans got the
role because he's just he's just perfect as
Cap. It's nice to also see that Wilson Bethel
still got a chance to play in the Marvel universe.
Yeah. because he seems like a pretty badass
actor, especially in the next trailer that
we get, where we get to see more regarding the
character of who they're calling Agent Poindexter.
This is Bullseye, right? It is. I don't remember
his name being Poindexter in our Bullseye vs.
Deadshot episode. Yeah, his name was Lester.
Yeah. They've never really revealed his name,
so I'm wondering if the show is kind of taking
liberty with that, or they're actually giving
him a name. I guess there's enough mystery around
the character where they can do something like
that successfully. Right. Like maybe his name
is Lester Poindexter or Dexter Lester or something
like that. That'd be a weird name. But yeah.
And, and the end, it could turn out to all
be an alias or something like that. So one never
knows, but Kingpin is impressed with his skills
as a corrupt FBI agent and hires him essentially
to impersonate Daredevil. Yeah. The guy looks
intense. Uh, he has a very intense look to him.
His, his bone structure is like freaking gaunt
as hell. Those are some sharp features, but
his voice is pretty spot on into what I would
imagine Bullseye's voice would be as well. And
just the things that he does where he's like
shooting guys from far distances, nailing him
with the headshot and you know throwing knives
into chest and stuff like that. He looks pretty
badass. Bullseye is pretty unstable. He's always
been like a scary kind of villain. And that
he's just like unpredictable and just so darn...
Talented. Efficient and talented. Yeah. I'm
excited for this season. I like one of the
later shots where it looks like... Bullseye
is about to kill a guy by throwing a billy
club through his head and at the very last moment
Matt Murdock is able to catch it right before
it hits the guy's face. Yeah, that was pretty
cool. Yeah So really looking forward to this
season. I don't have to wait long for it. Thank
goodness comes out October 19th So yeah, we'll
definitely have the review up by the end of
this month when we binge all those episodes
Yeah, yeah, it's coming up soon moving on to
DC television We got our final trailer the
official team up trailer for Titans which comes
out also this month I think next week actually.
Oh really? Yeah, yeah. This debuted at New York
Comic Con. It's not a long trailer. It's less
than two minutes long. It's my favorite trailer
so far that they've released. It's because
of the song, isn't it? It's not just because
of that cool cover song by Marilyn Manson of
Cry Little Sister. It was the Lost Boys song.
Yeah, the song from the Lost Boys movie. It's
such a great cover and it fits so well with
the visuals that we're seeing on the trailer.
Yeah. But it also does a great job with showcasing
each. Superheroes powers. I think in a way
that the previous trailers didn't they feel
more like their respective characters in this
than they have at any Previous point in the
marketing. Yeah, this probably is also my favorite
trailer better than like last week's Netflix
trailer It makes me want to be Robin and have
a collapsible bow staff that I can use to just
like point outward and then like have it Extend
and hit two guys on the sides of me. It's just
so cool They are totally selling Robin like
in a way that no live-action Robin. I mean,
there's only been one I guess Yeah Yeah, he's
such a badass in this. He looks like he's a
badass. Even Beast Boy is impressed. He's like,
it's Robin. Yeah, yeah. His reaction was my
reaction. Yeah, it was a great moment. But,
you know, it sets up the story. It's definitely
like a Rosemary's baby kind of thing. Raven's
the daughter of Trigon and, you know, this cult
is trying to bring him back through her. Right.
We can see her use her powers in this too. She
kind of like extends her soul self out of her
body. Yeah. Attacks on people with it. It doesn't
look. quite like I thought it would. It doesn't
look like a raven or anything. It looks like
a swarm of ravens. Yeah, they kind of form
like a tentacle kind of thing. Yeah, yeah, I
don't know if I'm the biggest fan. You know,
this has been getting good reviews, but they're
also saying like, it's not really the Titans
that people know. They're saying the acting
is really good and the story grows on you for
sure. So I'm glad that it's getting good reviews
because. These trailers don't inspire the highest
degree of confidence when it comes to faithful
interpretations of the characters Uh-huh, but
I'm still definitely gonna watch it for sure.
We see Beast Boy turn into a tiger We see Starfire
shoot her fire out Yeah Beast Boy like his introduction
is like Raven stumbling in on him when he's
like all bloody at the mouth and stuff like
that It's like the cult has him maybe trapped
in the same place that she's trapped in I don't
know and she rescues him and then it also looks
like Starfire rescues Raven as well Yeah, and
then they meet Robin and he's just being a
badass taking fools out in the dark and shadow
just being really cool What do you think of
the news that we heard that the reason that
robin is like branching away from batman in
this series is Because he disagrees with batman's
methodology in that he kills people in this
universe Do you think that's true? Do you think
it's been misinterpreted? I don't know I wouldn't
be surprised if that's the case judging on how
dark this is. Uh-huh. I'm not happy about it
But I don't know, it doesn't seem like Batman
will be that big of a character in this show.
So, I don't know. Hopefully they don't. Wait,
fuck it up DC. I know. If they did that. If
they did that. Apparently they didn't fuck it
up though, because I keep hearing good things
about it. There's some fascinating things in
this trailer, like this guy just covered in
blood and like the cult people like blinking
lights in their head. It's pretty crazy. It
looks pretty crazy. And of course we get that
Avengers team up shot at the end where all
of them are in frame and like, you know, Beast
Boy is a tiger and... Raven is in her white
form. Yeah. I'm looking forward to next week
just to get a taste of it. Yeah Too bad. It
doesn't all come out at one time. We did get
the release schedule for the DC Universe shows
Yes. Yep, and it looks like we're actually getting
Doom Patrol earlier than we thought we would.
Yeah, it's coming out next year Brendan Fraser
was on stage and he made a goof. He was like,
oh, yeah, it's coming out mid-december. That's
that's not the case That's when Young Justice
comes out. Yes. Yeah, and then Doom Patrol comes
after that, right? Another one of the shows
for DC Universe that we got a sneak peek at
was Harley Quinn. That's coming out next December.
Right, like more than a year from now. That's
insane. I'm surprised they gave us our first
look so early. But along with the first look
came the news that Kelly Cuoco of The Big Bang
Theory is voicing Harley Quinn. Now when I first
saw the sneak peek, which starts off in Arkham
Asylum, actually it stays there. It's just her
talking to the camera in her prison cell with
Poison Ivy. Yeah, breaking the fourth wall.
Yeah, I went to the audience. I wasn't exactly
thrilled with the voice initially until like,
I don't know, halfway through when she's talking
about extremely gratuitous violence. Then I'm
like, this is a pretty good voice to me. She
sold me on you're going to piss yourself. It
is a funny trailer. I watched it like 50 times
that I was just laughing every time. And my
wife was like, what are you watching? So I
had to show her. But yeah, I like the animation
style. I like the humor, I like the voice work,
Lake Bell as Poison Ivy is fantastic. And then
we even get a Batman cameo. And a dig at Deadpool.
Nice Marvel dig right in there. Ugh. Yeah, I
hated that. Because as we all know, Deadpool
was to get an animated series as well, and it
was supposed to be produced, and I think starring
Donald Glover as Wade Wilson, and it fell through
the cracks due to creative differences, allegedly.
Right. But... Yeah, this looks good. I think
I do like Kaley Cuoco's voice It's surprising
because her big bang theory cast mates Melissa
Rush I think is how you pronounce her name.
She was also Harley Quinn Yeah, in the Harley
and Batman movie that came out earlier this
year. I think yeah, yeah I didn't see the film.
I saw the trailer though. Honestly. I didn't
really care for the voice. I like this one much
more Yeah, I wonder if they were competing
for this role of Harley Quinn in this television
show I wouldn't be surprised, you know, along
with Tara Strong and probably all the other
voices wanted this role. But I'm kind of glad
it went to Kelly Cuoco because she does have
some nerd cred, some geek cred in there. A
little bit. The cast, honestly, for this show,
I don't know if you've seen the cast list,
it's fantastic. Really? It has, you know, Lake
Bell has Jason Alexander from Seinfeld. It's
just so many voices. It's gonna be great. We
don't know who everyone is gonna play yet.
Uh. But the cast is phenomenal. And now we just
have to wait a year to see it. A whole freaking
year. Yay. I guess they also give a dig to DC
as well when they're talking about like, shouldn't
it be like dark and bleak and depressing like
other DC stuff? Yeah. I just love Harley's
reaction. She's like, that is a wonderful way
to make movies and television shows, but not
my show. Just it's, there's so many like very
diplomatic kind of answer. There's a great
energy to Kelly Cuoco's voice. And you know,
she could hit the highs and she hits like more
serious notes. More serious notes. She does
a great job. Yeah. And like the logo is great
and she comments on that and they're like, ooh,
this logo. Yeah. Poison Ivy is like, they're
going to hate it. It's very Suicide Squad, that
logo, you know, very like neon blue and pink.
Yeah, it is. It is. Yeah. But I think that brings
us to the end of the news. Let's go ahead and
get into our review of the Venom film. Let's
do it.
Alright, so Venom, quite the polarizing movie
I've found. I think we're gonna have listeners
who are gonna hate this movie, I think we're
gonna have listeners that absolutely love this
movie, so what I don't want to have happen is
you guys hate us for thinking that the movie
was, you know, mostly good. Is there anyone
who really loves this movie though? Oh yeah,
oh yeah. Really? Yeah, there are people out
there who really love this movie. Because,
you know, it does have a lot going for it. You
know, despite everything that we say regarding
the movie's flaws, which there are a lot, and
we'll get into that, Venom surpasses a lot
of that negativity through what it does really
well, and that is, you know, the relationship
between Venom and Eddie, and the characterization
of Venom. I thought the film absolutely nailed
the Venom character, especially in regards to
the action, which, you know, is the primary
appeal of any superhero movie. As moviegoers
and comic fans, we want to see these characters'
personalities depicted accurately, and marvel
at the spectacle of their powers. And I think
in that regard, I think this movie succeeded.
And just a forewarning to those who haven't
seen the film, this is gonna be a spoiler review.
So if you haven't seen the film yet, go ahead
and turn the podcast off now. Don't listen to
the review. Maybe go see the film if you want
to, if you don't want to. I think I would recommend
it. I would totally recommend it. Go see it.
What are you doing? If you don't want to, what
are you doing? Yeah, don't listen to what everyone
else is saying. Go see it for yourself, because
you might enjoy it. The reaction that I get
most often that I've heard is a lot better than
I thought it was meant to be. Yeah, for sure.
I think almost everybody I talked to has said
that. So whatever you're thinking it's gonna
be if you haven't seen it, it's gonna be better
than that. Was it just the Lady Gaga fans who
were like telling everyone it was just gonna
be like the worst piece of shit ever? No, there
were legit reviewers who were coming down on
this movie pretty hard, and you know, overall,
the film got like a 30% on Rotten Tomatoes,
which is much lower than what it should have
gotten. Yeah, I agree. But as you know, sometimes
popular culture goes to a movie with somewhat
of an agenda. I think a lot of people were turned
off by the trailers for this film and therefore
kind of wanted to see it fail. Maybe also because
it wasn't part of the Spider-Man universe.
It has nothing to do with Spider-Man. So there
are reasons for people to wanna see this movie
not do well, but it has been doing well. It
broke box office records, made over 80 million,
I think, if the numbers came in correctly. and
it was like over 200 million worldwide, I believe,
like 213 or something. Oh, definitely. I mean,
it did better than Ant-Man and the Wasp. It's
going to get a sequel. And I think the best
thing that could be said about this film is
that knowing that it's gonna get a sequel now,
I'm super excited for that. Yeah, it's a good
starting point. It's a good launching pad. For
the franchise. Yeah, yeah, definitely. What
did you think of the action and the spectacle?
I don't know if I would agree that the action
was that great. To me, it's just like one step
above Transformers. Like the two big action
scenes, like the one in the lobby, you know,
it was full of smoke. It was kind of hard to
see what was going on. And then the other one,
you know, the final fight, Venom and Riot looked
so similar. And I was afraid this was going
to happen in the trailers, but, you know, it's
just so much CG. It just makes my eyes bleed.
That being said, like it was passable. It wasn't
the worst action I've ever seen. It was just
passable. I would have to disagree in that
I... Don't think I was ever confused by the
action. I found it easy to follow in both of
those major scenes. And I thought it was a highlight
of the film. I thought they were really well
done. The animation was on point, I think, for
the character and how he moved and how his
liquid biomass worked and everything like that.
There was one cool action scene that I thought
that worked. And that was, you know, before
he emerged fully as Venom in Eddie Brock's
apartment, and he was taking out the thugs.
I thought that was a cool action scene. Just
seeing the different ways he was using the Simba.
Like from there all the way to the motorcycle.
It was extremely versatile. Yeah, I was like,
oh I want a Symbiote, give me one. It could
do a lot of different things for sure. Venom
was so cool. I think one of the problems with
the movie was that it did take half of the film's
runtime to actually see the Venom character
fully realized, which is pretty typical of origin
story films. That's one of the problems with
origin films is that you have to kind of get
to know the character behind the mask before
you care about the hero wearing it. And I guess
that's not a problem so much as it's kind of
just old at this point. We've had so many superhero
films throughout these past decades that the
origin stories are pretty formulaic. You have
this guy who discovers this incredible power,
you know, learns how to use the power and then
fights the bad guy. They find a good way to
circumvent that lately in the Marvel cinematic
universe with both Spider-Man and Black Panther,
and that they established their characters in
other films before giving them their solo films.
So by the time they get their solo films, the
characters already established. Yeah. But yeah,
in this case, that wasn't what happened. And
it was 45 minutes of just Eddie Brock with
no venom. But that's not necessarily even a
bad thing too, because I definitely think that
Tom Hardy gave a good performance here. Oh,
definitely. I think it was a good performance.
I found it intriguing. I'm not 100%, but I think.
It was a good performance. Everything that
you saw there, I guarantee you was intentional.
You know, I read a lot of people saying that
they laughed at many parts. of this movie that
were perhaps unintentionally hilarious. But
I don't understand how you can question if the
film's attempts at humor were intentional or
not because the film obviously does not take
itself 100% seriously. I found it to be very
self-aware. It's trying to, you know, kind of
send up the typical conventions of modern superhero
films with its darker, unconventional subject
matter. And it kind of takes a sort of schlocky
monster movie tone in some parts. But I mean,
is there any doubt that this was on purpose,
given the director is Ruben Fleischer, who directed
Zombieland after all, which was a send up of
zombie films. Everyone who's questioning whether
or not they should laugh, the answer is yes.
It's supposed to be a dark comedy mixed in with
a superhero action film. There was a lot of
comedy in it, more than I thought there was
gonna be. And sometimes it worked, sometimes
it didn't, sometimes I kinda felt like it was
a little juvenile, like when Venom calls Eddie
Brock a pussy. I thought that was funny. No
one in my theater laughed. Really? No one.
I've seen the movie twice now and I think both
times everyone in the theater chuckled at it.
Really? I saw it with a pretty small crowd.
Like I saw it like on a Sunday afternoon. Okay.
There weren't many people in the screening I
saw. So. The tone of the film, you know, it
has humor. It is a little bit two dimensional
and comic booky because of that monster movie
tone. And you compare that to the more three-dimensional
fleshed out characters that we've been growing
accustomed to seeing in the Marvel films, it
felt kind of out of its time. Because the film
didn't take itself so seriously, it did somewhat
feel like some of the superhero films from
the early part of the century, like Blade II.
And that was another good film, also dark,
also didn't take itself too seriously. I agree.
You know, prior to Christopher Nolan's The
Dark Knight, a lot of studios just didn't know
how to tackle the subject matter. in a credible
manner and that was likely the main setback
here with this movie I think and why some people
even compared it to like Catwoman and Daredevil
and things like that. Yeah I mean I don't really
get those comparisons again. To me that's really
harsh actually, especially the Catwoman one.
But uh have they not seen Catwoman recently
because that movie is a fucking abomination.
It is it is freaking Horocious. Is that a word
Horocious? Sure you just made a word that's-
No. You don't want to? I don't want to. OK.
It is fucking atrocious. Yeah. I think the
reason Venom didn't come across like those other
films so much to me with its tone and everything
is because with a character like Venom, you
can actually get away with that easier, that
tone, because of the somewhat over the top nature
of the character. You know, he's an outer space
alien creature with a grossly exaggerated grin
full of shark like teeth that bite people's
heads off, you know. It's a long ways away from
a super soldier fighting Hitler in World War
II. Yeah. I think what people want, what I certainly
wanted was a certain amount of tongue-in-cheek
element to the story to keep it from being a
straight-up horror film. Though, you know,
a horror film could have been interesting too.
But in the comics, some of my favorite Venom
moments are when he's acting weird or sweet,
or something other than straight-up monstrous.
You know, it's those quirky moments that add
depth to him. He's always been a different
sort of Klyntar alien in the comics than, you
know, his alien brethren. And I think they
captured that really well here. They said he
was a loser. Right, he admitted to being a
loser. Yeah, which was interesting. I'm somewhat
of a loser on my planet. One of my favorite
memories of reading Venom in the comics were
during his team up with Spider-Man when they
first went up against Carnage. And while Venom
was certainly sinister in that story, where
he's constantly telling Carnage that he's gonna
kill him and things like that. There was a
nice moment where they were swinging toward
Madison Square Garden where Carnage was and
Spider-Man's kind of internalizing how weird
it is to be teaming up with Venom. And meanwhile,
Venom is singing Strangers in the Night. It's
just hilarious. That's kind of like the quirkiness
of the character. Those are my favorite moments
with him, I think. Yeah, I wasn't, like I'd
never read a comic with Venom, I don't think,
maybe I have. I don't remember, but those moments,
you know, where he's like telling Eddie Brock
to like say you're sorry and stuff like that,
it definitely did sort of like challenge my
expectations of the character. When I think
of Venom, I do think of it as just, you know,
like this bad ass monster, not as someone who's
kind of almost goofy in a way. Right, right.
Love that guy, love that character. I think
that the dark humor was well balanced with the
sci-fi action. I think overall the film was
pretty well balanced and palatable for a mainstream
audience. Though if it were rated R and it
showed Venom actually eating his enemies and
had more adult language and you know, stuff
in the vein of Deadpool, it might've actually
been a better film. I agree. But possibly only
marginally so, I think. I'm surprised you can't
show someone biting someone else's head off
in a PG-13 film. I was like, what? As long as
you don't show blood, right? I mean, dumb.
But they were so subtle about it here that I
wasn't even 100% sure. during those moments
if their heads were actually bitten off. It
was like, did that just happen? Yeah. They
really move the camera away from it quick. But
in the end, I think I'd rather sacrifice the
gore and keep the potential of a Venom Spider-Man
team up. True. It may be wishful thinking,
but it's not an impossibility. They're on opposite
sides of the country, I mean. Right. And my
guess is that maybe in a sequel to Venom, he's
gonna fight Carnage, and maybe Carnage is going
to go like across the country on a killing spree.
Venom is gonna chase him to New York because
he feels responsible being that carnage is his
offspring. And maybe like have a Spider-Man
team up kind of moment where at one point maybe
Eddie is knocked unconscious and the symbiote
has to attach itself to Spider-Man for a while.
I mean, that might be the best adaptation of
symbiote Spidey that we get within this universe,
within this franchise. Yeah. And you know,
given how they treated the source material here,
I mean, if that's the best that we could get,
then I'll take it because I think we have a
great Realization of the character of venom
within this film one that could be definitely
carried forward in future films I think they
were trying to go for something marvelous, and
that's why they didn't go the rated-r route
Well, I don't think the film itself was marvelous
at all. I think it was an attempt to be marvelous
I don't think it was you don't think no. I think
it was a purposeful attempt to not be like
Marvel I think the director has stated as such
hmm actually And I think he did a good job
of making the tone dark and edgy But also just
on the borderline of possibly being able to
be included in the mainstream Marvel Cinematic
Universe. Or the Spider-Man universe. Sony's
Spider-Man, whatever the hell it's called. I
think what primarily didn't work with this
movie goes back to the self-aware tone of the
film. Some of the dialogue and the character
reactions and the characters themselves weren't
real feeling. Some of the acting. Especially
Carlton Drake, the cardboard cutout villain.
or Anne, the cardboard cutout ex-girlfriend.
I think the only one that actually felt real
here was Eddie Brock, and maybe actually Jenny
Slade's character, Dr. Skirth, I think she felt
nuanced enough to be real as well. Yeah, it
was sad when she died. Yeah, but yeah, let's
go into the character breakdown, and we'll
start off with Eddie Brock. Eddie Brock and
Venom are gonna be separate in this character
breakdown, because they were very separate characters
in the film. As far as Eddie Brock goes, I
think Tom Hardy's performance was intriguing
as I said before. I think he elevated the material
he was given by injecting just a metric ton
of nuance, which made him feel believable.
And it was only because of Brock's performance
that I believed his relationship with Anne,
especially in the scene when he visited her
apartment and met her new boyfriend. That felt
real. That was a good scene. She was like, why
are you here, Eddie? Because I miss you. It
wasn't too long ago that we were going to get
married. I was wondering if we might find our
way back to that. That line, I thought, almost
belonged in a different movie. It was the only
time that I thought that these two actually
had viable chemistry and a viable relationship
at one point. That was one of my more favorite
Eddie Brock character scenes. I mean, the first
half of this film, when they're setting up the
peril of Eddie Brock and just like how his
choices have consequences and stuff like that
and everything that stemmed from that. I thought
this was all fantastic setup. Yeah, it really
was. In a way, like I think a lot of my problems
don't really come about until he gets the symbiote.
Because before that, it was a compelling film.
Eddie Brock was a compelling character. Yeah,
I think because of Tom Hardy's performance.
He's such a great actor, he really makes you
empathize with him. And on top of that, he's
fun to watch. I thought his voice was gonna
be grating based on the trailers, but I didn't
mind it. He sells his voices for sure. Yeah.
Eddie Brock's character arc was strange though.
Like he started out on top with his investigative
reports on the Eddie Brock show. He started
out giving a shit about his fellow man. You
know, standing up for others seemed to be his
life's purpose because he's a good guy, you
know? But then he stooped low to steal a document
from his girlfriend to support his agenda against
Carlton Drake, then hit rock bottom losing
his job, his relationship, and his home. which
somehow caused him to forgo his life's purpose
and be done with giving a shit about his fellow
man. Which is what he explicitly told Dr. Skirth.
And it was weird because it seemed like he resented
society for his own fuck-ups. Yeah. Yeah, absolutely.
I kind of wish they would have set up Carlton
Drake as more of a villain before Eddie was
saying how much he didn't like him. Right. Because
by that moment I was like, well, why? He seems
like not a horrible guy. Even in the interview,
like, Eddie Brock was the one being the asshole.
You know? Right. I didn't quite understand that.
And, but you're right. He turned his back on
society for, for his poor choice. And that was
hard to relate to. Yeah. So he's, you know,
he's a flawed character, which also makes him
feel real. But yeah, again, hard to relate
to. But on the Golden Gate bridge, which was
a fantastic scene where it almost seems like
he's contemplating suicide, which is in the
comics. Oh, really? Yeah. That's why he went
to the church was to ask for forgiveness for
what he was about to do, and that's where he
got the symbiote in the comics at the church.
But yeah, it was a great scene. It's where
he had his change of heart and decides to investigate
the Life Foundation and help others after all.
I think it would have been a little bit more
helpful if the movie had been more clear with
how one makes the leap from taking down villains
with investigative journalism to taking down
villains with vigilanteism. Because I wasn't
sure if he necessarily showed vigilante tendencies
prior to getting the symbiote. Right. No, I
mean, he didn't. He let that one guy extort
the bodega owner. Right, yeah. That would have
been an interesting exploration even if briefly,
but after his change of heart on the bridge,
at that point, there wasn't much more character
growth for Eddie Brock and the growth really
shifted at that point to the symbiote Venom.
Yeah. So let's talk about Venom, who was voiced
by Tom Hardy. The character of Venom himself
is really what saves this film and makes it
as fun and enjoyable as it is. Well, it's what
you went to see, you know, he's the titular
character. Yeah, I mean, it's crazy how much
joy I get. out of just seeing that huge ass
grin. And the voice, Tom Hardy nailed it. And
though he was a blast to watch, it was hard
to understand Venom's motivations, I think.
Because let's follow his arc. So first Venom
wants to get Drake's rocket, just like Riot,
to reconnect with his brethren on the comet
and invade Earth. Then all of a sudden, yeah,
at some point, Venom rejects the idea and decides
he's instead going to live on Earth because
he likes it here and because of Eddie. He says
that explicitly he made the decision because
of Eddie, but we don't know when that happened
or why that happened Yeah, other than you know,
he's like on my planet I'm kind of a loser and
that's kind of the most explanation we get
as to his change of heart, right? Which to me
like that was laughable. I was like what? Okay
Like I'd rather hang out with you here than
be with my loser siblings or whatever Yeah,
that was that was a loser with my siblings,
you know Yeah, that was a problem for me the
symbiotes like motivations We don't learn until
far down the road in this film. Like initially,
like the stakes of the film are that Eddie's
gonna die. But it's not until like the final
battle almost that it's like, hey, you know,
the symbiotes are going to bring back an entire
planet of symbiotes and take over our planet.
They're like, oh, too little too late. Maybe
not too little, but definitely a little bit
too late. Yeah. But overall with Venom, again,
he's the star of the show. The reason why I
get so much joy out of this movie and why I
liked it more than like say Ant-Man and the
Wasp or something like that is because of the
Eddie Brock Venom relationship. It's like a
buddy movie. It is, it absolutely is a buddy
movie. Yeah. One thing that confused me is like
the knowledge that Venom had like right off
the bat, like 60 gigahertz or something like
that. Or the 60 gigahertz frequency? Yeah.
60 megahertz frequency? I don't know. And it's
like, how long have you been on earth that
you like, you know, know words like that? I
guess just being inside of Eddie, but then.
But then he didn't know some things about Eddie
that he maybe should have known. Exactly. So
maybe he was just reading the wrong pages on
Eddie's brain or something like that. I don't
know. It's hard to know. Let's talk about Anne
Wayne played by Michelle Williams. I thought
she did a commendable job with the material
she was given. I think a lot of those lines
would have been a hard sell. Like, hospital,
right now, or Eddie, I think I just ate a guy's
head. Yeah. But despite her being an overall
like cliche girlfriend type, I thought she
was likeable. I didn't really care for the performance
honestly. Like at all. Really? Like at all.
I think she did a horrible job. What? She did
a horrible job. Really? Yeah. I don't know
about that. I liked it. Her reactions did not
seem believable in almost every way, I think.
Yeah, I would agree with that. I don't think
her actions were believable. I think most of
her reactions were kind of tug-and-cheek. I
think her performance was a little bit tongue-in-cheek.
Yeah, I agree. Yeah, that's what it felt like
for sure. Like she knew she was in this movie
that was beneath her or something like that.
I don't know. But I liked that. I don't know.
I guess it depends on what you enjoy as a moviegoer.
Like to me, I appreciated the subtle tongue-in-cheek
moments in this film. But, you know, if you
take your superhero movies super seriously.
then you may not enjoy that. And I do, I do.
I really like her turn as She-Venom. That was
something that I was not expecting to see in
this film. Is that from the comics? It is,
yeah. Anne has taken on the Venom symbiote several
times. And I kinda wanna see more of her, actually.
Is that weird? Like I remember seeing She-Venom
for the first time in the comics, and I was
like, whoa, that freaky ass monster has a nice
body. I learned something about myself today.
Oh jeez. She was super cool though. I liked
the voice that she had where she's like, hello
Eddie. And the kiss, that was, it was just such
a bizarre fucking moment. It was. It was awkward.
It was almost brilliant in its weirdness, I
think. Let's move on to Carlton Drake, played
by Riz Ahmed. I think I mentioned earlier that
I thought he was pretty cardboard cut out,
though I think Riz did the best he could given
the material like Michelle Williams. I think
he did a good acting job. Yeah. I think he did
a really good acting job. The character, he's
a little bland. Very, very, you know, God complex
character, generic God complex character, who
just kind of hates humanity for what it is and-
Or thinks he's above it. Yeah, yeah, absolutely.
He's supposed to be this unscrupulous, ambitious,
super logical villain, but without any nuance,
like Eddie Brock, he mainly just comes across
as super generic. So I mean, like he did have
those few interesting lines about being God
or something. but in the end it wasn't enough
to save him from being described as mostly bland.
Right. And he does make some weird choices
and if I was working for him, I'd be like, I'm
not working for this guy anymore. Jenny Slate
totally had the right idea. It's like, fuck
this guy, he's weird. Wouldn't want him as
a boss. So that's it for the characters. I don't
think there were any other standout characters
to talk about, but let's get into these highlights
from the film, the story highlights. So the
movie starts off with the rocket crash on earth
from the Life Foundation. Yeah. and it felt
very X-Files to me. Like I could've swore I
was watching an episode of the X-Files. I agree.
They had a nice little Easter egg in that first
scene though with J. Jonah Jameson's son. Really?
Yeah. Oh, he didn't make that connection. Yeah,
cause in the comics, he's an astronaut. And
actually, so what they did with this movie is
they took the animated series origin, where
in the 90s cartoon, Venom didn't come from the
secret wars event. He came down with John Jameson.
from space and that's what they did here. Yeah.
So while Venom's origin here is a radical departure
from the comics and I think a lot of people
maybe wanted to see the symbiote on Spider-Man
first, you know, it wasn't entirely unfaithful
to things that we've seen before that have
been praised such as the animated series. Right.
So that was kind of nice. Isn't his son like
a werewolf? Yeah, in the comics, John Jameson
is the wolf man or the man wolf, I forget what
they call him. But yeah, he's a werewolf and
he gets that ability from his visit to the
moon, which is kind of weird. From then, I don't
think there were too many highlights of the
film up until about the midpoints where we get
the apartment fight, which we talked briefly
about before. Really like the versatility that
was shown here and this is when Venom really
starts speaking to him. We get to know the character.
Eddie beats these dudes up. and Venom tells
them to pile their bodies in the corner and
bite their heads off and stuff. And it was
like, what the fuck did he just say? Exactly,
exactly. And then he jumps out the window and
we think that Eddie's gonna die, but the symbiote
saves him and swings him into this other building.
That was cool. And then they start shooting
at him, but Eddie's able to put up a shield.
Put up a shield, that was cool. You just start
seeing all these amazing moments in succession.
I think one highlight before the action scene,
if I may real quick. Yeah. was when he first
comes to his apartment after he's been infected
and he's just like eating chicken from the
trash can, he's just like feeling really terrible,
like you really feel how bad he feels. It was
like good camera work. Good acting too. Yeah,
really good acting. When he puked, I thought,
oh, I wonder if he actually puked. I know. I
don't know, maybe the sound effects, maybe
it was the lurch he did when he gagged, but
it looked like real puking. But no, when he
looked in the mirror and like Venom's eyes come
up for the first time, you just hear him scream.
That was like my scream as well. I was like,
ah! He just like falls onto the top. I thought
that was funny. It was funny and scary. It was
just a good moment. Yeah. After the apartment
fight scene, we go into the motorcycle chase,
which I thought was pretty cool. It was a little
bit reminiscent of the San Francisco chase scene
that we just saw in Ant-Man and the Wasp. Yeah.
But I maybe actually liked this one a little
bit more. I did, yeah. There were a lot of
different things that Symbiote was able to do.
He was able to push cars aside, he was able
to grab onto railings and jump over bridges
and move steering wheels of the enemy cars.
I think one of the coolest moments that he had
kind of reminded me of the 89 Batman, where
the Batmobile shot out this grappling hook that
latched onto a street pole and made him turn
a tight 90 degree turn, 180 degree turn. It
was a really tight turn, yeah. It was almost
the same thing, where the Symbiote latched out,
grabbed onto a street pole. and skid Eddie
Brock onto his side, but was protecting him
as like a cushion on the ground and then brought
him back up after he made the turn. That was
one of the more intriguing uses of the power
that I've never seen in the comics or anything
like that. But yeah, Venom can almost do anything
in that regard. He was a shield, he was offensive,
he was defensive. It was just such a cool power
set. It is really cool. One thing that really
bothered me during this scene though was just
how destructive the Like they just did not give
a fuck. No. Like they were blowing shit up
with these drones, which even then it's like,
those have gotta be expensive drones, right?
And also why you're trying to blow up the guy
who has the symbiote, right? Exactly. Are you
trying to kill your symbiote? They're like just
like plowing into cars and stuff. How are they
gonna explain that to the cops? I was thinking
that the whole time. Like when this finishes
and like the cops come for you, what are you
gonna say? Right. It's gonna be one hell of
an investigation. Exactly. I don't envy the
police officer that has to do the paperwork
for this. sure. But no, like, you know, when
it does end, we get the reveal of Venom, the
full body, like, envelopment. Yeah. It's really
cool. I thought that was really cool. And then
he bites the dude's head off. Yes. That was
great. Yeah. And right after that, you know,
he like swims to that, to that buoy. And that's
the first time we see like Venom's like head
come out and like just start talking to Eddie.
Yeah. Is that from the comics? Did you like
that? Yes. Yeah. He's done that in the comics
before. Okay. Um, yeah, he definitely has his
own face and he's spoken to him like that before.
I liked that scene. I especially like... some
of Venom's dialogue where Eddie was like, are
you gonna eat more people? And Venom was like,
most likely. I like that a lot. Such a great
character, especially in one of the later scenes
where Eddie goes to his old place of work, the
network, and he and Venom climb up the building.
And Venom gets to the top and it's just kind
of like this iconic image where he's looking
over San Francisco and like admiring the beauty
of the city and everything. And he's like,
it'll be a shame to see it all destroyed. And
Eddie's like, what? And then the plane flies
by and shocks the symbiote off of him. And like
never before in a movie have I ever felt so
much like I was falling as that scene right
now. That's like my worst nightmare. It was
like well shot. Like he's sliding down the side
of this building and he's pretty sure he's
going to die because he's afraid of heights
and everything like that. It was a good camera
angle. Just like you see the feet. It's almost
like a POV shot. You see his feet dangling
and it's just like the ground is just coming
up towards him and it's like, oh, shit. But
luckily he gets rescued. And then from there.
he goes into the lobby fight downstairs. Yeah.
And I really liked the effects there because,
you know, so far we've seen Venom a lot in
shadow and in darkness and things like that.
We got a few really good money shots here,
despite, you know, there being a lot of smoke
and stuff like that. But when like the strobe
effect would go off with the flashbangs and
you see him react to that. And even in the
thermal vision in the sniper's camera, I swear
that was Venom straight lifted off of the comic
book pages. I was so happy with that scene.
and how he was like so vicious, he was like
picking guys up, jumping in the air and like
spinning around and like throwing them away
and things like that. It was just, it was awesome.
Like leaping up onto the rafters and like ripping
off beams and throwing them at people. Yeah.
At that point I was like, I don't care what
happens with the rest of this movie, I'm definitely
satisfied with at least this moment. Hmm. It
reminded me kind of like almost like Batman,
like he was like a ninja, just like pulling
guys out of the smoke and stuff like that. Right.
Yeah, that was pretty cool. There's something
frightening about that. The attacker you can't
see. Right. So later on, you know, he goes
to the hospital and then and then he gets captured
by the Life Foundation and then he gets rescued
by she venom. I think we already spoke about
that. I really thought it was going to be the
dog in the forest, but I was really glad that
it was she venom because that was such a fantastic
Easter egg. I really like how protective venom
at that point gets of Anne where like she wants
to follow along and he's like, no, it's going
to get ugly. And Eddie's like, she can fight
ugly. And she's like, yeah, I can fight ugly.
And he was like, not today. And he like runs
off and she's like, that's bullshit. I thought
that was pretty funny. But also great character
moment. I don't know if that was funny. It was
funny. Why was Venom more concerned about her
than Eddie? I don't know, that's a good question.
Maybe because Eddie knows her better. And maybe
he didn't wanna do it alone or something. I
don't know. That is a good question, that's
valid. Let's go to the final fight. The setup
for the final fight was a little off, I think.
Like, can you just really throw together a last
minute rocket launch without a crew or anything
like that? Those things have to be like exactly
timed. Right. Because there's a ton of math
involved. Right, like is the Earth facing the
right direction for when you launch off? Are
you gonna be wasting fuel? Are you gonna be
heading toward the comet itself, right? Or
do you have enough fuel in case you need to
make a correction like that or something? It
was a little weird. But it was cool how Riot
just kind of like took out the entire mission
control with those giant... like blades. I don't
know, man. I'm sure one of those computers
was really important for the mission. Yeah.
You know, and uses one of those computers later
on to activate the PA system, which startles
the symbiotes later on during their fight.
And then she has that horrible line, which is
like, told you, I can fight ugly or something.
So the fight itself was so cool. It started
off on that bridge, connecting the launch pad
to the station and Venom's chasing riot on there.
And they have a fight where like Venom was
like, he has shit. you wouldn't believe or something
like that. Yeah, shit you've never seen before.
Yeah, and Wright really did. Like he busted
out some sweet ass moves that I've never really
imagined a symbiote could do. Like he had that
swinging mace, and like there was a one part
where he like shoved his spikes into the bridge
below them and was like popping them up, trying
to impale Venom. But Venom was like doing all
these crazy cool back flips and like swinging
off the bridge and back on and things like that.
Yeah. It was just such a cool fight scene between
those characters I thought. I really liked it.
Do you wish they would have gone with like
a different symbiote, like the blue one or the
yellow one? Yes, I do. While Riot did look
cool, you know, that kind of like silver, gray,
gunmetal finish kind of thing, I wish they
would have gone somebody who is more easily
discernible from Venom. Maybe somebody like
Scream, who actually was, I would say, the primary
member of those Life Foundation symbiotes,
I think. Yeah. She was like the head of that
group. Like the other four, they kind of actually,
they merged into one symbiote called Hybrid.
They were kind of a little bit expendable.
I think she had the unique look with the long
hair and the fact that she was yellow and stuff
like that. I think it would have been cool to
see her as the villain. Or at least have the
symbiote be yellow. Even if it wasn't Scream.
Even if it was still Riot or whatever. I don't
know. Just would have been cool. I think the
other two symbiotes that the Life Foundation
managed to capture, so they got four total.
So they got Venom. We know that. One of them
escaped, which was Riot. But the yellow one
and the blue one, I think that was Scream.
And the other one was Agony. Phage and Lasher
were nowhere to be seen. It would've been cool
to see them here too, especially since they
seemed so expendable. But back to the fight,
after they finally get to the actual rocket
and they're like trying to rip each other apart
and stuff like that, there's a weird moment
where Riot absorbs venom and they became like
one being for like a second before Anne was
able to separate them with the noise. Right.
But he had the same look later on too, so I
wasn't sure like if they were still combined
or not. I don't know, that part was kind of
confusing. Yeah, those like little tendrils
that were coming off his back. Yeah. So there
are two bodies in one body? I'm not sure how
the physics of that worked. I'm not sure how
the physics of venom works to begin with. So
because sometimes you see venom being ripped
apart and Eddie Brock's face is around like
venom's like chest area. And sometimes you see
venom's face being ripped off and Eddie Brock's
face is right beneath it. So it's hard to tell
exactly where Eddie Brock is inside of venom
at any given moment. I assume that when the
two merged, Eddie and Drake were like just
kind of like smashed up right against each other.
It's a little awkward. It's like, hey. But
the fight that the two had when the symbiotes
were off was pretty interesting. Like Eddie
Brock had this like weird martial arts moment
where he like slow motion spun around and punched
Drake right in the face. Yeah, there was a lot
of slow motion in this in this film. Yeah.
But I like the way that Venom ultimately defeated
Riot using the symbiotes weakness of fire,
you know? Yeah. He destroyed the rocket's fuel
tanks as it was flying up and the whole thing
exploded and nearly killed Venom himself. Do
you understand why Venom like told Anne earlier
like all of his weaknesses? That was weird.
That was awkward in the car. I think it was
more for the audience. There was a lot of like...
But also I think he liked Anne. He even stated
that much and that's why he told Eddie to get
in the car. I think he had a soft spot for
Anne. And it may have been grafted on from Eddie's
memories of her or something like that. Oh,
by that? That's a good explanation. So he was
like super vulnerable and honest with her basically.
Huh. And that takes us to one of the last highlights
of the movie. When they're talking on the steps,
I thought it was so fucking hilarious. when
all of a sudden Venom's voice pops back in
and he's like, look at her, she doesn't even
realize that we're going to get her back. He's
like, we love you, Anne. It was so great. Uh,
Venom playing Cupid is just awesome. But the
very final scene, the mid credit scene of the
movie is where we're introduced to Carnage
or Cletus Kasady being played by Woody Harrelson.
That scene felt a little bit off to me. It
was. It was bad. It was really bad. I don't
know if it was Harrelson's acting or if it
was his wig or if it was his dialogue. It was
probably a combination of all three. They were
trying to make it seem creepy, but it wasn't,
like at all. It was tongue-in-cheek. Maybe.
See, that I'm not sure on because Woody Harrelson
did look fucking bat shit crazy out of his
mind, but not entirely in a scary way. No. In
somewhat a funny way, I think. They could have
done a much better job like setting the atmosphere
for this. Uh-huh. Because it was almost comical
the way the guard was talking with Eddie. And
by the time you get to Cletus and he's like
writing Eddie's name in blood and it's just
like, you know, the things he's saying it's
do you want me to turn on the serial killer?
I could talk about like the Dada patterns of
arterial spray. Uh-huh. And just like, who wrote
this? I think they were going for silence the
lambs and they got more Suicide Squad than Silence
of the Lambs, I think. Oh, okay. Low blow,
wow. But that does it for the review. I think
we hit everything. All the story highlights,
talked about all the characters, and gave our
overall thoughts. I give this movie three and
a half stars. I liked it, it had its flaws,
but overall I think it had more going for it
than against it, because I came away from the
theater noting that I had a really good time.
I agree, yeah. I mean, I think that's a good
way of putting it. It did have more going for
it than against it. I definitely didn't hate
the film, but also wasn't, you know, like some
of the greater comic book films that we've kind
of become accustomed to recently. Yeah, not
even close. But is it as close to being as good
as a Venom film as you can get? Maybe. I agree
that if it was rated R, they had more language,
they had more violence, then it would have
been. And maybe if it took somewhat more of
a horror route, I think that would have been
a little bit more compelling. Yeah, for sure.
But for what we got, I had a blast. What's
your star rating? Also three and a half. All
right, that does it for the review. Go ahead
and let us know what you guys thought by reaching
out to us via social media on Facebook, Twitter,
or Instagram. We're on all those platforms and
you can find us there quickly by visiting dynamicduel.com.
Yeah, we have all of our links to our social
media accounts as well as a link to our merchandise
store, which we have various merchandise like
T-shirts and mugs and pillows and wall hangings.
Yeah. A whole bunch of stuff. Phone covers,
you could buy phone covers there. That's true.
It has our no-prize art on all of that stuff,
but also a few other illustrations that we've
done. Yeah, it's good stuff. Check it out for
sure. And as we've mentioned earlier in this
episode, please don't forget to rate, review,
share, and subscribe to our podcast, especially
on iTunes, to help us get to that 200 mark for
Rotten Tomatoes. It's a life goal to affect
the tomato meter, guys. I know. Help us realize
that goal, please. Alright, in our next episode
we will be reviewing a Constantine animated
film that's coming out called City of Demons.
Right. I think it was a web series that was
coming out on CW Seed, but it's being compiled,
I think, into a full-length feature film here.
Yeah, and there's additional footage, there's
like almost a half hour of additional footage
that wasn't seen in the web series. Yeah. And
then, you know, CW is doing some big thing with
it later on in the month too. I think it's
a way to kind of celebrate the fact that Matt
Ryan is going to... be joining the Legends
of Tomorrow cast this season, which starts in
a few weeks as well. Yeah. So this is like
a big Constantine month. Yeah. So we're going
to be reviewing that animated film and we're
also going to be doing a dual episode with Constantine
versus Brother Voodoo later on this month,
so look forward to that. Yeah, and if Daredevil
wasn't coming out, we also would have been
reviewing the Keanu Reeves film, but I think
we'll save that for another time. Yeah, probably
next Halloween time. Yeah. So yeah, that does
it for this episode. We'll talk to you guys
in a week. Up, up, and away. True believers.