This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
Welcome to the dynamic duel podcast a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC By comparing
their characters in stat-based battle simulations
I'm marvelous Joe and I'm his twin brother Johnny
DC and in this episode we're gonna find out
who would win in a fight between Morgan Le Fay
and Cersei being a Greek mythological figure
and Morgan Le Fay being an Arthurian legend
character. Right, and Cersei of course is a
Wonder Woman villain. Morgan and Le Fay is I
think an Avengers villain, is that right? Well,
she's an Avengers villain, she's a Black Knight
villain, she's also a Doctor Strange villain.
She's a general Marvel villain, and she's pretty
powerful, so I'm pretty sure that Cersei is
going down. So what you're saying is she's like
the Marvel villain village bicycle? Sure, sure,
whatever. I mean, if you're familiar with Arthurian
legend, you might not disagree with that statement.
Sweet! Can't wait for this match! Before that,
we're going to get into the latest comic book
movie news of which we only have one news item
this week, and that is that Ulrich Thompson
is going to play Sinestro in the HBO Lantern
series. Who the hell is that guy? We'll find
out later on. As always, we list our segment
times in our episode description, so feel free
to check out the show notes if you want to skip
ahead to a particular topic. Guys, our artificially
intelligent Duel simulator AJ9K has a quick
message for our listeners, so listen up. Why
hello there, do you want even more from this
podcast? Then become a part of the dynamic
Duel community on Patreon, where you can choose
from three tiers. The dynamic two-oh tier gives
you access to our Discord chat server. The fantastic
four tier gives you two bonus episodes each
month, and the X-Force tier makes you an executive
producer of this show. Lastly, The Diner Mike
podcast network tier lets you create your own
podcast using this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny
and Joe will help you develop your show, provide
graphic support and consultation, and get you
simulation results. Pitch the twins your ideas
via email at dynamicduelpodcast at gmail.com.
Check it out at patreon.com slash dynamicduel.
Pip pip cheerio. Thanks AJ9K and thanks to
everyone who supports the podcast. Be sure to
tune in to the other shows in the Dynamite
Podcast Network this week including Max Destruction
which pits your favorite action heroes from
film and television against each other. This
week, hosts Scotty and Gilly are finding out
who would win in a fight between Spawn and Hellboy.
That's going to be a great match. On the Senjoh World
podcast, host Zachary Hepburn speculates on
fights between fan favorite anime and manga
characters. This week, Zach's finding out who
would win in a battle between Sung-Jin Woo
of Solo Leveling and Sid Kaganu of The Eminence
in Shadow. And sorry if I butchered those names.
And on the Konsole Kombat podcast, hosts John
and Dean simulate battles between popular video
game characters. In yesterday's episode, they
found out who would win in a fight between
Zangief from Street Fighter and Wolf from Virtua
Fighter. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or click
the link in our show notes. to listen to all
of the shows in the DynaMic Podcast Network.
But with that out of the way, quick to the no
prize. A no prize is an award that Marvel used
to give out to fans. Our version, the Dynamic
Duel No Prize, is a digital award that we post
on Instagram for the person we feel gave the
best answer to our question of the week. Last
week, we asked you guys, what Marvel or DC television
series are you most looking forward to? in
2025. And we got a number of answers, but we
have three honorable mentions to go through
as well as the no prize winner. Our first honorable
mention goes to Michael Williams, who said,
But Marvel TV show I'm looking forward to is
Wonder Man. I know that they are fictional
characters and I'm not a big fan of gender swapping
or race swapping, but that's the world we live
in. So it'd be interesting to see. how they're
going to do these characters, backstory, change
it up, and introduce them into the Marvel Universe.
Yeah, I feel like Wonder Man is the Marvel
project that we know the least about currently,
probably because it's not coming out until
the end of 2025, but it has a great cast in
Yaya Abdul-Mateen II, who has had a number
of comic book roles under his belt, and also
like from the vague, preview of sorts that
we got from the last D23 event. It looks fairly
interesting. It focuses heavily on the Hollywood
system, but Michael Williams as a superhero
in Marvel is an actor and taking that route
is something that we haven't seen before. So
at the very least, it's gonna give us something
new. I'm excited just to get a Wonder Man series.
I've never liked the name Wonder Man because
it's just way too close to Wonder Woman. But
the character otherwise is pretty cool. Absolutely.
Yeah, if you guys want to learn more about Wonder
Man, listen to our duel episode where we pit
him against Captain Adam. He's a great character.
Thanks, Michael Williams. Our next honorable
mention goes to Lee Tapscott, who said, Hi,
this is Lee Tapscott. What Marvel or DC show
am I most looking forward to? Marvel zombies.
In this show, I'm hoping that they follow Spider-Man.
as he is traumatized by killing his family and
being the hero that he once was. Will he overcome
the constant hunger and keep killing or will
he find a way to stop the zombies? Dude, same.
And if you've read the Marvel zombies comic
books and followed the Spider-Man arc as far
as that goes, it's truly fascinating, especially
like when he eats Sandman. It's kind of disturbing.
I don't know if the Marvel Zombies television
show will go that route, but there's definitely
a lot of interesting areas to explore when it
comes to Spider-Man and the Marvel Zombies.
Like is he gonna eat Aunt May or Mary Jane and
all that stuff? We'll see if it follows the
comic books by watching the show when it comes
out close to Halloween this year. Yeah, we
broke down the storyline of Marvel Zombies in
our Deceased vs. Marvel Zombies episode. So...
Don't listen to that if you don't want to be
spoiled as to what happens or could happen
on the show. That was a fun episode. Thank you,
Lee. Our final honorable mention goes to McGee
Mathengian, who said, Hey, what's up, guys?
This is McGee. And the show I'm looking forward
to the most this year is My Adventures with
Superman Season 3. Now, I know it hasn't been
confirmed or anything, but hopefully we get
it this year. Me and my girlfriend have been
watching it. We actually just finished. like
I've already seen it but I was watching it
with her so it was her first time watching it
season two like season one and two um a couple
of weeks ago and she loved it and so it's kind
of like our show now so my adventures with
Superman is probably one of the best modern
adaptations of the character of Superman to
ever come out yeah totally I have yet to hear
anyone say that they dislike this series even
people who don't like the character of Superman
seem to like this series which makes me Superman
is DC's flagship character. And if there's one
character you need to get right, it's Superman.
Yeah, hopefully James Gunn's iteration of Superman
in his live action movie coming out this summer
matches the quality of the character that is
portrayed in this series. It needs to. And
hopefully Miggi could go see that movie with
his girlfriend who is totally real. Ha ha ha.
But special thanks to Daniel Alonso, Jess and
Betty. Mason Thompson and Travis Herndon for
calling in with their answer this week. But
the winner of this week's no prize is Jonathan
and not Johnny DC, but a different Jonathan.
He said, Hey, my name is John and my most anticipated
show for 2025 is obviously Daredevil for obvious
reasons. But Peacemaker season two is going
to be a close second because that show is awesome.
And Creature Commando season two would have
been there too. But there's no way they can
crank out a season two this year. But those
are my Most anticipated picks. Shout out Peacemaker
Season Two for sure. All right, Jonathan, it
comes down to this. What series is gonna be
better in 2025? Daredevil Born Again or Peacemaker
Season Two? Peacemaker Season Two. Oh, that's
the wrong answer. The correct answer was Daredevil
Born Again. Sorry. Try again next time. I do
think Daredevil Born Again is going to be a
fantastic show. Just based on the trailer, it
looks like it's going to be as good as the
seasons that Netflix put out. At least I'm hoping
that's the case. I'm also really looking forward
to Peacemaker Season 2 as well. Although I have
to say, it's not my most anticipated series
of this year from DC. That would probably be
going to Sandman Season 2 if that comes out
this year. It may not. Yeah. That whole Neil
Gaiman thing is just kind of a... Shit show.
Yeah, it's friggin' really weird. But no, I
love Peacemaker season one, and Peacemaker
season two is definitely high on my list of
shows this year. So congrats to Jonathan for
winning this week's No Prize. If you the listener
want a shot at winning your own No Prize, stay
tuned to later on this episode when we'll be
asking another question of the week. But now
that that's done, on to the news.
Alright, last week Deadline confirmed that Ulrich
Thompson has been cast as Sinestro for the
upcoming HBO series, Lanterns. This series of
course is set in James Gunn's DCU and it stars
Aaron Pierre as Jon Stewart and Kyle Chandler
as Hal Jordan. Sinestro of course is a major
villain figure in Green Lantern mythology, although
I'm assuming that by the start of this series,
he will still be a Green Lantern. I have no
idea who Ulrich Thompson is. Apparently he
has been in series like Banshee for Cinemax.
He also had a recurring role on The Blacklist
that aired on NBC for a time, as well as counterpart
HBO's The Young Pope. He's a Scandinavian actor.
Yeah, I've never seen a guy with so prominent
a filmography whom I've never heard of. He
has a good look though for... Sinestro, so I'm
hoping he does well. Yeah, looks wise, he looks
nothing like Mark Strong, who I thought nailed
the look of the character of Sinestro, if not
the behavior in the infamous Green Lantern film.
I don't know, this guy, it just doesn't say
Sinestro to me personally. It says maybe like
Hitler, who the character of Sinestro was based
on, just like comb his hair to the side and
give him like a mustache. Boom. Sure. I think
that's what they're going for in this casting.
Yeah, I think it'll be interesting how they
treat the character of Sinestro in this show
if he starts off as a Green Lantern and then
we see that transition into his more villainous
persona. It always struck me as odd that it's
surprising that a character with the name of
Sinestro turns evil. So I wonder how they're
going to play that off in this series because
if the actors from Earth aren't like, wait,
this guy... Just say his name is Sinestro. They
have to say something about it because otherwise
it's just too awkward. There's some things you
can get away with in the comics that you can't
get away with on screen. I'm sure the guy is
a terrific actor. Again, I don't know anything
about him. But speaking of great villain actors,
that brings us to our question of the week.
Which actor has given the best performance in
a villain role for a Marvel or DC series? Who's
your favorite villain in a television show for
Marvel or DC basically? Record your answer
at dynamicduel.com by clicking on the red microphone
button in the bottom right hand corner of the
screen which will prompt you to leave us a voicemail.
Your message could be up to 30 seconds long
and don't forget to leave your name in case
we include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer. and award that person a dynamic
duel no prize that we'll post to Instagram.
Be sure to answer before February 1st.
But I think that does it for all the news for
this episode, so let's go ahead and get into
our main event where we find out who would win
in a fight between the mythological DC character
of Cersei versus the Arthurian legend character,
Morgan Le Fay.
Alright, Cersei versus Morgan Le Fay. This episode
is coming off of Creature Commando Season 1,
in which Cersei played a minor role, but she's
a prominent Wonder Woman villain, so it was
important, I think, to get her in a duel against
one of Marvel's most preeminent sorceress villainesses,
Morgan Le Fay. Was Morgan Le Fay in that one
Renaissance what-if episode? Oh, what-if 1602?
She was not. But Morgan Le Fay has played a
prominent live action role in the Runaway season
three, where she was played actually by Elizabeth
Hurley. So she's kind of a big deal. Oh, Elizabeth
Hurley, huh? Yeah. Cersei would be so lucky.
I am not even gonna debate you on that, because
I agree. Yeah, Cersei was pretty cool in Creature
Commando season one. I really hope though that
she eventually plays a role as the primary villain.
of a Wonder Woman live action movie. Well I'm
hoping that she's going to pop up in the Paradise
Lost television series that was announced for
the DCU about the island of the Mascara and
the Amazons. Yeah, it would make sense for
her character to show up there. Yeah, and we'll
get into the backstory of Cersei and Morgan
Le Fay, but first to explain the methodology
behind our duels, let's go to our sentient
duel simulator, Alfred Jarvis 9000. AJ 9K, tell
our listeners how you go about determining
a winner. in our Duel matchups.
Additional stat categories are included such
as range, damage potential, versatility and
perception in order to create a more detailed
and accurate simulation. The results of the
1000 simulations provide a percentage of wins
for each character. The contestant with the
higher percentage is declared the victor as
they have a higher probability to win any given
battle. In an equitable pairing, neither character
should win 100% of the matches. The comic book
stories have shown that there's even a way for
Batman to defeat Superman. So the confidence
rate of my method falls in line with the precedents
that have been established in the source material.
My mathematical simulations are without subjectivity
or bias. Feats are not the sole consideration,
nor are fan votes tabulated for determination
of the winner. Thanks AJ9K! Before we run the
simulations though, we like to break down each
character's histories and abilities before
improvising a scenario on how we imagine one
of the 1000 simulations would play out beat
for beat. And it's my turn to go first with
the DC characters backstory, so let me tell
you all about Cersei. Now over 1200 years BC,
Cersei was born to the Titans Hyperion and
Persace and raised as the Princess of Colchis,
a kingdom in the Caucasus region. Known for
her beauty and cunning, she murdered her weak
and unworthy husband, an act that led to her
expulsion from the kingdom. Exiled and seeking
power, Cersei fled to the island of Aiea, where
she began studying the mystical arts and developed
a talent for sorcery. While her magic was initially
limited to the island, she used nearby sirens
to lure unsuspecting sailors and travelers,
transforming them into animals as punishment
for their intrusion and to perfect her powers.
Her prayers for greater power reached the Greek
goddess Hecate, the goddess of witchcraft and
an Olympian outcast who sought revenge against
the gods who had wronged her. Hecate offered
Cersei a pact, immortality, eternal beauty,
and immense magical power in exchange for her
soul. When Cersei accepted, Hecate transferred
her essence into the sorceress, dying in the
process by uttering a chilling prophecy, upon
the death of which and the birth of which,
Hecate, by name and choice, shall repossess
her soul. Initially unconcerned by the prophecy,
Cersei reveled in her newfound abilities, using
them to raise Colchis in a single day. She
became infamous for her power to transform humans
into animals, creating subservient bestiomorphs,
sometimes called animin, bound to her will.
Empowered by Hecate's hatred of the gods, Cersei
relished in fostering discord between men and
women, sowing mistrust and animosity wherever
she went. She became wary, however, when the
Amazons, warrior women blessed by the Olympian
gods, were created. Ares, the god of war, assured
Cersei that the Amazons would fall under his
schemes, however, and she initially allowed
him to act unchallenged. You can learn more
about Ares in our Ares vs Loki duel episode.
When Hercules enslaved the Amazons, Cersei
took advantage of the situation to create a
division amongst the group by manipulating
Ariadne. into murdering Antiochus, the sister
of Apollita, who had brokered peace with Athens.
This act resulted in a rift between the Themiscerian
Amazons and the newly formed Bona-Migdala tribe,
fulfilling Cersei's aim to weaken their unity.
For centuries, Cersei remained on Aaea, orchestrating
chaos and destruction from afar when it suited
her. By modern times, she had retreated to
her island as an enigmatic recluse. But when
Wonder Woman appeared in Man's World, Cersei
was surprised that Amazons had survived, as
all traces of them had vanished for hundreds
of years. You can learn more about Wonder Woman
in our Wonder Woman vs. Thor episode. Fearing
Diana was the fulfillment of Hecate's prophecy,
she plotted to destroy her, but feared direct
confrontation. Cersei's attempt to revert Diana
back into clay failed when the Greek gods intervened,
but her obsession with the Amazon Princess endured.
Cersei's hatred for the Amazons led her to
instigate a war of the gods between the Greek,
Roman, and Egyptian pantheons in an effort
to sap their power for herself. Cersei aligned
herself with the Banu-Migdhal Amazons, using
them as pawns in her effort to discredit Wonder
Woman and the Themyscirans. Her plan reached
their apex when she killed Wonder Woman by finally
reverting her into the clay from which she
had been formed. However, with the aid of the
Spectre and the Phantom Stranger... Wonder
Woman was resurrected and Cersei's plot unraveled.
Hecate's soul abandoned Cersei during the battle,
leaving her seemingly defeated. Following her
failure in the War of the Gods, Cersei turned
on her Bonamigdol Amazons, casting them and
the Themyscaryans into a demon-infested dimension.
The Amazons spent years fighting for survival.
When Wonder Woman confronted her, Cersei was
forced to return the island to its original
location after losing a wager with the Amazon
Princess. In one of her most insidious schemes,
Cersei disguised herself as Donna Milton, a
lawyer who befriended Diana to destroy her from
within. Cersei cast a spell on herself to suppress
her memories of her true identity, ensuring
the Donna Milton persona would remain genuine
and immune to one romance lasso of truth. Under
the skies, she became romantically involved
with Ares Buchanan. the mortal guise of the
god Ares, and gave birth to their daughter,
Leda Milton. Eventually, Diana realized Donna's
true nature, and though Cersei's memories returned,
she found herself emotionally conflicted due
to her new attachment to Diana as Donna Milton.
In a rare act of selflessness, she saved Diana
during a confrontation with a villain known
as the White Magician. Cersei later struck a
deal with the demon Neuron to increase her
magical power. She joined Lex Luthor's Injustice
Gang, attempting to destroy the Justice League
by turning its members against one another.
She clashed with Wonder Woman repeatedly, including
during an attack on New York City, where she
transformed male superheroes into beast geomorphs,
and transformed Superman into a doomsday-like
monster to kill Wonder Woman. Later, Cersei
empowered Wonder Woman's rogues, including Cheetah,
Giganta, and Dr. Psycho, to test the Amazons'
resolve. She stole Wonder Woman's powers during
this period and declared herself the new Wonder
Woman. However, Diana eventually regained her
abilities, defeated Cersei, and banished her
once again. In post-Flashpoint continuity, Cersei
was reimagined as a red-haired bearer of the
Witch Mark, which signified her possession of
a fragment of Hecate's soul. in a plot to manipulate
Superman into fighting Wonder Woman, the combined
efforts of Superman and Wonder Woman thwarted
her plans. Cersei later became entangled with
Veronica Cale, an entrepreneur seeking vengeance
against the Sons of Ares for kidnapping her
daughter. Together, they trapped Phobos and
Deimos, the twin Sons of Ares, in animal forms.
Cersei deduced that Cale's daughter was being
held on Themyscira, but refused to help further,
fearing the consequences of freeing Ares. When
Hecate sought to reclaim her soul through the
Witchmarks, Cersei manipulated events to inherit
Hecate's full power. She pretended to assist
Wonder Woman and the Justice League Dark in
fighting Hecate, but secretly sought to destroy
her patron. Her plan succeeded, and with Hecate's
death, Cersei became the new Goddess of Magic.
She formed the Injustice League Dark, recruiting
powerful magical beings to challenge Wonder
However, her plans were thwarted when Diana
used the power of Eclipso to defeat her. Rather
than destroy Cersei, Diana imprisoned her in
a magical mirror, allowing her to retain her
newfound power, but barring her from using
it against others. That's Cersei's backstory.
Power-wise, Cersei is a goddess-level sorceress
with vast magical power. Her abilities include
matter and energy manipulation, reality alteration,
and teleportation. She's best known for transforming
humans into beast geomorphs, which are animal-like
beings under her control. She can project destructive
magical blasts, erect defensive shields, and
summon creatures to do her bidding. Cersei's
immortality prevents her from aging, and she
is highly resistant to physical harm. She also
has limited clairvoyance, allowing her to foresee
events and sense the presence of other immortals.
And that's Cersei! I think the most surprising
thing there is that my knowledge of the mythological
Cersei was primarily from the Odyssey, but
the fact that the Amazonians came after the
events of that story was interesting. Well,
not necessarily, because she had been on the
island of Aya for a while, even after the Amazons,
so she stayed there. Alright, so I thought I
had the Amazons chronologically placed in a
certain time, but yeah, it's pretty vague, I
guess, when they started. Greek Myth! is not
as interesting as Arthurian legend. So, oh,
what? You heard me. That's right. Let me go
ahead and get into the Arthurian legend that
is Morgan Le Fay. Now, Morgan Le Fay was born
in the magical Celtic realm of Avalon during
the sixth century days of Camelot. She's the
daughter of a grain, the sea princess, and an
unknown father of fairy lineage. A young sorcerer
from Avalon named Merlin forewarned of a great
catastrophe that would befall Egraine's kingdom
and helped the mother and daughter flee to Earth's
realm in Britain. There Merlin arranged for
Egraine to marry Gorloi, Duke of Tintagel who
adopted the young Morgan. King Uther Pendragon
of England lusted after Egraine and killed Gorloi,
taking Morgan's mother as his own bride. When
Negrane birthed them a son, Morgan became the
half-sister of Arthur Pendragon, whom Merlin
had prophesied would become the greatest king
of Britain. Merlin trained Morgan Le Fay in
sorcery as she grew up, and she became his apprentice
and later lover. though the alliance soon unraveled
when she grew furious with his apparent abandonment
of their relationship in favor of King Arthur's
reign and the spread of Christianity, since
Morrigan was a disciple of the old Druidic
ways of Britain. She had resented King Arthur
from the moment of his birth, and allied herself
with his bastard son and her nephew, Mordred,
often conspiring with him against both Camelot
and Arthur himself. Morgan's long rivalry with
Merlin intensified, given his role as royal
advisor and enforcer against her plots. She
occasionally resided at Castle Le Fay, which
was gifted to her by Arthur in his attempts
to keep peace, but she continued to undermine
him from within. In her early forays into black
magic, Morgan led a cult who worshipped the
elder god Chthon, the god of chaos. She assembled
and helped bind his scattered scrolls into
a single tome known as the Darkhold. Unfortunately
for her, the summon to C'thun proved too powerful
to control, so Morgan and her followers bound
him within Wundergorm Mountain. You can learn
more about C'thun and Wundergorm Mountain in
our Zatanna vs Scarlet Witch One of her disciples,
Magnus, eventually saw the evil in her ways
and stole the Darkhold to prevent Morrigan
from abusing its contents. She slew Magnus in
retaliation, but lost her access to the book's
dark secrets. Her conflicts with Arthur often
centered on the sword Excalibur, which she
tried to sabotage by striking a chip from the
real blade and forging a hellish replica. She
resented Lancelot. one of the Knights of the
Round Table for spurring her affections, and
she eventually exposed Lancelot's affair with
Arthur's Queen Guinevere, fracturing the Court
of Camelot from within and helping incite the
civil war that spelled Arthur's downfall. As
these events reached their climax, Merlin intervened
repeatedly, eventually having Morgan imprisoned
with a powerful enchantment, though she managed
to project her astral form beyond physical
throughout time. When Mordred gravely wounded
his father, the king, Morgan's astral form
transported Arthur's soul to Avalon, yet her
hatred of his legacy of Camelot endured, and
she continued her quest for greater power from
within her imprisonment. She was particularly
determined to retrieve the Darkhold in future
centuries, believing it could finally free
her from Merlin's longstanding bindings and
allow her to rule unrestricted. Over centuries,
Morgan repeatedly manifested in eras beyond
her original timeline. In the modern age, she
often confronted heroes such as Doctor Strange
and the Avengers. She tried to possess people
to bypass her constraints, including the heroine
Spider-Woman, aka Jessica Drew, whose body
she temporarily took control of. Morgan also
clashed with Iron Man. whom she met when Dr.
Doom time traveled back to her era and struck
a deal with her in exchange for knowledge of
the dark arts. Doom promised to help Morgan's
forces if she would aid in rescuing his mother's
soul from hell, yet the uneasy alliance ended
in betrayal on both sides, creating an enduring
enmity. Morgan nonetheless taught Doom much
about sorcery, and the two maintained a recurrent
tangled relationship across time. sometimes
as lovers, other times as bitter enemies. They
even produced a daughter, Caroline Le Fay. You
can learn more about Dr. Doom in his duel against
Superman. Morgan later tapped into the magic
of the Asgardian artifact known as the Twilight
Sword, which she used to reshape reality, forging
a medieval-style Earth with herself as its
sole ruler, presiding over Earth's mightiest
heroes. She also raised armies of the dead,
enslaved powerful beings like the Scarlet Witch,
and attempted to resurrect the sunken continent
of Atlantis, mistaking it for her fabled Avalon.
From the past, she later fought Norman Osborn's
Dark Avengers with an army of demons. Although
the Dark Avengers destroyed her several times
in that confrontation, she kept resurrecting
herself in the past into the present until
Doctor Doom and Iron Patriot traveled back to
her timeline and magically exiled her. into
her own dark cauldron. Even that proved temporary
however as Morgan's daughter Caroline retrieved
her from the cauldron and Morgan raised undead
armies throughout Europe bringing her into
conflict with the Avengers yet again. She later
attempted to conquer Camelot which Merlin transported
into the realm of Avalon and she fought against
Captain Britton and his sister Betsy Braddock.
She put Captain Britton under her spell forcing
Betsy to don his amulet of right artifact to
become the new Captain Britain, which you can
learn more about in our Uncle Sam vs Captain
Britain Duel episode. And that's her backstory.
Powers-wise, Morgan Le Fay is an accomplished
sorceress with a vast array of mystical abilities
that include reality warping, magical time
travel, necromancy, self-resurrection, flight,
shape-shifting, transmutation, energy manipulation,
illusion casting, astral projection, and and
duplication. Her one weakness due to her fairy
heritage is the metal of iron. And that's her
backstory. I guess I should say that Cersei
has a weakness as well. And that is an herb
known as Molly, I think. Like ecstasy? It's
gotta be. I don't know. Well, so convenient
of you to leave that out of her backstory.
I'm pretty sure it's harder to find this herb
than it is fucking iron. That's ridiculous.
Who knows? Molly's everywhere these days. Stay
safe, kids.
Where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
Dynomic Podcast Network presents... Console
Combat, where video game legends brawl every
Monday. Dynamic Duel, where comic book titans
smash every Tuesday. Max Destruction, where
the world is at its limit. TV and action heroes
battle every Wednesday, and Sendro World, where
anime champions clash every Thursday. Join us
as we speculate on the matches and armed with
the power of mathematical simulations, discover
who will emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
Well now that we've got their histories and
abilities out of the way, let's speculate on
how one of the 1000 simulated matches will go.
The winner is determined by simulations, not
this speculation, but it's fun to imagine how
the fight could play out. AJ and NK, what are
the rules of our speculation? Well, I should
say there are no rules, other than the characters
have no prior knowledge of the other going into
the fight. All they are aware of starting out
is that the other character is a threat that
needs to be eliminated. For the speculation,
the contestants will begin approximately 50
meters apart in a non-descript environment
that will have no bearing on the match itself,
as no environmental statistics are considered
in my simulations. The contestants must earn
victory on their own merit. Alright, then let's
get into it. Cersei and Morgan Le Fay meet on
the battlefield. Who goes first? Morgan Le
Fay, she usually wears jewelry, right? Like
a necklace? Mmm... Like a skull necklace? Yeah.
Okay. Well, I'm going to say that Cersei starts
by transforming that skull necklace into like
this snake creature that just chokes and bites
her. All right. OK, well, before the snake
bites her, Morgan Lafay transforms it into a
chain, which she, you know, unfurls from around
her neck and she casts across the battlefield
over to Cersei and binds her up with it. And
it transports her into this dark dungeon. inside
a medieval castle. What is this chain made
of? Is it iron? No, like, I don't know. It's
fucking made out of lead or something. Okay,
just checking. In this medieval dungeon, Cersei,
she's just gonna blast off her chains, her
shackles or whatever, with these purple magic
bolts. And once she's free, she's also gonna
blast Morgan with those bolts as well. Except
that in this dungeon, Morgan Le Fay has like
this skeleton army guarding her. that takes
the brunt of this magical blast. And she uses
the fallen skeleton army bodies and she reforms
them into this massive bone dragon that just
blasts down a flame of green eldritch fire that
engulfs her sea and burns her alive. Forest
field, all right? Magical forest field. It blocks
those flames. And while she's protecting herself.
Cersei is going to take the stones that make
up the walls of the dungeon around her and
use them to form a giant rock minotaur that
just dashes straight into the dragon scattering
its bones everywhere and then the minotaur is
gonna look at Morgan Lafay and he's gonna charge
into her just impaling her on its horns Except
as the minotaur rushes at Morgan Lafay It's
gonna pass through this like time spell that's
gonna de-age this rock Minotaur until, you
know, it's just a Minotaur rock calf baby. And
it stumbles and falls onto the ground into
like a bunch of little pebbles, okay? And each
of those are gonna get transposed into this
fairy being. And now Morgan Le Fay is in command
of this fairy army, and she's gonna send them
out like a legion of kamikaze pilots that just
tear through Cersei. Like a barrage of glowing
magical bullets. Oh damn, okay. Like Tinkerbells.
Yeah. All right, so Cersei, she's being pummeled
by these fairy bullets and she's still in this
damn dungeon. So she's just gonna teleport
out of there and from outside of whatever medieval
castle they were just in, she's gonna cause
an earthquake beneath it that just brings the
whole castle crumbling down on top of Morgan.
Okay, so. Morgan gets buried by Castle Lafay,
but from the rubble, she's gonna sprout this
massive plant with like a flower bulb from which
she emerges safe and sound and she commands
the roots of this plant to emerge from the ground
and wrap up Cersei with all these vines that
drain her of her power until she's just a husk.
Okay, but as these roots are approaching Cersei,
that gives her an iron touch, you know, kind
of like Midas's golden touch, but with iron,
all right? So this plant that Morgan was inside
of is now just an iron trap that burns her
to death, giving Cersei the win. I said she
emerged from the plant. Okay, but not in time.
Okay, well, except that the giant plant that
Cersei tried to turn into iron, it actually
turns out that the plant Molly, the herb, which
disrupts Cersei's magic. So it doesn't turn
to iron. It turns into this like impure metal
that Cersei just thinks is iron. But it's actually
like some kind of like Molly metal compound.
We'll say molybdenum, okay? Molybdenum. What?
All right. And Morgan Le Fay crafts a giant
sword out of this metal that she swings at
Cersei and it decapitates her, ending this match.
How the heck did Morgan even know Cersei was
weak to Molly? Well, how did Cersei know that
Morgan Le Fay was weak to Iron? Dude, Cersei
is like a lot older than Morgan. She knows all
those Celtic fairies are weak to that shit.
How does she know that Morgan's like a fairy
folk, like a descendant of that? She doesn't
know that. And also, like Morgan Le Fay has
been around long enough to know by the present
time that like Cersei was... a figure that is
weak to the fucking molly herb. Morgan's been
around long enough. Oh, yeah. Morgan's been
around. All right. Yeah. Marvel villain village
bicycle over here, like you said earlier, checks
out. Hey, we don't villain shame around here.
OK. All right. Well, go ahead and run the stats
on these characters and find out which scenario
happens. Either Cersei traps Morgan Le Fay in
an iron plant that burns her to death. or Morgan
Le Fay creates a molybdenum sword that decapitates
Cersei. We'll run the stats and find out who
came out on top. AJ9K, hit it. Inputting data,
running calculations, processing results, simulations
complete. All right, these sorceresses were
pretty close in their statistics. There were
just a few instances in which they deferred.
Like we said that- Morgan Le Fay was faster
primarily because, you know, the official Marvel
power grid said that she was faster, I think
because she can transport her consciousness
through time and space. Whereas Cersei, you
know, sticks to the present. Right, but we did
give the edge to Cersei when it came to fighting
skill because she actually throws hands with
Wonder Woman on occasion, whereas Morgan Le
Fay really never fights physically. Right, yeah,
never. Regarding the rest of the stats, they
were actually similar. Like, they're pretty
much identical, especially when it comes to
abasiveness, durability, strength. Actually,
we did say that Cersei was a little bit stronger
than Morgan Le Fay physically. Right, yes, but
everything else was the same. So taking all
of this data into consideration, Joseph, who
do you think came out on top? Morgan Le Fay?
That's not even a question. Don't even ask me.
Morgan Le Fay. I literally just asked you.
Well, Don't do that again. And I don't even
want to know what the Instagram followers say.
71% of them picked Cersei to win, so they're
obviously biased. Actually, I've been looking
back at the Instagram polls, like a majority
of them have come out DC recently, which is
fascinating and awesome. And lame. What the
fuck is going on there? We have way too many
DC fans following us on Instagram. We need more
Marvel guys on there. Well, let's check out
the actual winning percentage. AJ9K the results
please. Here you are, sir.. The winner of the matchup
between Circe and Morgan Le Fay is... Circe
by 59.6% compared to Morgan Le Fay's 40.4%
which means she only wins 404 of the 1000 simulated
matches compared to Circe's 596. Well, I'm
going to call it bullshit. on those results,
even if it affects our credibility. I'm going
to call bullshit. Why? Because I don't like
it. When it came down to it. Yes, Morgan Le
Fay was faster, but she couldn't outmatch Circe's
strength and fighting skill. You can say that,
but it's still not going to make me accept it.
Oh, look, everyone, Joseph doesn't want to
accept reality. I accept my reality. OK. You
can take your reality. That's good for you.
I accept that for you. And then I'll just take
my reality where Morgan LeFay wins. Yeah. Ooh,
sorry, but the numbers do not lie. That does
not work. Sucks to suck, but that does it for
this duel. AJ9K, help close this out. Thanks
for listening to Dynamic Duel. Visit the show's
website at dynamicDuel.com and follow us on
Instagram at dynamicDuelpodcast. You can support
the show on Patreon at patreon.com slash dynamicDuel
and joining a tier that works for you, or by
rating and reviewing Dynamic Duel on Apple Podcasts,
Spotify, Podchaser or on our website. Don't
forget to listen to the other shows in the Dynamite
Podcast Network, including Max Destruction,
Senjou World and Konsole Kombat. In our next
episode, we are doing a duel that was chosen
by our executive producer, Mickey Math and Gian,
and that is Blockbuster versus Tombstone. Yeah,
Tombstone is a prominent Spider-Man villain.
And Blockbuster was a old video rental store
from the 90s. Tombstone's a pizza, bro. But
that is for this episode. We want to give a
big thanks to our executive producers, Ken Johnson,
John Sturowski, Zachary Hepburn. Dustin Balcom,
Mickey Muthengian, Brandon Estergard, Nathaniel
Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Austin Wyslowski, AJ Dunkerley,
Scott Camacho, Gil Camacho, Adam Spies, Dean
Molesky, Devin Davis, Joseph Kersting, Josh
Leiner, Mike Williams, and Oscar Galvez for
helping make this podcast possible. And we'll
talk to you guys next week. Up up and away,
true believers. Not Joseph having too many
drinks before recording this episode and slurring
his words like a dental patient. Damn.