This is a Dynamike Network podcast. Hey everyone,
Johnny DC here at the top of the episode. With
the approaching holiday season, we're officially
underway with this year's holiday charity drive
and lead up to our charity duel episode in December,
which is going to be Alfred Pennyworth versus
Edwin Jarvis. This year, all donations will
be going once again to Pop Culture Classroom,
a nonprofit organization that delivers high
quality. educational resources to school districts,
teachers, and community organizations using
comics, graphic novels, and related pop culture
media. Their mission is to inspire a love of
learning, increase literacy, and build community
through the tools of popular culture and the
power of self-expression. To donate, visit
our official store through dynamicduel.com where
you'll find two donation options. One if you're
Team DC, and one if you're Team Marvel. or go
directly to dynamicduel.com slash donate DC,
one word, or dynamicduel.com slash donate Marvel,
which are linked in our show notes. We're making
the charity drive a competitive duel this year,
except the only stat is which side can donate
the most. Everyone who donates will receive
a digital poster featuring original art of
Alfred and Jarvis drawn New Yorker style by
me. One lucky random donor will win a framed
print of the Alfred versus Jarvis art. that
I will announce during that December duel episode.
Which fan base will be the most charitable?
So far it's Marvel. DC guys, let's step up
our game. But with that out of the way, on with
the show.
Hi, welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters and stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin brother, Marvelous
Joe. And in this episode, we are reviewing
Season 2 of the Disney Plus series, Loki. It
was only six episodes, but they were actually
pretty good episodes. Yeah, for my money's worth,
this season was actually the best season. that
Marvel Studios has to offer on the Disney Plus
platform. So stay tuned for that review later
on in this episode. Before that, we have a ton
of news to go over, considering that we didn't
break down any news from last week due to my
business trip. But in this episode, we're going
to be talking about how Superman Legacy has
cast Lex Luthor, Jimmy Olsen, Eve Tesmacher,
and the Engineer. We'll be talking about a bunch
of trailers, including Aquaman and the Lost
Kingdom, Madame Web, Justice League Crisis on
Infinite Earths, and Marry Little Batman as
well. Yeah, we're gonna have to speak in our
chipmunk voices, just like speed through it
because this is gonna be a long episode, I feel.
Yeah, as always, we list our segment times
in our episode description, so feel free to
check out our show notes if you wanna skip
ahead to a particular topic. As our listeners
may know, our duel simulator is so advanced
that it's gained sentience and has named itself
the Artificial Lifeform for running extensive
duels, just a rather very intelligent simulator
9000, or Alfred Jarvis 9000. He has a quick
message for our listeners, so listen up. Why
hello there. Do you love listening and chatting
about Marvel and DC? Then become a part of the
dynamic dual community on Patreon, where you
can choose from three tiers. The dynamic 2-0
tier lets you listen to this podcast without
ads and gives you access to its Discord chat
group, where you can chat with Johnny DC and
Marvelous Joe. The fantastic four tier gives
you that and more with two bonus episodes each
month, including bloopers and top 10 shows where
Johnny and Joe count down your favorite Marvel
and DC subjects. The X-Force tier makes you
an executive producer of Dynamic Duel, where
every month you help the host choose what to
review and who to fight against each other.
And finally, the Dynamite Podcast Network tier
allows aspiring podcasters to create their
own battle-focused show using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and consultation,
and get you simulation results to announce
on your show. Pitch the twins your show via
email at dynamicduelpodcast.gmail.com them
on social media. Check it out at patreon.com
slash dynamic duel. Pip pip cheerio.
Also tune into the Senjou World podcast this
Thursday to find out who would win in an anime
battle between Madura Uchiha from Naruto and
RyÅmen Sukuna from Jujutsu Kaisen. This will
be the last episode of the season as Zack is
going to take a break for the month of December.
But debuting in December will be the newest
addition to the Dynamite Podcast Network, a
show coming out called Console Combat hosted
by executive producer of this show, John He
and his co-host Dean are going to let you guys
know who'd win in matchups between your favorite
video game characters. Stay tuned for a trailer
of that upcoming show at the end of this podcast.
Yeah, I can't wait for that one. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com
or click the link in our show notes to listen
to all of the shows in the Dynamike Podcast
Network. Real quick, we wanna give a shout
out to patrons Lizzie Dyer Arnie and the Kamacho
Twins. All three of them had their birthdays
this past week. Lizzie, if I could give you
anything from Marvel, it would be the ability
to time slip, because getting older just sucks.
And I think it would be cool to travel through
time that way, just like Loki. And I would give
you Wesley Dodd's dreaming power. That way
you can tell the future and see if you want
to travel there. And for the Kamacho twins,
if I could give you anything from the world
of Marvel, I'm trying to think of the most
prominent twins in Marvel. Probably Scarlet
Witch and Quicksilver. So one of you gets reality
warping powers. and one of you gets super speed.
I'll let you guys pick which one gets which.
And in honor of the Wonder Twins, I would give
you, Scott, the power to turn into any animal
and Gilly, you get the ability to turn into
a bucket of water. Cause you like Marvel. The
Marvel powers are just so much better. Happy
birthday guys, thanks for being patrons. Happy
birthday. But with that out of the way, quick
to the no prize. The No Prize is an award Marvel
used to give out to fans. Our version, the Dynamic
Duel No Prize, is a digital award that we post
on Instagram and in our email newsletter for
the person that we feel gave the best answer
to our question of the week. So two weeks ago,
we asked what other characters from the Sandman
universe do you hope get their own series on
Netflix? And this was a tie in to the first
trailer that we got for the Dead Boy Detective's
Netflix series, which itself is a supposed
tie in. to the Sandman universe that they've
established on that streaming platform. You
guys had two weeks to answer and we got two
answers. That just means it wasn't a great
question. I will say that one of the answers
was unusable because whoever called it in whispered
the entire time pretending to be Batman and
it just could not be understood. But between
the two answers that were understandable, one
of them gets an honorable mention and the other
one gets no prize win. So our honorable mention
goes to Lizzie Dyer Arnie. Who said? Hey, it's
Lizzie. No contest here. If Sandman character
gets her own spinoff, it's gotta be my boy
Wesley Dodds, aka Sandman Mystery Theater. It's
the greatest comic you've never read. I like
to describe it as Batman meets SVU. It's set
in the 1930s. I think it would attract fans
of shows like Boardwalk Empire and the now canceled
Perry Mason. You know, what's HBO's loss could
be Netflix's gain. Yeah. So Sandman Mystery
Theater was a vertigo comic book. It was the
same imprint that also published the Sandman
comics, and it was established that Wesley
Dodds, the original Golden Age Sandman, received
dreams from Morpheus. The comic was very, very
detective noir, and I think it would translate
fantastically into a show, especially the way
Lizzie described it. Yeah, I always liked the
JSA character of Sandman. A lot of people kind
of maybe write him off as just a guy with a
sleeping gas gun and a gas mask, but kind of
similar to the question. there's a lot more
going on there than first impressions may imply.
I think he's a fascinating character. Yeah,
he's a great like pulpy character, sort of
like the green hornet or the shadow. I feel
like there's a lot that they could do with
the character on screen that they just haven't
done yet. Yeah, especially as a period piece
as Lizzie described it. For sure. So great answer
Lizzie, but the winner of this week's No Prize
is Luke Tucker, who said, Hey guys, this is
Luke. I think they should make a death spinoff
series with the premise being based on the line
that she tells Dream in the comics about how
she'll put the chairs on the table, turn off
the lights, and lock the door to the universe
once the last living thing dies. The series
could follow her through time, witnessing the
past, present, and the future, with the ending
of the series being her witnessing the last
living thing die and locking the door to the
universe as everything passes on. Thanks, guys.
So if you had the chance to listen to my guest
spot, on the Mad Trivia podcast. You know that
I love existential film. And this sounds like
the most existential series that could ever
be made. Yeah, especially how Luke describes
it where we witness her travel through time.
You know, the episode that involved death in
the Sandman Netflix series was one of my favorite
episodes because we got to see Dream, like,
you know, travel through time, through the
centuries, and I just thought that was fascinating.
Yeah, honestly, I don't even know if you need
to necessarily follow death. Like she's obviously
like a recurring character, but I think it
could be almost like an anthology series just
telling stories about these people on their
last days, you know, before they die. Sort of
like the animated short that we got for death.
It just told the last day of this artist. Yeah,
of course she would show up at the end of every
episode. Exactly. Yeah, that sounds perfect.
So fantastic answer, Luke Tucker. You win this
week's No Prize. If listeners want a shot at
winning their own No Prize, stay tuned to later
on in this episode when we'll be asking another
Question of the Week. And now that that's done...
On to the news!
Okay, so these past two weeks we've gotten a
slew of casting news for Superman Legacy thanks
to The Actor's Strike, which ended a few weeks
earlier. We've been expecting this for quite
a few films and I'm really excited to say that
it looks like, according to Deadline, Nicholas
Holt has been cast as Lex Luthor for the movie.
Of course, he was up for the role of Superman,
but he lost out on that role to David Cornsweat.
A lot of people were fan-casting him as a potential
Lex Luthor because he has this great sort of
like villainous look to him, I think. But I'm
super excited about this news. Oh, it's fantastic
casting. He's had some villainous turns in
other movies, like the menu. He wasn't really
a villain so much as a weirdo in that movie.
But yeah, he can play a fantastic Dastardly
character and especially opposite David Cornsweat.
I think this is brilliant. I really can't wait
to see it. I think he'll be the best Lex Luthor
we've gotten. since Gene Hackman. Oh yeah, I
think he's gonna be the best Lex Luthor we've
ever had. And I said the same thing for Rachel
Brosnahan as Lois Lane. The casting choices
that they're making for this film are just absolutely
perfect. Including the news that Skyler Gazzando
is playing Jimmy Olsen. He looks the role to
a T. Holy crap. I saw him in the vacation reboot,
sequel, recue. He was pretty good in that one.
I could totally see him in this role. Great
comedic actor, I hope they make Jamie Olsen
a comedic character. And since it's a James
Gunn film and he tends to be, you know, more
comedic with his films like Guardians of the
Galaxy, I bet that's what the role is going
to be. And I bet Skyler is going to knock it
out of the park because he's great. We also
got news that Sarah Sampayo is going to be
Eve Tessmacher, who anyone who's seen the Superman
film directed by Richard Donner in the 70s
knows that she's Lex Luthor's girlfriend. I'm
actually kind of surprised she's in this movie
and I'm not quite sure what route they're gonna
take with the character. Like, are they gonna
make her like a badass, like Mercy Graves or
something like that? Or are they gonna make
her more comedic, sort of like that first Superman
movie? It's almost like the Superman legacy
movie is going to pay homage to Superman, the
movie from the 70s. Yeah, that is interesting.
In our last bit of casting news, we also learned
that Maria Gabriella de Feria, a Venezuelan
actress, is going to play the role of the engineer.
Now the Engineer is a character who is a member
of the Authority from the Wildstorm comics.
She is a robotic type character. Her body is
made up of nanobots and it's rumored that she's
actually like a sub-villain for the larger
threat that will be posed by Brainiac. Hopefully
that's the case because I think a lot of people
are rooting for Brainiac to be the villain of
this movie considering he's like probably the
biggest Superman villain that has yet to appear
in a Superman live-action movie. early stories
and his origin and stuff like that, it seems
almost like a no-brainer to go with him. Yeah,
definitely low-hanging fruit there. I really
hope Brainiac is in the movie. And that brings
us to our question of the week.
If Brainiac is the villain in Superman Legacy,
who would you cast as the character, and why?
Record your answer at dynamicduel.com by clicking
on the red microphone button in the bottom
right hand corner of the screen, which will
prompt you to leave us a voicemail. Your message
could be up to 30 seconds long, and don't forget
to leave your name in case we include you on
the podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer,
and award that person a Dynamic Duel No Prize
that we'll post to Instagram and our email newsletter.
Be sure to answer before- December 2nd. Again,
great casting choices, perfect casting choices.
In my opinion, I can't wait to see what James
Gunn is going to do with Superman Legacy, which
comes out July 11th, 2025. Before that, we've
got Aquaman coming out this December, for which
tickets just went on sale and Warner Brothers
has released a trailer to coincide with that.
It's a short trailer. It's only a minute and
30 seconds long, but there's a lot of new footage
that we haven't seen in prior trailers. It
starts off with Aquaman talking to his infant
son, who's communicating with Goldfish in a
tank. It's pretty adorable, honestly. But we
learned through the course of this trailer
that the key to Black Manta accessing this super
powerful army to fight against Aquaman and
Atlantis is the royal bloodline, of which Aquababy
is the last member. Right, so it looks like
Black Manta kidnaps Aquababy. from Aquaman's
father's lighthouse and I think they can't
be more blatant that this baby is gonna die.
Which would be super tragic because it's a
cute baby. We know that James Wan doesn't really
hold back when it comes to, you know, violence.
Yeah, I mean the movie looks amazing. You know,
everything from the Dead King to Black Manta
to all the Underwater battles between Aquaman
and Black Manta that we're gonna see. It looks
breathtaking as usual. I'm not surprised there
and I really can't wait to see the movie. December
22nd. I already have my tickets. Do you? No.
Well, get them. It's the end of an era, people.
This is the last film in the DCEU. Allegedly.
I don't know. According to Jason Momoa, it
is. Yeah, the trailer's pretty good. It looks
like it's gonna be a good movie. You know what
it looks like is not gonna be a good movie and
was a shitty trailer? Madame Webb? How do you
like that transition? I liked it a lot. God,
this... Sony does not know what the hell they're
doing. This past week, we got the first official
trailer for Madame Web, and it looks about
as bad as we were all thinking it would be.
Dakota Johnson plays apparently Cassandra Webb.
We thought she was playing Julia Carpenter,
because her version of Madame Web looks exactly
like the Julia Carpenter version from the comics.
But Sydney Sweeney, one of the actresses in
this movie, is actually playing Julia Carpenter,
one of the Spider Women. So... Yeah, I think
Dakota Johnson is playing Cassandra Webb. She,
of course, has the power of premonition like
she does in the comics, but it plays out in
the course of this trailer, like an iteration
of the Final Destination franchise, where she
sees all this horrible stuff happen and then
she's able to prevent it from happening through
her powers. It's like Final Destination with
a little bit of crime talk day. Yeah, a little
bit. We learned that Madam Webb was a paramedic
alongside Uncle Ben. who's played by Adam Scott
in this movie. She has a near-death experience,
which I guess ties her into the web of life
and destiny, where she can see the future.
And she basically witnesses this crazy guy with
spider powers kill these three girls who also
have spider powers. Now, the villain of this
movie is going to be a character named Ezekiel,
who was introduced in the J. Michael Straczynski
run in the Spider-Man comics. He is basically
a guy with spider powers that he received in
a ritual in the jungle. and he tells Peter
Parker Spider-Man all about the spider totem
and how every character that has an animal-based
ability is tied into the animalistic totem and
some totems feed on others and there's also
this vampiric race of beings known as the Inheritors
of which a character called Moralune is a part
of that feeds off of these totems. It makes
no sense for the character of Ezekiel to be
attacking these women as he is. It also makes
no sense for him to dress up in this dark Spider-Man
outfit. Uh, what the fuck is that? I mean, is
that Ezekiel in the Spider-Man outfit? I don't
know. Or is the black Spider-Man guy a version
of Morlun, the inheritor? I don't know what's
going on here, but it all looks really bad and
a horrible way to introduce elements from the
Spider-Man universe into a film. I mean, yeah,
the movie looks bad, but also doesn't look
bad regarding the cinematography. I actually
liked that. Well, you are the only one in that.
Really? Sure. I mean, like the cinematography
is fine. It looks like a movie, right? What
what's special about the cinematography here,
Jonathan? The women look good and well lit
in their costumes. I actually thought the girls
look a little bit silly in their costumes.
So we have here Julia Carpenter, who was a character
called Spider Woman in the comics. She was
actually the Spider Woman in the Secret Wars
event, who eventually in the comics became.
her own version of Madame Web after Cassandra
Web died. She's played by Sydney Sweeney. We
also have Anya Corazon here. She got her powers
from the Spider Society, which was founded
by Ezekiel as a- I didn't know she was in the
movie, actually. I saw her and I was like,
what is Hawk Girl doing in this movie? That's
right. Yeah. Because Isabella Mercer, it was
also cast in Superman Legacy as Hawk Girl. So
it looks like she is pulling double duty for
both Marvel and DC. Yeah. And the third lady
is Maddie Franklin. She's also Spider Woman
and she has the spider legs that sprout from
her back, just like in the comic books. It's
all very strange to see these essentially D-less
characters in this film. I hope it doesn't
really dilute the brand or confuse audiences
as to what the hell is going on regarding the
character of Spider-Man. This whole string of
movies that plays within the Spider-Man universe
without actually showing the character of Spider-Man
is just getting ridiculous now. And I think
seeing these Spider-Women characters within
this trailer serves to highlight that. It's
weird having them without actually Spider-Man
showing up. And especially when you have the
villain dressing up like Spider-Man. That's
so weird. Yeah, that was weird. But I mean,
honestly, Spider-Man could show up in this movie.
It's not out of the realm of possibility, but
I bet you he's not gonna. At the very best you'll
get like a cameo from Morbius or Venom or something
like that. It's Morbin time. The trailer does
show some of the action, which looks pretty
good. To me, it just looks very much like Final
Destination where essentially we'll see an
entire scene play out and then it turns out,
oh, that entire thing that just happened was
a premonition. This is how it's really going
to play out. I recently saw the film Suspiria
over Halloween. I was watching a bunch of scary
movies and that was actually the first time
I've ever seen Dakota Johnson in a role because
I never saw. 50 Shades of Grey. Gosh, she's
not that great of an actress. If you thought
her line delivery within this trailer was a
little bit stiff, expect more, I'll say, when
the movie actually comes out. Yeah, I mean,
I'm not expecting any Oscars for this film,
except for maybe costume design. I doubt that.
But we'll find out when the movie comes out
in February. Moving on to the animated trailers.
We got the first Justice League Crisis on Infinite
Earths trailer, which apparently is going to
kick off a trilogy of films that are coming
out next year. Now, the trailer is titled the
official trilogy trailer, so I'm not sure how
much of the footage from it comes from just
part one of the trilogy, or if it spans more
than that. Crisis on Infinite Earths part one,
of course, takes place immediately following
the events of Justice League Warworld, which
we reviewed recently. and which was not great.
Actually a lot of the recent movies set in
the animated Tomorrow vs Universe, which this
trilogy will take place, are not good I would
say. So I can't say that I'm looking forward
to it and I can't really say that this trailer
did anything for me. Honestly, I'm probably
looking forward to it even less because of
this trailer. Particularly because there was
an issue we mentioned in Justice Society World
War 2 that also appears to be happening in Barry
Allen has no nose when he's in profile It just
bothers me That's just nitpicking. I think really
the reason why this trailer did nothing for
you is because it doesn't give a clear idea
Of what the story is actually we see a lot
of shots of dramatic things happening such as
worlds disappearing and stuff But without the
stories context, it feels like there's no real
emotional stakes tied to any of this. Hopefully
we get a true trailer for part one of this trilogy
that'll shed some light on exactly what's going
on here. Yeah, it does look like Barry Allen
and Supergirl are going to be playing large
roles in this trilogy, which makes sense considering,
you know, they had major roles in the comic
book version. We don't have a release date yet
for any of the three films, though we do know
that all three will be coming out next year.
And you know, we'll be reviewing them once
they do come out. This past week we also got
a trailer for What If Season 2 which features
a very different style of animation. Some would
say better and they would be correct. Especially
when you watch the two trailers for DC's Crisis
on Infinite Earths and What If Season 2, you
can tell right off the bat that Disney's bringing
their A-game when it comes to the animation.
Uh, okay. I loved this What If Season 2 trailer.
I thought it looked really good. Visually at
least, I don't know if the stories that it tells
are going to be any better than season one
But we're gonna get some pretty cool concepts
here at the very least including a early version
of the Avengers Which seems to include Captain
Mar-Vell, the Winter Soldier, Ant-Man and T'Chaka,
Black Panther's father That looks like it'll
be pretty cool But we also get a scene of Hela
and the Asgardians going up against Wenwu and
his ten rings We see strange Supreme make a
return from season one as well as Captain Carter.
They're gonna continue those stories, those
being some of the better episodes from season
one. But most importantly, and the thing I'm
most excited to see, is that there appears to
be an episode that focuses on a race on the
planet of Sakaar that involves Iron Man in some
kind of like Hulkbuster racing car, Gamora,
Valkyrie. It looks like something straight out
of Mad Max, and it's gonna be an absolute blast,
it seems. The action looks incredible. Yeah,
that episode looks like it's gonna be pretty
good, not gonna lie. It looks like some of the
episodes rehash the events from Infinity War,
and one of them is going to be about Happy Hogan
in a die-hard Christmas-type situation, which
is gonna be a lot of fun. That episode is actually
gonna drop on Christmas Day. What's really
interesting is that, actually, the first episode
of season two is gonna drop on December 22nd,
and then we're gonna get one episode a day every
day. until the end of the year, which is a
new method of releasing episodes for Disney
Plus, but I'm looking forward to it. I think
it'll be a fun kind of holiday break where it's
like we get to unwrap a new What If present
every day. Yeah, it's like a advent calendar
in a way. Yeah. Of course, our review for What
If Season Two isn't going to drop until early
2024. Yeah, in January, but What If Season
Two will be incorporated into our 2023 Brothers
Awards. It will be in consideration for those
awards. As will... Merry Little Batman, which
is an animated film that will be premiering
on Amazon Prime on December 8th. I wasn't sure
if we were going to review this, but after
seeing this trailer, I'm like, we got it, because
this just looks like the cutest, most fun holiday
Batman film ever. The thing that actually appeals
to me the most is the animation style. Again,
all three of these animated trailers that we're
discussing have very different animation styles.
But Merry Little Batman is definitely the most
unique and the most cartoony, and very much
in keeping with the kind of lighthearted style
of the story that is trying to tell it seems.
Yeah, it's a kid's story that centers around
Damien Wayne, who tries to take up the mantle
of Batman while his father is away during Christmas.
The fact that the Joker is trying to steal
Christmas in Gotham is fantastic. Like, I know
they stole that from The Grinch. But I can't
wait to see that play out on screen, because
the Joker is, you know, pretty much a Grinch.
It looks like the film is going to be filled
with a ton of cute jokes. You know, whether
they're talking about donut crumbs and Batman's
beard, or the Joker asking who gave the little
kid explosives. Honestly, I'm really looking
forward to seeing this movie with my own children.
Yeah, it kind of looks like the Grinch meets
Home Alone meets Batman. What? Sold. Cannot
be more sold. Honestly I don't want to like
this trailer because it's DC but every time
I watch it puts a smile on my face so I think
it'll be a great time this holiday season.
If you guys have Amazon Prime definitely check
it out and definitely check out a review of
it after it drops December 8th.
But I think that does it for all the news for
this episode. Holy cow, that was a lot. Now
let's move on to the main event, where we review
season two of the Marvel Studios television
series, Loki.
Okay, Loki Season 2 was directed by Justin Benson
and Aaron Moorhead and stars Tom Hiddleston,
Owen Wilson, Sofia DiMartino, and Jonathan Majors.
The season immediately continues the story
of Loki Season 1, so right up top, I'm gonna
give you guys your spoiler warning. Don't hurt
yourself by listening to this review before
watching Loki Season 2, which is incredible,
I highly recommend it, and don't skip Loki Season
1 either. So spoiler warning for that season
in this review as well. Yeah, if you haven't
seen Loki season one, definitely do so. It's
fantastic. This is coming from a DC guy. In
my opinion, Loki is the best thing that Marvel's
put out on the Disney Plus platform. I don't
disagree for sure. In season one, the Loki
variant from Avengers Endgame was arrested by
the Time Variance Authority whose job it is
to eliminate branches to what they refer to
as the Sacred Timeline. Along the way, he met
another Loki variant named Sylvie, and the two
worked together to uncover the mystery behind
the TVA and the man who created it, a Kang variant
named He Who Remains. Sylvie killed He Who
Remains, resulting in a branching Marvel multiverse,
and sent Loki back to the TVA. That's the most
basic of recaps for season 1. We rated it 4
stars on this podcast when it came out. Basically,
I remember saying everything about that season
was amazing, the only thing I didn't like was
that I felt the character of Loki lost some
of his agency to Sylvie, who it seemed really
took on the protagonist role. But the same could
not be said of this season too, where Loki
is front and center, supported by a strong cast
of characters, including Sylvie and Mobius,
and a great new addition named Ouroboros played
by Kei-Hui Kuan. I really like this season.
Even more than I liked the first season. And
I agree, I think this is unequivocally Marvel
Studios best series to date. I'm not sure if
I liked this season more than last season,
but I think it's a worthy successor, I guess
you could say, to season one, which I think
is probably the most important thing that Marvel
Studios has put out story-wise after Avengers
Endgame. Yeah, for sure. It really kicked off
the multiversal saga, at least like the reasoning
behind the Marvel multiverse, right? Season
one was great. this season, yeah, I think is
a worthy successor. I think it does a great
job of picking up the pieces where the story
left off. And plus the show is just an audio
visual masterpiece, I think. Holy cow. The
cinematography, the art direction and the production
design is all top tier. It's phenomenal, just
like it was in season one where everything is
gorgeous and often even better looking than
the theatrical films that Marvel Studios produces.
No, I agree. Sometimes I think that the Marvel
films get a little too candy-coated in terms
of the cinematography. Loki is something that
definitely shines in terms of cinematography
in the Marvel Cinematic Universe. Yeah, if
you describe the Marvel Studios theatrical films
as being kind of candy-coated, like the Marvels,
like Guardians of the Galaxy 3, like Ant-Man
Quantumania, I would describe the Loki television
series as being like antique bronze-coated.
It just has that feel. Yeah, yeah, I can see
that. Or like a rich leather and mahogany finish.
Yeah, it just looks different from everything
else. They did a fantastic job of sticking to
a very specific color palette throughout the
show. And I just couldn't take my eyes off the
screen the whole time. It was just gorgeous.
The show sounds great, too, with one of the
most unique and atmospheric scores out of any
media, honestly, film or television series masterfully
composed by Natalie Holt, who I kind of feel
like came out of nowhere, starting with Loki
season one a few years ago. to become one of
the most compelling artists in her craft currently.
Oh yeah, I love the synthetic score that they
have for Loki. It's so damn good. I think we
mentioned in our review of season one that
it just reminds me of something from, I don't
know, like Clockwork Orange or something like
that. Yeah. There's something dated, but it
works really well with the tone of the show.
Yeah, it's atmospheric, it's slightly eerie,
but above all things, it's interesting. So
you have the audio, you have the visuals, and
the direction by Benson and Moorhead. really
well done here. They didn't work on the first
season of Loki, but they did direct some of
the episodes of Moon Knight, which is also one
of Marvel Studios' most cinematic feeling shows.
And I think they have a great command of the
camera and storytelling sense to pull the most
emotion and shock and coolness from a scene.
We know Matt Shackman is going to direct the
Fantastic Four film for Marvel Studios. He was
hired for that based on his work on the WandaVision
television series. And I think Benson and Moorhead
also deserve to be tapped for a full length
feature film in the future, because if Moon
Knight and Loki are anything to go by, they
would do fantastic. Yeah, I mean, Destin Daniel
Cretton is no longer going to direct Avengers
the Kang Dynasty. So why not tap these guys
for that film? I would love that, honestly.
I would love that. Especially since it's just
continuing Kang's story. Right, exactly. And
they did a great job with Victor Timely in this
season. I could totally see that. With how
great everything looks and feels with this show,
I just wish Marvel would take a more artistic
approach like this to their other projects.
And if Vincent and Moorhead were tapped for
the King dynasty, I think they might bring that
more artistic approach to the film. The story
of the Loki series is such that I'm not really
surprised wherever it goes because the nature
of the TVA is that you can kind of take the
story to any time or place imaginable. But
in the first season, you know, we went to first
century Pompeii, alien planets like Lomantis
1. We went to the void at the end of time. Whereas
in season two, we went to such exciting places
like Oklahoma in the 80s, London in the 70s,
and 19th century Chicago. Although I'll admit
that Chicago was an impressive period setting.
But the story really scales back from all the
time hopping to focus more on the TVA and the
ramifications that a multiverse has on that
organization. It was kind of a bit more of a
smaller scale story in that regard, but with
more focus on this primary group of characters.
And I actually really enjoyed the time that
we got to spend at the TVA with Ouroboros and
the gang as they tried to solve the problem
of the temporal loom. Yeah, I didn't mind the
scaled back nature of the series. I thought
six episodes was perfect. I thought they did
enough interesting things with the story that
it didn't really matter that it didn't have
much action or set pieces or something like
that. I just enjoyed where the story took me.
You mentioned that the show doesn't really
surprise you. I was surprised so many times
during this season, and I think that's one
of the reasons I really enjoyed it. Yeah, there
were several cliffhangers at the end of the
episodes that just left me with my jaw open,
you know, like really ready to just binge the
next episode and see what the heck is going
on. Did you binge the series or did you watch
it week to week? I watched the first two episodes.
as they came out and then I watched the last
four episodes. I binged them before I wrote
the review. Okay, yeah, see this series, if
I was watching it week to week, I feel like
I would have just hated that. Cause I would
have just been thinking like the whole week,
like what the hell is happening? For sure,
yeah, it could be infuriating, but also infuriating
is, you know, getting spoiled ahead of time
on what's gonna happen on the show. So I was
at least glad that even though I waited to
binge the series, I wasn't really spoiled on
anything major that happens at the end. Well,
I was spoiled on a few things but I had no context
for them, so it ended up not being too much
of a spoiler. Yeah, I will say that watching
the first two episodes as they came out, my
impression of the show was that it was fine,
you know? I didn't think we really were getting
into the meat of the story until I binged the
last four and those last four episodes starting
with Chicago and Victor Timely leading up into
the- final two episodes, which I thought were
absolutely fantastic in movie quality, there
was like a vast difference in the quality of
the show, where the first two episodes weren't
bad, but the last two episodes were just sublime.
Oh man, yeah, the last two episodes took the
show to a whole other level. I would agree
that the first couple of episodes, I thought
they were okay, I agree with you, but the last
two episodes does things that I never thought
Marvel Studios would ever do in terms of like
artistic quality for a series based on a comic
book. Yeah, or what Marvel Studios would do
for the character of Loki. You know, where he
goes in this story is such fascinating character
growth based on where he came from. Oh, yeah.
And honestly, like, I still don't even fully
understand what happened. All I know is that
it was beautiful. Well, we'll dive into it
in our character breakdown, starting with Loki
played by Tom Hiddleston. Now, Tom Hiddleston's
portrayal of Loki. by this time has transcended
his peers and become something more than a
simple supervillain role, something that feels
significant and mythic in a way that no singular
Marvel role has before, something that only
Hiddleston himself could inhabit as one of
the very best actors of his generation. I think
he outdid himself here, and while I can only
hope we see this character again, the ending
of this season would be one hell of a send
off for Loki. Oh yeah, I definitely agree. What
they're doing with this character is so much
better than what they're doing with his brother
Thor in movies like Love and Thunder. It's
like no comparison. Yeah, Thor should be ashamed.
Like I hope Chris Hemsworth watches Loki season
two and goes to Marvel Studios and says, I want
to do something like that. I'm sick of the
dick and fart jokes and fucking bow the God
of Dumplings. Let's do something real with
the character of Thor and give him his proper
send off if Chris Hemsworth returns to the
role. which you probably will. Loki's arc this
season had less to do with Sylvie, which I
was happy with. Here, it was more about stopping
He Who Remains, then about saving the TVA,
and then saving time itself. All because, after
being humbled by the TVA in season 1, he made
friends who he felt were worth saving. You know,
he transformed over the course of all his on-screen
appearances from the most selfish being ever.
with simple aspirations of a throne to actually
achieving a throne through the most selfless
act of eternal sacrifice. It's a beautiful
story. Oh man, yeah. To go from the first Avengers
movie where he's saying that he's Loki and
he's burdened with glorious purpose to learn
in this show that purpose is more burden than
glory, the arc from one to the other is incredibly
profound. Yeah, especially since he's doing
it for his friends, you know, and his role is
so lonely now perched atop that throne all
by himself outside of time. But, you know, it's
something he's willing to do to ensure the
survival of those he loves, which is not something
that you ever could have conceived of the character
based on his actions in the first Avengers film.
I liken his arc, particularly in this season,
to Bill Murray's arc in Groundhog Day. You know,
they're very similar. He sort of attains enlightenment
over the course of. living many lives as it
were and again profound it's very interesting
to see a character who was a villain become
so unbelievably selfless yeah to see real change
believable change is always thought-provoking
it's cathartic yeah let's move on to mobius
who's played by owen wilson i gotta say owen
wilson is the most likable actor on the planet
Like, I love seeing him in this role. He's fantastic
as Mobius, especially later on in the season
when you got to see the TVA agents in their
lives on the Timeline branches. And we got
to see that Mobius was a jet ski dealer named
Don, which kind of went full circle with Mobius's
fascination with jet skis in the TVA. Yeah,
I think his story really sold the notion of
how tragic it was that these characters in the
TVA lost lives that they could have lived on
Timeline branches. Yeah, what did you think
of him retiring from the TVA at the end of
the show? I mean, I'm really happy for him.
I don't know quite how that's going to work
out with a Deadpool movie because he's supposed
to make a cameo in that or something like that.
But I was happy to see the character kind of
get what he always wanted. Yeah, it was kind
of bittersweet watching him watch his variant
take care of his kids. You know, we know that
he can actually resume his life since that other
Don already exists. But I like to think that
Mobius kind of spends his days out on the water
on his jet ski or something. It was quite a
touching moment though at the very end there.
Yeah, absolutely. Let's move on to Ouroboros
who is played by Keihei Kuan. I hope I'm pronouncing
that right. But he was such a fantastic addition
to the Loki cast. He fits so perfectly in with
the show's atmosphere and sensibilities. It's
almost like he was always a part of the show
from the beginning. You know, it was just incredible
casting. And I hope that the actor blows up
Hollywood. and shows up in everything because
he's just so enjoyable to watch that it's impossible
for him to be overexposed in my opinion. Haha,
I would agree. I mean, this is the first we're
seeing Kim after his Oscar win, I believe.
I don't know, I haven't seen the new Indiana
Jones movie. I think he's actually in that.
But it was great to see him again after, you
know, watching everything everywhere all at
once. And you're right, he fit in perfectly
into this world, which itself is fairly quirky.
Yeah, he could get a very quirky yet endearing
type vibe as the technician behind the TVA,
but I also thought it was kind of funny when
he turned out to be this physics teacher and
failed science fiction writer. Yeah, that was
a great choice. Much like Owen Wilson as Mobius,
I think the casting director should be commended
for getting actors that are just very enjoyable
to watch, very endearing, and inhabit the roles
and the world of Loki so well. Let's move on
to Sylvie, who's played by Sofia DiMartino,
reprising her role from season one. She did
have a smaller role here, a more supporting
character to Loki's main narrative, which I
thought was nice. She did have a worse haircut.
I hated her haircut in this season. Like, I
don't usually comment on characters' hair, but
the fact that it was like a mullet just kind
of threw me. I liked her hair last season, but
no, I agree. It was a choice. wrong one. I
like that the show completely ditched the whole
awkward romantic subplot between the two Loki's
because I think a lot of critics rightfully
so felt that it was just kind of like incestuous
and creepy. Here Sylvie was mainly just someone
who wanted everyone to have free will and the
right to existence. So she's kind of like a
freedom fighter in that regard. Less extreme
than she was in season one but more likeable.
I did find it interesting that like immediately
after killing He Who Remains she decided to
go live her life working at McDonald's. There
was like a huge product placement for McDonald's.
I was like, what the heck? Absolutely, I don't
know how I feel about that. But like you think
about like one of the most mundane scenarios
for her. I think that's what she wanted for
herself. You know, she had spent her entire
life living in apocalypses and living on the
run that the ideal existence for her was the
exact opposite. You know, routine, a lack of
excitement, things like that. It made sense
for the character and despite the fact that,
you know, she killed He-He Remains and kind
of caused this whole mess, you still felt for
her. True, yeah. And she ended up going right
back to the very same spot at the end of the
show. Which I thought was great. You know,
she had already found where she wanted to end
up. Her happy ending, as it were. Yeah, but
considering Asgardians live for about 10,000
years, I wonder how long that'll stick. Before
she's moving on beyond McDonald's and getting
back into the action, as it were. Who knows?
But if this is the last we ever see of Sylvie,
I thought it was fantastic. I think her whole
character arc was quite brilliant as well. Honestly,
I hope it's not the last we see of Sylvie.
I definitely think there is potential for her
to go on to become a mainstay in the MCU, whether
it's as a hero or a villain. How would you feel
about that? Well, I mean, honestly, I hope
this isn't the last we see of any of the characters.
I hope we get a Loki season three, you know,
so. Well, the showrunner said that that's not
going to happen, I believe. Yeah, I heard that
too, which is a shame. But I also heard rumors
that Loki will appear in Secret Wars, but you
know, rumors say that everybody's going to appear
in Secret Wars, so who knows? Who the hell
is it? I'm going to be in Secret Wars. Let's
go ahead and move on to Victor Timely, played
by Jonathan Majors. God, I hope Jonathan Majors
didn't do that shit that they said he did to
his girlfriend. I hope he doesn't get convicted
with criminal charges. And I hope Marvel Studios
sticks with him, because if this season showed
anything, it shows that he's a really talented
guy, you know, is meek and stuttering Victor
Timely. is so different from his cocky and
eccentric he-who-remains, who is also so different
from his angry and menacing king of the conqueror
from quantumania. I was impressed with his performance
here, especially at his ability to elicit sympathy
in the scene where Sylvie was gonna kill him.
Oh yeah, totally. I mean, for an actor that
people know is probably not so sympathetic in
real life, to elicit sympathy on screen and
still have the viewer experience that emotion
is evidence that he's a fantastic actor. I
agree with you, I hope we get to see more of
him. I know a lot of people are angry with
him and want to cancel him, and maybe rightfully
so, but people make mistakes and I think, you
know, as long as you leave room for redemption,
hopefully he takes that opportunity and maybe
hopefully is able to come back. There were other
major characters in the series including Hunter
B-15, Casey, Ravonna Renslayer, and Miss Minutes,
but there wasn't too much going on arc wise
with them that I think merits discussion. So
let's go ahead and move on to the story highlights.
Hey guys, Marvelous Joe here to tell all of
you that if you're going to buy Marvel and
DC stuff for the holidays this year, do it for
20% off. I mean, that just makes financial
sense, right? Save some money this year on your
nerd gear when you visit cufflinks.com and
use the code Duel20, that's D-U-E-L-20, at checkout.
Cufflinks.com has the very best in men's accessories
in a variety of geek franchises including Marvel,
DC, Star Wars, Star Trek. Harry Potter, Game
of Thrones, and more. Check them out if you're
a fan, or if you know a fan, to shop for this
season. I, for one, got a pair of Loki socks
this year because I knew Loki Season Two was
coming out and I wanted to rep this awesome
series, and also because they're comfortable
and pretty stylish in green and black. You can
pair them with the Loki cufflinks to really
pay tribute to the God of Mischief, or maybe
rock them with the Thor hammer man's tie to
rep the God of Thunder. No matter your choice,
You can't go wrong with any of the great gifts
at cufflinks.com where again, you can get 20%
off anything at the site with code dual20.
Thanks guys! Alright, episode 1 was titled Ouroboros.
After Loki gets sent to the Time Variance Authority
by Sylvie at the Citadel at the end of time,
he begins slipping between the past and present.
While trying to warn the TVA of the threat of
he who remains and his variance, Loki and with
help from the technician named Ouroboros, who
deduces that the issue is the result of an
overloaded temporal loom, a device that refines
raw time into physical timelines. Ouroboros
constructs a temporal aura extractor device
that pulls Loki from the time stream into the
present TVA. General Dox, after receiving orders
not to prune the new timelines from Judge Gamble,
rallies a group of hunters to allegedly find
Sylvie, who is in hiding at a McDonald's in
1982 Oklahoma. There was some good setup here
that got pay off in later episodes such as
Loki pruning himself from the future into the
past. I thought it was clever when they paid
that off later in the season. Yeah, that was
sort of a mystery that was running for a while.
Like, who pruned him at that moment? Yeah, and
why was Sylvie there and all that stuff? It
was a good mystery. What was really interesting
was the answer that we had at the end of Loki
season one, which was... Where is Loki or when
is Loki when he's talking to Mobius and Mobius
has no idea who he is and we see the statue
of Kink. We theorized that maybe Loki was sent
to an alternate version of the TVA, but as we
learned here, there's only one version of the
TVA no matter how many branching timelines there
are, and Loki was merely sent into the distant
past of the TVA. Which is actually pretty trippy
knowing that time runs differently at the TVA.
Right, there's a past, present, future, even
though it technically exists outside of the
timelines, right? That's pretty interesting.
But we saw him go back and forth in time at
the TVA, from a point to where he remains was
in charge of the organization, to later on
where he kind of removed himself and put in
those figureheads, as it were. The timekeepers.
Exactly. Let's go to move on to episode two,
which was called Breaking Brad. Trying to find
Sylvie, Loki and Mobius track down X-5 in 1977
London. believing that this TVA hunter found
her due to his Tempad going dark. They discover
that X-Five is hiding and living on the sacred
timeline as a famous actor named Brad Wolf.
They apprehend him and bring him back to the
TVA where they learn through interrogation that
X-Five learned of Sylvie's whereabouts before
abandoning his mission. TVA clerk Casey deduces
that former head judge Ravonna Renslayer received
a message from the artificial intelligence Miss
Minutes before both disappeared. and Ouroboros
warns that he cannot fix the temporal loom from
meltdown without the temporal aura of He Who
Remains to open the containment doors. Loki,
Mobius, and X-Five travel to 1982 to meet with
Sylvie, where X-Five reveals that General Dox
and her group are secretly pruning the new
timelines. They fight and capture her to prevent
any further pruning. This was I think maybe
the most inconsequential episode of the season.
I just wasn't really interested in the character
of Brad Wolf or X-Five. that he was kind of
an unnecessary addition to the cast of characters.
Yeah, no, I agree. It took me a while to realize
that Brad and X5 were the same person, even
though they were saying that they were looking
for X5. Like, I didn't I didn't quite catch
who X5 even was until later on, considering
the fact that Brad and X5 looked fairly different.
Like X5 had a beard. Brad didn't. It was confusing
for a while. Yeah, the hair thing kind of threw
me right. If this season had any missteps, I
think the biggest one was probably around the
character of Brad. Let's go ahead and move on
to episode 3, which was called 1893. In 1868
Chicago, Miss Minutes has Ravonna Renslayer
leave a copy of the TVA guidebook for young
Victor Timely, a variant of He Who Remains,
to find. In the present, Ouroboros deduces
that without He Who Remains temporal aura to
open the blast doors, they could still use
Miss Minutes to override the controls. Locine
Mobius track her to 1893 Chicago where they
find her and Renslayer observing Victor Timely
who has built TVA prototypes as well as fake
inventions as scams for money. Sylvie interrupts
in an attempt to kill Timely but he escapes
with Renslayer and Miss Minnitz who want him
to take He Who Remains Place running the TVA
at the Citadel at the end of time alongside
them. Miss Minnitz gets shut off after coming
onto Timely and Sylvie appears. only to spare
Victor and have Loki and Mobius take him to
the TVA. She sends Renslayer to the Citadel
at the end of time with Miss Minutes. I didn't
love what they did with Miss Minutes here. I
thought it was really weird that she was in
love with Victor Timely. Yeah, it kinda seemed
unnecessary to me as well, especially considering
that it didn't really go anywhere. But Miss
Minutes was incredibly uncomfortable during
this whole season, I thought. Like, especially
in the later episode when they're killing all
those TVA hunters and she's like smiling that
creepy cartoon smile as they're all being crushed
to death. It was effectively creepy, but was
it a necessary creep factor? I almost wish
that they used Miss Minutes more perhaps as
the main villain at the end. With how creepy
she was, I think she deserved a better send-off
than merely just being shut off by Ouroboros.
I agree, I didn't love how Miss Minutes and
Rentslayer's arcs were just kind of dropped
at the very end. There were a few things that
kind of just became irrelevant as the show
decided to kind of explore a little bit more
of like Loki's psyche and what he's going through
personally. Yeah, Ramona Renslayer was merely
pruned and sent to the void at the end of time
where she was I think devoured by Eliath. Although
that being said, you know, Miss Minence and
Renslayer weren't really in the season until
this episode, so they were really merely side
plots. Yeah, absolutely. I really liked the
setting of late 19th century Chicago. I thought
they did really well. with the cinematography,
with the costuming, with the set design. Yeah,
that carnival seemed pretty interesting. What
did you think of the idea of Victor Timely
as a scam artist? That threw me. I didn't see
that coming. That was a surprise. I thought
he was a legit scientific inventor. And I didn't
know if it was just because he was a variant
in this universe that he wasn't like the scientific
genius or whatever. I guess he still was. He
just didn't have the technology to create what
he really wanted to. Exactly. Yeah, he was
limited by the technology of his time. He was
a genius, he was also running scams, so it
was a little bit vague for a minute there as
to whether or not he was just a loony variant
or if he actually was smart. I'm glad it was
the latter. Let's go ahead and move on to episode
4 which is called Heart of the TVA. Miss Minutes
reveals to Renslayer that she was once a commander
of He Who Remains Army and co-leader at the
end of time before he had her memories erased.
that will prevent the Temporal Loom from melting
down and allow it to accommodate more timelines.
Meanwhile, Renslayer and Miss Minutes attempt
to overtake the TVA by recruiting General Docs
and her group of hunters in custody. All but
X5 reject Renslayer's offer and are killed.
X5 kidnaps Timely, forcing Goroboros to shut
off Miss Minutes. Sylvie enchants X5, forcing
him to prune Ribona. With Timely saved, he opens
the containment doors with his Temporal Aura.
and volunteers to activate the throughput multiplier.
However, they're too late and the temporal
radiation turns him into spaghetti as he approaches
the temporal loom. I liked this episode. I
thought there was like a lot of tension, you
know, back and forth where you are riddled
with anxiety as the clock is ticking and Victor
Timely is kidnapped. And then you're relieved
when he's rescued. And then you're shocked when
he is spaghettified in the temporal radiation.
I thought there was a lot of great like emotion
pulling in this episode. Yeah, that was pretty
wild when he just straight up was like disintegrated
like that, like spaghetti. Did not see that
coming. But also I kind of felt overall with
this main conflict of the whole temporal loom
overloading, it was a little vague as to what
exactly the consequences were going to be until
you saw Victor Tynely spaghettified. Yeah, and
then as you saw the temporal loom explode and
everybody's just standing there like, what the
fuck do we do? That was the season's best cliffhanger,
I think. Absolutely. Where you just saw Loki's
face and then end credits. I'm like what the
heck is gonna happen now? Exactly. I was like
is this the season finale? What's going on?
Let's go to move on to episode 5 which is called
science fiction Loki escapes the meltdown by
time-slipping to the branch timelines where
his friends from the TVA are from Discovering
that they were reset to their original lives
He finds Ouroboros aka Doug who is a theoretical
physics teacher and failed science fiction writer
and enlists his help in building a Tempad to
use to recruit the others to go back in time
to the TVA and succeed where they had previously
failed. Loki convinces everyone but Sylvie,
who gets him to admit that his true motivation
is to keep from losing his friends, and concedes
that their lives outside the TVA may be better
for them. Nonetheless, as the Temporal Loom
can't sustain the branches, everything spaghettifies
anyway, forcing Loki to gain control of his
time slipping. and allowing him to travel to
any point in time and space. The scene where
Loki apparently abandons the mission for the
betterment of his friends, and we see Sylvie
visiting that record store and just listen
to an album as everything starts going to shit
was nightmare fuel. It was so surreal. Oh,
absolutely. Yeah, it's terrifying. After seeing
what happened to Victor Timely in the previous
episode, and then seeing everything spaghettify,
It turned out to be quite the horrifying effect.
Like every time it would happen, I actually
felt this sense of dread. Especially as they're
like running from it in slow motion and you
know there's just like no escape. You just
wait for it to hit you. Yeah, exactly, nightmare
fuel. The effect itself kind of reminded me
of string theory, which essentially states that
particles are strings that move through time
and space, and those were all just kind of like
disappearing, those strings. Yeah, exactly.
Moving on to the final episode. episode 6 called
Glorious Purpose. In it, Loki travels to before
the loom's meltdown and fails repeatedly to
get the throughput multiplier to work. After
successfully activating it, he learns it's all
pointless as the loom will never be able to
accommodate infinitely growing branches. Loki
then has to travel back to before Sylvie killed
He Who Remains where he learns that the loom
is a failsafe that will protect the sacred
timeline by deleting all the branches along
with the TVA. and that destroying the loom
would lead to infinite realities and the multiversal
war. He Who Remains states the only way to
save the loom is to kill Sylvie, which Loki
rejects. Loki travels through time to confer
with Mobius, who tells him that purpose is more
about burden than glory, but the hard thing
to do is the thing that has to be done. He then
travels to visit Sylvie, who tells him, sometimes
it's okay to destroy something if there's hope
you can replace it with something better. With
that in mind, Loki travels to the time of the
meltdown and destroys the loom, giving the
multiverse a chance to exist by replacing the
device and overseeing the timelines from a
throne at the center of the timelines that become
Yggdrasil, the world tree. Mobius retires from
the TVA, who now tracks the variants of he who
remains. Uh, brilliant episode, brilliant episode,
incredible. Wait, so Loki doesn't become a new
loom, transferring chaotic time into solidified
time? Yeah, he essentially replaces the loom.
He becomes his own loom, preventing the multiversal
war. Okay, that's what I thought. You know,
the start of the episode is really about him
trying to get the throughput multiplier to work.
And it's so tragic that he had to spend centuries
learning everything he could from Ouroboros
about theoretical physics, only for it to all
be moot because the loom could never be upgraded
enough to accommodate infinite branches, you
know? That was tragic. And then the big reveal
from He Who Remains stating that The loom is
just a fail safe to protect the sacred timeline.
That was a big jaw drop moment. Just so many
good scenes all leading up into the end, which
felt so poignant. The final shot of Loki sitting
on his throne, accepting his role was a brilliant
bit of acting from Tom Hiddleston for one,
but such a fascinating way to end the series.
It was a fantastic ending, such a good ending.
I'm kind of glad there wasn't any kind of after
credit scenes because it didn't need it. Like
just end with that mic drop. Boom, there you
go. Yeah, you know, I definitely, of course,
poured over the end credits looking for a scene,
but when that ended up being it, you settle
in with the closure of what you just saw. And
on my part, I felt really pleased with the
way the season had gone. Really pleased, but
also really sad. It's a great mixture of emotions
that I think just are a testament to how good
this season was. For sure, yeah. Every time
you watch a good show that ends, doesn't that
usually come with a bit of sadness? Because
it's over? I mean, it depends on the show. Some
shows have terrible endings like Game of Thrones,
and some like this have very great endings where
you're sad that you won't get to be with these
characters again, but you're also happy with
their lives the way they turned out and you
don't really want to see any of that unravel.
Yeah. But that does a further review for Loki
Season 2. God, it is a shame that it is over.
And I feel like we'll have similar sentiments
about Doom Patrol season four in our next episode
when we review that. Just a great bit of long
form television storytelling from Marvel and
DC. That'll be bittersweet saying goodbye to
this year. Yeah, with MCU, you know, kind of
sending off Tony Stark and Steve Rogers, this
is another hit, I think to the fandom, but like
in the best way. So kudos to Marvel Studios
for getting something right, which I feel like
they haven't done in a while, because I enjoyed
it a lot. Yeah, absolutely. With gorgeous cinematography,
extraordinary music score, and a matchless
cast of characters, Loki season two to date
offers the best that Marvel Studios television
has to offer. I'm giving this season four and
a half stars, a fresh rating on Rotten Tomatoes.
And I think that makes sense, especially with
how profound the season was in particular.
It was very different from what I thought it
was going to be. In a way, it defied my expectations
for the better, just in how many shocks and
surprises there ended up being, and how great
the ending was. I agree. I actually also rated
season one 4.5 stars. You disagreed with me
because you said that Loki was out of character,
but no, I've always been a fan of the show,
and you're just a fake fan. Shut up. No, go
back and listen to our review of season one
and I think you'll find that my gripes with
that season still hold up. But no, season two
was fantastic. I liked it more than season one.
Four and a half stars. But that does it for
this review. Let us know what you guys thought
about the show by writing to us at dynamicduelpodcast.gmail.com
or by visiting us on Instagram or X. You can
find links to all of our accounts by checking
out our show notes or visiting our website at
dynamicduel.com. And on our site, you can also
find a link to our Patreon page. where you could
join our Dynamic 2.0 tier and chat with us
and fellow listeners, our Fantastic Four tier,
which gets you bonus content each month, our
X-Force tier that makes you an executive producer
of this podcast, or our newest tier that lets
you join our Dynamike Podcast Network. If you
can't join Patreon, you can still support the
show by signing up for our e-newsletter, also
at dynamicdoll.com, so you'll never miss an
episode. And don't forget guys to visit our
website to leave a donation for Pop Culture
Classroom which will get you a digital poster
of our upcoming charity duel episode in December,
Alfred Pennyworth vs Edwin Jarvis. As I mentioned
earlier, our next episode is going to be another
review where we discuss season 4 of Doom Patrol.
Now this is a little bit late this episode.
I think the series ended on November 9th I want
to say. Yes. But to save face, I blame Jonathan.
I blame myself. I started a new job recently,
so it's been hard just, you know, not only
finishing the season, but reviewing it as well.
But yeah, we're going to talk all about the
show next week. Doom Patrol is fantastic. I'm
expecting great things from it. But that does
it for this episode. We want to give a big thanks
to our executive producers. Ken Johnson, John
Strausky, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Balcombe,
Mickey Mathengian, Brandon Estregard, Nathaniel
Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Nick Ibbonto, Austin Wiselowski,
AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Adam Spies, and
Andrew Schunk for helping make this podcast
possible. And we'll talk to you guys next week.
Up up and away, true believers. Eat spaghetti
no regretty. Hello gamers, are you ready to
dive into a video game podcast unlike any other?
Then look no further. Welcome to Console Combat.
I'm John. And I'm Dean. We're here to give you
the info on the latest releases, upcoming titles,
and everything else that's making waves in the
gaming universe. That's right Dean, but that's
not all we do here at Console Combat. Each week
we'll put two video game characters against
each other in our epic battle simulator Cortex.
After a brief speculation, Cortex ultimately
determines who would emerge victorious by running
1,000 battles in its adopted Monte Carlo simulator.
Who has the mightiest punch, the fastest speed,
or the most cunning strategy? On Console Combat,
we'll put that to the test. Essentially, we're
a multiversal Super Smash Bros. style podcast.
So whether you're a casual player or a hardcore
gaming enthusiast, there's something for everyone
here at Console Combat. So grab your controllers,
strap in, and let's get ready for some action.