you
Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the superiority
between Marvel and DC by comparing their characters
in stat-based battle simulations. I'm Johnny
DC. And I'm his twin brother, Marvelous Joe.
And welcome to the 2021 holiday animal battle,
that sounds weird, charity episode. Yeah, every
year around Giving Tuesday, which is today,
Jonathan and I like to host a charity duel between
two of the more whimsical Marvel and DC characters.
This episode, we're going to find out who would
win in a fight between Gleek and Hitmonkey.
They're both monkey characters for their respective
universes, and we think it'll be pretty funny
considering, you know, monkeys are just hilarious.
Yeah, especially little tiny monkeys like these
guys. You know what's not hilarious though?
COVID-19. Which I have right now recovering
from. So if it sounds like I'm out of breath,
it's because I am. And if it sounds echoey,
it's because I'm in my quarantine space recording.
So apologies for the audio this time. Yeah,
I mean, I told Jonathan that we could skip this
week, but he was willing to push forward and
keep our record of never missing an episode
of this podcast going on six years now. Yeah,
I mean, I don't feel terrible. I do encourage
anyone who can get vaccinated to get vaccinated.
I think that's really helped me. So yeah, I
didn't want to miss this episode, especially
this one, because this one's gonna be fun. Yeah,
I can't wait to get into it before we go into
the histories and backstories of Gleek and Hitmonkey.
we're gonna go over the comic book movie news
from the past week, of which there was just
one news item, and that's the DC League of
Super Pets official trailer. So we'll talk about
that, then get into the duel. As always, we
list our segment times and our episode description,
so feel free to check out the show notes if
you wanna skip ahead to a particular topic.
And guys, if you listened to one of our charity
duel episodes before, you know that every year
we give to a different organization. For the
past couple of years, we've given to Pop Culture
Classroom, but this year, in light of COVID,
we're switching it up a bit. What we're going
to do is raise money for the HealthWell Foundation,
which is a leading nonprofit dedicated to improving
access to care for America's underinsured.
If you're listening to us from outside of the
US, you probably don't get this, but we have
a shitty healthcare system and some people can't
afford to pay for the healthcare services they
receive, especially during these trying times.
So with this organization, when health insurance
is not enough, they fill the gap by assisting
with copays, premiums, deductibles, and out-of-pocket
expenses. through their crowd-sourced disease-related
funds. What this podcast is gonna do is set
up a Facebook fundraiser. So if you guys aren't
following us on Facebook, go ahead and search
for Dynamic Duel DC versus Marvel, and you can
find the fundraiser there. Go ahead and donate
any amount between today, giving Tuesday, and
Christmas Day. And at the end of December,
Jonathan and I will pick two random donors to
award a free Dynamic Duel card game to. Jonathan
and I have made a couple of card games. that
are Marvel and DC based, and we wanna give
it to two of you donors. So if you feel so inclined
to this Giving Tuesday, again, visit this podcast's
Facebook page and donate to the HealthWell Foundation
using that pinned post. And because we want
you guys so badly to donate to this organization,
we are currently making all of our archived
episodes available to the listening public.
Instead of subscribing to our show, we want
you guys to instead put that money toward our
fundraiser. And it doesn't matter what amount
you donate, anything helps. But during this
giving season, we appreciate any amount of
giving. So those of you who are currently subscribed
to this show on Spotify, I don't believe you'll
get charged for the month of December. And those
who are currently subscribed to us on Patreon,
you'll still get access to all of your standard
bonus perks, including the bonus episodes,
access to our Discord server, blooper reels,
and more. I just wanna give a quick special
shout out to one of our patrons, Dustin Balcom,
when he found out that I had COVID. His family
sent my family a couple of pizzas, which was
just awesome. My family and I are super grateful
for the act of generosity. We really appreciate
it, and I just wanted to give you a shout out
and say thank you very much. But with that out
of the way, quick to the No Prize. A No Prize
is an award Marvel used to give out up until
the 90s to fans. Our version, the dynamic dual
No Prize, is a digital award we post on social
media that Jonathan personally draws for those
who we feel gave the best answer to our question
of the week. Last week's question was in regards
to the Spider-Man No Way Home trailer that we
got a few weeks ago. We asked you guys who
has been your favorite live action Spider-Man
villain and why. We got a few great answers
for this. Let's go ahead and run down our honorable
mentions as well as the no prize winner. Our
first honorable mention goes to Jacob Bell who
said, Hey guys, this is Jacob Bell. My favorite
live action Spider-Man villain has got to be
the vulture. I think Michael Keaton. plays
a great villain and I honestly think that the
Vulture and his motivations are probably the
best just because, I mean, you can really almost
get on board with what he's doing and also
the twist with him being Liz's dad was just
incredible and so I love Michael Keaton as
the Vulture, that's my favorite. And yeah, I
would have to agree. I'd say the Vulture is
probably one of the MCU's like top three villains.
Yeah, while most Spider-Man villains are seeking
power, the vulture in Spider-Man Homecoming
was really motivated by survival and providing
for his family. Of course, it got a little bit
out of hand and he needed to be stopped, but
it was really easy to identify with the character.
And Michael Keaton just gave great performance.
Yeah, the way they adapted his costume from
the comics too, like, mwah, chef's kiss, so
well done. Oh yeah, movie version of the vulture
was a huge improvement over the comic book
version. Although we'll be getting to a vulture
duel before long on this podcast. Our next
honorable mention goes to Benjamin Alves, who
said, Hi guys, I think Alfred Molina as Doc
Ock was the best Spider-Man villain. He's such
a great actor. I love all his movies. And I
love the part where he was with Otme on the
building. So menacing. It was awesome. I think,
and it's just, there's no other word to describe
it. Bye. Great answer, Benjamin. Yeah, Doctor
Octopus is definitely one of Spider-Man's best
villains to ever appear in live action. We
all know that Spider-Man 2 is one of the best
Spider-Man movies ever made, mainly because
of how great Doc Ock was in that film. Alfred
Molina just knocked it out of the park. He
also created a Spider-Man villain that we could
sympathize with. And there's no discounting
the design of those tentacles, right? Those
were badass looking. Oh, man. Yeah, those were
really well designed. It's no surprise that
Doctor Octopus is many people's favorite Spider-Man
villain. Yeah, and one of the reasons why he's
playing such a big role in Spider-Man No Way
Home allegedly. Our final honorable mention
goes to Marquis High, who said, Hello gentlemen,
so Marquis High here. Just give me a call. I'd
say for the villain, must off-top go with Michael
Keaton. Always just a great actor, even if he
doesn't really know too much about the characters
that he's acting. But besides that, I definitely
would have to go with Doc Ock. He's always
just... had more of a human aspect, very relatable.
And the fact that he turns into a potential
hero is something big. Marquis has a great radio
voice, doesn't he? Yeah, he does. Yeah, but
great answer. This is kind of a combination
of the previous two where he mentioned both
Vulture and Doctor Octopus. I think those two
guys are widely regarded among the Spider-Man
fan community as the best villains to appear
in these movies. Hopefully. We get to see them
team up in the upcoming Spider-Man No Way Home
movie, but we don't know yet what kind of role
Vulture will play in that film. We want to give
a quick shout out to Evan Tompke for visiting
our website to record an answer, but the winner
of this week's No Prize is Miggy Mathengian
who said, Hey guys, this is Miggy and my favorite
live action Spider-Man villain is Green Goblin.
In my opinion, it's best when the villain makes
it personal. And he definitely did that when
he attacked his aunt and girlfriend. He also
endangered a lot of innocent lives, like when
he attacked the Macy's Day Parade and dropped
those kids off the Washington Bridge and attacked
the Daily Bugle. And he continued to ruin Peter's
life by deteriorating his relationship with
Harry even after his death. More so than any
other Spider-Man villain, I would say that
Green Goblin has a knack for making it personal,
not just in the movies, but also the comics.
Oh yeah, he makes Peter Parker's life a living
hell. I really like the way they exemplified
that in these movies. Like Miggy said, even
affecting Peter Parker after his death. When
you have a villain that not only attacks the
hero's grandma, but also drops a bunch of kids
in a cable car off a bridge, you know you're
dealing with some hardcore shit. Yeah, he's
like borderline Joker, right? Yeah, if like
the Joker were way better and on Marvel. Just
like that, for sure. He's a villain that's so
good they included him twice in both Spider-Man
and The Amazing Spider-Man 2. But I'm really
looking forward to Willem Dafoe's return as
the character in the upcoming No Way Home film.
So congrats again to Mickey, Matt, and Keon
for winning this week's No Prize. If you, the
listener, want a shot at winning your own No
Prize, stay tuned to later on this episode when
we'll be asking another Question of the Week.
And now that that's done, onto the news!
Okay, so last week we got our first official
trailer of the DC League of Super Pets film.
And I gotta say it's different from what I thought
it was going to be. I was hoping it was going
to be based on the children's book series DC
Super Pets that is pretty faithful to the comic
books. This movie however is not. Yeah, it seems
like it's not about a super team of pets of
the main DC superheroes. It looks like it's
a film about these shelter animals that happen
to get powers. So it seems like this isn't like
Ace the Bat Hound or the terrific What's It,
they're entirely original characters. Well,
I mean, Kevin Hart's character is named Ace
in the movie, who's not supposed to have any
powers, looks like he has invulnerability.
They have Chip the Squirrel, but he doesn't
have Green Lantern powers, he has electricity
powers apparently. The Turtle is the only one
that makes sense, because the Turtle's apparently
named Merton, you know, Merton McSnurdle, the
Turtle. You know, we talked about him in our
What's It versus Spider-Man episode, Still one
of my favorite episodes. I love that guy. But
in the movie he's called Shell on Wheels. Yeah,
I guess the pig whose name is PB for pot belly.
It doesn't even look like it's Wonder Woman's
pet. Just gives the characters like random
names. I don't think those will stick. Do you
think by the end of this movie each of these
shelter pets will be adopted by the Justice
League? I hope so, honestly. You know, I think
the turtle should be adopted by the Flash. You
know, the pig by Wonder Woman. Chip becomes
a Green Lantern. And we get to see Wonder Woman,
Green Lantern, Cyborg, Batman in this trailer,
which was a huge surprise. They have different
costumes. Not really in love with the designs
here, but that's fine. I imagine we won't be
seeing too much of them. I like the designs
of the DC characters. You know, they're very
like Incredibles-esque. It was cool to hear
John Krasinski as Superman. Yeah, I think he
sounds pretty good as the character. What did
you think of the rocks depiction of Krypto?
It was fine, it was fine. As was Kevin Hart
as Ace and Vanessa Bayer as PB. Diego Luna,
I guess, does the voice for Chip, which this
trailer revealed. Mark Maron, apparently, is
the voice of Lex Luthor in this film. Oh, interesting.
Yeah. The same guy that was in the Joker movie
and who also like was dissing comic book films?
Yes. Okay. He just likes DC. What can I say?
But there's a few more cast members that we
still don't know what role they're going to
play, like Kate McKinnon, Keanu Reeves, Ben
Schwartz and Jamila Jamil. Maybe there's gonna
be like other members of the Justice League
we don't know yet. Maybe one of them is gonna
be the cat, Streaky, who has a very different
superpower in this movie. That was weird. Yeah,
the tail like shoots out rockets and flames
and stuff. I was like, what? It can't be Streaky.
I'm not sure I'm loving like the random power
assignment that a lot of these guys have. Me
neither. But you know, it's a movie for kids.
It's supposed to be as whimsical as possible.
I think that also explains the jokes, which
I'm also not in love with. A lot of them didn't
really land for me. I think felt like the timing
was off. Like when Crypto was talking to that
other dog about like the federation of exes,
the dog was like, why it's taking my owner so
long? I was like, okay. Yeah, that was horrible
delivery. Yeah. It was a little bit too slow.
Also the joke about like, they should call
me Iron Man. Nah. Dude, what is up with DC animation's
obsession with Iron Man? Like you get the Iron
Man reference in this movie and in Lego Batman
you had the reference with Batman's Batcave
password. Iron Man sucks, what can I say? They're
just jealous as hell. They're just jealous.
There was also another Marvel reference in this
when Krypto was basically saying with great
power comes great responsibility. Wait, what?
He says when one has an abundance of power,
they have a certain duty to use that power.
Exactly. Same thing. Sure. Yeah. I don't know.
I can't quite say I'm looking forward to this
movie just yet. Well, I'm guessing this is
going to be an origin story where we see these
characters evolve into the team you know and
love, just maybe with different powers. Maybe.
Maybe I need another trailer or two, which
we'll probably get. The movie doesn't come out
until May of next year, so we have some time.
But this all brings us to our question of the
week.
Who is your favorite DC or Marvel animal hero
and why? There's a lot of them to choose from,
both on DC and Marvel, but let us know which
one you like the most. Yeah, record your answer
at dynamicduel.com by clicking on the red microphone
button in the bottom right hand corner, which
will prompt you to leave us a voicemail. Your
message could be up to 30 seconds long, and
don't forget to leave your name in case we include
you on the podcast. We'll pick our favorite
answer and draw that person a dynamic duel no
prize that we'll post to social media. Be sure
to answer before December 4th. But I think that
does it for all the news for this episode,
so let's go ahead and hear from our sponsor,
HBO Max. Bruce Wayne may appear to be a wealthy
playboy, but beneath his facade his true identity
is that of the Batman, waging an endless war
against crime. Join the Caped Crusader in Batman,
the Audio Adventures, the first scripted audio
original featuring Batman and his villainous
rogues gallery in a world premiere story. of
life and death in Gotham City, debuting exclusively
on HBO Max. Starring Jeffrey Wright as Batman
and a who's who of Incredible Saturday Night
Live alums, this rollicking adventure, told
across 10 episodes, is written and directed
by Emmy winner Denis McNicholas, includes devilishly
delightful original music by Doug Bossie, and
performances by Rosario Dawson, John Leguizamo,
Chris Parnell, Melissa Villaseñor, Seth Meyers,
Jason Sudeikis, Brooke Shields, Fred Armisen,
and many, many more. Go to hbomax.com slash
Batman Audio Adventures for more and stream
Batman the Audio Adventures only on HBO Max.
Thanks to HBO Max for sponsoring this episode.
But now let's get into the main event of this
episode where we find out who would win in
a fight between the Wonder Twins' pet monkey,
Gleek, and Deadpool's rival, Pit Monkey.
Okay, Gleek versus Hitmonkey. This matchup was
actually a fairly last minute decision. You
could tell because this year we didn't commission
an artist to do artwork for this episode because
it was so last minute. Yeah, but we were inspired
by one of our patrons on our Discord who asked
us who would be good in a matchup against Hitmonkey
since that character now has his own television
show currently on Hulu, which is actually pretty
good. I've been watching it. Yeah, they both
have their own cartoons. It's pretty awesome.
And Jonathan and I have been trying to get
Gleek in a matchup for the longest time. We
thought he might be good in a fight against
Spider Ham, but eventually we went with the
terrific What's It for that matchup. I think
when you have an alien monkey who can stretch
his tail infinitely long against a monkey who's
really good with guns, you have a pretty solid
matchup there, right? Yeah. I have no idea
who's going to come out on top. I just know
it's going to be fun. Again, this is our charity
matchup as we do every year. So if you feel
inclined to give this holiday season, Again,
visit us on Facebook and donate to the HealthWell
Foundation, which is a nonprofit dedicated
to helping America pay their health bills. So
let's get into it. If you've never listened
to one of our dual episodes before, the way
we determine a winner between these two characters
is by running 1000 Monte Carlo simulations using
their statistics. Now a Monte Carlo simulation
is a probabilistic model used to determine outcomes
through random sampling. In our case, it randomizes
statistics along a normal distribution, which
is a bell curve. as a way to simulate the many
variables that can occur during battle. The
stat parameters we use are based on the official
Marvel power grid, and we use that criteria
to extrapolate the DC character's stats. We've
included some additional stat categories of
our own, such as range, damage potential, versatility,
and perception, in order to create a more complete
and robust simulation. Running these 1000 simulations
gives us a percentage of wins for each character,
and we declare the one with the higher percentage
to be the ultimate victor. considering that
they're more likely to win any given battle.
No character ever wins 100% of the time. Comics
have shown that there's always a way for Batman
to defeat Superman. We feel our method falls
in line with the precedents that have been
established in the comic book stories. And we
use this method because it was the least subjective,
most unbiased way to determine who would win.
Of course, we are both heavily biased toward
our respective allegiances, so instead of debating
these matches forever, we just let the math
decide for us. So there's no fan votes here
and no relying on just feats. Before we run
these simulations though, we like to break down
each character's histories and abilities before
improvising a scenario on how we imagine one
of the 1,000 simulations we run would play
out beat for beat. And I think it's my turn
to go first with the Marvel character, so let
me go ahead and tell you all about the comic
book backstory of Hitmonkey. So much is steeped
in legend surrounding the origins of the assassin
known as Hitmonkey. The tale regarding this
mysterious killer of killers is said to begin
in the snowy mountains of Japan, where an unnamed
assassin fled after being double-crossed in
a failed political coup. In the freezing wilderness,
the lost and injured man was discovered by a
group of Japanese macaques. The primates took
the assassin to their hot springs and nursed
him back to health with their herbal remedies.
Though the macaques were willing to accept the
man into their monkey clan, One skeptical monkey
didn't trust the outsider and watched him closely.
This monkey observed as the assassin healed
from his wounds and prepared for revenge against
those who betrayed him by honing his skills
in the snowy mountains. The monkey watched and
learned as the man demonstrated his various
lethal maneuvers in hand-to-hand and weapons
combat. And he watched how easy killing was
for the outsider. The monkey tried to warn his
clan that harboring the assassin was only going
to bring more violence their way. When the clan
rejected this notion, the monkey accidentally
injured one of his fellow primates during his
effort to convince them of the oncoming danger.
This monkey was cast out of his clan and into
the wilderness on his own. Several days into
his exile, he noticed a group of soldiers headed
up the mountains toward his former home, and
he rushed back to the hot springs to warn his
fellow primates. The monkey was too late, however,
as he arrived only in time to witness the soldiers
gun down the assassin and all of his macaque
family. The Monkey picked up the weapons of
the Assassin and used the skills he learned
from observing him to shoot and kill the soldiers
there that murdered his clan. At that moment,
he became Hitmonkey. The spirit of the Outsider
Assassin appeared before Hitmonkey and told
him how the soldiers were sent by a politician
named Hideki Hayashi, who in turn worked for
General Kato. The spirit told Hitmonkey that
by killing these men, he would achieve vengeance
not only for his dead Monkey brethren, but also
for the Assassin himself. Hitmonkey traveled
to Tokyo and, under the assassin's guidance,
stole a truck and crashed it into Hayashi's
limo. Barely clinging to life, the politician
was sent to the hospital where he was smothered
by the assassin Bullseye, who was hired by General
Kato to cover his tracks. The following day,
Hitmonkey snuck into General Kato's daughter's
wedding and stole the suit from the child ring
bearer, pretending to be part of the ceremony
to get in close. He managed to decapitate General
Kato despite Bullseye's efforts to stop causing
Bullseye to kill the rest of Kato's men to
avoid the humiliation of being bested by a primate.
Bullseye found and hurled a knife at Hitmonkey,
though the blade was intercepted by the ring
bearer child, who annoyingly stepped in the
way. From then on, Hitmonkey, having achieved
his own vengeance, vowed to seek revenge for
those innocents whose blood had been spilled,
and he became a killer of killers. He fell
into urban legend, believed only by the very
few who had ever seen him in action, and disregarded
as a joke by everyone else. Spider-Man was one
such non-believer who refused to buy Deadpool's
story about the legendary hit monkey who was
targeting him. Spider-Man then witnessed the
merciless primate bust in, and like a furry
blur, filled Deadpool full of lead. What? To
get back at the monkey, Deadpool stole Spider-Man's
spare costume, and pretended that Spider-Man
was a victim of collateral damage from Hitmonkey's
attack. A funeral was held for the wall-crawler,
which Hitmonkey attended out of remorse, believing
he had accidentally killed Spidey. As the primate
approached the casket to pay his respects, Deadpool
burst out and tried to gun down the monkey,
but Spider-Man swung in and stopped their fight,
leading to Hitmonkey's escape and to the long-lasting
rivalry between the two murderers. Eventually,
however, Deadpool and Hitmonkey talked it out,
and Hitmonkey turned over a new leaf, joining
SHIELD's howling commando subdivision that
dealt with supernatural threats. Hitmonkey later
joined Deadpool and Domino's mercenary team
called the Mercs for Money, though the primate's
mission was to monitor the team on behalf of
SHIELD. At one point, Deadpool inadvertently
assisted the evil organization HYDRA during
its takeover of the United States, and he put
a 20 million dollar bounty on his own head
as a means of Punishment. Hitmonkey was brought
in alongside other heroes to help put a stop
to the resulting chaos caused by villains out
to collect Deadpool's head. And that's Hitmonkey's
backstory so far. Now, he has no powers to speak
of, save for his simian physiology that makes
him stronger and faster than your average human.
He has opposable thumbs on his hands and feet,
allowing him to wield weapons such as guns and
swords with extreme dexterity no matter which
limb he uses. This ability, combined with his
mastery of martial arts and marksmanship skills,
make him an unpredictable and dangerous killer.
He carries two handguns and often uses a samurai
sword in battle. Occasionally, Hitmonkey has
been known to commune with the spirit of the
deceased assassin that instructed him in how
to kill. And that's Hitmonkey. So he's like
a small version of John Wick. Exactly, that
is a fantastic way to put it. He's a small
version of John Wick if John Wick couldn't speak
any human language. and also had thumbs on
his feet, even though Hitmonkey would annihilate
John Wick because he's just that little bit
better. This actually makes me like really interested
in the cartoon. I haven't started watching
it yet, but that sounded like a lot of fun.
Not going to lie. And honestly, now that I
have covid, like I have all day to watch it.
You know, I don't know any Marvel fans that
have caught covid. It's only DC fans that I
know of. What? Yeah. Wow. Interesting, huh?
DC must stand for like Delta covid. I'm going
to go cough in your face. I think that's illegal,
isn't it? Yeah. Okay, nevermind. Go ahead, I'll
sue your ass. Well, you know what else I've
been watching on TV this past week? Super Friends
as research for this episode. And I gotta say,
I love those classic Justice League cartoons.
They're great. How big is Gleek's role in the
Super Friends cartoon? It depends on episode
to episode. They're all kind of like anthological
in a way. But he is one of the recurring characters.
He's in almost like every episode. Since we
began doing these charity animal duels. I would
say all of the DC characters have been pretty
obscure. Gleek is probably the least obscure
character I've done since he was a regular
on the Super Friends cartoon, but he also has,
I would say, the least amount of incontinuity
backstory for a character I've ever written
about. Like all in all, he's had around 20
issues of canonical appearances, with the vast
majority of them being minor cameos. Gleek
and his Wonder Twin owners first appeared in
1977. during the Hanna-Barbera animated series,
The All-New Super Friends Hour, which was a
spin-off of 1973's Super Friends. The Super
Friends have had a total of six spin-off series
that lasted until 1986, and of all the series,
Gleek and his Wonder Twin owners appeared regularly
in five of them. The All-New Super Friends
Hour series also notably introduced a more diverse
cast of new characters in Black Vulcan, Apache
Chief, Samurai, and El Dorado. As I mentioned
in our Wonder Twins vs Cloak and Dagger episode,
the Wonder Twins and Gleek supplanted the powerless
characters of Wendy, Marvin, and their Wonder
Dog from the original Super Friends series as
the young audience surrogates on the show,
as Gleek and the twins were able to take a more
active part in the stories since they had superpowers.
Gleek, like the Wonder Twins Xan and Jaina,
was from the planet Exor, where, according
to the Super Friends show, many monkeys existed
just like him. In fact, in one episode, they
all visited Earth in spaceships in an attempt
to take over the planet because X-Or doesn't
have bananas. They had been monitoring Gleek
for some time and sought from him information
on how to destroy the Super Friends. Bombarded
by a banana brain blaster, Gleek was forced
to reveal the team's secrets and nearly succeeded
in destroying Superman, Batman, and Wonder
Woman with a disintegrator ray, but was stopped
by Jan and Xana, after they broke free from
the clutches of a giant Gleek robot. Jaina immediately
transformed into an electric eel and zapped
Gleek free from his mind control. Once the Water
Twins and Gleek rescued the Justice League,
the Exorian Monkeys were returned to their ships
and escorted back to the planet Exor. The episode
ended, as most Super France episodes did, with
a gag from Gleek, who this time confused a
banana blaster for an edible banana, zapping
himself silly. In the non-canonical Super Friends
comic, it was revealed that members of Gleek's
species are known as Elastomunks. Gleek was
first owned by an Exorian clown named Illic,
who trained him as part of a traveling intergalactic
circus from Exor. Illic was a good man who helped
educate the Wonder Twins when they were brought
on as part of the show. Gleek took a liking
to the twins and escaped the circus with them
when they found out they weren't getting paid
for their performances. After their escape,
the twins discovered on a nearby planet that
the Superman villain, Grax, was going to attack
Earth, and Gleek traveled with the twins to
Earth in order to warn the Super Friends, and
they stayed on the planet in order to learn
to use their powers as superheroes. After the
Super Friends cartoon and comic ended, the Wonder
Twins would enter mainstream DC continuity
in the mid-90s in the title, Extreme Justice.
But Gleek, unfortunately, did not appear with
them. He did appear, however, in the line of
children's books based on the DC superpets
where he helped Beppo the super monkey defeat
Gorilla Grodd when the circus came to Metropolis.
It wasn't until 2019 that Gleek made his official
DC comics debut in a 12 issue Wonder Twins
miniseries. In this post-Flashpoint continuity
it was established that Xan and Jaina weren't
circus performers but the grandchildren of Exor's
equivalent of Hitler. Their father sent them
to earth with Superman, so that they wouldn't
have to suffer the shame and sense of their
grandfather. While on Earth, Zand bought Gleek
through a magazine ad that some circus performers
put together in order to save Gleek from his
abusive circus environment. Gleek's circus
was run by a supervillain known as the Ringmaster,
who would force Gleek to ride a tiny bicycle
through flaming hoops and other hazards. Because
of the kindness Zand showed Gleek, he single-handedly
rescued the twins when they were captured by
the League of Annoyance. a small-time cadre
of villains organized by Lex Luthor to cultivate
sporadic chaos around Washington, D.C. Later,
when the League of Annoyance tried to get a
Phantom Zone projector from the Wonder Twins,
their recent recruit, Ringmaster, succeeded
in ring-tossing the twins into another trap,
only for Gleek to emerge from Zan's backpack
and start punching out his former abusive owner,
Ringmaster. Gleek was tased by cell phone Sylvia
during the pummeling. but the distraction worked,
and the Wonder Twins were able to send the bad
guys to the Phantom Zone. Most recently, Gleek
and the twins were seen helping Young Justice
bring down rogue scientists within Star Labs,
and became official members of that team by
its conclusion. Powers-wise, Gleek has the
physiology of an Exorian Elastomonk, granting
him his blue-furred appearance and prehensile
tail that he's able to extend to any length,
with a tensile strength that allows him to
lift up to a quarter ton. He's also smarter
than your average Earth Monkey, capable of
understanding human speech, average human, often
to humorous effect. Well, same thing with Hitmonkey.
While he can understand humans, he's not as
smart as them. But Gleek is also clever by
nature, capable of hiding empty buckets and
bananas and drawing them out from seemingly
nowhere at will. His ass? We'll never know,
but probably. Not gonna lie. He has that infinitely
stretchable tail, but also probably an infinite
stretchable colon, is my guess. And that's
Gleek. This will be pretty good, it kind of
reminds me of like Mr. Fantastic vs. The Punisher
or something like that. But now that we got
these monkeys' histories and abilities out
of the way, let's speculate on how one of the
1000 simulated matches will go. The winner
is determined by simulations, not the speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how this fight could
play out. Now we don't set any rules for this
match other than the characters don't know
anything about each other going in. Except that
the other character is a threat that needs
to be put down. We say that they start off about
50 meters apart in an environment that has
no bearing on the match itself because we don't
take stats for the environment. Plus, certain
characters have advantages in some environments
over others, and we want these characters to
win on their own merit. So let's get into it.
Gleek and Hitmonkey meet on the battlefield.
Who goes first? Okay, I'm gonna say Hitmonkey
goes first because he's kind of like this little
ball of fury. Okay? So he's gonna start off
by reaching into his suit jacket, and with
one hand, he's gonna pull out his cool shades.
and put him on, and with the other hand, he's
gonna pull out a fucking Glock 19. And he's
gonna point it right at Gleek, like badass
sideways gangster style, and he's just gonna
start unloading rounds. Okay, once Gleek sees
the gun, he's gonna be like, wow! He's gonna
use his tail to like spring away as Hitmonkey
is shooting. And while Hitmonkey is like focusing
on hitting center mass as Gleek is just like
bouncing around like a pinball, Gleek is going
to stretch out his tail and just whip the gun
right out of Hitmonkey's hand. Well that pisses
Hitmonkey off, you know, he's gonna screech
in frustration and then he's gonna charge Gleek
on all fours with his monkey speed and he's
gonna leap through the air and he's gonna do
this flying kick that, well, I guess, is it
a kick or is it a punch? Right, yeah, with the
monkey it's probably always a punch But it's
gonna connect and hit Gleek right in his dome
piece Okay, okay so Gleek probably drops to
the floor and he's gonna retract his tail but
when he gets up to his feet he's gonna put
his arms up like a boxer and start hopping back
and forth like, wah-wah-wah-wah, wah-
I'm trying to add insult to injury. That's gonna
infuriate Hitmonkey. So he's gonna screech
again, and he's gonna reach toward his back
and ensheath the samurai sword that he has.
What? And he's gonna spin it around, and he's
gonna swing it at Gleek and just slice off
his tail. How does Hitmonkey have a samurai
sword small enough for his body? You know,
it's one of those short swords. Oh, like the,
what is it called, the Shoto? Yeah, sure. One
of the, okay. Okay, that's dumb. So Gleek, he's
gonna yell. and run away. And I'm sure Hitmonkey
is gonna be chasing after him, just swinging
that sword around wildly. But Gleek, he's gonna
conjure a banana, all right? And he's gonna
peel it, eat the banana, then throw the peel
behind him, causing Hitmonkey to slip and drop
his sword, which Gleek grabs with this still
functional stretchy tail, even though it's been
cut, he can still stretch it. And he's gonna
start swinging that around like crazy. So Gleek
is still able to stretch his tail, even though
it's been cut. Yeah, essentially you did nothing
by cutting it. Gleek is, you know, trying to
swipe at Hitmonkey with his katana sword, but
Hitmonkey is agile, you know, he dodges these
slashes and he runs around Gleek, and by running
around him, Hitmonkey causes Gleek to wrap
himself up with his own tail and drop the sword.
Then with Gleek all wrapped up, Hitmonkey's
just gonna punch him right in his face. And
that's gonna send Gleek flying back, but Hitmonkey's
gonna grab his tail and just yo-yo him back.
What? Causing him to come winding back up and
then get hit again. And Hitmonkey just keeps
doing this. That's a pretty good move. You
know, Gleek, he's probably dizzy and seeing
stars, but he's just gonna shake it off. Since
Hitmonkey is holding onto his tail, Gleek is
just gonna loop his tail around Hitmonkey's
wrist, and he's just gonna lift him into the
air and start slamming him into the ground
repeatedly, like, bam bam! Well, after getting
slammed a few times, I'm gonna say that Hitmonkey
reaches into his suit with his feet. And he's
gonna pull out another Glock. And then before
Gleek can slam him again, he shoots that blue
monkey right through one of his eyes. Dang!
Why? Jeez. No, I mean, that would kill Gleek.
I'm gonna say that once Gleek sees the gun,
he's gonna pull out his trusty metal pail and
put it over his head like a helmet, blocking
the bullet.
That pale, he uses that to carry Xan, right?
Yeah, whenever he's like in a water form. Okay,
so this metal pale blocks the bullet from killing
him, but Gleek is gonna be rattled by this,
you know? And therefore he's gonna let go of
Hitmonkey with his tail. So Hitmonkey falls
to the ground, probably drops his gun, but when
Gleek removes his metal pale helmet, he's gonna
see like multiple Hitmonkeys like vibrating
around just because he was so rattled. And
in addition to seeing multiple Hitmonkeys, he
also sees multiple brown gooey masses flying
at his face. What? Yeah, that's right. Hitmonkey
just threw some feces, and it blinds Gleek,
hits him right in the eye. I had a feeling this
was gonna turn into a shit show. Ha ha ha.
And when Gleek wipes the monkey poo away from
his face, he sees nothing. Hitmonkey has vanished
from the battlefield. He's gone? Yeah, like
Batman. He's stealthy like that. Okay. Gleeky,
you know, he's probably gonna be clutching his
pale helmet and just like looking around for
Hitmonkey. I don't know. Well, Hitmonkey suddenly
appears behind Gleek with like this loud screech.
He unleashes a flurry of shit missiles that
just pelt Gleek to death like being stoned.
Dude, why is this monkey so constipated that
his shit is so hard and sharp that it would
kill someone? He had a lot of dairy. Okay. But
you said he screeches, so Gleek is gonna hear
that screech, and he's just gonna instantly
begin twirling his tail like a fan blade, just
generating a gust that's strong enough to redirect
these turd torpedoes back at Hitmonkey, killing
him instead. Hitmonkey's not gonna go down by
his own poo, alright? He just did. Wha- Can
we just end it here then? So either Gleek dies
from getting pelted to death from Hitmonkey's
poo, or Gleek is able to redirect the turds
back at Hitmonkey who dies. I'm fine with that.
I honestly have no idea how you could top poo
flinging in a monkey battle. Alright, so let's
go ahead and run these characters through the
Monte-Caller simulations and come back with
a winner.
In what other Marvel vs DC matchup can you do
a poof linking battle? Besides this one. Yeah,
I don't know. I guess technically you could
do it for any battle, but why would you? That's
true. These guys were fairly comparable. I thought
that Hitmonkey was absolutely going to have
an advantage due to the fact that he has fucking
guns, you know, and he could shoot at Gleek
from a long range. But surprisingly, Gleek has
an even longer range than Hitmonkey with his
stretchable tail. Right, right. Also, Gleek
is stronger than Hitmonkey because of that
same tail. Yeah, yeah, the tail is his strongest
weapon. It's his only weapon, and it's no joke.
And it's so versatile too, like able to form
a spring to like a helicopter twirl. Yeah,
that's right. But where Gleek couldn't touch
Hitmonkey at all was in his martial arts ability.
Hitmonkey is vastly superior in his hand combat.
in every other category, these monkeys were
comparable. Considering that, who do you think
won this match? I think it's Gleek. I think
his tail is way more special than, you know,
a couple of guns and maybe a knife. Though
I have to say, Instagram does not agree with
me. 73% of our Instagram followers who voted,
voted in favor of Hitmonkey, which I'm not surprised.
Like, how many of them actually watched the
Super Friends cartoon? How many of them actually
know about Gleek? I'm gonna assume all of them.
and that they are very smart and well versed.
Maybe. Hitmonkey does have a show that is like
on Hulu right now. So I'm sure his popularity
factor played a part in why he won this poll.
Well, he won the poll, did he win the matches?
I have the results here. Let's find out. The
winner of the duel between Gleek and Hitmonkey
is Hitmonkey. Damn it! But it was fairly close.
This was a commendable fight. Hitmonkey won.
534 matches out of the 1000, whereas Gleek
won 466, so that's 53.4% to 46.6. Fairly close,
but Hitmonkey is a straight up killer, and
just way more badass than Gleek. I can't even
argue with that, honestly. Like Gleek is anything
but badass. He's silly though, he's cute and
silly. I am surprised by the results though,
I thought Gleek was gonna just spank that monkey's
red ass tail. Oh, we didn't do that in speculation
then. We should have done that. Well, Hitmonkey
is just on top of the world now. Not only did
he win this duel against Gleek, he of course
has that show on Hulu, which has been doing
really well. It has like a 90 percent audience
score on Rotten Tomatoes and an 80 percent
critic score. I'm like five episodes in. It's
pretty good. We're going to review that show
in our next episode. So look forward to that.
And when it comes to Gleek, I would actually
recommend checking out Adult Swim's parody of
the wonder twins? Yeah, they did these wonder
twins shorts based off of like old quote unquote
lost footage of their adventures. There's like
five of them. They're hilarious. You could find
them on YouTube. But that does it for this
duel. Let us know what you guys thought about
the Gleek versus Hitmonkey results by writing
to us at dynamicduelpodcast at gmail.com or
by visiting us on Facebook, Instagram or Twitter.
You can find links to all of our accounts by
checking out our show notes or visiting our
website dynamicduel.com. And also don't forget,
since this is our charity duel episode, to
check out our Facebook specifically in order
to donate to the Healthwell Foundation. Again,
it doesn't matter how much you donate. We were
not asking for large amounts. Right. We will
randomly pick two donors when this fundraiser
ends on Christmas day and we'll be gifting
them a dynamic duel Marvel vs. DC card game
that we created. And remember for the duration
of this fundraiser, all of our archived episodes,
every episode that we've done at this podcast
will be available again to the listening public.
So if you haven't checked out our back episodes,
go ahead and do that. But that does it for this
episode. We want to give a big thanks to our
executive producers, John Spies, Ken Johnson,
Jace Crump, John Staroski, Zachary Hepburn,
John Bechinina, Mitchell Phipps, Dustin Belcombe,
Salvador Hernandez Contreras Jr., and Levi
Yeaton for helping make this podcast possible.
We'll talk to you guys next week. Up up and
away. True believers?