This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
And welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters and stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Marvelous Joe. And I'm his twin brother
Johnny DC. And in this episode, guys, we are
reviewing the only DC film that is going to
be released in theaters this year, Joker Folie a Deux.
And was the movie a colossal waste of time?
I'm going to say yes. And I'm going to say...
I hate you, but damn do I respect your opinion.
We're gonna talk all about our opinions on
this film later on this episode. It'll be a
spoiler review, so make sure you've seen the
film before you listen to us. Or not. I actually
take that back. Why would you say that? I really
don't care. Before we get into the review, we're
gonna break down the latest comic book movie
news to come out this past week, of which there
was only one news item, and that is that there
is a Robin-focused animated film in development
called Dynamic Duo. Totally ripping us off.
We're duel though. D-U-E-L. As always guys,
we list our segment times in our episode description,
so feel free to check out the show notes if
you want to skip ahead to a particular topic.
Our artificially intelligent duel simulator
AJ9K has a quick message for our listeners,
so listen up. Why hello there, do you want even
more from this podcast? Then become a part
of the dynamic duel community on Patreon, where
you can choose from three tiers. The dynamic
two-oh tier gives you access to our Discord
chat server. The fantastic four tier gives
you two bonus episodes each month, and the X-Force
tier makes you an executive producer of this
show. Lastly, The Diner Mike podcast network
tier lets you create your own podcast using
this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe will
help you develop your show, provide graphic
support and consultation, and get you simulation
results. Pitch the twins your ideas via email
at dynamicduelpodcast at gmail.com. Check it
out at patreon.com slash dynamicduel. Pip pip
cheerio. Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone
who supports the podcast. Guys, be sure to
tune into the other shows in the DynaMic Podcast
Network this week, including Max Destruction,
which pits your favorite action heroes from
film and television against each other. This
week, hosts Scotty and Gilly are breaking down
a Sting vs. Undertaker matchup. On the Senjoworld
podcast, host Zachary Hepburn speculates on
fights between fan favorite anime and manga
characters. Last week, he found out who would
win between Gridman and Kaiju 8. We teased
the episode incorrectly. Zach will find out
who will win between Muzan from Demon Slayer
and Femto from Berserk. And on the Console Combat
Podcast hosts John and Dean simulate battles
between popular video game characters. In yesterday's
episode, they determined who would win in a
fight between Wukong from Black Myth Wukong
and Asura from Asura's Wrath. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com
or click the link in our show notes to listen
to all of the shows in the DynaMic Podcast
Network. But with that out of the way, quick
to the no prize! A no prize is an award Marvel
used to give out to fans. Our version, the dynamic
duel no prize, is a digital award that we post
on Instagram for the person that we feel gave
the best answer to our question of the week.
Last week we asked, what is your theory as to
what the asterisk means in the Thunderbolts
movie title? And we got a few answers. Some
pretty good theories here. Let's go ahead and
run down our honorable mentions as well as the
no prize winner. Our first honorable mention
goes to Mike Williams, who said, Hey gang, this
is Mike Williams out of St. Louis, Missouri.
The asterisk on Thunderbolts movie probably
means that this is not the real team or they're
going to introduce a team at the end of the
movie. Who knows? So until DC makes a hit movie,
make mine Marvel. That is correct. Until DC
makes a good movie, make mine Marvel. Way to
go Mike Williams. That's the sentiment we want
from all the callers that call in for sure.
Why am I not surprised that he's talking about
movies and not comics? Typical Marvel fan.
I think he's right there. So yeah, the primary
theory regarding the asterisk at the end of
the Thunderbolts movie title is that this is
not the real Thunderbolts team. And that could
mean either that the team labeled as the Thunderbolts
in this film is actually a different team such
as the champions. Secret Avengers, Dark Avengers,
something like that. Or that they are called
the Thunderbolts, but it's not like an official
team title because they're classified. I think
either of those options would make sense. Yeah,
that second option there is what I actually
think the asterisk means personally. So great
answer, Mike Williams. Let's go ahead and move
on to our next honorable mention. Scott Camacho,
who said, Come on, we know what the asterisk
is. They're trying to find another subtitle,
but I'm gonna help them out. It's gonna be
called Thunderbolts Red Alert. Why? because
in the trailer we didn't see Ross. Where is
Ross? I mean, I'm pretty sure the name Thunderbolts
is affiliated with the Red Hulk. So I'm gonna
say that it's gonna be a surprise maybe in the
second trailer that we're gonna see the Red
Hulk and it's gonna be Thunderbolts Red Alert.
Now I would actually be surprised if Harrison
Ford made some kind of cameo as a member of
this team. Though I do think that perhaps one
of the reasons the name of the team is classified
is because it's a team that's sanctioned by
Thunderbolt Ross in the same way that the Suicide
Squad is sanctioned under Amanda Waller. That's
possible. I can understand why a lot of people
think that the Thunderbolts team is somehow
affiliated with President Thunderbolt Ross.
That's actually not the case from the comics.
Thunderbolt Ross had nothing to do with the
original Thunderbolts team led by Baron Zemo.
But I can see how they might go that route in
the MCU as a rationale for the name of the
team. It'll be interesting to see how that all
shakes out. If in fact, the Red Hulk will join
the team, given that he was once a member of
the Thunderbolts in the comic books. Great
answer, Scott Camacho. Our next honorable mention
goes to Mason Thompson. Who said? What's up?
It's Mason. So this is this is the fact is,
you know, this is just as simple as that. It's
a star. Who's a star? Robert Downey Jr. Who
does he play? Dr. Doom. Who's the villain?
Dr. Doom. I hate you 3000. He's gonna be in
the movie! But if I'm being for real, I think
that they were like villains. And then by the
end of the movie, they like changed good. If
that makes sense. RDJ better not be in this
movie. I'm still holding out hope that Marvel
will actually still recast the role of Dr. Doom
as unlikely as that will be. I don't want to
see Robert Downey Jr. in the role for reasons
that we discussed when that news was announced
at Comic-Con. But- The whole conceit of the
Thunderbolts team as they exist in the comic
books is that the Thunderbolts are a group of
villains trying to be heroes. So what you're
saying is the Thunderbolts asterisk could be
like, oh, it's a super team asterisk, actually
it's villains. Or it's a villains team asterisk,
it's actually heroes. One or the other. That
barely makes sense. I'll take it. So great answer
Mason Thompson. We want to give a quick shout
out to Travis Herndon for taking the time to
call in and leave an answer. His answer is
actually pretty much almost exactly the same
as the no-prize winner of this week, who is
Jose Marcial. Who said? I have heard a pretty
interesting theory pertaining to the asterisk
and the thunderbolt. That at the end of the
movie, somebody, preferably Norman Osborn,
hopefully, William DeFoe, is going to come out
and reveal that the whole movie or whatever
was a tryout for them to see what they're capable
of and this is going to be the Dark Avengers.
Personally, I really vibe with this theory,
so I hope that is the case. Yeah, I really
like this idea that the Thunderbolts, as they
exist in this movie, is more of just like a
tryout exercise to see who's gonna join the
Dark Avengers set up by Norman Osborn, who
led the team in the comics and in the movies
is played by Willem Dafoe, at least in No Way
Home. But you know, it could be the same actor
for the MCU. I think that'd be fantastic. The
reason this answer got the win over Travis Herndon
is because Travis did say that this is potentially
a recruitment team, but the idea of having Norman
Osborn in the movie is really exciting and
that was an added element that Jose Marcial
threw in there. I do like the idea of there
being some kind of secret benefactor of the
team that's like the major villain. I don't
think it's going to be Green Goblin though.
I actually think it's going to be Dr. Doom,
if anybody. Just stop, okay? Leave Dr. Doom's
name out of your mouth. Robert Downey Jr. is
not the real Doctor Doom, at least not the one
that real Doctor Doom fans are hoping for.
We want the real Victor Von Doom, so just keep
his name out of your mouth if you know what's
good for you. Well, only because Julia Louise
Dryfist seems to be spearheading this whole
group. She bought Stark Towers. How did she
afford that? It's gotta be Doctor Doom money.
I hope not. I don't want to see that version
of Doctor Doom just yet. It wouldn't make sense
outside of the context of the multiverse. The
Thunderbolts movie, I believe, is not like
a multiversal film. Well, it could lead into
Avengers Doomsday. Possibly, I guess so. But
great answer Jose Marcial. Congrats on winning
this week's No Prize. If you the listener want
a shot at winning your own No Prize, stay tuned
to later on this episode when we'll be asking
another question of the week. And now that that's
done, on to the news!
So last week, Deadline broke the news that a
Robins Origin story titled Dynamic Duo is in
the works with DC Studios and it's going to
be made with puppetry animation. Actually,
it's called specifically Momo animation and
it's a new type of animation that a studio
known as Swaybox has created that combines CGI
with practical effects like stop motion and
live action real-time performances. It's still
in an experimental stage, but they wanna make
a full length feature film to be played in theaters.
The movie is being written by Matthew Aldrich,
who also wrote Coco and Lightyear, and it's
gonna be about the early days of Dick Grayson
and Jason Todd as Robin. The film is gonna be
set in James Gunn's DC cinematic universe,
right? We don't know that 100%. I think it's
going to be. All we know for sure is that it's
not going to be a part. of the Matt Reeves Batman
universe. Okay, well, I guess this animated
film is a way for fans to see the origins of
these characters that aren't gonna show up
in the Brave and the Bold film. Cause we know
the Brave and the Bold film is set to be a
father, son, Batman and Robin movie where Damien
Wayne is the character of Robin. But that would
mean that Dick Grayson and Jason Todd and likely
Tim Drake have already gone through the mantle
in James Gunn's DC universe. So. It's nice that
they're kind of getting their due diligence
within this film. That's all their own. But
it is strange that it's going to be animated.
Does that make it seem like it's going to be
a kid's film? It is 100 percent going to be
geared towards families. Actually, one of the
film's producers, Matt Reeves, has pretty much
said that he's excited to do a family film with
this studio. Does that mean that the film's
not going to include a savage beatdown of Jason
Todd at the hands of the Joker? Oh, that's
a good question. That would be tragic if it
didn't, but who knows? If they're gearing it
towards families, it may be something that happens
off screen. Who's to say? I've seen some of
the test footage that they've been doing with
Swaybox and some of the puppetry. It's not
like the Muppets puppetry or anything like that.
This is some high tech quality stuff. Almost
in the same vein as Leica Studios, what they
do with their stop motion animation. They made
Kubo and the Two Strings and Corpse Bride, Paranorman,
Coraline, stuff like that. What I'm wondering
is who they're gonna cast in these roles, since
James Gunn once stated that the voices that
he casts for animated roles will be playing
the characters in live action. Does that mean
that when he casts Dick Grayson and Jason Todd
in this dynamic duo movie, will we eventually
see them in live action in the Brave and the
Bold film? I think as long as like the adult
live action actor can pull off a kid's voice,
you could probably argue that would be the
case, but I would be surprised. I guess we'll
find out. Yeah, there's no release date for
this film. It was just announced, but we'll
keep you guys updated as news breaks. But considering
that this film is Robin focused, that brings
us to our question of the week.
Who is your favorite Robin from the comics and
why? There have been a number to choose from
the comics and they all have their own fanbase
so really excited to see what your guys answers
are. Record your answer at dynamicduel.com by
clicking on the red microphone button in the
bottom right hand corner of the screen which
will prompt you to leave us a voicemail. Your
message could be up to 30 seconds long and don't
forget to leave your name in case we include
you on the podcast. We'll pick our favorite
answer and award that person a dynamic duel
no prize that we'll post to Instagram. Be sure
to answer before October 12th.
But I think that does it for all the news for
this episode, so let's go ahead and get on
to our main event, where we review the latest
Warner Bros. DC theatrical release, Joker,
Folie a Deux.
Alright, Joker, Folie a Deux, the sequel to
2019's Joker, which up until Deadpool and Wolverine
was the highest grossing rated-R film of all
time and won the Oscars for best actor and
best score, though it was nominated in more
categories including Best Picture, best screenplay
and best director, and it even won the coveted
Golden Lion, the highest honor bestowed at
the Venice Film Festival where it premiered.
The sequel, Folia De, also premiered at the
Venice Film Festival this year to much less
critical acclaim, though I didn't think too
much of it because critics didn't exactly love
the first movie. Many thought it irresponsibly
praised disenfranchised men and would inspire
them to commit violence like the film's lead
character Arthur Fleck, a somewhat valid concern
considering the perpetrator of the 2012 Aurora
Theatre shooting cited the Dark Knight Heath
Ledger version of the character of the Joker
as inspiration. Now, we reviewed 2019's Joker
and gave it 4 stars, though I regret not giving
it a higher rating. At least a 4.5, because
the film was just so unbelievably well
a result of me initially being uncomfortable
with the film. That said, I'd argue now that
the film was intentionally made to be uncomfortable
and therefore succeeded as a work of art. So
it's perhaps strange that while I'd argue the
very same thing for Folly Ado, I'd also argue
that this quote unquote work of art, with its
fantastic performances and cinematography,
unfortunately fails to deliver on the promises
it set up. deciding instead to subvert audience
expectations in the most unsatisfying of ways.
It's like the first movie was this disturbing
yet beautiful portrait of the Joker. And for
the second movie, screenwriter and director
Todd Phillips began painting yet another masterpiece.
Only in the final moments of working on the
painting, he decided to shit on it and just
smear it across the canvas, just fucking ruining
everything. almost as if he wanted to play a
joke on the audience. As much as it breaks
my heart, I can't recommend seeing this movie
just because of that ending. If you have seen
the movie and want to know my thoughts on it,
please keep listening to this spoiler review.
And if you haven't seen the film and want to
spare yourself of watching it, you can still
keep listening too. Yeah, yeah. Now, the premise
of the film is actually pretty good. It's an
experimental portrait of a sympathetic murderer
Arthur Fleck, who learns he's facing the death
penalty for his crimes right after falling for
a manipulative and obsessive fan of his, Harleen
Quinzel. I say it's experimental in the way
it subverts audience expectations at the end,
but also in the way music plays a role in the
film. The movie was described by the press
as a musical while it was in production, but
while it does have characters singing in it,
to me it felt more like a biopic of a musician.
rather than a quote-unquote musical. Usually
in musicals, the music serves the story in some
way. You often have a song establishing the
setting of the story and the protagonist's goals,
and you'll have a number by the villain that
expresses what they want as well. There's a
whole formula to it that Follyado doesn't adhere
to. Whereas in music biopics, music is often
used simply as entertainment, as a way to liven
up the story and visuals of the film. Well,
music biopics are usually about musicians.
Exactly. The Joker is not a musician, but I
could see where Todd Phillips would kind of
almost see him in that way. I understand why
Todd Phillips would have wanted to focus on
music in the sequel. The score of the first
film composed by Hildur Gudnedadder was so
damn moving. So expanding upon that with actual
songs, I thought was going to be pretty genius,
especially with Lady Gaga cast as Harley Quinn.
If you've listened to the podcast for a while,
you'll know that I've been excited for the idea
of this film as a musical, because not only
was it going to add something new to the comic
book film genre, but also musicals could be
pretty moving and powerful. I'm not one of these
musical haters who refuse to see Folly Ado
just because people sing in it. I'll hear people,
even co-workers, say that, and I'm like, really?
So you don't like Nightmare Before Christmas
or- You know, the South Park movie or Prince
of Egypt, Flight of the Concords. I want you
to look me in the eyes and tell me you can't
sing along to the songs in Aladdin. Well, to
that end, I think this musical would have been
more successful as a musical if the songs were
original, building upon Hilda Gunnadadter's
talent. Oh, 100%. Yeah. Hilda Gunnadadter's
talent and Lady Gaga's songwriting talent.
If she has any, I don't actually know if she
does. Maybe someone else writes all of her
music. But yeah, when we first learned. that
this was going to be a jukebox musical. I was
pretty disappointed by that when we were talking
about it in our news section. And it turns
out that disappointment was just the tip of
a giant iceberg of disappointment I would have
by the end of watching this movie. Now, another
reason I understood the musical direction is
because Todd Phillips has explained when talking
about the first movie that music lives in Arthur's
soul, as evidenced in Joaquin Phoenix's graceful,
masterful performance. It was merely glimpsed
in the first film. But in the sequel, Arthur's
internal melody comes to life in the form of
several imagined musical numbers. Though again,
I'm hesitant to call this a musical. As I mentioned,
musicals tend to drive the narrative forward
and provide some insight into a character's
thoughts and feelings. And some of the songs
in this film do indeed provide that function,
but not very well. Partly because the songs
are unoriginal and weren't written for this
film. And also because the songs are really
short. Like we just hear snippets here and
there. and if they're not being sung by Harley
Quinn as a way to mesmerize and manipulate
Arthur, they take place in Arthur's imagination
as fantasies or ways to cope with what's happening
to him. I didn't mind the way Harley sank to
him because of the whole music therapy thing
that they had going on in this film, but I will
admit the short imagined musical numbers were
kind of pointless to the narrative of the film
and halted its flow. Most of the musical numbers
feel like they existed merely to take a break
from the film's courtroom drama, but unnecessarily
so. Like, the courtroom scenes are some of the
most interesting in the movie, I felt, and
that we learn some profound information that
expands upon the tragedy of Arthur from the
first film. Yeah, there were some musical scenes
that we saw here that made sense to me in the
context of what was happening in the plot. But
by the time we got to the scene of Joker tap
dancing and stuff like that, I'm like, the film
has lost the plot. Yes, absolutely. And more
than that, it made the film seem like it had
no plot. Really, there's not too much story
here. It felt like filler, like they were padding
the runtime, like they just wanted to insert
different musical numbers and various random
places because they have Lady Gaga or some
shit. Exactly. Part of the tragedy of Arthur
in this film comes with the realization that
Harley is only in love with Joker and what he
represents rather than the pitiful Arthur,
who she selfishly manipulates and tries to bring
more and more of the Joker out of in him. There's
this line that she repeats over the course of
the film, and I took it almost as an explicit
promise to the audience that she and the Joker
were going to, quote, build a mountain, unquote.
Now, this was in reference to a song by Sammy
Davis Jr. who played a clown character in the
musical Stop the World I Want to Get Off. He
seems the line that he's going to build a mountain
from a little hill, build a heaven from a little
hell. Now that heaven was going to be the new
world the Joker ushered in, a world for the
downtrodden, built from the havoc that Joker
and Harley were seemingly going to wreck upon
the court and the system in glorious retribution
for the difficult life Arthur and members of
society have had. But in an almost apologetic
and perhaps socially responsible way, Todd Phillips
dashes any and all hopes for poetic justice
or cathartic bloodlust, deciding instead to
emphasize the tragedy of Arthur Fleck, but
without any kind of beauty whatsoever. Todd
Phillips has said that he thought it would
be interesting if Arthur wasn't the comic book
Joker, but maybe just the inspiration for him.
But then why call your film Joker? Why make
that promise that you can't keep or that joke
for which you have no punchline? For sure. This
pisses me off about Todd Phillips. You said
that maybe this film was apologetic. I totally
saw it that way. The vibe that I got walking
out of the theater was that Todd Phillips kind
of pussed out at the message that he had set
up in the first film wanting to not perhaps
instigate chaos and anarchy in the world, even
though that didn't really happen. Like the first
film, for all the fear that it instigated in
clickbait news media, you know, nothing really
came of it. People just saw it as an interesting
film. But I think the idea of the first film
almost scared Todd Phillips. And it seemed
like he rode himself into a corner or he was
just disavowing the first film. Yeah, it definitely
seems that way. I'm definitely seeing a narrative
emerge around this film that Todd Phillips
must be ashamed of how his Joker has influenced
to the culture and become a symbol for a type
of revolution that perhaps is attractive to
the same kind of people that critics were afraid
would be inspired by the first film. I'm not
sure that's exactly the case, though I will
admit I did get like I said earlier, those apologetic
vibes during the Joker's closing argument.
But on my way home from seeing the movie, I
actually thought of a different possibility
for what went wrong with this film, and that's
studio involvement. Not from the new DC studios,
but from Warner Bros., who's been known to get
too involved with DC's films like Suicide Squad
and Justice League. And to me it makes sense
that the studio would get involved if they
felt one of their major characters was being
mishandled, namely Harley Quinn. a character
that DC head Jim Lee has called the fourth pillar
of DC comics, along with the trinity of Batman,
Superman, and Wonder Woman. Now between 2020's
Birds of Prey film and the Harley Quinn animated
series, Harley Quinn has been established as
an independent feminist icon separate from
the Joker and Thriving. This film couldn't end
with Joker and Harley riding off together into
the sunset, as I suspect many people wanted,
like I wanted. For the sake of Harley, they
needed to break the two up, though they managed
to do so in the most anticlimactic way possible.
Now we know from scenes from the trailers, like
Harley with a haircut going down an elevator,
or Harley and Joker high kicking their way down
the steps of a courthouse, as well as set footage
of Harley pushing Arthur down the steps at the
end, that there was probably another cut of
this film. And since Warner Brothers has said
this film was never screened, in front of a
test audience prior to its premiere, to me it
makes a lot of sense that it was the studio
itself that made Todd Phillips change his original
vision. I'm not saying that's what happened,
I'm saying it wouldn't surprise me. Yeah, to
that end, maybe we'll be getting a director's
cut of this film considering the poor reception
that the movie is getting both critically and
financially. If a hashtag restore the Phillips
cut starts trending, I would not be surprised.
Because we've praised Todd Phillips on this
podcast before. We've called him an auteur.
If he is entirely to blame for what went wrong
with this film, then I am really confused.
Like experimentation is admirable somewhat,
but not with $200 million, not with fan expectations.
If you're not going to make a comic book movie
for comic book fans, then who are you making
it for? Like was he making it just for Harley
Quinn fans? Like they're not gonna like this
movie. Lady Gaga fans aren't gonna like this
movie. Fans of the first movie aren't going
to like this movie. Why make a movie with actors
of this caliber, with cinematography this beautiful,
that no one is going to like? Well, as we've
said on this podcast before, Todd Phillips
wanted to make a movie about mental illness
and knew that the best way to get people to
see it is to attach a comic book character's
name to it. Hence, Joker. Todd Phillips doesn't
really care about the comic book universe, which
really makes me question why he also includes
elements like Harvey Dent. getting his two-face,
you know, that was pretty interesting. Or the
new Joker at the very last shot of this film
slicing the Glasgow smile onto his face and
everything like that. Those seem like Easter
eggs for the fans, but it's clear that Todd
Phillips also doesn't care about the fans. So
he cares about the fans, but he doesn't care
about the fans. Again, I'm confused. I think
it's less about him caring for the fans and
more about he probably has some kind of studio
exec giving him notes on how to include comic
book Easter eggs within his that would excite
fans. Oh, yeah, I could see that for sure.
So fucking mind boggling that studios like Sony
and Warner Brothers get this shit wrong because
literally it just seems so easy to give the
fans what they want. I feel like so much commentary
is out there by the fans on exactly what they're
looking for, what their hopes are. And studios
really just need to fucking do that and do nothing
else. Studios really just need to fucking give
me a call. I will tell them what they should
do. Yeah, let's move on to our character breakdown.
Now, Arthur Fleck, I'm not going to call him
the Joker because clearly he's not. He was
played by Joaquin Phoenix. I'm not sure I could
say anything about his performance that I didn't
say the first time around. It's perfect. It's
perfection. I've seen some people say that
he seemed lazy in this film, like he was just
phoning it in or cashing a check. I didn't
get that at all. Like, sure, Arthur is pretty
timid at the beginning, but I also noticed
that over the course of the film. more and more
of the Joker character was brought back out
in him up until the end when he rejected the
idea of the Joker. No, I mean, well, Arthur
Fleck is a sad character, so he's going to be
mopey for a lot of this runtime. You know,
he's in prison and the character of Harley Quinn
starts kind of bringing him out of his shell.
And I totally saw the difference between his
pre-Harley Quinn state and his post-Harley
Quinn state. So I definitely think that honestly,
for such a terrible film, he still gave an
Oscar caliber performance here. It's just gonna
be sad that, you know, he's not gonna get any
recognition for that because of how terrible
the writing was at the end. Right. Yeah. Now,
Arthur's arc in the first film was all about
being seen. He felt invisible, like no one
saw or cared about him, someone who was abused
and needed help in a harsh world. It wasn't
until he struck back, killing three men who
had been beating him, that he started to get
noticed and he thrived on that newfound attention.
This sequel asks whether or not the Joker was
an alternate persona. and we do get an answer
from Arthur himself that Joker was simply an
act, a mask of sorts that he was able to hide
behind to do or say things under a guise of
anonymity. But Arthur's mask becomes a symbol
for the oppressed rising up against the elite,
and it's a cause he never intended to start.
And by the start of this film, he's largely
removed from the fanaticism surrounding him
until he meets Harley and his trial starts.
In the same way that Arthur initially became
drunk on the attention he received as Joker,
Arthur in this film becomes intoxicated by Harley's
infatuation with him and seemingly the perceived
mission of the Joker. The guy's incredibly lonely
and is tantalized by the prospect of a normal
life with a family and in the end he chooses
that over any kind of revolution. Arthur never
wanted to change society, he wanted to be a
part of it. and not be rejected by it as someone
with mental illness. One of the reasons I feel
this film is so pointless is that Arthur is
so unbelievably tragic and you pity him and
you hope for him and all of that hope is dashed.
Yeah, he dies at the end. He gets stabbed and
nothing happens. What the fuck? Yeah. He like
dies basically alone and no one cares that we
know of. It's just it's OK. Thanks. Thank you.
Thanks a lot, Todd Phillips. You jerk. One of
the biggest things that upset me about the
film regarding the character of the Joker is
trying to determine what the exact catalyst
was for him turning his back on his made up
persona. Now, there are a lot of events that
happened that you could say served as that catalyst
for his change of heart. Whether it was the
testimony of Gary Puddles, his friend, or because
his friend Ricky died who he had inspired.
Or maybe it was because the guards beat the
shit out of him and then raped him. Uh, which
I was not okay with. Like I don't understand
why they needed to include the scene. The idea
that you can make the argument that the reason
Joker changed his mind about everything was
because he got sodomized just infuriates me.
We don't know what the exact catalyst is, but
the argument could be made that his rape caused
this change of heart. Like I, I don't understand
what kind of movie this is that would include
something like that. I just didn't appreciate
it as a fan of the character or as a fan of
the first film. Or as a human being? Exactly.
Yeah, it's not explicit what happens to him
in the showers, although I think it's pretty
clear what they were trying to imply. I for
one though don't think that was the catalyst.
I think ultimately what it was, was the death
of Ricky. You saw Arthur lying there in his
cell after what just happened to him and he's
listening. to this guy who took a liking to
Arthur and was definitely, like you said, inspired
by him, die as a consequence of Arthur's actions
riling up the inmates as the Joker, as a figure
of someone who's standing up for himself. It
gave Ricky a courage that he didn't have before,
and he died because of it. But there was no
clear indication that Arthur Fleck cared at
all about Ricky. Well, there was a number of
times that Ricky was the first to stand up for
Arthur. He would sit next to him in the prison
courtyard. And I think he had a closer relationship
with Ricky than many of the other inmates,
you could argue. And by nature, Arthur is a
sympathetic guy. Like he cares about other
people. And I think one of those people he did
care about was Ricky because he liked him and
Arthur likes people who like him. So I actually
think it was that realization that the symbol
of him could put innocence at risk. I think
that was ultimately his decision. I'm not 100%
on that. I'm sure other arguments could be made,
but that's what I thought about. Because I
was like, yeah, I was like, what happened? What
was the catalyst? What changed his mind? And
that was the conclusion I came to. Yeah, personally,
I think it was the testimony of Gary Puddles.
Even though right up until the moment he got
the shit kicked out of him by the guards, he
was still being honorary. He said to the guards,
I guess I'm in trouble, joking around right
before they did that to him. Yeah, still making
jokes like, Oh, aren't you going to buy me
dinner first? Yeah. Which I know there's actually
a number of jokes that were very dark like
that one, like I hope you get cancer, things
like that. You mentioned Arthur being ornery
even after his questioning of Gary and leading
up to him talking with the guards and stuff
like that. He was actually ornery going all
the way up to his closing arguments in front
of the jury, pulling up the stool, grabbing
the microphone like he was going to do a stand
up bit. Even the judge saw that coming. So I
was completely. taken aback when he didn't
do anything as noteworthy as his conversation
with Marie Franklin from the first film. I
thought all chaos was about to break loose like
in that movie and it was the exact opposite.
It wasn't a bang. It was a complete absolute
whimper and one that I felt really betrayed
by. Probably in the same way that Arthur felt
betrayed by Lee. And speaking of which, let's
move on to Harleen Quinzel played by Lady Gaga.
I'm not a huge fan of Lady Gaga's music. I'm
not really familiar with it. But the mere fact
that they cast a musician who can't act got
me pretty excited when her casting was first
announced. And I think she did a terrific job
in the role. I don't think she's a better Harley
Quinn than Margot Robbie, but I also think
that's because of what was on the page. For
as different as they made Harley Quinn in this
movie, I also think Lady Gaga did a great job
capturing the crazy slash dangerous aspect
of the character. She was as interesting in
the role as Joaquin Phoenix is as the Joker.
I found it really fascinating what they did
with the character and it had so much potential,
so much promise. The crazy was palpable. 100%.
And I appreciated that for sure. Now in the
comics, Harley was a psychiatrist at Arkham
who was manipulated by the Joker into falling
in love with him and becoming a henchwoman for
him to abuse. This film is sort of the opposite
of that. Arthur Fleck isn't confident enough
to entice a romantic partner. But Harley, or
Lee as she's called in this film, is crazy enough
to check herself into a mental institution
just to get close to Joker. It's mentioned that
she did postgraduate work in psychiatry, and
I'd like to think that simply by studying Arthur
Fleck's case, she pitied him and empathized
with him to the point that she took on his worldview.
And that's the whole reason behind the title
of Folly Ado. But that backstory is never explored,
so I may just be giving the film too much credit.
You know, Folly I Do refers to a shared delusional
disorder. And outside of my headcanon, I can't
think of what else the title would be in context
to in the film. I mean, that's a great headcanon,
but it's also one that the film doesn't deserve,
because if the film was better and smarter,
they would have done exactly that. Exactly.
Now, Harley met Arthur while she was in music
therapy class, and she uses song manipulate
him, drawing out the Joker from Arthur like
a Gotham City siren, with the intention of helping
the Joker usher in a new world, seemingly,
though it's not clear why. Maybe it was out
of guilt for her affluent upbringing, or maybe
she knew some kind of ugly underbelly within
the elite world that helped her identify with
Arthur's victimization. It's a huge mystery,
and one that should have been expanded upon.
Yeah, what did she mean by we're going to build
a mountain? Now, I know it was a reference
to a song, but I have no idea what the metaphor
was in reference to in the context of this
film. I was thinking that it was going to be
like a literal pile of corpses that they were
going to build this new world upon. And so my
expectations were completely dashed. Yeah,
same. Instead of a mountain, it was more like
a pile of shit, you know, we're going to build
a pile of shit, apparently. At the end of the
film, when Arthur has given up the act of the
Joker, Harley tries singing to him again. And
when he's like, no, stop singing. I just want
to talk. I think that's when she realizes that
she can't manipulate him anymore. And so she
abandons him like everyone else has. Possibly.
At the end of the film, Arthur is informed
that he has a visitor waiting for him. And that's
when he's killed. Do you think that visitor
was Harley? Did she have a change of heart?
That's a good question. I don't know who else
it could possibly be. Maybe it was his former
lawyer. Those are the only two people I can
think of. Well, it could have been Gary. Oh,
yeah. That's true. I think Gary was too afraid
of Arthur, though, to do that, in my opinion.
Possibly. But he was still, I think, like the
closest thing he had to a friend, maybe. So,
yeah, it was probably either Harley or his
lawyer. And in that sense, maybe there is sort
of like this romantic tragedy at the very end.
But we'll never know. Yeah. Fuck it. Who cares?
Damn it. It's all pointless. Let's move on
to the story highlights.
Where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
DynaMic Podcast Network presents Console Combat,
where video game legends brawl every Monday.
DynaMic Podcast Network Comic Book Titans smash
every Tuesday. Max Destruction, where TV and
action heroes battle every Wednesday. And Sendro
World, where anime champions clash every Thursday.
Join us as we speculate on the matches and armed
with the power of mathematical simulations,
discover who will emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com,
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
Now the film opens with an animated, Looney
Tunes-esque cartoon sequence showing Arthur
Fleck arrive at the Marie Franklin show, only
to be beaten and impersonated by his shadow
who acts on Arthur's worst impulses, humiliates
him, and leaves Arthur to take the rap, a victim
of his shadow, and police brutality. In the
real world, Arthur is medicated and imprisoned
in the criminal wing of Arkham State Hospital,
where he awaits trial for the murder of five
people two years prior. While imprisoned, he's
abused and ridiculed by the security guards
for their amusement, as his ordeal was made
into a made-for-TV film and has made him a
minor public celebrity. On his way to meet his
lawyer, Mary Ann Stewart, Arthur is escorted
past a music therapy class where he first encounters
a patient named Harleen Quinzel, aka Lee. While
meeting with Mary Ann, she explains her hopes
that they can argue Arthur has dissociative
identity disorder and is mentally unfit to be
held accountable for his crimes. having can
meet with a psychologist to gather evidence
for her case. Now, the animated opening was
an interesting surprise. It was actually created
by the same studio that did the triplets of
Belleville, which is a fantastic animated film.
Yeah, I was really taken back by the opening.
I thought it was pretty clever, actually. I
just like cartoons, you know, and the idea
of having the movie open with a cartoon kind
of brought me back to, you know, the 1989.
VHS copy of the Batman movie that you had with
Bugs Bunny and Duffy Duck and I don't know
if this was an homage to that per se but it
was At least an interesting way at the very
least to open your film. That's right You can't
watch your Warner Brothers movie with our Warner
Brothers ballcat Now regarding Arthur's trial
for the murder of five victims I was trying
to count in my head the five victims. Now we
knew that he killed the three people on the
subway, that he killed the clown who bullied
him. And we know that he killed Murray Franklin
live on TV. So right away, I was like frustrated
thinking that they had got the number wrong
because we knew that he killed his mom. And
I was under the assumption that he did kills
as a beats character from the first Joker film.
So I had my number at seven. I was actually
higher than that because I assumed he killed
the psychiatrist lady at the end of the movie
as well. Right, right, right. Yeah, I was wondering
about her too, and then I was surprised to
see that, you know, he didn't kill the psychiatrist
at the end of The First Joker. Yeah, so this
film actually answered quite a number of questions
as to who was killed in the first movie and
who wasn't. I'm actually pretty happy that Zazie
Beats and her daughter were not killed. Right.
Yeah, because I think we described her state
as kind of like a Schrodinger's cat type situation.
You know, she was neither alive nor dead until
the movie chose to reveal that fact, and here
they did. What is your theory as to what the
hell is up with Brandon Gleason's character?
Like, he obviously wasn't a nice guy. They kind
of portrayed him as a fairly straightforward
prison guard who was an asshole, right? But
he wasn't always an asshole. It was really
hard to crack his character, I found. He wasn't
consistent in the slightest. I think he just
enjoyed being entertained by Arthur. I think
he enjoyed kind of the celebrity of Arthur.
I was just kind of semi-fascinated by that.
The fact that he had power over someone who
was a celebrity. That's what I got. He almost
wanted to tease Arthur by taking him to the
music classes, but also it was kind of just
an excuse for him to sing as well, because
the dude loved to sing. Now, after Jackie Sullivan,
a security guard known for singing, gets Arthur
to kiss a fellow criminal inmate named Ricky
for the guard's amusement, Jackie informs Arthur
that he signed him up for a music therapy class
due to his good behavior. During his first
session, Lee tells Arthur that she was forced
into the mental care facility by her mother,
after setting fire to an apartment building,
that she lives in the same neighborhood he
did, that her father died, and that she's a
big fan of the movie they made of Arthur's
crimes. Arthur, beguiled by Lee, confesses to
her that he actually killed six people, including
his mother. Upon his return to the hospital's
criminal wing, Arthur learns that district
attorney Harvey Dent is seeking the death penalty
for Arthur's crimes, sending Arthur into an
before succumbing to a fit of uncontrollable
laughter in reality. The song that played while
all the inmates were watching TV made me realize,
oh, Joaquin Phoenix is not a great singer,
at least not in the musical theater type of
sense. Oh yeah, I don't know if he's ever been
a stage performer, but I could see where he
hasn't. He has been in a band though, I know
that. Yeah, yeah. I don't remember if he was
the lead singer or not though. But not every
lead singer in a band can be in a musical. It's
just a different type of voice training really.
True. So it was kind of awkward hearing him
sing in this moment and being like, oh shit,
no. Yeah, that's harsh. I didn't think he was
that bad. Now the scene after that where he
was crying out on the rain really communicated
the message that he is afraid of dying. He
does not want to receive the death penalty at
the hands of the state. Yeah, that was a pretty
powerful scene and brought up an interesting
theme of the fear of mortality. But it wasn't
one that was really expanded upon too much more
considering that Arthur had something to live
for now. That was Lee. Mm hmm. I do think perhaps
that scene was misplaced. I think it was just
a really powerful performance by Joaquin Phoenix
and they had to put it somewhere. And so they
put it there. I don't think that's the only
place you could have put it, though. Honestly,
I would have saved that for the very, very end
after Lee dumped him and he was back in Arkham.
That would have been perfect. Absolutely. Now
during a movie screening of the 1954 musical
The Bandwagon for the musical therapy animates,
Lee sets fire to a piano to get Arthur's attention,
and the two escape the hospital building alone,
singing and dancing together and capturing
the attention of press outside the hospital
who wanted Arthur to comment on his upcoming
trial. After the two are captured by the hospital
guards, Arthur is placed in solitary confinement,
where he dreams of dancing with Lee upon the
Gotham rooftops. Upon awakening from a dream,
Arthur finds Lee beside him, claiming one of
the guards let her in, and she informs him
that the hospital is sending her home because
he's a bad influence on her. While painting
his face with Joker makeup, she encourages him
to stop taking his medication, promising that
they'll build a mountain and be together. when
his trial is over before the two have sex in
Arthur's cell. Now, I totally thought that this
was a scene that was all in Arthur's head,
because no way in hell did I ever think that
a prison guard would let another mental patient
into Arthur's cell for a conjugal visit or anything
like that, you know? It just didn't make sense.
It wasn't until we hear Lee speaking to reporters
about how they're going to build a mountain
referencing the line that she had previously
told him in the cell that I realized, okay,
so maybe that did happen. It still just doesn't
make any sense to me. Well, I didn't realize
it until she told him that she was pregnant.
And I was like, oh, wait, so that was real,
what? I guess if he was gonna make up a love
scene between him and Lee, that he probably
would have performed better, is what I'll say.
Hey man, it was probably his first time, he
did his best. That's true, that's true. This
musical number where they're dancing on the
rooftops was actually my favorite musical scene.
You know, you have Lady Gaga silhouetted against
the full moon and you have the sign on the rooftop
that says Arkham Hotel. I just thought it was
beautifully rendered. Oh, absolutely. Yeah,
the dancing was fantastic. There was actually
no singing in that scene. But yeah, it was great
as a dream sequence. Now, in an attempt to
garner public support for Arthur and the argument
that he has a split personality. Mary Ann schedules
a live television interview with a sensationalist
journalist named Patty Myers, who riles Arthur
up into singing about his love for Lee. The
next day, Arthur arrives at the courthouse
with hundreds of protesters outside, both for
and against him. While Harvey and Mary Ann
question several mental professionals in regards
to the possibility of Arthur's split personality,
Lee shows up late to the trial and argues with
Mary Ann in front of the press, about how her
approach is making Arthur look bad for his fans.
After advocating for more involvement from
Lee, Arthur learns from Marianne while back
in his cell that Lee has been lying to him,
that she actually grew up with wealthy parents
who are still alive, studied postgraduate psychology,
and checked herself in and out of Arkham willingly.
When Lee visits Arthur and he confronts her,
she confesses to everything but convinces him
that she still loves him, that she's moved
into his old home. and that she's pregnant with
his child. The Patty Meyers interview with
actor Steve Coogan, I thought was going to be
a much bigger thing than it was in the actual
movie. I thought Steve Coogan's life was going
to be threatened in some way. I'm not sure
why, but I also thought this was like the weirdest
musical performance of the entire movie. Yeah,
I was actually surprised Patty just let his
interview essentially become a music video.
You know, the cameras were zooming in on Arthur
as he was singing and everything like that
and the whole thing just totally got derailed.
It's things like that, like that moment and
even the judge letting Joker wear makeup in
the courtroom and stuff like that, that just
add this surreal, unbelievable quality to the
film that just didn't ring true and was kind
of annoying. Well, another thing similar to
that was during the Patty interview when Lee
was watching from outside a department store
window with televisions. She's rich. Go inside.
Buy the TV. You don't need to break the window.
grab the TV and then walk away and get away
with it. Like people saw you do that. Yeah,
I'm surprised nobody confronted her about it.
I was actually pretty excited when I saw Ken
Lung, a psychiatrist up on the stand as one
of the expert witnesses for the prosecution.
I thought that was Hugo Strange because I totally
didn't hear them say his name during the movie.
But after doing my research, it turns out that's
Dr. Victor Liu. So that was... I feel like a
wasted opportunity. When Marianne calls Arthur's
old neighbor and romantic crush Sophie Dumond
to the stand, Arthur is reminded of past childhood
trauma while learning the hurtful truth of how
his mother expressed her feelings toward him
to others. Enraged and humiliated, Arthur fires
Marianne, and that evening, the prisoners riot
as they cheer on Arthur for standing up to authority.
The next day, Arthur represents himself at
the trial while wearing Joker makeup. While
questioning his former co-worker, Gary Puddles,
on the stand, Arthur argues that those who he
killed deserved to die. Gary reveals to Arthur,
however, that his actions have more victims
than just the men who hurt Arthur. Victims
like Gary, who witnessed one of the murders
and is still traumatized by it. After Harvey
rests his case, Arthur refuses to call any more
witnesses in his defense. instead chastising
society and insulting the hospital guards, after
which Arthur leaves the courtroom with Lee
and the two fantasize about getting married.
The Gary Puddles questioning I thought was
a really powerful scene in the movie. I'm not
sure why WKF decided to go with the Southern
accent for the Joker in this scene, but to me
it wasn't necessarily as important as him breaking
character when he was realizing what Gary was
saying was true. I think he was just kind of
emulating some of the more popular Southern
lawyers in the vein of like Gose of Mississippi
or the Lincoln lawyer or something like that.
I don't think it was necessary because I don't
think that like Southern lawyer archetype is
broadly known, but I do think that the Gary
Puddles questioning was the strongest scene
of the film. Yeah, one of them for sure. I
totally agree. The judge in this trial just
fucking sucked though, man. Like, why the hell
did he not put Arthur Fleck in contempt of court,
or at least, you know, like silence him when
he was going off on his rant. I guess it didn't
matter if he held him in contempt because he's
already in prison and everything like that,
but he should have called for order so many
more times than he did in the course of this
trial. Yeah, 100% he should have. I thought
it was weird how they had that sequence of Joker
and Harley getting married. Like, why include
that if it's not going to happen? I understand
you want to show maybe Joaquin Phoenix fantasizing
about that. But he did it after a moment when
he ran off with Lee. So it's almost like it
was a shared fantasy between them. When, if
there was a shared fantasy between them, why
didn't they get married in real life? There's
probably no opportunity to. I think you could
marry someone who's locked up. All you have
to do is sign papers. Don't ask me, man. Now
upon returning to Arkham, Joker is assaulted,
seemingly sexually, by the guards in the hospital
showers. After being dragged back to his cell,
Arthur listens as the inmate Ricky gets riled
up and is strangled to death by the guards.
The next day in the courtroom, Arthur prepares
to go on a tirade during his closing remarks
to the jury, blaming society for his life and
actions, but instead he confesses that it wasn't
an alternate personality that killed those
people, that the Joker persona isn't something
he grapples with or a rebellious cause of the
disenfranchised that he wants to champion. Enraged,
Lee storms out of the courtroom and returns
home, where she seemingly attempts suicide as
Arthur leaves a voicemail expressing his feelings
for her. That was strange. Like, super strange.
I don't understand why they had that attempted
suicide scene with Harley if they didn't address
it in any way, shape or form later on. It just
seemed kind of random. It feels like there was
a missing scene. Yeah, that's what it feels
like. Like, why didn't she go through with it?
Why did she give herself a haircut? Why was
she just like hanging out on the steps? Was
she waiting for Arthur? Was she responsible
for the bomb? Yeah. No idea. My guess is that
she struggled with pulling the trigger, decided
not to cut her hair, and let the Joker go from
her life. Basically deciding that this facade
of a guy was not worth killing herself over.
That's like another headcanon piece regarding
the character of Harley Quinn that they should
have shown in the movie, and they didn't. So
many better scenes could have been included
in this film other than these musical numbers
that were just totally unnecessary. 100% Absolutely.
That is the truthiest truth that has been truth
on this review. Now when the jury reads their
guilty verdict, Arthur begins laughing uncontrollably,
causing a member of one of the victim's families
to attack him. In the chaos of the courtroom,
a random car bomb explodes outside the courthouse,
injuring many in the courtroom, including scarring
one half of Harvey's face. When a dazed Arthur
stumbles out of the rubble into the street,
He encounters a man dressed as Joker, who helps
him get into his friend's car. As the two drive
away discussing how Arthur is going to help
bring to a head a societal revolution, Arthur
escapes the vehicle and eventually makes his
way to the steps outside of his old apartment,
where he finds Lee, still alive, but with a
new haircut. Rather than flee with Arthur,
Lee tells him it's over between them and that
their relationship was only ever a fantasy,
while cops surround them and take Arthur back
to Arkham. The next day, Arthur is informed
by a guard that he has a visitor, and as he
goes to see who it is, he's stopped by another
unnamed inmate who had been observing him throughout
the film, who tells a joke expressing his disappointment
in Arthur for giving up the Joker persona before
stabbing Arthur repeatedly in the stomach.
Then, laughing, uses the blade to slice a smile
into his cheeks. As Arthur lays on the ground
bleeding and dying, A smile forms on his face
just before he passes. Okay, you covered a
lot of ground there. Going back to the bomb,
you said it was a random car bomb that went
off. I don't think it was random, but I'm wondering
who even set the bomb. Like where did the bomb
come from? Were they trying to kill Arthur Fleck
for disavowing the Joker or were they trying
to free him or what was the point of it all?
Oh, that's a good question. I never considered
that someone might actually be trying to kill
Arthur. That's valid. It's random in the sense
that we don't know why it went off or who set
it off, essentially. At first I thought maybe
it was the people who rescued him, but that
wouldn't make sense necessarily. It's almost
like the guy in the Joker makeup had no idea
what was going on with the trial because him
and his buddy were talking about how Arthur
Fleck was going to change the world and everything
like that, but he had just got done disavowing
the Joker, right? I want to know why everyone
seemingly got horribly injured in this blast.
and yet Joker, who was pretty close to it,
was not. That's a great question. It felt inconsistent.
Friggin' Harvey Dent got his face all fucked
up. That was actually a pretty neat moment,
I thought. That was cool, that was cool. I
like the actor who played Harvey Dent. I agree,
I liked the choice that they went with. I liked
his voice, he did a fantastic job. Now, as I
mentioned earlier, there are set photos that
were taken while filming was occurring of Harley
pushing. Arthur down the steps and that's what
I thought was going to happen. It should have
happened. Yeah, possibly. Either that or they
went off together, but I totally thought that
Harley was going to kill Joker in that moment.
I've seen people say that the man who kills
Arthur at the end is the Dark Knight's Heath
Ledger's Joker. This is obviously not the same
universe as The Dark Knight considering we
have different origin stories for Harvey Dent
and the death of the Waynes. Right. Oh, yeah,
this is totally not Heath Ledger's Joker. I
think maybe they were trying to reference that
version of the Joker. But no, there are too
many discrepancies between this universe that
Arthur Fleck exists in and the Dark Knight's
continuity. And after this movie, I don't want
them to be related. Like this movie already
kind of ruined the first Joker movie. Don't
let it ruin the Dark Knight trilogy as well.
Now, we've been bashing on this film for. the
whole duration of this review basically. I do
want to emphasize though that for the most
part, I thought the film was really well made
and I liked it up until the final moments.
Because once Arthur disavowed the Joker, the
film was essentially anti-climax after anti-climax
after yet another anti-climax. And therefore
unbelievably disappointing as a comic fan or
the lover of story in general. I think the film's
craze-worthy performances and gorgeous cinematography
just can't salvage the poor punchline of an
ending in this ultimately disappointing follow-up
to the original, which again was fantastic.
I really, really wanted to give this film three
stars, but upon doing this review, I realized
I can't in good conscience do that. I liked
the movie up until the final act for the most
part, but There are a lot of problems throughout
the film, not just in the final act. So I'm
giving it two and a half out of five stars,
a rotten rating on Rotten Tomatoes. Yeah, I
think I would go along that route too. Two
and a half sounds fair. You know, it's an F
rating. Definitely not recommended. Definitely
getting a rotten tomato from me. I just can't
believe how disappointed I was walking out
of the theater. Dude, and that being even from
someone who didn't have the highest of expectations
for the film regardless, it just on so many
levels was not the movie that it should have
been. It didn't live up to its potential set
up by the first film or even, you know, its
premise. And that's one of the most tragic things
about this story. But you know what? As long
as people saw the first one, they don't need
to see this one. This one, as far as I'm concerned,
is dead to me. I don't ever want to talk about
it again. Warner Brothers had one job this
year, one job, put out a good DC movie, and
they blew it. And that, kind of in a twisted
way, makes me happy, because an L for DC is
a W for Marvel, as far as I'm concerned. This
is an L for the comic book genre, because this
was supposed to be yet another film that elevated
it to the point of it winning accolades amongst
the broader Hollywood industry. So yeah, you
should not have a smile on your face. We should
all have our upside down Joker faces on. No,
I think the success of Deadpool and Wolverine
is still riding pretty high. Although, you
know, that may entirely change if the Venom
movie really sucks that's coming out in a few
weeks and if Craven really sucks. We may be
in dire straits here as far as the genre is
concerned. I hate to tell you this, but Deadpool
and Wolverine is not winning any Oscars. I
don't care. You should. You want the box office
saying so many people saw it. So many people
loved it. So the Joker is just a moot point.
But it's more than that. It's way more than
that, unfortunately. Its failure, I think, is
a massive blow to what James Gunn and Peter
Seifert and want to do with DC Studios. It just
it's that's funny, too, though. Oh, fuck you.
Whatever, dude, whatever. I'm done with this
review. AJ, help close this out. Thanks for
listening to Dynamic duel. Visit the show's
website at dynamicduel.com and follow us on
Instagram at dynamicduelpodcast. You can support
the show on Patreon at patreon.com slash dynamicduel
and joining a tier that works for you, or by
rating and reviewing Dynamic duel on Apple
Podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser or on our website.
Don't forget to listen to the other shows in
the DynaMic Podcast Network, including Max
Destruction, Senjow World and Console Combat.
In our next episode as part of Spooktober, we
will be doing a duel between Clarion the Witch
Boy and Agatha Harkness. It's a witch on witch
battle. And which witch is going to win? We'll
find out next week. But that does it for this
episode. We want to give a big thanks to our
executive producers. Ken Johnson, John Swarovski,
Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Balcom, Mickey Mathengian,
Brandon Estregard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yeaton,
Austin Wazilowski, AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho,
Andrew Schunk, Dean Molesky, Devin Davis, Joseph
Kirsting, and Josh Leiner for helping make
this podcast possible. We'll talk to you guys
next week. Up up and away, true believers.