This is a Dynamike Network podcast.
Hi and welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast,
a weekly show where we review superhero films
and debate the superiority between Marvel and
DC by comparing their characters in stat-based
battle simulations. I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his
twin brother Marvelous Joe. And in this episode,
we are doing a duel between the two landmass
characters, Danny the Street from the Doom
Patrol comics and Kercoa, a mutant from Marvel's
X-Men comics. This matchup has been an idea
that our executive producers came up with a
while back. I never actually thought you would
ever do it because the speculation is going
to be weird for this one. Like I still have
no idea how it's going to go down. We're going
into uncharted territory here, folks. Somebody
give us a Guinness World Record because I think
we're going to be the first people ever to
speculate on how a fight would go between two
locations, not people or things to locations.
No idea how that's going to work out. Right,
yeah, wish us luck. Before the matchup, we're
going to break down the comic book movie news
from the past week, of which there was still
not really any news thanks to the ongoing writers
and actors strikes. We are going to talk about
Ed Boon, the creator of Mortal Kombat, talking
about a potential Marvel vs. DC fighting game,
and that's about it. As always, we list our
segment times in our episode description, so
feel free to check out the show notes if you
want to skip ahead to a particular topic. As
our listeners already know, our dual simulator
has become so advanced it's gained sentience,
and has named itself the artificial life form
for running extensive duels, just a rather
very intelligent simulator 9000, or Alfred Jarvis
9000. Here's a quick message for our listeners,
so listen up. Why hello there. Do you love listening
and chatting about Marvel and DC? Then become
a part of the dynamic dual community on Patreon,
where you can choose from three tiers. The
dynamic 2-0 tier lets you listen to this podcast
without ads, and gives you access to its Discord
chat group where you can chat with Johnny DC
and Marvelous Joe. The Fantastic Four tier
gives you that and more with two bonus episodes
each month. including bloopers and top 10 shows
where Johnny and Joe count down your favorite
Marvel and DC subjects. The X-Force tier makes
you an executive producer of Dynamic Duel, where
every month you help the hosts choose what
to review and who to fight against each other.
And finally, the Dynamite Podcast Network tier
allows aspiring podcasters to create their own
battle-focused show using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and consultation,
and get you simulation results to announce on
your show. Pitch the twins your show via email
at dynamic dual podcast at gmail.com or by reaching
out to them on social media Check it out at
patreon.com slash dynamic dual pip cheerio Thanks
a j9k and thanks to everyone who supports the
podcast Be sure to tune into the max destruction
podcast this week guys Wednesday August 30th
They're gonna do an episode where they find
out who'd win in a fight between Sarah Connor
from Terminator versus Ellen Ripley from alien
that's gonna be a Big episode, definitely check
it out. The speculation between Dustin and Ken
should be awesome. Yeah, this is an episode
that I've been waiting for since the start of
Max Destruction, so I'm super excited. But
also be sure to tune into Senjou World, a new
battle podcast featuring your favorite anime
characters that drops every Thursday. Tune in
this week to find out who had went in a fight
between Hayato Ferengi from Kenichi, the Mightiest
Disciple, and Yujirō Hanma from Baki. Visit
dynamicpodcast.com or click the link in our
show notes to listen to all the shows in our
network. But with that out of the way, quick
to the no prize! A no prize is an award Marvel
used to give out to fans. Our version, the Dynamic
Dual No Prize, is a digital award that we post
on Instagram and in our email newsletter for
the person that we feel gave the best answer
to our question of the week. Last week's question
was... Who's your favorite robot character
from Marvel and DC and why? And that was coming
off of the announcement of my and Jonathan's
card game that we invented called Chronicle
AI, which is about artificial intelligence
robots. We got three answers total, so let's
run down our two honorable mentions and the
no prize winner. Our first honorable mention
goes to Christopher Menotti, who said, Hi guys,
Christopher Menotti. My favorite Marvel DC robot
character is Red Tornado. Red Tornado is a
great character that is not used enough. I think
his powers are very unique for a robot. Robots
tend to have a lot of the same powers. Plus,
it's a lot of fun watching his character grow,
especially in Young Justice, when he creates
an alternate body to experience humanity. I
think that's really interesting. Yeah, Red Tornado
is very unique when it comes to other robots.
Not many of them are elemental forces of nature
like the Red Tornado, right? And the character
was very well done in Young Justice, which was
a callback to his mentorship role in the comic
of the same title. Yeah, Red Tornado has always
been this interesting mix of like technology
and nature, you know? So there's always been
that dichotomy within the character that I
thought has been pretty interesting. If you
want to learn more about Red Tornado, check
out his dual episode against Sandman. It was
basically wind versus earth powers. It was
pretty cool. Yeah, our next honorable mention
goes to Mitchell Smoothie, who said, Hello,
Mitchell Smoothie here. And I would say my favorite
robot is probably from Marvel, and it's the
sinister Adaptoid. Due to his abilities to copy
all the sinister six, he's just the best robot,
taking the best parts of Super Adaptoid and
putting them into his own spin. That's why
he's just the best robot. and he is a robot.
I checked it out. Thank you. Have a great day.
Yeah, the sinister adaptoid is an adaptoid with
the powers of the sinister six. I would argue
that super adaptoid is actually better. The
super adaptoid gave birth to the adaptoid after
acquiring the power of the cosmic cube. And
the super adaptoid itself was created from
AIM, Advanced Idea Mechanics using a portion
of their cosmic cube. Basically the robot can
adopt any sort of power that it wants to. We're
hoping to get a dual episode with Super Adaptoid
against Amazo at some point, because Amazo is
a robot with pretty much the same power too.
That'll be a good one. Yeah, I remember Super
Adaptoid from the Modok show and he was hilarious.
That's my only experience with him. But yeah,
I think he's a fantastic robot. Thanks Christopher
and Mitchell for taking the time to visit our
website and record an answer. But the winner
of this week's no prize is Travis Herndon, who
said, Hey guys, Travis here. So my pick would
have to be Baymax. I know he's not completely
accurate, but he's still an iconic robot character
after just one movie. From his design, from
his voice, you can't hate Baymax. And if you
do, well, you deserve to get throw-a-chopped.
Not punch, but chopped for that comment. Yeah,
I mean, if you don't like Baymax, who the hell
do you think you are, right? Baymax is one
of the most original, unique robot character
designs in the history of robots, honestly.
The way Pixar adapted him from the comic books
where he was more of a techno shapeshifter
to the film Big Hero 6 where he is like a cuddly
balloon healthcare robot I thought was pretty
ingenious. I mean, I don't like Baymax. Well
you're a piece of shit then. Guess what? Prepare
to get throat chopped. I'm just kidding. I like
Baymax. I love the design, like you mentioned,
of the character from the movie. Have they incorporated
that version into the comics? No. No, they
haven't. He's still like a metallic robot. Although,
you know, they don't appear too much. Well,
apparently Marvel Comics doesn't care for Baymax
either. They've kind of relinquished the characters
to Disney publishing, because Disney kind of
took the characters in a direction that seems
a little bit more iconic and lasting. Interesting.
So congrats to Travis for winning this week's
No Prize. If you the listener want a shot at
winning your own No Prize, stay tuned to later
on this episode when we'll be asking another
question of the week. And now that that's done,
on to the news.
All right, this past week, ComicBook.com did
an interview with Ed Boone, who is the creative
director behind NetherRealm Studios, which is
a video game production company behind the
Mortal Kombat franchise. And they've also done
video games like Mortal Kombat versus DC and
the Injustice fighting video games. Ed has been
talking for a while about how one of his dream
projects would be a Marvel versus DC fighting
video game. And that's pretty cool because
it is also a dream project for us. Marvel versus
DC fans. You know, that's the end all be all,
I think, is a fighting video game between these
comic book characters. And when Ed Boon talks
about it, it feels more and more like it's within
the realm of reality, you know? Hopefully we
see this before we get too old, you and I, Jonathan.
But it was interesting because like a while
back, he posted a poll on Twitter asking fans
what they hoped his next project would be.
And one of the options on that poll, was a Marvel
versus DC game, and it overwhelmingly won his
Twitter poll, and nothing has been heard since,
other than Ed Boon basically stating that it
would be difficult to bring this into fruition.
I mean, I kind of feel like if DC and Marvel
don't agree to do this, they're just leaving
the money on the table, right? Absolutely,
yeah. I think with both film franchises struggling
as well, this would be a great way to test
the waters to see how eager audiences are for
a Marvel and DC crossover. Yeah, it might be
a good transition from like a cinematic universe
to a video game universe in which they release
a bunch of, you know, different spin-offs and
stuff like that. I think that would be a hell
of a good time. I'm gonna go ahead and read
a quote from comicbook.com's interview with
Ed Boon regarding this project in which he said,
I mean, we did a number of games with DC characters
with your kids and you're like, who would win
in a fight? Mighty Mouse or Superman? Just
these dumb different universe things. There's
part of us that still has those immature conversations.
To me, Spider-Man and Batman would be the coolest
thing in the world. So of course we'd love
to do that, but it's probably very difficult
to jump that hurdle. To which I say, Jonathan
and I have made it a weekly thing to have those
immature conversations. It's so much fun to
speculate on how battles between these characters
will go. And even more exciting, I think, would
be to actually play it out using a controller.
Oh yeah, absolutely. We've mentioned this before.
maybe once or twice on this podcast. That's
the whole reason we even have this podcast
is because we've been dreaming about a Marvel
versus DC video game since we were teenagers.
Legit, no lie, sometimes I like go to bed at
night just dreaming up different ways that
a Marvel versus DC video game could go. Usually
in my dreams, it ends up something like Super
Smash Brothers or the recent DC multiverses
game. But I would settle for literally any
version of this game. For real, I would take
anything like Even like a Tetris version of
it, I would take like a Pokemon like back and
forth, choose your move, kind of RPG style.
Anything! Anything Marvel vs. DC. Yeah, of course
DC characters are in a fighting game called
Injustice, which uses the same combat engine
as Mortal Kombat. And the Marvel characters
are commonly featured in the Marvel vs. Capcom
video games, which uses a Street Fighter type
fighting engine. So there's a lot of different
ways that this game could go, but... That brings
us to our question of the week.
Pitch us your perfect Marvel vs. DC video game.
What would it be like? Yeah, record your answer
at dynamicduel.com by clicking on the red microphone
button in the bottom right hand corner of the
screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long, and don't forget to leave your name in
case we include you on the podcast. We'll pick
our favorite answer and award that person a
Dynamic Duel No Prize that we'll post to Instagram
and our email newsletter. Be sure to answer
before September 2nd.
So that does it for all of the news for this
episode, now let's move on to the main event,
where we find out who would win in a fight between
the Doom Patrol member, Danny the Street, and
the X-Men member, Krakoa.
Okay, Danny the Street versus Kracoa. As we
mentioned, this is a lead up to episode 350
in a few weeks. That's going to pit the teams
of the Doom Patrol against the Guardians of
the Galaxy. When we and the executive producers
were trying to think of the rosters for that
team matchup, we figured that Mento was a good
member to put on the Doom Patrol team. Although
I don't think any of us loved that Mento is
not a really well known member and he's kind
of an asshole douchebag. He's just not a very
good character, but everyone loves Danny the
Street. You know, he's very popular on the Doom
Patrol television series. And so when we were
thinking of the idea of maybe we replace Mento
with Danny the Street, I have to admit, I got
a little frightened because I knew that more
people were going to like Danny the Street
than Mento. And sure enough, we voted to include
him on the roster, which brings us to this
episode. Yeah, of course, there's not a whole
lot of people that Danny of the Street can
go up against on Marvel. The most prominent,
like, physical location other than Ego, the
living planet, which we've already done a dual
episode with him. But the other best example,
I think, is Krakoa, the sentient mutant island
that is the current home of the X-Men and all
mutants on Marvel's Earth. Yeah, the closest
thing we've done to two locations fighting
each other is... ego, the living planet against
Mogo, the Green Lantern, which was like a month
ago. Yeah, but that was like relatively easy
because the two planets are still, you know,
like separate entities, you know, they exist
within their own space and everything, but
to like locations like a street and an island,
how do you get them to fight against each other?
We're going to figure it out. But to explain
the methodology behind our duels, let's go
to our sentient dual simulator, Alfred Jarvis,
9000 AJ 9K. Tell our listeners how you go about
determining a winner in our dual matchups.
from which the DC characters' statistics are
extrapolated. Additional stat categories are
included, such as range, damage potential, versatility
and perception, in order to create a more detailed
and accurate simulation. The results of the
1000 simulations provide a percentage of wins
for each character. The contestant with the
higher percentage is declared the victor, as
they have a higher probability to win any given
battle. In an equitable pairing, neither character
should win 100% of the matches. The comic book
stories have shown that there's even a way
for Batman to defeat Superman, so the confidence
rate of my method falls in line with the precedents
that have been established in the source material.
My mathematical simulations are without subjectivity
or bias. Feats are not the sole consideration,
nor are fan votes tabulated for determination
of the winner. Thanks AJ9K! Before we run the
simulations though, we like to break down each
character's histories and abilities before improvising
a scenario. on how we imagine one of the 1000
simulations would play out beat for beat. Yeah,
and I believe it's my turn to go first, this
time with the Marvel character, so let me go
ahead and tell you all about Krakoa. Two billion
years ago, the very first mutants outside of
the normal cycle of evolution thrived on Earth.
One of these mutants was named Grov, a being
who, along with their fellow mutants, formed
a group called the Threshold. The Threshold
was attacked by a group of undersea mutants
called the Unbreathing, and Grove sustained
heavy injuries in battle. Grove's mutation,
which allowed them to heal through vegetative
growth, transformed them from a wood-elf-looking
being into a bark-covered creature much like
the species Flora colossi, of which the hero
Groot is a member. No longer resembling themselves,
Grove changed their name to Okara. And though
both the threshold and unbreathing mutants would
eventually perish, Grove, now Okara, lived
on, changing and growing through the millennia
until they reached the size of an island, free-floating
in the South Pacific. Several thousand years
ago, Okara became an island home to a new generation
of mutants led by Apocalypse, whom you can learn
more about in our Black Atom vs Apocalypse
duel. These mutants were attacked by an other-dimensional
demon horde. to cleave Okara in half. Grove,
which had become Okara, now became two separate
beings, Oroko and Krokoa. Apocalypse sealed
the dimensional breach, trapping the demon horde
in their native realm, but sacrificing his
fellow mutants alongside Oroko, half their home.
This left Krokoa alone, once again existing
as a free-floating island, now just a part of
its former whole and without much of its former
sentience. Years later, during World War II,
Krakoa played a small role in the Pacific Theater
when Nick Fury and his Howling Commandos stumbled
upon the island and discovered it was sentient.
Fury and Krakoa reached an agreement that allowed
the commandos to leave the island as long as
they kept its existence a secret. You can learn
more about Nick Fury in his duel episode against
Rick Flag. Eventually, Professor X telepathically
discovered Krakoa via his power amplifying
device called Cerebro. He sent his X-Men to
investigate, but the island captured them.
Professor X then sent additional mutant recruits
to rescue the X-Men. Krakoa formed itself into
a giant humanoid shape and attacked the mutants,
but Polaris, a mutant with powers of magnetism
like her father Magneto, used her abilities
that were supercharged by Storm's lightning
to interact with the Earth's magnetic field,
and she launched Krakoa's landmass into space.
While in orbit, Krakoa was captured by the enigmatic
cosmic entity known as the Stranger. The Stranger
took the island to its lap for study, however
some spores of Krakoa had broken off prior
and landed on Earth. One spore became a danger
room-like training ground called the Danger
Grotto, which was used by the Generation X mutant
team. Another spore swallowed up 56 construction
workers before it was stopped by the new mutants.
And another spore... landed in the British
Isles where the mutant team Excalibur defeated
it. Eventually, a member of the Eternals race
managed to free Kakoa from the Stranger's Lab
in space and it returned to Earth. Professor
X began working to reawaken the island's consciousness
and reshape Kakoa into a paradise for mutants
as it had once been thousands of years prior.
He bioengineered new flowers on the island
that produced chemicals that solved many of
regarding antibiotics, longevity, and mental
illnesses. Professor X offered these drugs to
any country that recognized Krakoa as a sovereign
mutant nation, transforming the island into
a pharmaceutical titan and world power overnight.
He also created flowers that could bloom into
self-sustaining biomes anywhere in the universe,
which also served as gateways to and from the
main island. After a period of prosperity on
Krakoa, where Professor X and Magneto seemingly
achieved a compromise regarding human and mutant
relations, Krakoa's other half, Arako, returned
from the other dimension where it and its mutant
residents had been trapped. Angry at Apocalypse
for his actions several millennia ago, both
islands chose a series of champions to represent
them in a fighting tournament instead of an
all out war. Ultimately, Krakoa's champions
won the contest and Apocalypse was sent to
while Arako was brought to Earth. Though the
two island halves had finally gotten their
chance to reunite, they had grown so different
over the millennia that Krakoa and Arako decided
to remain separate and unique. However, a new
island of warlike mutants didn't seem feasible
on Earth when the mutants of Krakoa had just
achieved a semblance of peace with humans.
Therefore, Magneto developed a plan to relocate
Arako to Mars, where he would terraform the
to accommodate that island and its mutants.
Mars was then claimed as the first mutant world,
with Arako serving as the new capital of the
solar system. Back on Krakoa, which achieved
a total population of approximately 250,000,
mutantkind celebrated their new achievements
with an annual celebration event called the
Hellfire Gala. And that's as far as I'll get
with Krakoa's backstory. Powers-wise, Krakoa
is a sentient hive-mined landmass incorporating
all vegetable and animal life forms that reside
on it outside of its mutant inhabitants. It
has full control of its mass and can terraform
in any manner it chooses, including creating
natural formations such as forests, volcanoes,
and lakes, and unnatural formations such as
massive tentacles, or a giant humanoid rock
plant monster, or even small life forms that
serve as an extension of itself. Krakoa can
drain the life force out of any being that
steps foot on its surface. And its biome can
also survive in any environment, even the cold
oxygenless void of space, and it can create
gateway portals allowing residents to travel
between portions of itself. Krakoa has also
demonstrated the ability to create a variety
of chemicals via manipulation of its own natural
chemistry. Though the island is conscious,
it has limited intelligence and operates mostly
out of instinct. That's Krakoa. That was pretty
convoluted. I'm not sure it needed to be that
convoluted. Well, that describes Hickman's
run on X-Men to a T, right? I mean, Hickman
threw in this entire mythology that he developed
that stretches from ancient prehistory to outer
space. And it's a lot, you know, it's one of
the most unique things about his run on X-Men
and also one of the worst. It's almost like
he brought in all these different elements and
ideas that. don't necessarily fit the mold
of the X-Men, but I still admire Hickman as
a writer nonetheless. Just the whole thing
of like, Krokoa being like initially a like
wood elf that became a plant island that was
split in two. Just make it a fucking mutant
that was an island, period. That's all you
need to say. Right, right, right. I think the
biggest bullshit thing is that he decided to
name the original land mass as an anagram for
Krokoa called Okara. And then it split into
Arako and Krakow. It's just he didn't need to
do that. You know, they didn't need to be rearrangements
of the same six letters. You know, right. Right.
How old is Krakow is like Krakow, like one
of Stanley's old, like monsters like Fin Fum
or something like that. Krakow made its first
appearance to my recollection in Giant Size
X-Men, where we were introduced to characters
like Storm, Nightcrawler and Colossus. Oh, really?
That's cool. And you know what else is cool?
Danny the Street. Let me get to his back story.
Danny the Street is a sentient, male, genderqueer
pocket dimension that most often presents himself
by appearing as a street full of macho military
surplus stores and sports shops, but decorated
with feminine flourishes such as frilly pink
curtains and awnings. Danny is the last survivor
of a dream dimension of pure imagination known
sometimes as Wonderland, Neverland, or Oz that
caught the sickness of the real world and fell
apart. Since then, for decades and perhaps longer,
Danny has traveled the world, warping space-time
to integrate himself seamlessly into any location
in search of the lonely outcasts of the world.
Whether it's an alley in Hong Kong or a street
in Toronto, Danny attracts those who feel unaccepted
and gives them a place to live and feel welcome,
often entertaining them with drag shows performed
by the Perpetual Cabaret, a drag troupe who
also lives on Danny. Danny's existence was
eventually discovered by The Men From Nowhere,
a group founded by Darren Jones who was obsessed
with eliminating from the world any and all
strangeness, peculiarity, or anything that's
not essentially a white picket fan's 1950s sitcom,
which is how he lived his life, going so far
as to have his wife hit a laugh track button
whenever he made a joke in his home. When The
Men From Nowhere arrived on Danny, they began
killing its citizens and breaking Danny's property.
The Doop Patrol arrived and began being attacked
by the men from nowhere as well. After bringing
them down, Danny teleported next to Darren Jones'
home and had the perpetual cabaret dress him
up in drag just before his boss visited for
dinner, which resulted in Darren being fired
and his reputation tarnished after Danny teleported
away. Sounds like the laugh track would be
used a lot in that situation though. It was
used in that situation, exactly. It was revealed
one of Danny's residents was an amnesiac hero
named Flex Mantallo, who had regained his memory
after seeing the Doom Patrol come to the rescue
of the citizens. Flex, attempting to rebuild
his life, was captured by the Men From Nowhere
along with the Doom Patrol member Dorothy Spinner
and imprisoned in the sub-sub basement of the
Pentagon. Danny helped the Doom Patrol rescue
Flex and Dorothy, by teleporting himself into
the Pentagon basement, after which Danny became
the Doom Patrol's headquarters. Not long after,
however, Danny was seemingly abducted by Mr.
Nobody and the Brotherhood of Dada, villains
of the Doom Patrol and outcasts in their own
right, though it was revealed that the Brotherhood
merely wanted Danny to take them away, which
he was happy to oblige. When an evil entity
known as the Candlemaker emerged from the mind
of Dorothy Spinner, After healing from the ordeal,
Danny eventually grew to form Danny the World,
an interdimensional planet and became the home
of several Doom Patrol members such as Crazy
Jane and Negative Man for a time when they left
the team. Danny the World was annihilated by
the Gentrifiers, however, who had attempted
to take him over. Leaving Danny as only a brick,
Crazy Jane fled with him back to the Doom Patrol,
which was based on Oolong Island at the time.
After taking some time to heal, Danny eventually
became Danny the Bungalow. He and Crazy Jane
rejoined the Doom Patrol, during which time
he returned to being a Street. In post-Flashpoint
continuity, Danny the Street was revealed to
be a teenager, who was discovered by Red Robin
of the Teen Titans and recruited to infiltrate
an organization known as Nowhere, which captured
and experimented on young metahumans.
Danny became a member of the Teen Titans, acting
as the team's spy. Danny was later nearly destroyed
by Nowhere and used the last of his strength
to teleport the Teen Titans from Mystery Island
to New York, seemingly sacrificing himself in
the process and ending up as a mundane ally
in the city. It was revealed later, however,
that Danny had actually reverted to the form
of a brick, which was found by Crazy Jane and
the two traveled to the cosmos together. After
being used as a weapon by an entity known as
D to kill a god, Danny retreated to Earth and
grew to become Dannyland, an amusement park.
With the happiness he was able to bring the
masses, Danny gained enough strength to create
his own sentient life, bringing to life a comic
character from the Danny-published Danny Comics
named Casey, space case Brink, to see what
she would be like in the real world. Unaware
of her true nature, Casey was contacted by
Danny and urged to reform the Doom Patrol when
Danny land became threatened by an alien organization
known as Vectra, who wanted to use Danny's new
ability to create life in order to create cheap
meat for their chain of intergalactic fast food
restaurants. Taking on an additional form as
Danny the Ambulance, Danny helped Casey find
the Doom Patrol members to reform the team
and together they defeated Vectra. When the
Dupatrol member Robotman received an upgrade
that caused him to become his own planet, Casey
sacrificed herself to stop him, and she returned
to being a comic character in Danny Comics.
And that's Danny's history so far. Powers-wise,
Danny is a sentient pocket dimension capable
of warping space-time to teleport to any location
and integrate his space seamlessly into it.
Danny has a spatial sense that allows him to
move to any location, in any universe, even
some hidden or unknown areas. He's able to
generate buildings, structures, and objects
to fill his space, and the more inhabitants
that exist within him, the stronger he becomes
and the larger he's able to grow. potentially
even to planet size. When these structures and
objects are damaged, however, Danny is weakened
and is unable to maintain his size. Recently,
Danny has shown to be able to generate sentient
life, though this requires a deal of strength.
He is able to communicate with his inhabitants
by telekinetically transforming the environment
to form words, whether on a window display
or even a puddle on the ground. That's Danny
the Street. I gotta say that's every bit as
whimsical and fantastical as I hoped it would
be being familiar with the character on the
Doom Patrol television series. Anytime Danny
of the Street shows up on that show, I'm always
thrilled because it's just such a unique concept,
especially his method of communication. Just
the way he expresses himself is quite brilliant
actually. I think it's a truly unique concept.
Yeah, he's really cool. I'm glad we're gonna
include him on the team duel match that's coming
up against the Guardians of the Galaxy. I feel
like I have a better idea of how that will
play out where it's an environment versus a
group of superheroes as opposed to how this
will play out where it's an environment versus
another environment. But let's go ahead and
give it a shot.
Because now that we got their histories and
abilities out of the way, we're going to speculate
on how one of the 1000 simulated matches will
go. The winner is determined by simulations,
not the speculation, but it's fun to imagine
how the fight could play out. Alfred Jarvis
9000, what are the rules of our speculation?
Well I should say there are no rules, other
than the characters have no prior knowledge
of the other going into the fight. All they
are aware of starting out is that the other
character is a threat that needs to be eliminated.
For the speculation… The contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the
match itself as no environmental statistics
are considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. And since
both characters are environments, we could go
ahead and disregard what AJ9K said about environments
not being a factor. But let's go ahead and get
into it. Danny the Street and Krakoa meet on
the battlefield and they are the battlefield
as well. But who goes first? OK, so I'm assuming
this match starts off with the environments,
like the street and the island about 50 meters
apart from each other, while the space around
them is otherwise void and empty. But I think
Danny is going to start by teleporting himself
onto Krakow. So now this island has a bustling
street in the middle of it. And am I allowed
to have people on Danny the street? Would you
say like? the perpetual cabaret maybe. I think
like how usually in our duels the environment
has no bearing on the characters. Here, the
characters are gonna have no bearing on the
environments. So the locations have to win on
their own merits basically. Okay. So no people.
Okay, let's say Danny teleports onto Krakoa
and he's just gonna cause like one of the shelves
in his army surplus store to break. So these
boxes of kerosene fuel tanks are just going
to roll out of the store into Krakow, which
is going to cause this huge fire to break out
on the island. And Danny's going to teleport
away from that to prevent any damage to himself.
Okay. So Krakow has this fire going on it, but
it's going to terraform and it's going to divert
a river that's flowing through the island over
to the fire to put it out. And then once it's
out, Krakow is going to divert the river again.
to wherever Danny has teleported and the river's
gonna flood Danny the street. And the flash
flood is basically gonna tear everything apart.
I cannot think of her signs and small buildings.
Except one of the signs is gonna read F-U.
It's gonna be like, oh shit. Okay, so Danny's
definitely hurt by this and he's gonna become
Danny the boat. No, no, Danny the pirate ship.
And on this pirate ship are cannons and that's
going to allow Danny to begin firing cannonballs
in all directions that are just going to tear
through Krakow as Danny sails down the river.
Okay, but Danny the pirate ship now has to
navigate through the series of large jagged
rocks that Krakow puts in the river's path.
So the pirate ship is going to be crashing and
breaking apart all over these rocks and then
oh no, it goes over a waterfall.
Okay, I mean, Denny's sustained more damage,
so he's going to shrink again and transform
as he falls into Denny the fighter jet, because
now he's pissed off. Can he turn into a fighter
jet? Yeah, he could turn into a vehicle. Like
he was once Denny the ambulance, right? Though
he probably can't pilot himself, but you know,
that's what autopilot is for. Okay. So he's
gonna be just like tearing through the sky.
with Highway to the Danger Zone playing a full
blast, and he's gonna begin firing missiles
at the Krakoa surface. I do have to say, this
is very uncharacteristic for Danny. He's normally
very peaceful. You just made him mad. I mean,
it's no holds barred action, so you gotta do
what you gotta do. Right, so Danny's a fighter
jet, but Krakoa is gonna manifest this large
volcano on its surface, which is gonna erupt
a mass of lava and ash into the air. and that's
going to blind Danny while he's flying and
just burn him with the lava. And that's going
to cause him to crash into the mountainside
and die. Well, actually, you know, Cucurro is
going to see the plane go into the smoke, but
he doesn't see Danny emerge because Danny teleports
away to another part of the island, it's like
a flower meadow as Danny, the flower meadow.
And from here, while he's camouflaged. he's
going to gather strength from the life force
of Kercoa itself to become Danny the super
highway. And this thing is going to stretch
across the entirety of Kercoa. It's going to
be full of like massive diesel trucks that are
all running and they're just polluting Kercoa's
environment. Oh no pollution. So earthquake
basically all those streets and vehicles are
going to come crashing down because Kercoa is
going to generate an earthquake. that just
swallows everything up in this massive tremor.
Okay, so Danny's underground. Let's say now
he becomes Danny the mine. Okay, and mines are
full of explosives. So let's say that happens.
The explosives are going to detonate just blowing
up like a huge chunk of the island. And now
Danny is going to teleport across the island
as Danny the pit mine, just causing explosions
all over the island and causing it to cave in
on itself. That's pretty good. Shit. Okay.
All right, in order to stop the explosions from
happening, Kracoa is gonna have to catch Danny,
as it were, right? So when Danny the Mine teleports
to a new underground location on Kracoa, before
he sets off the explosives, Kracoa is immediately
gonna send him up to the island's surface,
and waiting for Danny there are a group of large
stone golems with like giant stone clubs that
just- proceed to beat the ever loving shit out
of this pit mine, rendering everything to dust.
I don't even know what that looks like. Okay,
I mean, if Danny gets hit by a bunch of stone
clubs, he's hurt for sure. So I'm gonna say
he just teleports away, which is gonna cause
the space time that he occupied to fold back
in on itself. And that circle of golems that
were surrounding him hit and destroyed themselves,
all right? Oh, and also I didn't mention this.
but those mines were uranium mines. So chunks
of uranium are all over the island, just poisoning
the shit out of it and just making everything
die essentially. Okay. Well, I mean, in the
comics, the US did atomic bomb testing in the
South Pacific Ocean near where Krakoa lived.
And actually that was what Professor X theorized
turned Krakoa into a sentient mutant, was that
radiation. Dude, that's so much better than
what Hickman came up with. Yeah, that was actually
Krakow's origin story before Hickman wrote the
new backstory. Wow. I'm pretty sure Krakow
has been around radioactivity before and survived
just fine. So I don't think Danny's attempt
to poison Krakow with uranium will do anything.
And if Danny's now a bunker, Krakow is just
gonna drain the life force out of Danny the
bunker and reduce him to, you know, Danny the
rivet. And then Danny the nothing, because he's
dead. But like... If Krakoa wasn't actually
mutated via radiation, then we don't know actually
if it was exposed to it, right? Like that was
just a theory. True. I say Professor X's theory
was wrong, and that Krakoa was never exposed,
and that Krakoa withers and dies, well, Danny
survives. Off of spam and tank. Pfft. Ha ha
ha. Well, let's go ahead and leave the match
there. Either... Danny poisons Krakoa with
uranium by becoming... uranium mines teleporting
all over the island, or Krakowa drains the
life force from Dany as the island can do with
any life form that exists on its surface. Let's
go ahead and find out which of these scenarios
happens by inputting the character stats, running
the simulations, and coming back with a winner.
AG9K, hit it! Inputting data. Running calculations.
Processing results. Simulations complete. I
think actually that speculation went better
than I thought it would, because with Krakoa,
I just had to come up with these natural disasters,
essentially, considering Krakoa is a natural
landmass. So it was easier than I thought it
was going to be, honestly. Yeah, it wasn't too
bad. The stats were not easy, I would say,
and they're very different from any other characters
that we've done before. Things like movement
speed were interesting. We said that Danny,
since he could teleport, was much faster. than
a Krakoa who's essentially stationary. Neither
of these guys evade and their fighting skill
is basically non-existent. Yeah, the stats that
Krakoa really shined in where Danny wasn't
quite up to snuff were durability and damage.
Yeah, Danny could get injured pretty easily,
even just by breaking one of his glass panes.
And he's not very offensive, so his damage
stat category was much lower than Krakoa's.
However, in addition to speed, Danny also excelled
in intelligence because we said Danny's a little
bit smarter than Krakoa, who largely operates
off of instinct. But we said that Danny was
also more perceptive. Yeah, thanks to his spatial
sense that allows him to teleport to locations
and find people. Danny definitely has this
like psychic readout thing going where he knows
exactly what form to take wherever he's teleporting
to. So we accounted for that in his perception.
But both can perceive largely everything that
occurs within them. Right, exactly. Both Krakoa
and Denny are highly versatile, able to do
essentially anything they want with their own
existence, which makes them highly adaptable.
With all these stats in mind and their disparities
and similarities accounted for, Jonathan, who
do you think is walking away with the win on
this? I personally think Denny the Street is
going to win just because he's faster and smarter.
Instagram disagrees with me apparently.
I was surprised actually. I was surprised just
because, you know, Kakoa has never been seen
in live action before, whereas Danny the Street
has. So you think that Danny the Street is
actually more popular than Kakoa? I would have
assumed so. I think a lot of people are taking
landmass into consideration because an island
is a much bigger size than a street. True,
but like Danny the Street can't accommodate
for that. He could become the size of a planet
if the circumstances are correct. You're not
wrong. But I have the results here. Here you
are, sir. The winner between Danny the Street
and Krikoa is Danny the Street. Yes. Which
surprises me. Really? Honestly. Yeah. Danny
the Street out of 1000 matches, won 573 of
them or 57.3 percent of the time, whereas Krikoa
only won 427 or 42.7 percent of the time. The
biggest disparity. within their stats was speed.
Cause apparently Danny the Street can just
teleport all over the place wherever he wants.
That speed advantage of Danny's cannot be overcome
by Krakoa's durability and damage. And then
you have like the intelligence thing kind of
putting Danny a little over the edge. I called
it. Honestly, I think another way this fight
would really play out is that Danny would sense
how lonely Krakoa is just as the solitary island
and then become a planet for him to occupy itself
on. I thought he would just drown the island.
It is pretty interesting the way it played out.
I just think about how much damage like these
creatures that Krikoa manifests could do to
a street. But in the end, that was unable to
help Krikoa get the win, especially when he
considered that Danny could have created his
own life to combat those monsters as well if
he chose to. I don't know. These stats are
like largely theoretical and I guess there's
like a thousand different ways the match could
have gone. It's just that Danny wins slightly
more of them. Boom! But that does it for this
duel, let us know what you thought about the
results by writing to us at dynamicduelpodcast
at gmail.com or by visiting us on Instagram
or X. You can find links to all of our accounts
by checking out our show notes or visiting our
website at dynamicduel.com. And on our site
you can also find a link to our Patreon page
where you can join our Dynamic Duo tier and
chat with us and fellow listeners, our Fantastic
Four tier which gets you bonus content each
month, our X-Force tier that makes you an executive
producer of this podcast, or our newest here
that lets you join our Dynamike Podcast Network.
If you can't join Patreon, you can still support
the show by signing up for our e-newsletter,
also at dynamicduel.com. Or you can also rate
the show on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser,
or on our website. In our next episode, we
will be reviewing the DC animated series, My
Adventures with Superman. It's available on
HBO Max and I think Cartoon Network as well.
It was only 9 episodes, it's not a long watch,
I definitely encourage you guys to watch it
because it's pretty dang good. Yeah, I haven't
started watching it yet so I have some catching
up to do. But looking forward to see how it
is. Well that does it for this episode, we want
to give a big thanks to our executive producers
Ken Johnson, John Storowski, Zachary Hepburn,
Dustin Balcom, Miggy Mathen-Geehan, Brendan
Eschergard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Nick
Ibbonto, Austin Wisselowski, AJ Dunkerley,
Scott Camacho. and Adam Spes for helping make
this podcast possible. We'll talk to you guys
next week. Up, up and away, true believers.
Flawless victory.