This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
Hi and welcome to Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Marvelous Joe. And I'm his twin brother
Johnny DC. And for Spooktober in this Halloween
season, guys, we have a special treat for you.
Just like last year, how we kind of surprised
you guys with our DCs vs. Marvel zombies team
duel episode. We're doing it again. We're going
to do another spooky... team duel and find out
who would win in a fight between the creature
commandos and the legion of monsters slash hellen
commandos. Yeah, of course, this is perfect
timing because DC has a creature commandos television
series that will be coming out later on this
year. Yeah, I really can't wait to get into
this duel match, learn about both teams and
of course find out who will win. That's all
coming later on this episode. Before that,
we're gonna break down the latest comic book
movie news to come out this past week. Of which
there's quite a bit of news coming out of New
York Comic Con. Including our first look at
Crypto in the DCU Superman film, the Creature
Commandos official trailer, the Batman Ninja
vs Yakuza League new trailer, and the Watchmen
Chapter 2 official trailer. All DC news! Yeah,
that's kinda lame, but Marvel got a lot of big
news coming out of D23 a few months ago. Marvel's
going to win this matchup, so... What do you
think, huh? I'm not too concerned. Yeah. As
always, we list our segment times in our episode
description, so feel free to check out the
show notes if you want to skip ahead to a particular
topic. Our artificially intelligent duel simulator,
AJ9K, has a quick message for our listeners,
so listen up. Why hello there, do you want
even more from this podcast? Then become a part
of the dynamic duel community on Patreon, where
you can choose from three tiers. The dynamic
two-oh tier gives you access to our Discord
chat server. The fantastic four tier gives you
two bonus episodes each month, and the X-Force
tier makes you an executive producer of this
show. Lastly, The Diner Mike podcast network
tier lets you create your own podcast using
this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe
will help you develop your show, provide graphic
support and consultation, and get you simulation
results. Pitch the twins your ideas via email
at dynamicduelpodcast at gmail.com. Check it
out at patreon.com slash dynamicduel. Pip pip
cheerio. Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone
who supports the podcast. Be sure to tune into
the other shows in the DynaMic Podcast Network
this week, including Max Destruction, which
pits your favorite action heroes from film
and television against each other. This week,
hosts Scotty and Gilly are determining the
winner between Beetlejuice and Freddy Krueger.
That's gonna be really good. On the Central
World Podcast, host Zachary Hepburn speculates
on fights between fan favorite anime and manga
characters. This Thursday, Zach will find out
who will win between Shinji Ikari from Evangelion
and Monster King Orochi from One Punch Man.
That's gonna be another good one. Hell yeah!
Finally on the Console Combat Podcast, hosts
John and Dean simulate battles between popular
video game characters. In yesterday's episode,
they reviewed Willy's Wonderland, following
their review of Five Nights at Freddy's from
the previous week. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com
or click the link in our show notes to listen
to all of the shows in the DynaMic Podcast
Network. But with that out of the way... Quick!
To the No Prize! A No Prize is an award Marvel
used to give out to fans. Our version, the Dynamic
Duel No Prize, is a digital award that we post
on Instagram for the person that we feel gave
the best answer to our question of the week.
Last week, we asked, What has been your favorite
live-action Marvel or DC television series
so far and why? And that was coming off of the
hype of the Green Lantern casting for the upcoming
Lantern series on HBO. We got a number of answers.
Let's break down this week's honorable mentions
before revealing the no prize winner. Our first
honorable mention goes to Colby Henches who
said, hey boys Colby Henches The best live-action
comic show from Marvel or DC was Marvel's Runaways
on Hulu. It was three seasons It was amazingly
cast and acted. They even brought the girl
who played Nico back to play her again in the
Marvel Midnight Suns video game I don't regret
a minute of that show. It was fun start to finish.
It should have had more seasons. So this one
gets the honorable mention right out of the
gate because I feel like it was controversial,
at least as far as my feelings go regarding
the Runaways television series. If you listen
to our review of the Runaways season two, which
is the only season that we reviewed on this
podcast, you'll note that I didn't really like
the changes that the show had made from the
original comic book series, which I... I thought
it was a lot more exciting than the television
show. The television show kind of became its
own thing. And I'll admit that it was well
cast and the special effects were great, but
it was largely a teen drama, which is how I
guess you could describe the comic book series.
But there was a lot more adrenaline and suspense
and fantastical elements in the comic book series
that weren't present in the live action show.
But I appreciate an opinion that differs from
mine. I don't know if Colby Hentges is a fan
of the Runaways comic books. but I know that
a lot of people really like The Runaways and
it was always interesting to get their perspective
on why. I feel like it appealed to a younger
generation than you and I are. Man, that's cool,
that's fine. I do have to say though that the
comic book series, while I never read it, I
am a big fan of the author, Brian K. Vaughan.
He wrote another one of my favorite series,
Why the Last Man. It was a DC Vertigo comic
book. Fantastic piece of literature. Brian K.
Vaughan is the man. And I kind of wish they
would have adapted the comic series more faithfully
in the television series. But critics like
The Runaways too, so yeah, maybe it should have
got more seasons, but I think that ended due
to Marvel Studios' takeover of Marvel Television.
Yeah, that's right. Great answer, Colby. Our
next honorable mention goes to Michael Williams.
Who said? Mike Williams, I was saying goes
to Missouri. Live action show between DC, the
Peacemaker, and Teen Titans. Really loved Peacemaker
the last episode where the Justice League showed
up. As far as Marvel, Falcon, Winter Soldier.
Enjoy your show. And as always, make mine Marvel.
Take care. Yeah, in reference to the Teen Titans
series, I think he's referring to the live action
Titan series that was on Max, which I think
got better season by season. Peacemaker is also
on Max. I love that show, which was written
by James Gunn, the new head of the DCU. And
I'm really looking forward to season two, along
with everything else he's going to bring to
the universe. Yeah, and Michael also mentioned
for Marvel, The Falcon and the Winter Soldier,
Disney Plus series, and yeah, for my money,
the first episode of that series had one of
the best MCU action scenes of all time. Great
answer, Michael. Our next honorable mention
goes to Daniel Alonso. Who said? Okay, well,
there's only one answer for this, and it's gotta
be Daredevil. I mean, hands down. It's got
incredible fight scenes, the cinematography
is amazing. The freaking acting, the all-star
cast, Charlie Cox, Vincent D'Onofrio, John Bernthal,
Debra Anne Wohl, like come on, it's incredible.
And Daredevil, oh my god, we finally get Daredevil
how he should be. Dude, there's not enough
that I can say about that. I mean, yeah, hands
down, it's gotta be Daredevil, there's no other
answer. That's it. Daredevil's not just one
of the best superhero television series out
there, it's one of the best television series
of all time, period. It's so well made. and
I think it truly transcends the comic book genre
and totally appeals to fans of crime series
and stuff like that as well. I can't say enough
good things about the Daredevil show. Yeah,
I definitely agree with you about it transcending
the genre, particularly in season 3. That season,
I was just riveted every episode. It was so
damn good. I've gotten pretty nervous with
the character popping up in the Spider-Man movie
and She-Hulk. I really don't want Disney to
ruin the character. But it looks like with all
of the different crew changes and reshoots
that they've done with the upcoming Daredevil
Born Again series, it should be pretty good.
I don't think there's anything to worry about
regarding the show making its transition from
Netflix to Disney+, because it's been confirmed
that on Disney+, Daredevil Born Again is going
to be TVMA. And judging from, you know, the
leaked trailers and stuff that have come out
of New York Comic Con and D23, it's going to
be incredible, still keeping in the tone of
the Netflix show. And they announced the premiere
date for... Daredevil Born Again. It's going
to be March 4th, 2025, and the season is going
to be nine episodes. Are you serious? I didn't
know that. Oh, it's going to be forever until
March now. Dig it. Yeah, it's quite a ways
away. But good things come to those who wait,
as they say. We as comic book movie fans know
this most of the time. Great answer, Daniel.
We want to give a quick shout out to Mason
Thompson for taking the time to visit our website
and record an answer. But the winner of this
week's no prize is Travis Bailey. Who said?
Hey, what's up Travis Bailey. Shout out to
my good twin. Look, Marvel, everybody knows
this, dominates every form of media as far
as common sense is concerned. Print, movies,
animation, yes, animation. But if we're being
honest, it has to be watchmen. I mean, the product
that they put out on HBO, I mean, known for
pressing these television, it did not disappoint.
Got some Emmy nods. It validates everything
incessant DC fans say about their work. I think
the main point that we want to take away from
Travis Bailey's answer is that Marvel dominates
everything over DC, including animation. Except
apparently television, which I guess you're
admitting. No, yeah, Watchmen hands down is
the best series that I think has ever been produced
as an adaptation from the comics. Now, of course,
the Watchmen series was a sequel to the Watchmen
comic, but holy cow, was it a phenomenal one.
It was a better sequel than anything DC has
produced since then. including Doomsday Clock.
I don't know if Watchmen is a better show than
Daredevil. Yes, it is. But it's up there. It
was a really damn good show for sure. And not
only did it get a few Emmy nods, it freaking
won more Emmys the year it came out than any
other show it was competing against. It won
a Peabody Award, which is unheard of. Like a
television series, one based off of a comic
book that wins a Peabody, incredible. Yeah,
if you haven't seen Watchmen on HBO, and you're
a fan of Watchmen, definitely check it out,
because it was really well conceived, really
well made. Yeah, Damon Lindelof served as the
showrunner for Watchmen, and he's also serving
as the showrunner for the upcoming Lantern series,
which gets me super, super pumped for that.
So congrats to Travis Bailey for winning this
week's No Prize. If you, the listener, want
a shot at winning your own No Prize, stay tuned
to later on in this episode when we'll be asking
another question of the week. And now that that's
done, on to the news.
So last week, James Gunn on social media not
only confirmed that crypto will be in the upcoming
Superman movie that's going to hit theaters
in 2025, but he also shared the first look
at crypto as he's sitting next to Superman on
the moon overlooking the planet Earth. And
I just want to give the dog a huge hug because
he's so cuddly. And don't deny you don't either.
I'm good. I'm good, bro. You know, you know
that is just like the scruffiest, just fluffiest
dog ever. want to pet that guy. In the social
media post where he made the announcement,
James Gunn talked about the inspiration for
including crypto in this movie and it was a
dog that he had rescued named Ozu and he was
talking about how when they first got him he
was just destroying everything in the house
and it kind of inspired James Gunn to be like
oh what if Ozu had superpowers like that would
be so much more wild and possibly humorous.
So it kind of indicated a comedic tone that
crypto may have in the Superman movie. So does
that mean that the Superman movie is gonna be
about how Superman gets crypto? No, I don't
believe so. We're entering the DCU as an established
universe. And so I think crypto is just gonna
be, you know, one of Superman's allies in the
film. I'm not sure how large of a role he'll
have in the movie, considering it looks like
he's CG and he may be expensive to produce.
But I also just love the fact that they're including
him. We haven't seen crypto since League of
Superpets, the animated film. But it's really
cool to actually see him make the jump to live
action. What do you think of the image itself
of Superman sitting nice to crypto on the moon?
I love this image. I really freaking love it.
It made me so much happier than I thought it
would and just kind of really washed all of
the bad taste of Joker 2 out of my mouth. I
think DC fans are getting a little bit overhyped
about this image because essentially you're
just looking at Superman's back and crypto's
back and it's like, who cares, right? But it's
like an iconic. looking image like it just framed
really well as they look over the planet and
it's just a joy I guess to see Superman with
his dog. I guess so. You cold-hearted piece
of shit! Why? Because I'm not gushing all over
this image. It's been posted to death by this
point. Like I'm sick of seeing it as a teaser
image. It's fine but like I'm waiting for a
trailer already. Oh same. Yeah absolutely. The
movie comes out in summer of next year so...
I actually think we'll be getting a teaser trailer
soon, maybe by the holiday season. Yeah, I'd
put my money on that. Around Christmas time
we'll get the trailer for Superman. Fingers
crossed. Moving on to the trailers that were
released during New York Comic Con, starting
with Creature Commandos. This show is coming
out December 5th and it's going to kick off
James Gunn's DCU. We've already seen some footage
from the teaser trailer, but this is the first
official trailer that has been released by DC
Studios. The premise of the show is setting
up. is that because the government found out
about Amanda Waller's Task Force X or Suicide
Squad due to the events at the end of Peacemaker
Season 1, she's now forced to pull from a different
set of prisoners, namely ones that aren't human,
in order to accomplish these dangerous and
possible tasks, and that is the Creature Commandos.
From this trailer, it looks like the core team's
roster is going to be The Bride, Dr. Phosphorus,
Weasel, Dr. Nina Mazursky, and GI Robot. Frankenstein
is also going to be making appearances and he's
going to be voiced by David Harbour, but it
looks like maybe he's just a side character
for the team. He won't be there the whole time.
And of course, Rick Flagg Sr. voiced by Frank
Urlo is also a member of the team. Is the villain
Magenta at the beginning of this trailer? It
looks like her kinda. I don't believe so. I
don't actually know who this character is. I
think it's Cersei because I
in the show. So my bet is that it's her. We
also get to see Clayface in this trailer, which
I thought was pretty surprising because I didn't
know he was going to show up either. Yeah,
Clayface is just showing up everywhere, isn't
he? This is like the year of Clayface, I swear
to God. Between Suicide Squad, Isekai, Batman
Caped Crusader, and his guest appearance in
Kite Men, hell yeah, season one. Yeah, he's
all over the place. Yeah, it's kind of cool.
And he looks really cool in this trailer. I
swear if they adapt this version to live I
will lose my mind, because that would just be
incredible. There's also some cameos from some
rather obscure characters, including Kongarilla
and Rubber Duck. I've never heard of that character
before, but apparently it's a thing. The show
looks like it's going to be really good. I
especially like the character arcs that it looks
like we're getting for The Bride and Dr. Nina
Mazursky, and G.I. Robot. I think the show is
going to be really heartfelt, and I can't wait
to see it when it comes out in early December.
This trailer definitely has me pumped for the
show. I love the creature commandos. It does
look like this one's going to be gratuitously
violent, but that's pretty much in keeping with
James Gunn's The Suicide Squad film and Peacemaker,
so I'm not surprised. Yeah, as everyone knows,
the Creature Commandos are a team comprised
of kind of spooky characters, so that brings
us to our question of the week.
Who do you think is the scariest Marvel or DC
character and why? Yeah, we'll be going through
these answers for our next episode, which will
drop on Halloween Day. So record your answer
at dynamicduel.com by clicking on the red microphone
button in the bottom right hand corner of the
screen, which will prompt you to leave us a
voicemail. Your message could be up to 30 seconds
long, and don't forget to leave your name in
case we include you on the podcast. We'll pick
our favorite answer and award that person a
Dynamic Duel No Prize that we'll post to Instagram.
Be sure to answer before October 26th. Another
DC trailer also came out during New York Comic
Con, Batman Ninja versus Yakuza League. I loved
the first Batman Ninja and everything I see
coming out about this sequel just gets me more
and more pumped for this film. In the previous
teaser trailer that we got for this, we speculated
that perhaps the actions from the first film
resulted. in the future being affected and influencing
the modern world with more Japanese elements,
particularly in Gotham City. But it actually
looks like this alternate dimension is being
folded on top of Gotham City, sort of like origami.
And in this alternate dimension of Japan, it's
ruled over by a Yakuza League or different Justice
League members that are like evil Yakuza versions
of themselves, or at least most of them are.
It kind of seems like Wonder Woman might be
good in this movie whereas everyone else is
bad? Well it's like competing Japanese factions.
The Ninkyo versus the Yakuza. And I thought
it was really cool how it looks like the islands
of Japan are over Gotham City. So you have things
like Yakuza storms where they just rain down
onto Gotham City and cause chaos. Which is wild
because the Yakuza storms are actually Yakuza
gangsters just like flooding a city. It's pretty
cool. The character designs as we've said before
Particularly Aquaman as we get to see a little
bit more of him. The different looks for Wonder
Woman are also really cool I can't wait to see
Superman. They're still hiding him from us
I figure he's gonna be the main bad guy or at
least like the final bad guy because it definitely
looks like Rosselle Gould is heavily involved
in whatever is going on with these dimensional
folds. The story looks like it's gonna be really
good too really heartfelt You know like the
line from Batman who says it's most dangerous
when a friend becomes an enemy and things like
that seems pretty deep And everything the only
thing that I don't like about this project
is the animation itself is no good. Especially
coming off of like Suicide Squad Isekai. Yeah.
And how that was hand drawn traditional anime
animation. And you go to this computer generated
shit. There were parts of Batman Ninja in the
first one that were computer animated that
I really liked, like the statues of the villains
that Catwoman was introducing Batman to when
she was setting up the feudal world that Batman
was currently in within Japan. I do hope we'll
get more animation in that style, but who knows?
I agree. Like Suicide Squad Isekai totally
ruined a lot of other DC animation for me, but
I'm still looking forward to the story for
this one. It's coming out in early 2025. We
don't have an exact release date yet, but look
for it then. But speaking of bad-looking CG,
the last trailer we want to talk about this
episode is the official trailer for Watchmen
Chapter 2. Now, if you've listened to our review
for Watchmen Chapter 1, care for that film.
It was kind of pointless. Yeah, being an inferior
version adaptation-wise of the Zack Snyder 2009
live-action film, this kind of felt a little
bit redundant. And the second part to the Watchmen
animated movie also looks the same. I mean,
yeah, not only was it not as good as Zack Snyder's
adaptation, it's just not as good as the book
either in that it tries to be a perfect adaptation
of the book and yet fails to capture a lot
of the things of what makes the book in the
form of the comic medium so special. So considering
that, it's really hard to get excited for Watchmen
Chapter 2. The animation still looks like it's
going to be very wooden and not nearly as good
as some of DC's other animated projects. That
being said, the second half of the Watchmen
story has some incredible moments like Rorschach's
origin story, the prison escape scene, the fight
in Karnak. So there's a lot to look forward
to story-wise here. Oh, absolutely. Yeah, some
of the best moments from Watchmen happen in
the second half. The first half was really all
built up for this, right? Including a killer
twist. I'm really interested in seeing the design
of the squid and how they incorporate that
here. I wonder if it'll be as good as what they
showed in the HBO Watchmen series, or if it'll
look more like the comics or what it'll look
like. Well, based on what we've seen from this
two part film. It's gonna be almost exactly
like what we've seen in the comics considering
that they're really trying their hardest to
capture artist Dave Gibbons style. It's not
gonna top what we saw in the Watchmen television
series. I already know that. I'm already prepared
for that. Really, I'm prepared for the whole
damn thing because, again, I read this book
like once every year, every two years. I know
it by heart, basically. So there's not much
to look forward to. Maybe for people new to
this story, but like we said in our review,
I think if someone's coming in new, I would
just recommend a different adaptation than
this one. Or just, you know, read the original
comic. Oh, absolutely. I have multiple versions
of the graphic novel for that very purpose.
Someone tells me they haven't read Watchmen.
I'm like, here, take it. Just take it and read
it. I'm not anticipating any kind of surprise
with this adaptation. Again, I think it's going
to be very much by the numbers from the comic,
but who knows? We'll see. Part two of this film
is coming out on digital and Blu-ray on November
26th. So we will be reviewing this in a little
bit over a month. If you haven't read Watchmen
and don't know how it ends, read the comic before
part two comes out and before you watch that.
Or if you're a Marvel fan, just go on living
your life because who cares? If you're a Marvel
fan, you should read Watchmen so that you know
what a good comic is.
But that does it for all the news for this episode,
so let's go ahead and get into our main event,
which will be a team duel between the spook-tastic
Marvel and DC teams of creature commandos and
the Legion of Monsters.
Alright, Creature Commandos vs. The Legion of
Monsters. We decided to go with this duel episode
along with the executive producers because it
was just too good of an opportunity to pass
up. You know, we got a lot of great feedback
last year when we did the deceased vs. Marvel
zombies and this is always a fun time of year
to do these type of duel episodes. It is nice
to do something special around these seasons.
Yeah, absolutely. Especially when it comes
to characters that I love like the Creature
Commandos. Yeah, we figured this would be good
to do in lead up to the Creature Commandos animated
television show that'll be coming out in a
few months. Both teams are comprised of like
classic Halloween creatures. It's kind of like
the Monster Mash of Marvel and DC. Absolutely.
This is going to be a graveyard smash. When
did the Creature Commandos originate in DC Comics
in terms of publication history? Because the
Legion of Monsters came out in the 1970s. And
actually, the Legion of Monsters number one
issue was published by an imprint of Marvel
called Curtis Comics that refused to carry
the Comics Code Authority seal. So they could
tell these more supernatural stories, like
with Dracula and Frankenstein and the creature
from the Black Lagoon, or Manfibian, as he's
known in Marvel. Well, I guess it looks like
Marvel came out first here, because the Creature
Commandos didn't come out until 1980. What a
rip-off. Damn ripoff. Hey, hey, it's like you
always tell me. It's not about who comes first,
it's about who does it better. So Legion of
Monsters then. Alright, but to explain the methodology
behind our duels, let's go to our sentient
duel simulator Alfred Jarvis 9000. AJ and IK
tell our listeners how you go about determining
a winner in our duel matchups. Yes, of course,
sir. The way I determine a winner between the
two teams is by running 1000 Monte Carlo simulations
between every character on each team using
their statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation is
a probabilistic model used to determine outcomes
through random sampling. In this case, I randomised
the statistics along a normal distribution
as a way to simulate the many variables that
can occur during battle. The stat parameters
are based on the official Marvel power grid,
from which the DC characters statistics are
extrapolated. Additional stat categories are
included such as range, damage potential, versatility
and perception in order to create a more detailed
and accurate simulation. The results of the
49,000 simulations provide a percentage of wins
for each character on both teams. The team
with the higher average win rate is declared
the victor as they have a higher probability
to win any given battle. In an equitable pairing,
neither team should win 100% of the matches.
The comic book stories have shown that there's
even a way for Batman to defeat Superman, so
the confidence rate of my method falls in line
with the precedents that have been established
in the source material. My mathematical simulations
are without subjectivity or bias. Feats are
not the sole consideration, nor are fan votes
tabulated for determination of the winner.
Thanks AJ9K! Before we run the simulations though,
we like to break down each team's histories
and rosters before improvising a scenario on
how we imagine one of the thousands of simulations
would play out beat for beat. And I believe
it's my turn to go first with the DC team's
backstory, so let me tell you all about the
creature commandos. Now during World War II,
the United States government launched a top-secret
project known as Project M, aimed at creating
experimental super-soldiers and psychological
weapons. Led by Professor Mazursky, the program
operated from a hidden laboratory beneath the
Statue of Liberty. Recognizing the fear that
monsters evoked, Mazursky aimed to weaponize
this by transforming volunteers into grotesque
beings inspired by classic horror archetypes.
The first volunteers included Warren Griffith,
a soldier suffering from delusions of lycanthropy,
who was transformed into a werewolf. Vincent
Velcro, a court-martialed soldier turned into
a vampire, and Elliot Lucky Taylor, a severely
wounded soldier reconstructed as a patchwork
Frankenstein-esque monster. Dr. Myrna Rhodes,
a plastic surgeon exposed to mutagenic chemicals
that transformed her into a gorgon with snakes
for hair, also joined the team as Dr. Medusa.
This team became the Creature Commandos, led
by the hardened Lieutenant Matthew Shreve, who
often viewed the commandos as mere tools for
the war effort. The Creature Commandos were
deployed across Europe and beyond, taking on
both conventional and supernatural threats.
Their first mission in France involved destroying
Nazi android duplicates of allied leaders, proving
their effectiveness as a strike team. Operating
out of London, including the mission to rescue
Dr. Rene Frederique, a scientist with knowledge
of chemical nerve gas. Though the commandos
initially rescued a Nazi agent posing as Frederique.
In a rare moment of humanity, the agent sacrificed
herself to save the team, challenging the commandos
perspective. The team eventually found the real
Dr. Frederique in a death camp, but under orders,
killed her to prevent her knowledge from falling
into enemy hands. This mission deeply affected
the team, particularly Lucky Taylor, who attempted
suicide afterward. Though doctors repaired
his body, the trauma left him mute. As their
missions continued, the commandos faced morally
ambiguous tasks, testing their loyalty and moral
compass. One mission involved eliminating Nazi
super soldier children at a German boarding
school. While the commandos hesitated to kill
children, Shreef took matters into his own hands
and gunned them down, creating a rift within
the team. Despite these dark tasks, the commandos
also found moments of redemption. In one mission,
they rescued a group of blind French children
from a Nazi attack, earning medals of honor.
Yet internal conflict persisted and Shreeve
briefly left the team, feeling his leadership
style was too harsh. After a successful mission,
rescuing French civilians, Shreeve was reinstated.
In 1943, the commandos were sent to the South
Pacific to investigate the disappearance of
of allied planes near Dinosaur Island. There
they discovered a hidden Japanese naval fleet
and turned the island's dinosaurs against the
enemy ships, using the creatures as weapons.
Shrieve documented the dinosaurs for military
intelligence, but Velcro destroyed the photographs,
fearing that war would bring destruction to
these creatures. The commandos later returned
to Dinosaur Island where they encountered Jake,
the first GI robot. Together they discovered
a supposed lost colony of Atlantis. responsible
for sinking ships. Atlantean robots had taken
control of Jake, but he ultimately overrode
their programming and sacrificed himself to
destroy the colony, preventing further attacks
on allied vessels. Following Jake's destruction,
the commandos met his replacement Jake II, who
joined the team and expanded their capabilities.
As World War II neared its end, Project Am tasked
the commandos with a final mission, piloting
an experimental The rocket malfunctioned, veering
off course and drifting into space with the
commandos aboard. With the original team lost,
Project M later shifted its focus to creating
new super soldiers. Over time, the program produced
a series of new recruits to replace the original
commandos, expanding its reach beyond traditional
monsters. One such recruit was Captain Lucius
Hunter, who took over leadership duties in place
of Shrieve. Hunter, an older veteran who had
undergone extensive rejuvenation therapies,
led a new iteration of the creature commandos
called M-Team Alpha. M-Team Alpha included fresh
faces like a Ten, a mummy-like communication
specialist, the Bog Man, an amphibious creature
resembling a Gill Man, and Gunner Mackie, a
revived World War II soldier turned into a cyborg
zombie. This modernized version of the Creature
Commandos continued Project M's legacy, adapting
to new threats and expanding its roster to
face evolving challenges. Years later, the original
Creature Commandos were discovered aboard an
alien vessel controlled by Brainiac. Freed from
stasis, they joined forces with other heroes
to fight their captors. Upon returning to Earth,
the team was captured by General Sam Lane and
integrated into Project
Cryptonians. Despite their capture, the Commandos
were never deployed against the Cryptonians
during the tensions between Earth and New Krypton.
Following the disbandment of Project 7734,
Maxwell Lord took control of the Commandos and
deployed them against the Justice League International.
Under Lord's telepathic influence, the Commandos
fought for a time but eventually broke free
from his mind control. Realizing they no longer
had a clear purpose or allegiance in this new
era, The Commandos faced uncertainty as their
monstrous forms and tortured pasts left them
relics of a bygone age. In the post-Flashpoint
timeline, the Creature Commandos were reimagined
as field operatives for the secretive organization,
SHADE, or the Superhuman Advanced Defense Executive.
This version of the team was led by Frankenstein,
replacing the original leader, Matthew Shreve.
Dr. Nina Mazursky, now a scientist and geneticist
for SHADE, spearheaded the program, using the
legacy of Project M to design a new generation
of creature commandos. Mazursky herself transformed
into a hybrid amphibious creature resembling
a Gill-Man to better fight alongside her creations.
Vincent Velcorro was again turned into a vampire,
with his abilities derived from a modified
version of Dr. Kirk Langstrom's Manbat serum,
wherein Griffith retained his werewolf form,
now more stable and controlled, allowing him
to harness his primal nature more effectively.
The team also included Khalees, an enigmatic
Egyptian mummy whose origin remained a mystery,
but who served as the team's medic. Under Frankenstein's
leadership, the commandos tackled a range of
supernatural threats. One of their missions
involved combating giant monsters emerging
from Bone Lake, Washington, showcasing their
role as humanity's frontline against the monstrous
and supernatural. The team faced personal challenges
as well. The bride, Frankenstein's estranged
wife, departed after learning the fate of their
son, leaving a void in the team's dynamic.
Despite their monstrous appearances, the Commandos
remained dedicated to defending humanity, evolving
under Mazurski's guidance as she continued merging
cutting-edge science with the macabre legacy
of Project M. Team-wise, I knew that for my
seven-person roster, I'd want a blend of the
old, original team members that showcased classic
monster archetypes with the newer more tech
and occult focused commandos that we've seen
in recent iterations of the team. From the
early roster, I'm including Warren Griffith,
the werewolf, Vincent Velcoro, the vampire,
Dr. Mira Rhodes, aka Dr. Medusa, and the GI
robot, Jake 2. Noticeably absent from this
original roster is Lieutenant Shreve, because
who wants a human on a monster team, and Lucky
Taylor, whom I'm replacing with Frankenstein.
who you can learn more about in our Frankenstein
vs Bloodstone duel episode. Along for the ride
will be Frankenstein's bride, as well as a
third agent of shade, Dr. Nina Mazursky, the
aquatic kill woman responsible for creating
the newest versions of the commandos. So to
recap, that's Frankenstein, his bride, Lady
Frankenstein, the werewolf Griffith, the vampire
Vel'Koro, Dr. Medusa, Dr. Mazursky, and Jake
II, the GI robot. I think one of the most interesting
things I learned there was that the team was
created in World War II just because the professor
wanted soldiers that would be scary in a traditional
Halloween monster sense. Yeah, he wanted to
scare Nazis with classic Hollywood monsters,
essentially. That's kind of lame. That's okay.
Kind of an anticlimactic origin for the team,
I think. Like if they were to make a creature
commandos for today, they would create soldiers
that look like, I don't know, Freddy Krueger
or Mike Myers or something like that. I don't
know, it seems weird. But sure, in concept,
they're a cool team, but not as cool as the
Legion of Monsters. Let me go ahead and break
down their backstory. The Legion of Monsters
was never a traditional superhero team. It was
a collection of outcasts brought together by
strange circumstances and united by their monstrous
nature. The original lineup came together during
an encounter with the Starseed, the benevolent
alien entity. While investigating its appearance,
Morbius, the living vampire, Werewolf by Night,
Man-Thing, and Ghost Rider found themselves
drawn together. Overcome by their monstrous
hungers, Morbius and Werewolf by Night attacked
Starseed, inadvertently causing its death. The
dying starseed, in a final act of mercy, tried
to cure the Legion of their monstrous forms,
but was too weak to succeed. Disillusioned,
the team parted ways, barely recognizing themselves
as a team, not yet realizing that they had
laid the foundation for something much larger.
Now, Jack Russell, also known as Werewolf by
Night, inherited his curse from his father's
bloodline, transforming into a werewolf with
every full moon. Though he initially lacked
control, he graduelly learned to manage his
transformations. making him a powerful ally
when the Legion briefly came together to investigate
Starseed. Russell's superhuman strength, speed,
heightened senses, and near savers vulnerability
to Silver made him one of the most fearsome
members of the Legion of Monsters, though the
team's dissolution left him once again wandering
the world alone. You can learn more about him
in our Solomon Grundy vs. Werewolf by Night
duel episode. Years later, Morbius found himself
at the helm of a new incarnation of the Legion
of Monsters. this time with a clearer mission,
to protect monsters from being hunted. The world
had grown increasingly hostile toward any creatures
perceived as a threat, and Morbius, along with
his old ally Man-Thing, sought to create a
safe haven for monsters. They were soon joined
by the Living Mummy, Man-Phybian, and Simon
Garth the Zombie. The Living Mummy, once known
as Nkantu, was the prince of a North African
tribe before being captured and cursed by Egyptian
priests. Mummified and held in a state of eternal
life, N'Katu awoke in the modern era and joined
the Legion of Monsters. His superhuman strength,
able to lift around 5 tons, and durability,
along with his immortality, made him a valuable
protector of those who could not defend themselves.
Although he longed for peace, his curse bound
him to a world he barely understood. Manphibian,
an alien who had traveled to Earth thousands
of years ago while pursuing the murderer of
his mate, also joined the Legion's ranks. His
amphibious physiology gave him tremendous strength,
able to lift around 15 tons, sharp claws, a
healing factor, and skin tough enough to withstand
missile attacks. Simon Garth the Zombie had
once been a businessman in New Orleans before
being sacrificed by a voodoo cult and transformed
into a zombie. Though bound by the amulet of
Damballa, which allowed his controller to command
him, Garth retained a shred of humanity that
fueled his desire to protect those who could
not protect themselves. As part of the Legion,
Garth used his immense strength, mystical senses,
and healing abilities to fight with the Legion
for a better future for all monsters. As the
Legion solidified its purpose, they established
Monster Metropolis, a sanctuary city hidden
beneath the streets of New York in the Moorlach
tunnels. This underground refuge provided safety
to countless creatures, but it also put the
Legion in direct conflict with groups like
the Hunter of Monster Special Forces, led by
Robert Hellsguard. During one battle between
the groups, the Legion resurrected the Punisher,
transforming him into the Monsters' Frankencastle.
With his newfound form, Frankencastle fought
alongside the Legion to defend Monster Metropolis,
though his return to humanity would eventually
lead him away from the team. You can learn
more about this in our Red Hood vs Punisher
duel episode. As the Legion of Monsters grew,
their ranks began to attract other powerful
beings, including the half-demon daughter of
Marduk Kurios, aka Satan. Satana spent years
as a succubus, feeding on the souls of men
to sustain her powers. When she joined the Legion,
her mastery over black magic, teleportation,
and hellfire proved invaluable in their battles.
Though her motivations often remained mysterious,
Satana's raw power made her a force to be reckoned
with, and her demonic nature tied her fate
to the other monsters who sought refuge in Monster
Metropolis. While the Legion of Monsters fought
to protect their own, another group was forming
in the shadows, this time under the auspices
of SHIELD, the global peacekeeping organization.
The team was called the Howling Commandos,
and they were a special unit tasked with handling
supernatural threats that ordinary agents could
not. Based at Area 13, a secret facility designed
to contain paranormal entities, the Howling
Commandos recruited several members of the Legion
of Monsters, including the living mummy Manfibian,
and Zombie, who formed a new strike force against
supernatural and extraterrestrial dangers.
Alongside these veterans came new recruits,
including Nina Price, the Vampire by Night.
Nina, the niece of Werewolf by Night, had inherited
the family's curse of lycanthropy, but was
later bitten by a vampire, transforming her
into a hybrid of both creatures. She joined
the Hellen Commandos to keep her powers in check,
and quickly became an integral part of the
team. using her supernatural strength able to
lift half a ton, agility, hypnosis, fangs,
and healing abilities to fight against mystical
threats. Her immunity to sunlight made her
a unique asset as she could operate during the
day, something most vampires could not. Another
addition to the Howling Commandos was Glob,
a creature formed when Joe Timms, a petty criminal,
drowned in a radioactive swamp and was resurrected
as a near indestructible monster. Despite his
simple-mindedness, Glob's immense strength,
able to lift around 100 tons, and resilience
made him an effective member of the Howling
Commandos, particularly in missions where brute
force was needed. His body, made of swamp matter,
could absorb physical attacks with little effect,
making him nearly impossible to harm. The Howling
Commandos' first major mission came when they
were called to stop the ancient sorcerer Merlin
from transforming England into a mythical kingdom.
They launched a daring assault on Merlin's forces,
ultimately forcing the wizard to retreat. His
victory cemented the Hellenic Commandos as a
key player in SHIELD's Supernatural division
and the team continued to take on threats ranging
from demonic invasions to rogue mystical artifacts.
As both the Legion of Monsters and the Hellenic
Commandos battled supernatural threats, the
members constantly confronted the duelity of
their existence. They fought not only to protect
their fellow Monsters, but also to reconcile
the parts of themselves that were both human
and monstrous. Choosing the roster for this
Legion of Monsters team duel was particularly
difficult. because a lot of Marvel's most prominent
supernatural characters like Morbius, Ghostwriter,
and Man-Thing I already used in our Justice
League Dark vs. Midnight Suns duel episode.
That being said, there was still Werewolf by
Night and a slew of other prominent Halloween-ish
characters I could pull from for this Halloween
duel. First on my list, of course, is Werewolf
by Night, who was a founding member of the Legion
of Monsters and the Howling Commandos. Next
is the Living Mummy. who was also an early member
of both teams alongside Zombie and Manfibian.
Satana became a prominent member of the Legion
of Monsters in their second iteration, and
from the Howling Commandos I'm pulling two members
that are largely serving as stand-ins for Legion
of Monsters characters. And that's Vampire by
Night, who's substituting for Morbius, and
Glob, who I'm substituting for Man-Thing. Because
if you're gonna have a Halloween creature duel,
you need a Vampire and a Swamp Monster. So that's
my lineup. Werewolf by Night, The Living Mummy,
Zombie, Manfibian, Satana, Vampire by Night,
and Glob, the Swamp Monster. Your names are
terrible. What? Yeah. Why? I said it. Griffith,
Vel'Koro, Mizzurski, those are way better names.
Those are just fucking last names. And? Better
than fucking Glob. Glob is a Hulk villain.
It's a great name for a Glob-ish creature. Zombie?
Yeah, Zombie is a zombie. Do you know any other
villains named Zombie? Just saying, it's a little
on the nose.
Where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
Dynomic Podcast Network presents Console Combat,
where video game legends brawl every Monday.
Dynamic Duel, where comic book titans smash
every Tuesday. Max Destruction, where the world
is at its limit. And the final episode of the
show. TV and action heroes battle every Wednesday,
and Sendro World, where anime champions clash
every Thursday. Join us as we speculate on
the matches and armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge victorious.
Visit dynamicpodcast.com where we settle the
debate and settle the score.
Well now that we got these teams, histories,
and rosters out of the way, let's speculate
on how one of the simulated matches will go.
Now the winning team is going to be determined
by simulations, not the speculation, but it's
fun to imagine how the fight could play out.
AJ and IK, what are the rules of our speculation?
Well, I should say there are no rules, other
than the teams have no prior knowledge of the
other going into the fight. All they are aware
of starting out is that the other side is a
threat that needs to be eliminated. For the
speculation... groups will begin approximately
50 meters apart in a nondescript environment
that will have no bearing on the match itself,
as no environmental statistics are considered
in my simulations. The teams must earn victory
on their own merit." Alright then, let's get
into it. The creature commandos and the legion
of monsters meet on the battlefield. Which
team goes first? Well, I mean, I don't know
how my team would start. You know, they're
a military team, so most of them, like Frankenstein,
Lady Frankenstein, Dr. Medusa, Jake 2, even
Nina Mazurski, they all have guns. So they're
just going to start by gunning down the League
of Monsters and the hail of bullets. Well, you
know that most of the Legion of Monsters are
like invulnerable to gunfire, right? Like no
werewolf by night can only be killed by silver
bullets. Same thing with vampire by night. Living
mummy and zombie, you know, they can't really
be hurt too much by small arms fire, manfibian,
the bullets would bounce off of them and the
glob would just like completely no sell these
bullets. So I guess the only one that could
be shot is Satana, but she's probably also one
of the most powerful members on my team. So
Satana is gonna dodge the bullets by flying
up into the air, and then she's just gonna
rain down hellfire, like grenades just exploding
all over the battlefield. And it's gonna scatter
the creature commandos all over, and it's gonna
make them stop shooting and start diving for
cover. Okay, well, as the team scatters, I'm
gonna say that Vel'Koro... dodges the flames
by transforming into a bat, so he's a smaller
target. And with his transformation comes a
rolling mist that's going to surround his teammates
and hide them from the hellfire. And within
the mist, Griffith, with his enhanced wolf senses,
he's going to track down Zombie and attack
him, just chomping down on his bones. Why Zombie?
Because he smells bad? Because bones, man.
Dogs love bones. Well, Zombie doesn't give a
fuck about this werewolf biting down on his
bones. In fact, I'll do you one better. I'm
going to say that Griffith straight rips off
zombies arm bone and swallows it. OK, so zombies
missing an arm. But all of a sudden, that arm
is going to burst out of Griffith's chest because
it's still animated by zombie. So what Griffith
like falls onto his back in pain and he's dead
now. And zombies arm is going to reach up evil
death style. Zombie grabs it and attaches it
back to his shoulder. So Griffith's out of
the match already. Okay, killing right out the
gate, I see. Well, a lot of these guys are
kind of like one trick ponies, you know. That's
true, that's fair. Well, I'm gonna say that
as Zombie is reattaching his arm back to his
shoulder, all of a sudden, his head freaking
explodes because Lady Frankenstein, with her
four arms and four firearms, she just blasts
his head with like four simultaneous headshots,
turning his brain to slush. She has four arms?
Yeah, yeah, she's like Goro. She doesn't have
forearms in the television show that's coming
up. Maybe not at the beginning, but I'm pretty
sure by the end of it she will. That's interesting,
okay. All right, so Zombie gets headshot four
times and dies, but Nina Price, you know, the
vampire by night, she turns into her wolf form,
because, you know, in addition to being a vampire,
she's also a werewolf. She's actually a white
wolf, unlike her uncle, who's brown. But as
a werewolf, She uses her senses to track down
Vincent Velcoro, who's still in his vampire
bat form, flying around. And she snatches him
out of the air with her teeth, which is gonna
force Velcoro into his human form. And vampire
by night is gonna come out of her wolf form.
So you have two vampires standing off against
each other, except that Nina also happens to
be a vampire hunter. So she just stakes Velcoro
through the heart, killing him. That backstabbing
bitch! Oh, by the way, when I say bitch, I'm
only saying that because she's a wolf. Okay,
that's fair. She stabbed him in the chest, not
the back. Oh, okay. You know who is backstabbing
though, or rather back shooting? Frankenstein.
Because as Vel'Koro is dying, Frankenstein,
he's gonna load a silver bullet into a steam
gun, which hits like a steam powered train,
and he shoots vampire by night's entire heart
right the hell out of her chest. Where did
he get his silver bullet from? Dude. He's going
up against monsters all the time. You think
he doesn't carry a silver bullet? That's very
convenient, I'll say that. Werewolf by night
sees this and he's pissed and he lets out a
blood curdling howl because his niece just
died and he goes into a rabid frenzy. And because
Frankenstein took out one of his family, now
Werewolf is gonna take out Frankenstein's bride.
So like in this blur of teeth and claws, Werewolf
is just gonna rip apart Lady Frankenstein. ripping
off all four of her arms in an attack that
basically looks like she was thrown into a blender.
All of her limbs just scatter across the battlefield.
Hmm, okay. Well, with Werewolf by Night in this
frenzy, and he's probably looking around for
another target, and that's when he's gonna meet
the gaze of Dr. Medusa and her glowing eyes.
So BAM! Instant petrification, Werewolf by Night
is now just an angry-looking stone statue.
She could turn people into stone? Okay, so she's
never done it in the comics, but only because
for some reason, anytime she tried to use it
in the comics, the people that she used against
were unable to turn into stone like robots.
Okay, that's weird. Yeah. All right. Bullshit.
Okay. All right. So werewolf by night is a statue,
but living mummy at this point has lumbered
over to Dr. Medusa and he's just gonna grab
her by her snake hair and just slam her to
the ground. Yeah, and he gets bitten by her
snakes. So he's poisoned and dying now. But
how can Living Mummy be poisoned? He doesn't
even have blood in his body. It's like a special
magic Egyptian embalming formula. So he doesn't
get poisoned. Snake poison does nothing. And
Living Mummy just rips Dr. Medusa's head off
like Perseus did to the mythological Medusa.
So she's out. He just rips off her head with
his bare hands? Yeah, he's strong. He can lift
like five tons. Okay. Well, I'm going to say
that... As the living mummy is holding Dr.
Medusa's head, suddenly he just bursts into
flames thanks to Jake Two, who transformed
his left arm into a flamethrower and is just
gousing the living mummy's very, very flammable
body wrappings in a stream of fire. That was
actually a pretty good move because living
mummy is pretty vulnerable to fire since he's
all desiccated and stuff, you know? But uh,
you know who's vulnerable to basically nothing?
Glob. And he's gonna walk over to GI Robot
as he's doing this, and he's gonna completely
swallow him up in his swamp muck body. And
the swamp matter is just gonna ooze into all
of GI Robot's inner workings, like shutting
down his gears and his weapon systems. And Glob
is actually the strongest member out of the
entire Legion of Monsters, you know. His strength
level approaches the Hulk, so just by like
flexing, he completely dismantles the guy. And
then just expels all the robot parts from his
swamp body. So now G.I. Robots out of this match.
OK. Uh, well, Glob was once human, right? Yeah,
he was a criminal named Joe Timms. That's right.
OK. So while Glob is busy shitting out Jake
two parts from his body, that's when Dr. Nina
Mazursky is going to plunge a syringe right
into his thigh, injecting him with a formula
that's going to revert Glob back into human
form. You know, as Joe Timms. And right when
that happens, she's gonna blast his head off
with her energy gun. How does she know how to
turn glob back into a human? She's an expert
in turning humans into monsters. So, yeah, she
just did a reverse formula for that. It's stupid.
I'll allow it. All right. Well, man, Fibian
sees what Dr. Nina Masursky did, and he's a
Gilman creature just like her. But for some
reason, she only breathes water, right? She's
not amphibious like him. Like she always. No,
no. walks around with that water cooler helmet
of hers. She could breathe air. Like initially
she couldn't. She had to wear that helmet full
of water, but the mummy Khaleese made it so
that she could breathe both water and in the
air. Oh, well regardless, Manfebian's gonna
shatter her water helmet by smacking it with
his razor sharp claws. And all the water is
gonna come pouring out. And as she adjusts
from breathing water to breathing air, that's
when Manfebian... grabs her energy gun from
her hand and uses it to blast a hole through
her chest. Just destroying her lungs and destroying
basically her life. Well I mean maybe she reaches
for another syringe to turn him human. Manfibian's
an alien. Like what is she gonna do? Revert
him back into an alien? Yes. No. I don't know.
She's dead. Okay. Well right when Manfibian
kills Dr. Nina Mazursky that's when Frankenstein,
who now has six arms. picks up Manfibian because
Frankenstein collected and grafted his bride's
arms onto his body. And so each of the bride's
forearms are holding one of Manfibian's limbs,
just stretching them out so he can't move. While
Frankenstein is going to use his own super
strong arms to squeeze a Manfibian's neck until
pop, just gets popped like a zit. So I just
have Satana left, but you only have Frankenstein
left. So it's just those two left on the battlefield.
So, Seitan is gonna swoop in and land a big
ol' smoochy smooch right on Frankenstein's
lips. She was like, come here you big lug. Mwah!
And Frankenstein's like, whoa. And he's probably
feeling pretty good about himself, except that
Seitan is a succubus, okay? By kissing Frankenstein,
she just stole his soul and it comes out of
his body in the form of a butterfly out of
his mouth and his body gets all desiccated and
just goes straight to hell. And with him out,
the Legion of Monsters win. I mean, I don't
think Frankenstein was as flattered as you
think. For one, you know, his heart belongs
to the bride. And they were actually in addition
to grafting his bride's arms onto his body.
He also grafted her head into his chest where
his heart is in order to save her. He's like
Quato from Total Recall. Her head is just in
his chest. So his body has two consciousnesses
now. And while Frankenstein's soul. may have
been stolen sure the bride is still around and
she's going to take control of the body and
She doesn't appreciate this demon hoe trying
to make moves on her man so You know the bride
is gonna grab Frankenstein sword which once
belonged to the Archangel Michael by the way
So it's holy and she's gonna plunge that blade
right into Satanas head sending her back to
hell meaning the creature commandos win, uh
I'm going to say that Frankenstein meant to
graft the bride's head onto his body, but he
just forgot to. He just did the arms. So I
literally just said that he did that. Well,
I'm saying that he didn't that he forgot to.
So we'll go ahead and find out which of these
scenarios happens by inputting the character
stats into our team simulator, comparing thousands
of matrices against each other and coming back
with a winner. A.G. 9K hit it. Inputting data.
running calculations, processing results, simulations
complete. This was actually a pretty close matchup.
I didn't think it would be that close because
the character of Satana turned out to be way
more powerful than she had any right to be
within this team duel. Like, she was far beyond
anybody else on either of these teams. Out
of all of her matches, she actually won over
90% of them. So uh... Yeah, that was a little
bit of a mismatch, including say 10 on the Legion
of Monsters. But I also had Zombie on my team,
who was by far the weakest character out of
anybody on either team. He only won one fifth
of all of his matches. Yeah, as we learned in
our werewolf by night versus Solomon Grundy
match, zombies are pretty weak stat wise. But
at least even Solomon Grundy had super strength
going for him. Well, I mean, zombie has super
strength, but like zombies in general, they
don't have. great stats in terms of speed or
range or intelligence, you know, things like
that. So I'm just convinced that we would all
just be fine if a zombie apocalypse were to
ever happen. You had the strongest guy and the
weakest guy. My strongest guys were actually
Frankenstein and GI Robot. Both of those guys
ended up winning 60% each of their matches.
And overall, the stat categories that the Leech
Dome Monsters had over the creature Like it
is really hard to kill most of the Legion of
Monsters characters, but also strength. A lot
of my guys were pretty damn strong. But the
Creature Commandos had intelligence and range
going for them. Not only do we have several
doctors and members who have lived for centuries
on the team, but they're all pretty much packing
heat as well. Yeah, yeah. A lot of my guys
didn't have any range at all basically. They
had to get in close and personal in order to
inflict any sort of damage. So taking all of
this into consideration, Joseph, who do you
think came out on top? I'm gonna say it's gonna
be Legion of Monsters. I think it's gonna be
close, but I think Legion of Monsters is still
gonna come out on top largely because they're
just more ferocious and badass. The Instagram
poll takers though disagree with me. 53% of
them voted in favor of the creature commandos
winning this fight. I have to think that maybe
that's just due to the upcoming television show
that's coming out, but who knows? It's gonna
be a close match. Oh, you think so, huh? Well,
let's find out. AG90K, the results please.
Hey, Yuasa. The winner of the team matchup between
Creature Commandos and Legion of Monsters is
Legion of Monsters. All right. They won 517
of the 1000 matches or 51.7% of the time compared
to the Creature Commandos who won 48.3. Now
I have to say, I... I'm actually kind of surprised
that the Legion of Monsters did not have a higher
win rate. This is a closer match than I thought
it would be. Once we started putting in the
stats and I saw how powerful Satana was compared
to everyone else, I was like, oh crap, I totally
am going to lose this match for sure. But I
thought it was going to be by a lot more. So
in a way, I still feel good about this because
my team did better than I thought we would.
Well, let's be real. If I didn't have Satana
on my Legion of Monsters team. These guys may
not have been able to pull off a victory. Like
she was far and above everybody else. And yeah,
it was kind of a little bit of a mismatch.
You could say or you could just say that was
strategic thinking on behalf of myself and
the executive producers. Or you could say you
guys were a bunch of cheaters. There's also
that you could say anything, really. You could
also just say that you chose your team wrong.
You know, oh, I actually liked my team, though.
I'm still proud of our turnout. I liked your
team, too. Yeah. I liked it as well in the fact
that they lost and in your face. And I hope
that everyone's Halloween is as scary as these
results were to DC fans. OK, so not that scary
because you guys didn't win by that much. Gotcha.
That does it for this episode, guys. AJ 9K
help close this out. Thanks for listening to
Dynamic Jewel. Visit the show's website at
dynamicjewel.com. and follow us on Instagram
at Dynamic Duel Podcast. You can support the
show on Patreon at Patreon.com slash Dynamic
Duel and joining a tier that works for you
or by rating and reviewing Dynamic Duel on Apple
podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser, or on our website.
Don't forget to listen to the other shows in
the DynaMic podcast network, including Max
Destruction, Senjo World, and Console Combat.
In our next episode, we will be reviewing the
upcoming Sony Marvel film, Venom the Last Dance.
I'm not expecting huge things, I'm hoping that
it's at least better than Venom Let There Be
Carnage, but we will find out and discuss it
next time. But that does it for this episode
guys, we want to give a big thanks to our executive
producers Ken Johnson, John Sturowski, Zachary
Hepburn, Dustin Belcombe, Mickey Mathangian,
Brandon Estergard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yeaton,
Austin Wyselowski, AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho,
Gil Camacho, Adam Spies, Andrew Schunk, Dean
Molesky, Devin Davis, Joseph Kirsting, and
Josh Leiner for helping make this podcast possible.
We'll talk to you guys next week. Up up and
away, true believers. I was working in the lab
late one night when my eyes beheld an eerie
sight, for my monster from his slab began to
rise, and suddenly, to my surprise, he did
the monster mash.