This is a Dynamike Network podcast.
the Dynamic Dual Podcast, a weekly show where
we review superhero films and debate the superiority
between Marvel and DC by comparing their characters
and stat-based battle simulations. I'm Johnny
DC. And I'm his twin brother, Marvelous Joe.
And in this episode, we are reviewing the second
season of the Disney Plus MCU animated series
What If. Of course, the show ended last year.
We're barely getting around to reviewing it
now. But literally it was just like a week
and a half ago, so we'll let you guys know what
we thought about the show later on this episode.
Before that we're going to break down the latest
comic book movie news to come out this past
week. Of which there was really only one news
item, which is that Steven Yeun has exited
the Thunderbolt film. As always we list our
segment times in our episode description, so
feel free to check out the show notes if you
want to skip ahead to a particular topic. Our
artificially intelligent dual simulator, AJ9K,
has a quick message for our listeners, so listen
up. Why hello there. Do you love listening and
chatting about Marvel and DC? Then become a
part of the dynamic dual community on Patreon
where you can choose from three tiers. The
dynamic 2-0 tier lets you listen to this podcast
without ads and gives you access to its Discord
chat group where you can chat with Johnny DC
and Marvelous Joe. The fantastic 4 tier gives
you that and more with two bonus episodes each
month including bloopers and top 10 shows where
Johnny and Joe count down your favourite Marvel
and DC subjects. The X-Force tier makes you
an executive producer of Dynamic Duel, where
every month you help the host choose what to
review and who to fight against each other.
And finally, the Dynamike Podcast Network tier
allows aspiring podcasters to create their own
battle-focused show using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and consultation,
and get you simulation results to announce on
your show. Pitch the twins your show via email
at dyna or by reaching out to the them on social
media. Check it out at patreon.com slash dynamic
duel. Pip pip cheerio. Thanks, AJ 9K, and thanks
to everyone who supports the podcast. Guys,
be sure to tune into the Max Destruction Podcast,
which is part of the Dynamike Podcast Network,
which last week found out who'd win in a fight
between Clint Eastwood's Dirty Harry and Dolph
Lundgren's Punisher. The Sinjoworld Podcast
is a show that speculates on fights between
your favorite anime characters. This week. Host
Zachary Hepburn will find out who would win
between Tian Xinhang from Dragon Ball against
Zebra from Toriko. And the newest show in the
Dynamite Podcast Network, Console Combat, hosts
John and Dean find out who would win in fights
between your favorite video game characters.
In yesterday's episode, they speculated on
who would win between Earn.Rex from Mass Effect
and Nemesis from the Resident Evil games. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click on the link in
our show notes. to listen to all of the shows
in the Dynamike Podcast Network. But with that
out of the way, quick to the No Prize! A No
Prize is an award Marvel used to give out to
fans. Our version, the Dynamic Dual No Prize,
is a digital award we post on Instagram and
in our email newsletter for the person that
we feel gave the best answer to our question
of the week. Last week we asked, now that the
DCEU is finished, what would you say are the
top three DCEU and why. We only received two
answers but it's okay because we have an honorable
mention and a winner to announce. The honorable
mention goes to Connor Pierce who said Connor
Pierce- Hi guys, I think Shazam, Wonder Woman,
and Black Adam are the top three best DCEU films
of all time. They are just so good and Shazam
is one of the better ones because had Zachary
Levi in it and Asher Angel and I think that
they need to do more movies like that. Thanks
guys. Yeah so Shazam, Wonder Woman, and Black
Adam are actually a pretty good trifecta of
quality that DC has put out. I know a lot of
people didn't like Black Adam but the superhero
action in that movie was top-notch and it was
really cool to get to see the Justice Society
on screen. Yeah for some reason people give
Black Adam shit but... Even as a Marvel guy,
someone who doesn't really care about the DC
characters, I had a lot of fun with it. It wasn't
like groundbreaking, well, like maybe in terms
of like PG-13 superhero violence, but it totally
worked for what it was trying to be. Yeah,
it would have been nice if Shazam was in the
movie, but of course Shazam already had a really
good film. It was a great origin story, a great
movie with family themes, and it was funny,
probably one of the most funny films in the
DCEU. and Wonder Woman of course was extremely
well made by Patty Jenkins. I loved the World
War I setting for that first film. The sequel
didn't quite hold up, but the first Wonder Woman
film absolutely is one of the DCEU's best.
Yeah, as far as I'm concerned, Wonder Woman
is like Oscar caliber. I don't think it won
any, but it's Oscar caliber in my book. Great
answer is Connor, but the winner of this week's
No Prize is Abner O'Terry, who said, Oh, this
is Abner O'Terry. My answers would have to
be Blue Beetle. because of his connection with
his family. Black Adam, because you get to
see the Justice Society of America. And then
Snyder Cut of Justice League, because you get
to see the whole Justice League together. And
they're awesome. Thank you. Yeah, so I thought
Blue Beetle was the best DC film of last year.
Spoiler alert, if you haven't listened to last
week's episode of the Brothers Awards yet. But
yeah, I really enjoyed that movie. It actually
reminded me a lot. of the Shazam movie in that
it was comedic, action packed, and had strong
family values. But the real reason that this
answer gets the win is because I think the
best DC movie ever made is Zack Snyder's Justice
League. You had to get a Zack Snyder film in
there for as much hate as the director and his
films get. I still think that could have been
a masterful cinematic universe if Warner Brothers
had just let him create it. I don't know man,
have you heard the reviews for Rebel Moon? The
fuck do I care about that for? Hehe
And then it's like a three way tie between Wonder
Woman, Aquaman and Shazam. And I don't know
if I'd probably go Aquaman or Wonder Woman on
that one. Yeah, the DCEU had some really good
films and it will be missed now that it's over.
That said, I am really looking forward to seeing
what James Gunn brings us next year. We have
to wait a whole damn year. Sucks. But great
answer, Abner O'Terry. You win this week's no
prize. If you the listener want a shot at winning
your own no prize, stay tuned to later on in
this episode, where we'll be asking another
question of the week. And now that that's done,
on to the news!
Alright, this past week we learned that Steven
Yeun will not be playing the Sentry in the
upcoming Thunderbolts film. It was never actually
officially announced by Marvel Studios that
Yeun was cast as the Sentry, but it was almost
all but confirmed. The reason that Yeun is
leaving that movie is because, according to
him, scheduling conflicts due to the writer
and actor's strikes. We know that the strikes
caused the Thunderbolts film to be pushed from
July 2024 to July 2025, a whole year back. And
yeah, that can always create conflicts for
actors who try to squeeze in multiple projects.
Yeah, when I first heard this news, I was actually
pretty bummed. I was like, what scheduling conflicts?
Like, what could possibly top starring in a
Marvel movie? But it sounds like he's pretty
bummed. And he said that he still hopes to
one day star in an MCU film, which is nice.
Yeah. I mean, he's a fantastic actor. and I
think Marvel would be lucky to have him in any
role, really. He was always an interesting
choice for the Sentry. He never quite resembled
the character from the comic books, who's like
this white blonde-haired guy, but taking it
in the direction of Yen entirely works, and
I think it would have been a fantastic performance
because Yen is just such a quality actor. Yeah,
honestly, like, the Sentry is not a well-enough
known character, where I think anyone would
have been up in arms over colorblind casting.
I thought it was a really good choice because
first and foremost, You want a quality actor
who would be able to capture the psychological
complexity of a character like Robert Reynolds,
aka the Sentry. Aka the Void. Yeah, there's
a great duality to the character of the Sentry
that I think Yun would have been fantastic
playing. So it's a shame I don't think that
this casting change is going to alter the plot
of the movie at all. I still think we're going
to get the Sentry character within the film.
So it'll be interesting to see who they cast
for that. going forward, you'd think we'd get
a casting announcement soon, considering that
they should start filming here in a few months.
Yeah, I mean, Marvel's pretty secretive, so
I wouldn't be surprised if they held the back
of the news until, like, Comic-Con. Like they'll
cast someone, but they won't say what character
they're playing until, you know, they're ready
for some huge announcement. You're probably
right about that. We'll see. But on the subject
of this entry's casting, that brings us to
our question of the week.
Who would you cast as the Sentry in the MCU's
Thunderbolts film? Now that Steven Yeun's out
of the picture, we'd like to hear who you guys
think would make an awesome Sentry. If you
want to learn more about the character, make
sure to check out our General Zod vs. Sentry
duel episode. Record your answer at dynamicduel.com
by clicking on the red microphone button in
the bottom right hand corner of the screen which
will prompt you to leave us a voicemail. Your
message could be up to 30 seconds long, and
don't forget to leave your name in case we
include you on the podcast. We'll pick our favorite
answer and award that person a Dynamic Duel
No Prize. that we'll post to Instagram and our
email newsletter. Be sure to answer before
January 13th.
I think that does it for all the news for this
episode. Now let's move on to the main event,
where we review the Disney Plus animated Marvel
series, What If, season two.
Season 2 is an animated series on Disney+, directed
by Brian Andrews, written by A.C. Bradley,
and starring many familiar names and voices
from the live-action Marvel Cinematic Universe.
Based on the What If comic books, the show explores
the multiverse with a series of anthological
tales told from the perspective of The Watcher,
who is the cosmic entity that oversees the
events happening in each episode. Each story
is set up with a question of what if. that
explores how a single change in the primary
MCU timeline would affect continuity and unfolds
the universal effects from that change. The
season is the follow-up to the first season
which we reviewed on the show a few years ago,
saying that while the show has a great premise,
the first season squandered its potential with
a hit or miss run of episodes, some that felt
so pointless that I felt more like asking but
why? When watching them. Exactly like Party
Thor. Yeah. That being said, I thought that
this second season improved upon the first
one and chose to tell more interesting tales
and therefore is actually more worth your time.
With that in mind, if you haven't watched What
If Season 2 yet, be sure to do so before listening
to this review because we will be delving into
spoilers. All the reviews that we do on the
show are spoiler heavy. Now one of the criticisms
that we said about the premise of the What
If show was that it inherently doesn't require
much investment on behalf of the audience because
any anthological exploration outside of the
primary universe is just a sandbox that writers
can let thrive or destroy and it technically
doesn't affect anything that matters to the
primary timeline. Because we don't have to care,
sometimes it's hard to, but this season didn't
feel pointless because of the worthwhile stories
they chose to explore. Yeah, no, I mean...
Whether they affect the main timeline or not
to me was never really too much of the draw
of What If. I like Elseworld Tales, What If
Tales. They're some of my favorite stories
because you're able to do things with characters
that you would never be able to get away with
in the Prime Continuity timeline. My issue with
the first season of What If was that I didn't
think that the questions they asked, as you
mentioned, were worth asking in any way and
I will agree with you that this season asked
much more interesting questions. Yeah, I think
in hindsight, Season 1 was trying too hard to
set up its Guardians of the Multiverse team
in its final episode, prioritizing that roster
over telling good stories. Because of that,
we got such duds from Season 1 as T'Challa Star-Lord,
Party Thor, and who I like to call a more convoluted
Killmonger that were less interesting versions
of what was in the main MCU timeline. In season
2 however, the overarching narrative only played
out as ending scenes in a couple of episodes
before the finale with Doctor Strange Supreme.
Beyond him, there were only two other characters
that mattered to the finale which were Captain
Carter and the newcomer character, Kihori.
And because the show had more freedom, it could
explore better concepts in its other episodes.
I think that made all the difference in the
world for this season. Yeah, a lot of the Guardians
of the Multiverse weren't even in the season
at all, which I think worked for it as a whole.
Absolutely, yeah. And while the first season
had some concepts that married classic films
with multiversal events such as The Night of
the Living Dead in the Marvel Zombies episode
or Risky Business with the Party Thor episode,
the second season did it with greater success,
I think with episodes taking cues from movies
like Blade Runner, Mad Max, Fury Road, and
Die Hard. I really liked that how they were
able to merge other pop culture stuff with
Marvel and interesting ways in alternate universes.
And they weren't shy about it either. Like
they explicitly were mentioning characters from
Die Hard in that Christmas episode. Yeah. It's
a lot of fun when they do that though. In addition
to the movie homages though, I really like
the fact that this season also delved into what-if
tales from the comics, like 1602, which actually
isn't necessarily a what-if story, but it is
an Elseworlds alternate universe tale that
Marvel published. Right, yeah. It was written
by Neil Gaiman. and it was a fantastic story
about the Marvel Universe manifesting at the
end of the Renaissance era. This 1602 episode
was nothing like that story, and really didn't
hold a candle to it, honestly, because I thought
it was one of the lesser episodes of the season.
But the fact that they're exploring ideas like
that was still fun. Like, there were still great
ideas there. Like, in the comic, Steve Rogers
was like a Native American guy. And in this
episode, Steve Rogers was Rogers-hood, a riff
on Robin Hood. Even though that should have
been Hawkeye, but... Yeah, you're absolutely
right. I just like the call out to the comics,
you know, I'm glad that they're looking towards
the source material for ideas. Yeah. Usually
I prefer my alternate Unova stories to be wholly
original accounts as opposed to retellings of
familiar tales, which is like one or two minor
changes. Season 2 did something interesting
where they mashed up their own franchises a
bit, like the What If Captain Carter Fought
the Hydra Stomper episode. was essentially
a retelling of Captain America the Winter Soldier
that incorporated elements from the Black Widow
film, specifically the Red Room and Melina Vostokov's
work with the Mind Control Agent that worked
so well within the concept of Russia manipulating
an old hero that is cherished to the protagonist.
I thought that was really well done. Yeah, that
was really cool. Similarly, What If Hela Found
the Ten Rings was basically the first Thor film,
but with Hela as the lead with the setting
of medieval China from Shang-Chi and the Legend
of the Ten Rings. Now if Shang-Chi had father
issues in his movie, Hela also had father issues.
Thematically, I think it just worked for me.
And I think these mashups were a very interesting
way to approach these stories. Yeah, honestly,
ancient China is way more interesting than modern
day New Mexico. Sorry to all of our listeners
from New Mexico. I don't know, man. Did they
have green chili? Hell yeah. Did medieval China
have hatch green chili? You win, that's fair.
It's harder to go into my overall thoughts
on the show without going into specifics on
each episode, so let's go ahead and get into
our episode highlights. Episode 1 was called
What If Nebula Joined the Nobacore? It stars
Karen Gillan as Nebula, Jude Law as Yonrog,
Michael Rooker as Yondu, Seth Green as Howard
the Duck, and Taika Waititi as Korg. Note that
if I don't see an actor with the character,
it just means that the character was played
by a primarily voice actor who may not be a
recognizable name. I just want to point out
when the actual actors from the films portray
the same roles in animation. I always really
like that when the actual actor came back to
voice the role. It really helps me decide which
MCU actors are like too stuck up and snobby
to return to the role for animation. You know,
which ones aren't greedy assholes. Yeah. So-
What the heck Robert Downey Jr. Too good for
us or what? Scarlett Johansson, come on! Hahaha.
But in the story for episode 1, in this timeline,
Ronan the Accuser kills Thanos and his forces
wage a campaign against Xandar and the Nova
Corps. Nebula, without purpose after her father's
death, joins the Nova Corps. To protect Xandar
from Ronan, Nova Prime seals it off with a
planetary force field, throwing the population
into chaos. Nebula comes across the murdered
body of Yondu, though there is suspiciously
no investigation. Prompted by Nova Prime to
covertly look into things, Nebula learns that
Yondu discovered the source code to the planetary
shield generator. Believing that an invasion
is in the works, Nebula enlists the help of
Yonrog, a former Kree soldier, to help infiltrate
the Nova Corps mainframe and destroy the codes.
He betrays her, however, and steals the codes,
nearly killing her before revealing that he
and Nova Prime plan to give Xandar up to Ronin.
Nebula survives with help from Howard the Duck,
and along with Korg, Groot, and Meek, the group
breaks into the Nova Corps headquarters to
stop the shield opening. It's revealed that
Nebula suspected Nova Prime's intentions through
her unorthodox request to investigate Yondu's
death by any means necessary, and that she
altered the shield codes to close right after
opening to destroy Ronan's ship and stop his
invasion. Nova Prime falls to her death in the
fight, and Xandar is freed. I thought this
was a really strong episode to start the series
with. I really liked it. Not only did I like
the Blade Runner aesthetic and the Technonore
genre that it was, but the classic like Houdonnet
mystery was also pretty well done, I thought.
Yeah, it was a little bit convenient that Nebula
was on to Novo Prime the entire time and so
everything just kind of neatly fell into place
at the end. But you know, it's only like a 30
minute episode and I can forgive it for how
cool everything was. Just the environment of
this post-apocalyptic Xandar was really cool.
Yeah, I'm not sure why Jude Law had to be in
this episode. I kind of feel like he was just
filling a contractual obligation. But the rest
of it I thought was great. My favorite part
was when I realized that Korg, Groot, and Meek
was rock, paper, scissors. Like, they were
playing up on that whole thing. I thought that
was funny. Yeah, that was fantastic. I thought
it was really interesting to see how Ronin killing
Thanos meant that the Guardians never formed,
therefore Nebula never joins them. instead joining
a different team, the Nova Corps, and finding
her redemption there. So like, no matter what
path Nebula goes on, it's always within this
family team situation. Yeah, right. Alongside
Howard the Duck in this version, which I thought
was great. I thought Seth Green did a fantastic
job with that role as always. Yeah, he showed
up a few times in season one as well, like in
the Party Thor episode and in T'Challa Star-Lord,
but I thought he was best served here as this
casino owner. In all, I give this episode 4
stars. So what I'm going to do since this is
like an anthology thing and each episode kind
of stands on its own, I'll rate each episode
on a star rating and my overall score for the
season is basically an average of those ratings.
Yeah, I'll agree with 4 stars. Episode 2 is
called What If Peter Quill Attacked Earth's
Mightiest Heroes. In it you have Michael Douglas
playing Ant-Man Hink Pym, Lawrence Fishburne,
playing Goliath, aka Bill Foster. Sebastian
Stan returned as the Winter Soldier, aka Bucky
Barnes. Atandwa Connie revisited his role as
T'Chaka, Black Panther. Haley Atwell played
Peggy Carter. John Slattery played Howard Stark.
And Kurt Russell returned as Ego. Kudos to Kurt
Russell for coming back, that was awesome.
Yeah, it's really interesting to see these big
name legends come back to do animated work
for the MCU, like Michael Douglas. For sure.
They're not too cool for school, Chris Evans.
Right? In this timeline in 1988, the Ravagers
deliver Peter Quill to his father, Ego, who
unlocks the child's cosmic powers. Escaping
his father to Earth, Peter crash lands in New
York and makes his way to Missouri, causing
destruction in his path out of self-defense.
In response, Shields Peggy Carter and Howard
Stark assemble an early version of the Avengers,
including Ant-Man, Goliath, the Winter Soldier,
Black Panther, and Captain Mar-Vell. Their
attempts to contain him at Coney Island fail
until Thor intervenes, having tracked Peter
across the cosmos by the destruction left in
his wake. Taken into S.H.I.E.L.D. custody,
Peter is befriended by Ant-Man's kid daughter
Hope, who frees him and informs S.H.I.E.L.D.
about the threat Ego poses. Ego's avatar travels
to Earth after losing communication with Peter,
and his arrival is detected by S.H.I.E.L.D.
who sends Black Panther, Goliath, and Thor
to confront the while Ant-Man, Captain Marvel,
and the Winter Soldier find Peter visiting
his mother's grave. As the first group struggles
against Ego's cosmic powers, the latter group
tries to convince Peter to help them against
his father. They join the battle, and Peter
harnesses the cosmic power in Ego's expansion
seed to destroy his avatar. The team celebrates
their victory and prepares to venture into space
to confront Ego the Planet. I loved this episode!
I thought this was a really, really cool episode.
I love seeing the early Avengers that could
have been. Yeah, the 80s roster. It's interesting
because like you forget how many superpowered
beings there were in the MCU's history. It's
kind of a surprise that Nick Fury was the first
one to come up with the Avengers initiative
in the main MCU timeline and that the idea
of assembling these superpowered beings into
a team didn't manifest sooner. Yeah, I agree.
And this was just an awesome roster, too. Yeah,
I liked it a lot. It was nice that Thor actually
felt more like Thor again, like he wasn't cracking
jokes at every turn. Exactly. I also liked
that Mar-Vell was in there as well in a callback
to Captain Marvel, although I kind of wish
that her Tesseract ship had blown up and she
had received the powers from the Tesseract.
I thought that would have been way cooler. That
would have been awesome. Yeah. I did have the
question of why Peter Quill destroyed other
planets like Jotunheim if Ego wasn't fully
in control of Peter's actions, but that was
never really addressed in this episode. I think
he was just listening to his father. I think
the whole reason he didn't destroy Earth was
because it was his home. That's where his mom
lived and he lived when he was younger. Yeah,
that makes sense. I even liked the hope and
young Peter Quill dynamic. You know, I didn't
mind that. Yeah, honestly, I'm kind of pissed
off at fucking Yondu for not delivering Quill.
Yeah, because then Earth would have been equipped
with an Avengers team three decades earlier.
Yeah. And a dope one. That was really cool.
I read this episode four stars. I thought it
was really well done. I had a lot of fun despite
questioning why. Thor would struggle against
Ego's avatar beings just as much as Black Panther
and less powerful heroes were. That's fair.
I also still feel like Marvel has an issue with
what they're calling a celestial and what they're
not. I don't know. Yeah, that whole thing is
weird. Maybe since Ego is a planet and celestials
are born within planets, Ego is just like an
alternate version of a celestial, one that
merged into the planet as opposed to erupting
from it. I guess that makes sense. I do really
like Ego as a villain. I like seeing him come
to planet Earth and terrorize heroes here.
I really like this episode. I'm giving it 4
and a half stars. It was one of my favorites.
Episode 3 was called What If Happy Hogan Saved
Christmas. It had Jon Favreau as Happy Hogan
aka the Freak, Sam Rockwell, as Justin Hammer,
Mark Ruffalo as the Hulk aka Bruce Banner,
Jeremy Renner as Hawkeye aka Clint Barton, Kobe
Smulders as Maria Hill, Kat Dennings as Darcy
Lewis, Lake Bell as Black Widow aka Natasha
Romanoff, and Chris Hemsworth as Thor. Wait,
you said the Freak. Is that an actual character
from the comics? Yes. In the comics, Happy
Hogan was mortally injured at one point and
Tony Stark used some experimental technology
on him and it transformed him into like this
bald, strong, not as strong as the Hulk, but
he was like about as strong as Spider-Man. It
was nice that they had this precedent here
for the character. It wasn't just some random
thing that they introduced. Yeah, that's cool.
That's really cool. Yeah. In this timeline,
Justin Hammer escapes from prison prior to
the events of Avengers Age of Ultron. He and
his henchmen seize the Avengers Tower during
a time that the Jarvis AI is down for maintenance,
where Happy Hogan is overseeing security at
the building's annual Christmas Eve party. Stumbling
on the villain's plan to steal a sample of
Hulk's blood, Happy works his way through the
building's vents to get to the lab and retrieve
the sample first. He accidentally injects himself
with the sample, which causes him to begin
transforming into a Hulk-like monster known
as the Freak. He tries to get ahold of the
Avengers members, but Natasha is fighting Hydra
at the Nutcracker Ballet, Tony is playing Santa
Claus for kids at a Stark charity event along
with Steve who is an elf, and Bruce and Clint
are shopping for a hard-to-get Iron Man action
figure for Clint's kids. Happy calls his intern
Darcy, asking her to reboot Jarvis and regain
control of the building. But she is captured
and Justin Hammer dons the Hulkbuster armor
to fight Happy, who has fully transformed into
the Freak. Though Happy defeats Justin Hammer,
the Avengers return and attack him, believing
he is a villain. Darcy convinces them that the
Freak is Happy and everyone celebrates. Thor
arrives late. I thought this was a fun and entertaining
episode, exactly what it was supposed to be
as an homage to the Die Hard movie. I thought
it was great that they dropped it on Christmas
Day. I did have a small issue with the dialogue,
specifically Justin Hammer's dialogue was a
little bit punny and kind of overwritten and
not all the jokes landed, but I thought it
was a great concept where Justin Hammer filled
in as the Hans Gruber character. Yeah, I thought
that was perfectly well done. I did not mind
the puns. I thought it was totally appropriate.
I was laughing a lot during this episode. I
like the part where he falls out of Avengers
Tower like Hans Gruber fell out of Nakatomi
Plaza. They did it in slow motion and everything.
So many great little call outs to the Die Hard
movie. Darcy is usually hit or miss for me,
but I actually really liked her in this episode.
I thought she was funny. She was like, Happy,
are you making me your Reginald Val Johnson?
And Happy is like, wait, that's what you remember
from the movie? Yeah, John Favreau is a great
voice actor. I have to say he actually does
really well in this episode and in the 1602
episode. He has a lot of range as a voice actor.
Definitely. Yeah, I would agree. In all, I give
this episode four stars as well. So far, all
the episodes have gotten four stars for me.
Yeah, I'll go four stars as well. I liked it.
I didn't like it as much as the last episode,
though. Episode four is called What If Iron
Man crashed into the Grandmaster? It has Jeff
Goldblum as the Grandmaster, Tessa Thompson
as Valkyrie, Taika Waititi as Korg, and Josh
Brolin as Thanos. In this timeline, Iron Man
didn't make it back through the wormhole after
sending the nuclear missile into the Chitauri
ship and ended up on the planet of Sakaar. The
Grandmaster invites him to celebrate his birthday
and Tony obliges under threat of being melted.
He witnesses the Sakaar Grand Prix, a death
race in a gladiatorial arena. where Valkyrie
impresses Tony with her driving, despite the
fact he's put off by the barbarism on display.
Tony tries to rescue Korg, but Gamora enters
the scene, attempting to kill Stark for defeating
Thanos' army. Gamora and Tony are hit with
obedience discs and imprisoned, though Stark
escapes by overloading his disc using his arc
reactor. He recruits both Korg and Valkyrie
to help him overthrow the Grandmaster's tyrannical
rule over Gamora is also forced to participate
in the race, whom Tony tries to reason with
and convince her to step out of her father's
shadow. Despite the Grandmaster cheating at
every turn, Tony wins the race and Valkyrie
becomes the new ruler of Sakaar after the Grandmaster
accidentally gets melted with his own weapon.
On Tony's way out of Sakaar, Gamora confronts
him and the two execute a plan to kill Thanos
using Grandmaster's Melt Stick. I feel like
this was an episode that was really good on
paper. And, you know, just hearing you describe
it, it sounds like a fantastic episode. I just
think the voice actor for Tony Stark was fricking
terrible. I really liked it. No, I think he
delivers his lines very differently from how
Robert Downey Jr. would actually deliver. I
don't know. The actor's name is Mike Wingert.
And I actually liked a lot of his delivery here,
especially when it came to Tony Stark's approached
the absurdity of the planet Sakaar. His reactions
to everything kind of reminded me of Robert
Downey Jr's reaction to the Guardians of the
Galaxy in the Infinity War movie, where he's
just at his tipping point all the time with
this weird cast of characters. I thought it
was a lot of fun. Maybe it was just the combination
of the face animation and the voiceover. I
just knew the whole time that it was not Robert
Downey Jr. And it just took me out of the whole
thing. I also never liked Jeff Goldblum as the
Grandmaster. What? Yes, it's you're on the
wrong side of history on that one. I got irritating
shit. I don't like it. It's just so unbelievably
played for laughs. And I personally don't find
Jeff Goldblum that funny. I know I'm on the
wrong side of history there. I don't really
give a fuck because that's irritating to shit.
He's like the personification of debauchery
and hedonism. I thought it was fantastic. I
loved the Mad Max for your road premise. The
action was so chaotic at times. It was sometimes
hard to follow because you don't have that.
depth of field in animation like you do in
live action. Right. But the cars were incredible.
I liked that one car that would swallow up
cars ahead of it in the jet turbine and then
grind them up and spit them out as bullets
behind it. I was like, I need that in Mario
Kart. That'd be like the perfect car. My favorite
car honestly was Iron Man's suit that he made
for this episode. Holy cow. It made me honestly
really miss Iron Man as a character just because
of all the really cool stuff you could make
and do. Yeah, when his chariot car blew up and
he ejected his suit, which like reformed into
this race car kind of thing, that was a bad
ass moment. Really cool. Honestly, that may
be like one of the biggest highlights of the
entire series. If only it was live action.
Holy shit. This would have been a cool episode
in live action. Yeah, I really like the ending
where Gamora melts Thanos. I thought that was
a powerful ending. This is the same Gamora
that went on to become one of the guardians
of the multiverse from season one. Although
we never see Thanos melted. We see him partially
melting. You know, he's going to melt. He's
going to melt. That's what the melt stick does.
It melts. True. I did not think that Cynthia
McWilliams, who was the actress who played Gamora
in this episode, sounded anything like Zoe
Saldana, though. No, same. Absolutely. Come
on, Zoe, where are you making billion dollar
films, I guess? In all, I give this episode
four stars again. I think the series has been
nothing but consistent so far. I give it three
and a half just because it's too much Jeff
Goldblum for me. Did you see the after credit
scene on that one? Yes, unfortunately. Wasting
my time. Sponge me up.
Episode 5 was called What If Captain Carter
Fought the Hydra Stomper. It had Hayley Atwell
as Captain Carter, Lake Bell as Black Widow,
Samuel L. Jackson as Nick Fury, Rachel Weiss
as Melina Vostokoff, and Sebastian Stan as Bucky
Barnes. In this timeline, Peggy Carter received
the Super Soldier Serum after Steve Rogers was
shot at Project Rebirth. She became Captain
Carter in World War II as Rogers donned a precursor
Iron Man suit called the Hydra Stopper developed
by Howard Stark and powered by the Tesseract.
Together, they helped stop a plot by the Red
Skull from using the Tesseract to bring an extra-dimensional
entity to Earth. Captain Carter's actions sent
her nearly seventy years into the future where
she became an Avenger. On one mission for S.H.I.E.L.D.,
she and Black Widow stumbled upon Steve Rogers
and the Hydra Stopper armor who attacks them
and then escapes. Peggy learns that Steve was
captured by the Russian Red Room during the
Cold War and brainwashed into serving as their
assassin, with the armor keeping him in stasis
until he was needed. The Hydra Stomper attacks
the S.H.I.E.L.D. Treskeleon headquarters in
an attempt to kill Bucky Barnes, who had become
Secretary of State. Peggy manages to subdue
him, and she and Black Widow take Steve to a
secret safe house in Scotland where they reboot
the Hydra Stomper and decide to dismantle the
Red Room. Steve takes them to an old KGB base
built like an old American suburb where they're
attacked and confronted by Melina Vostokoff,
the new Red Room leader and the one in charge
of Steve's brainwashing. During the battle,
Peggy appeals to Steve who overcomes the mind
control to sacrifice himself to destroy the
Red Room headquarters. Believing that Steve
is alive, Peggy sets out to find him but falls
through a portal that takes her to a renaissance
themed universe that is looking for her help.
This was another one of my favorite episodes.
I really liked it because, as you mentioned,
it's essentially the Winter Soldier storyline,
but if Peggy became Captain America. Yeah,
with, again, those elements from the Black Widow
movie, which I thought plot wise played in
brilliantly with the story of the Winter Soldier.
Great episode. I was excited to see Rachel
Weisz voice the role. She's a phenomenal actress.
And for her to come back for animation for
this just shows, you know, how much they, I
guess, like Marvel as a whole. Right. I think
like Bell does a pretty good job of voicing
Scarlett Johansson. I mean, at some points
I would hear just Poison Ivy speaking, but I
would say a lot of the times she passed for
Scar Jo. I would agree. Watching the beginning
of this episode, I was trying to figure out
why Captain Carter's existence in the past led
to Bruce Banner not becoming the Hulk and being
part of the original Avengers, though it was
cool to see the Wasp as one of the original
Avengers. Yeah, that was cool. I mean, not as
cool as the 80s team from episode two, but
still pretty cool. Yeah. I want to bring up
the huge power levels problem that this show
seems to have. I brought it up in a previous
episode where we see how Thor and Black Panther
struggle similarly in a fight against Ego's
avatars. And that problem continues in this
episode. Like how can Captain Carter take on
the Hydra Stomper, which is basically an Iron
Man suit, as well as tank dozens of widow's
bites that are shot at her before they even
seem to affect her. She also had a car slammed
into her that then exploded. and she was fine
afterward. It was just very strange. Not going
to lie, they make Captain Carter way too OP
in the series. I understand that she's sort
of like the protagonist of maybe the whole
what of series, but it's like, OK, yeah, we'll
talk about that again later on in the last
episode. But I rate episode five three and a
half stars. Wait, what? Yeah, I didn't think
it quite held up as much as the other ones.
Mainly because the dialogue and line delivery
between Hayley Atwell and Lake Bell started
getting grading to me. I don't think Hayley
Atwell is a solid voice actress. She kind of
reads the lines like she's reading lines, you
know? That's fair. That's fair. I did like the
episode though. I would give it four stars.
Let's go to move on to episode six, which is
called What If Kehori Reshaped the World. In
it, we have Devory Jacobs playing the character
of Kehori. In this timeline, the fire demon
Surtur... destroyed Asgard during Ragnarok centuries
earlier, resulting in the Tesseract hurtling
to pre-colonial eastern America on Earth. Falling
into a lake, the Tesseract created a portal
to an alternate dimension, causing the local
Native American tribes to name the area Forbidden
Lake. In the late 15th century, a young Mohawk
woman named K'Hori and her little brother Wata
encounter a group of conquistadors ransacking
their village in search of the Fountain of
Youth. Fleeing, the siblings stumble upon the
Forbidden Lake. Kahori is shot and falls into
it, and the portal within, which transports
her to what the natives refer to as Skyworld.
There she learns to control the vast telekinetic
powers granted to her by the energy of the
tesseract, including telekinesis, enhanced speed,
concussive blasts, energy shielding, and portal
creation. Though the inhabitants are content
to stay within Skyworld, Kahori's knowledge
of the Conquistadors motivates her to use her
abilities to try and leave the dimension in
order to save her brother and her tribe. She
returns home and attacks a fleet of ships that
had chained up her tribe, though they bombard
her with cannon fire. The inhabitants of Skyworld
return just in time to help, and they free her
people, being referred to as Thunder Beings
by Wata. Empowered by their victory, they confront
Queen Isabella of Spain, though it is cut short
by Doctor Strange Supreme, who recruits Kihori
for a mission. I thought this was an amazing
original story. When I first heard that they
were going to introduce a new character within
one of the I wasn't thrilled because I thought
that the concept of what if should be restrained
to explorations of existing stories, but I thought
this was a beautiful story. The setting of
Skyworld I thought was really cool. It was like
Avatar. It kind of reminded me of that. I love
how they chose to do the entire episode in the
Mohawk language and Spanish. That was an awesome
choice. I saw on the internet a few people call
K'Hori a Mary Sue because she was just immediately
so adept at using her powers. But I think the
story provided the context and why she would
be because she was the only one out of the natives
in Skyworld that knew of the conquistadors.
And she knew that she had to return in order
to save her people, whereas everyone else was
kind of complacent. In all, I loved the world
building that they had here, the character
building. I think Kihori is a fantastic new
addition to the Marvel Universe. I'm really
interested in seeing where they take her from
here. I hope that she makes an appearance in
the comic books. I hope they don't just relegate
her to this television show because I think
her character is worth further exploration.
Do you think they would ever bring her about
in live action? That would be awesome. And I
think the actress who does the voice for her
could play her in live action. I think that'd
be great. In all, this is probably one of my
favorite episodes of the season, so I give it
four and a half stars. Yeah, it was good. It
was solid. Honestly, no real gripes with it.
I'll give it four and a half stars. I thought
Kohari as a superhero was really cool. Her power
set is just incredible. Yeah for sure. Moving
on to episode 7, that is called What If Hela
Found the Ten Rings. It has Cate Blanchett
playing Hela and Idris Elba playing Heimdall.
Fucking Cate Blanchett doing voice over, that
was awesome. She did such a good job. Really
good job. She really owns that character, I
think. Lot of personality there. For sure. In
this timeline, instead of imprisoning his daughter
Hela in the realm of Hell, Odin banishes her
to Earth to learn respect for life, enchanting
her crown to be worn on her. Only by those with
mercy, Odin sends Hella to medieval China where
the Mandarin finds her. He takes a liking to
her and tries to recruit her into his army,
though she attempts to steal his rings. Unsuccessful,
Hella flees his compound and encounters a hand-done
creature that guides her to the realm of Ta
Lo. There, a woman named Yi reveals to Hella
her true desire of freedom from control, and
teaches her the mystical martial arts, bringing
Hella peace. Odin learns from Heimdall that
he can no longer see Hela and that the Mandarin
is in possession of a god-destroying power.
Convinced his daughter is in danger, Odin leads
an army of Asgardians to Earth and goes to battle
with the Mandarin's forces. Hela arrives to
assist and fights her father, eventually subduing
him and granting him mercy. At that point she
becomes worthy of her crown again and Odin grants
her his throne, where she strives to free the
nine realms from Asgard's empire and becomes
a hero across the cosmos. later alongside the
Mandarin, the two defeat Thanos, the Mad Titan.
I think this is another amazing story, again
melding the first Thor film with the Legend
of the Ten Rings movie. Yeah it was a good
episode, honestly I was just really excited
to see the Ten Rings come back again. I think
we were way past due for a Shang-Chi sequel,
so it was nice to get a little taste of that
again here. Yeah, it was funny that Wenwu took
a liking to Hela. I liked how Hela was humbled
by her mortal trappings. You know, she came
in with such confidence and she was a good
fighter and everything. But you just saw how
devastated she was when she couldn't lift up
her crown. And I thought it was a believable
journey going from there to trying to steal
the rings, to going to Talo and then really
being humbled again there and coming to be
at peace with herself. I thought it was really
cool to see Odin in battle as well. It's something
we've never really seen before in the MCU. He's
a badass. He is such a badass. with Gungnir,
like especially going up against the Ten Rings,
where Odin was like twirling his spear, Kung
Fu style, to block the rings that are flying
at him. Everything about that battle was fantastic.
I honestly don't think that Hela and Wenwu would
ever defeat Odin in battle, so that was kind
of like a power levels thing here, because Odin
is pretty much all powerful. But, I think for
the purposes of the story that they were telling,
where Hela really grew as a character due to
her experience on Earth, I thought it all worked
well. Yeah, I thought the ending was kind of
bullshit too, but overall a pretty good episode.
I liked when you saw Hela and the Asgardian
army side by side with the Mandarin's forces
and they were charging into battle against
Thanos together. And when Wu was like running
on air on top of his rings, using them as like
stepping stones. That was badass. I just love
how the ten rings are depicted always. I want
the ten rings. I give this episode four stars
and all. I thought it was another solid great
exploration. Yeah, I'll go four stars as well.
Episode 8 was called What If the Avengers Assembled
in 1602. It had Hayley Atwell as Captain Carter,
Samuel Jackson as Sir Nicholas Fury, Elizabeth
Olsen as Wanda Merlin, Chris Hemsworth as King
Thor, Mark Ruffalo as the Monster in the Iron
Mask, Jon Favreau as Sir Harold Hogan, Paul
Rudd as Scott Lang, and Sebastian Stan as Bucky
Barnes. In this timeline, Marvel heroes lived
during the time of the late Renaissance. In
the year 1602, Captain Carter is summoned to
save the dimension from an incursion that is
slowly destroying reality due to the presence
of a time displaced individual. However, after
failing to stop the tears in the universe, King
Thor has Peggy branded an outlaw, believing
her to be the cause. She turns to Tony Stark
to find the individual, but he tells her they
need the Time Stone and King Thor's scepter
to power the device that will locate them.
To steal the scepter, Peggy turns to a group
of thieves consisting of Steve Rogers, Bucky
Barnes, and Scott Lang. However, their rendezvous
is ambushed by the Yellow Jackets and the Destroyer,
led by Sir Harold Hogan. Peggy is imprisoned,
but she escapes and frees Bruce Banner. Rejoining
with Steve Rogers' band of thieves and Tony
Stark, Peggy and the group storm King Thor's
court to get the Time Stone. With Wanda Merlin's
help, the group acquires the gem to Power Stark's
device, which identifies Steve Rogers as the
Man Out of Time. a result of Steve striking
the Time Stone in his battle with Thanos during
the events of Infinity War. Peggy uses Stark's
device to send Steve back to his home timeline,
and after the battle, she's approached by Doctor
Strange Supreme. I thought this episode sucked.
I thought it was a lame excuse to have another
episode with Captain Carter. Do not think she
belonged in this universe or was even needed.
I thought there was a lot of missed opportunities,
like low-hanging fruit when it came to making
Hawkeye Robin Hood and Tony Stark the man in
the Iron Mask. Yes, I totally agree with that.
Just too much that I did not like. The main
issue with this episode is that it was a fight
that could have been a conversation, right?
For some reason, King Thor was the antagonist
just due to his stubbornness. But ultimately
what he was wanting was to stop this incursion
from happening. And if they had basically, I
think just had a conversation and were like,
dude, we just need to borrow the scepter. We'll
find out who this guy is using this device.
What was the point of all the fighting? It just
kind of made Thor seem like this overly stubborn
character and really unlikeable, which, you
know, you don't want to dislike Thor. Yeah,
I know. Right. I mean, like Thor, Love and Thunder
already did enough of that. I do. Question
though, if the Steve Rogers that was in this
1602 episode was the one from the Infinity
War battle in main MCU, because if so, does
that mean that the Chris Evans version of Steve
Rogers that we know has these memories of being
in the past? I think it's really unclear as
to what memories Steve Rogers had. Like when
he was Rogershood, did he still retain his
memories from battling Thanos? I think he did.
And if so, why didn't he just come out as the
individual who was causing these terrors in
space time? It's possible that he didn't know,
but you think that he would have been informed
of that during the debrief as to why they needed
the time stone and all that stuff. You know,
a lot of questions with this episode. I mean,
he knew that he had hit the time stone. He explained
that. So I think it's clear that he had memories
of it. I think the implication was that being
flagged by the time stone kind of awakened
those memories. I don't know. I don't know.
And honestly, I don't care. Because this episode
sucked. I think the biggest crime that this
episode committed was that it was nothing like
the 1602 comic book, which would have been a
lot of fun. Yeah, I'm sure Neil Gaiman is like,
what the fuck, guys? Really? I rate this episode
three stars out of five. I'll give this one
three stars as well, but even then I think that's
a little bit generous. In the final episode,
episode nine was called, What If Strange Supreme
Intervened? It had Hayley Atwell returning
as Captain Carter, Benedict Cumberbatch as Dr.
Strange Supreme, and Devory Jacobs as K'Hori.
In it, Strange Supreme reveals to Captain Carter
that he's been imprisoning universe killers
as his atonement for the destruction of his
own reality. He asks her for help in catching
an escaped variant, though this turns out to
be K'Hori, who warns Peggy about Strange's
true intentions, to recreate his reality using
a dimensional forge fueled by beings of great
power. As Strange attempts to kill K'Hori, Captain
Carter frees his captives and they encounter
Killmonger from the first season wearing Infinity
Ultron's armor. K'Hori teleports him out of
the suit, which Peggy then dons to wield the
Infinity Stones. After an extended battle,
Captain Carter and K'Hori acquire Hela's Crown,
Mjolnir, the Ten Rings, and what appears to
be the sword Excelsior from a variant of Hulkling.
Strange is overtaken by the demonic personification
of his guilt, who Carter and Kihori knock into
the forge, killing Strange by creating a new
universe where Strange's love, Christine Palmer,
lives. The Watcher takes Peggy on a journey
to see the multiverse, which manifests as the
Yggdrasil tree from the end of Loki Season
2. Uh... But majority of the runtime was taken
up by this insanely epic fight between Strange
Supreme and Captain Carter and Kahori. As enjoyable
as that fight was, I kept being annoyed by
the power levels issue because it was established
in season one that Doctor Strange Supreme was
the most powerful being in existence in that
reality. He basically overcame everybody and
destroyed the universe in his quest to acquire
enough power to resurrect Christine Palmer,
who died in his reality. So you have the most
powerful being in existence of one universe
going up against Kahori who has telekinesis.
And she was basically holding her own and I
thought that was a little bit strange. More
annoying than that, you have Captain Carter
wearing the Infinity Armor that Ultron created
from season one. The big thing there is that
somehow both Killmonger and Captain Carter are
able to wield the energies of the stones and
the subsequent radiation, which we know is powerful
enough. to render the Hulk out of action and
kill Tony Stark. And yet these guys were wielding
the stones energies effortlessly. Not only
that, I don't get why the stones worked outside
of the universe that they originated to begin
with. Right, that's a whole thing too. In the
comic books, the stones don't work outside
of their native dimension. I'm not sure if that's
the case within the MCU. Well, Loki said it
was. We learned that in Loki season one. They
didn't work in the TVA because the TVA is outside
of time and space. but we don't know if the
same rule applies to, you know, carrying stones
across dimensions. We just know that they don't
work in the TVA. Okay. Now, some people might
say that the reason that Peggy Carter was able
to wield the Infinity Armor was because the
armor granted the wearer enough protection against
the stones' energies, to which I reply, there
is a shot in this episode where Peggy loses
the stones from the armor and Kihori telekinetically
throws them back at Peggy. Peggy catches all
the stones in her hand, which she then uses
to deliver an insanely epic punch against the
demon creature that is Strange Supreme. So
she has the stones in her hand, which should
have just torn her apart. Right, like the Power
Stone alone should have done that as we saw
in Guardians of the Galaxy, unless she's like
half celestial like Peter Quill was. There's
no way she's even close to being half celestial,
right? It's a problem. I have questions. Last
point about the stones. I made this point in
our review for season one is that I feel like
these people aren't wielding the stones right.
Like literally you just have to snap things
away. Like wire Infinity Ultron and Captain
Carter using the stones with a warrior's mentality.
Like you don't have to do all that. Once you
have all the stones, you're literally omnipotent
and you can do anything and you don't have
to like shoot laser beams. Like why would you
do that? Just blink Doctor Strange away. That's
all you have to do. It's weird. It's true. Yeah,
I mean we saw Killmonger snap away Thanos with
his Infinity Gauntlet. Why not just do it to
Doctor Strange Supreme? Yeah, it was really
cool to see all the like bonus characters in
this episode from previous seasons and from,
you know, the MCU and stuff. We saw Thanos,
we saw Hela, we saw Zombie Wanda. That was
all really cool. I'm really curious why we didn't
see benevolent Hela like. If there were any
characters that could like change the universe
completely, you'd think that version of Hela
would do more to change things than Kehori.
You're not wrong. Honestly, I'm not sure why
Dr. Strange Supreme even needed Captain Carter
to capture Kehori for him. Like this whole
thing was fucking pointless. That's entirely
true. That is a great question. Um, I guess
because Dr. Strange wanted to capture both of
them ultimately. But you're right, with how
powerful as Strange Supreme is, he should have
had no problem getting Kahori back into his
collection. And also it's not like if he needed
to capture both of them, he didn't need one
to do the other. He's fucking Doctor Strange
Supreme. Right. I did think that the ending
for this episode though, was kind of a poetic
for Strange Supreme's story. Wherein he ultimately
got exactly what he always wanted, which was
Christine Palmer reborn in a new universe,
but one that he would never be born into. at
the end of the day. It was ironic. Yeah, it
was definitely poetic justice, like you said.
I did think it was cool that they managed to
squeeze Yggdrasil in at the very end of this
considering that just happened in Loki. Yeah,
that was really cool to see. I know that they're
working on a Season 3 of What If, and they've
already released a preview clip of that. I think
it's supposed to come maybe sometime this year.
I hope that they kind of explore the whole Loki
serving as the multiversal loom thing within
this upcoming What If season. They hinted at
it here. I think it's worth exploring and we'll
see what happens. As we talked about this episode,
I actually originally gave this episode four
stars, but I think I'm gonna knock it down a
half star because while I thought the action
was awesome, there was just kind of a lot to
question, such as like why Dr. Strange needed
Captain Carter. Although the ending was good,
I'm still gonna give this episode three and
a half stars. I'm gonna give it three. I think
there were just too many plot holes that were.
critical to the story such as why Captain Carter
got involved and how Dr. Strange was punched
in the face with infinity stones. Things like
that just break the episode for me. Yeah, but
those are all the episodes. When you average
out all my ratings, it comes to around four
stars, which is one whole star higher than what
I rated season one. And I think that sounds
about right. I really enjoyed season two. I
think it was the first time that audiences
will see the premise of the show really come
to life. The stories were just better. You
know, the sophomore season focused less on the
overarching narrative and more on telling worthwhile,
compelling stories that better serve the show's
concept. I rate the season 4 stars, a fresh
rating on Rotten Tomatoes. Yeah, I would agree
with 4 stars. I do think it was better than
season 1. I just love anthology series in general
and there were a lot of great episodes in this
season. Definitely better than what we got in
season 1. So yeah, I'll agree with four stars.
Do you know if all your star ratings averaged
out to about four stars? Yeah, I'm not doing
the math. I'll just agree with you. Yeah. But
that does it for this review, guys. Let us
know what you thought about what if season two
by writing to us at dynamicdualpodcast at gmail.com
or by visiting us on Instagram or X. You can
finally see all of our accounts by checking
out our show notes or visiting our website at
dynamicdual.com. And on our site, you could
also find a link to our Patreon page where you
could join our Dynamic 2.0 tier and chat with
us and fellow listeners are fantastic 4 tier
which gets you bonus content each month our
ex-force tier that makes you an executive producer
of this podcast or our newest here that lets
you join our dynamike podcast Network if you
can't join patreon you can still support the
show by signing up for our e-newsletter Also
at dynamic duel comm so you'll never miss an
episode or you could also rate the show on apple
podcast Spotify Podchaser or on our website
In our next episode, we will be doing a duel
between the characters of Livewire, the Superman
villain, and Claw, the Black Panther villain.
Yeah, these are two energy beings, essentially
one made of electricity and one made of sound.
I think it'll be a pretty fun duel episode.
It'll be nice to get back to the duels, considering
it's been a few weeks since we've done one.
But that does it for this episode, we want to
give a big thanks to our executive producers
Ken Johnson, John Storosky, Zachary Hepburn,
Dustin Balkam, Miggy Mathengian, Brandon Estregard,
Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Nick Abonto,
Austin Wiselowski, AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho,
Adam Spies, Andrew Schunk, and Dean Molesky
for helping make this podcast possible. We'll
talk to you guys next week. Up up and away,
true believers. What if God was one of us?
Just a slob like one of us? Just a stranger
on the bus trying to make his way home?