This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
Hi, welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters and stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin brother, Marvelous
Joe. And in this episode, we are doing a review
of the Harley Quinn spinoff series, Kite Man.
Hell yeah. It wrapped up season one a while
ago, but we're just getting around to it now
because, of course, everything else... from
Marvel and DC has been released within the past
few weeks and these upcoming weeks. There's
gonna be a lot of reviews. Yeah, we are still
in the middle of review hell. Again, bear with
us folks. We will get through all these reviews
eventually. We'll be talking about Kite Man
Hell Yeah later on in this episode. Before that,
we're gonna break down the comic book movie
news to come out this past week, including the
Thunderbolts teaser trailer that was released,
the news that Kyle Chandler has been cast as
Hell Jordan in the Lantern series, and the
news that a Bane and Deathstroke combined film
project is in development.
Why hello there, do you want even more from
this podcast? Then become a part of the dynamic
duel community on Patreon, where you can choose
from three tiers. The dynamic two-oh tier gives
you access to our Discord chat server. The fantastic
four tier gives you two bonus episodes each
month, and the X-Force tier makes you an executive
producer of this show. Lastly, The Diner Mike
podcast network tier lets you create your own
podcast using this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny
and Joe will help you develop your show, provide
graphic support and consultation, and get you
simulation results. Pitch the twins your ideas
via email at dynamicduelpodcast at gmail.com.
Check it out at patreon.com slash dynamicduel.
Pip pip cheerio. Thanks AJ9K and thanks to
everyone who supports the podcast, including
our patron Abner O'Terry. Whose birthday was
this past week? Happy birthday Abner. Happy
birthday. If I could get you a birthday gift
from Marvel, I would get you Cyclops Ruby Quartz
Visor because even though you don't shoot optic
blasts from your eyes, at least it would block
you from UV rays and the sun. Oh, does Ruby
Quartz do that? I don't know. I'm just gonna
make that assumption. Well, in that case, I
would get you the Penguin's Parasol. Cause that
for sure is going to protect you from those
harmful sun rays. Plus it shoots bullets. I
mean, winter is coming up. I don't know why
we're doing this, but whatever. Happy birthday,
man. Happy birthday. Thanks for being a patron.
Guys, be sure to tune into the other shows in
the DynaMic podcast network this week, including
Max Destruction, which pits your favorite action
heroes from film and television against each
other. This week, hosts Scotty and Gilly are
breaking down a Chucky versus Megan matchup.
And that's Megan with the three. from the movie
Megan. Yeah, of course this will be kicking
off the Halloween month of October, a month
where we like to do a lot of spooky duels.
So look forward to that to get into the Halloween
spirit. Playing up on the spooky theme, this
week on the Cinderworld podcast, host Zachary
Hepburn will be speculating on a fight between
Muzzin from Demon Slayer and Femto from Berserk.
Of course, on the Cinderworld podcast, Zach
determines who would win in fights between fan
favorite anime and manga characters. And on
the Console Combat podcast, hosts John and Dean
simulate battles between popular video game
characters. In yesterday's episode, they determined
who would win in a fight between Warden Eternal
from Halo and Saren Arterius from Mass Effect.
Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link
in our show notes to listen to all of the shows
in the Dynomic Podcast Network. But with that
out of the way, quick to the no prize. A no
prize is an award Marvel used to give out to
fans. Our version, the Dynamic duel No Prize,
is a digital award we post on Instagram for
the person that we feel gave the best answer
to our question of the week. Last week we asked
you guys, what musician would you cast as a
live action Marvel or DC character and what
character would that be? And this is coming
off of Lady Gaga's casting in the upcoming
Joker Follyado film. You guys came out of the
woodwork for this question even though Apparently
we've already asked it before like a couple
years ago when Lady Gaga was first cast But
we got a lot of great new answers So let's go
ahead and run them down as well as our no prize
winner our first honorable mention goes to Travis
Herndon who said let's our dynamic dudes Travis
here shout out to my evil twin So my answer
would have to be the great ice cube as what
character you ask Luke Cage I mean, he's got
that look He got the swagger, he got the attitude.
I think Ice Cube could pull off a cool ass Luke
Cage. I mean, come on, he got the look. And
I could definitely see him rocking the yellow
tee, painting tea in the bracelet. So yeah,
Ice Cube is Luke Cage. I thought this was a
fantastic answer. I think Ice Cube would definitely
make a great Luke Cage because he definitely
has the attitude, right? But part of me also
hates this answer because I feel like I would
wanna give Cube a lot of flak for representing
Harlem over Compton, you know, I think it would
be weird for rap fans to see cube representing
the East Side. Yeah, they'd have to like retcon
the character in the film universe so that
yeah, he's from California. There you go. Not
New York. I mean, otherwise you'd have to get
like someone from the Wu-Tang Clan or I don't
know, Puff Daddy, although he's in a lot of
trouble right now. So maybe not him. Yeah, not
him. Puff Daddy, Diddy, whatever he's calling
himself, the Diddler, that guy. Great answer,
Travis. Our next honorable mention goes to
John Speas, who said, Hey fellas, John Speas
here. This one's a little far out, but stay
with me. I would cast Danny Elfman as Norman
Osborn, the Green Goblin. I think he's just
crazy enough to do it. There you go. So one
of the reasons Willem Dafoe was such a great
Norman Osborn is because he has a goblin face.
I've been saying this for years, but there
is another person in this world. who also has
a natural goblin face. And that man is Danny
Elfman, the former singer for Oingo Boingo,
and of course the famous film composer, you
know, who actually wrote the music for the initial
Sam Raimi Spider-Man trilogy. I think he would
be a great Norman Osborn. I think he'd be an
even better Green Goblin. You know who he would
be perfect casting for though? Who? Cletus Kasady
Carnage. He looks exactly like that character
from the comics. Oh, interesting. Yeah, I could
see him as either character. Whenever I think
of characters like Norman Osborn or Cletus Kasady,
I just think of evil Ginger. That's what Danny
Elfman is, there you go. Exactly. Great answer,
Jon Spears. Our next honorable mention goes
to... Miggie Mathingian, who said... Hey, what's
up guys, this is Miggie. And this question
was inspired by Lady Gaga, which, uh, who recently
released a single with Bruno Mars, who's Filipino
and half Puerto Rican, so I was thinking, oh,
he would be a good vibe because they're both,
like, great dancers and they both have Puerto
Rican. heritage and then I was thinking he
was in a duo with uh it's called silk sonic
with anderson pack who is african-american
and korean heritage just like connor hawke so
I would just Bruno Mars as vibe and anderson
pack as connor hawke thanks guys yeah connor
hawke is a pretty obscure character he's the
son of green arrow and took up the green arrow
mantle for a while not a terrible answer I
do like Bruno Mars as vibe a little bit more
just because I feel like Bruno Mars as Vibe
is like peak casting for the character of Vibe.
Like you cannot do better casting than that.
If Vibe ever was cast as Bruno Mars, like the
character has arrived. Like he's A-list now.
That's right, because the character Vibe has
a music background in the comic books, right?
Right, exactly. He was a break dancer. But you
know, you could turn it into like Bruno Mars
smooth style of dancing. I don't know what you
call it. It's smooth as hell, though. I think
it's just hip hop style. Boom. Smooth hip hop
style. I like Anderson Paak though. He did
some music for the Shang-Chi soundtrack and
yeah, he definitely looks like Connor Hawk.
I think the Anderson Paak casting is peak casting
too. So great answer, Miggy. We wanna give
a special shout out to Brandon Estregard who
said Jenny Ico is Poison Ivy. Cyrus Moore who
said Justin Timberlake as the Riddler. Daniel
Alonso who said Ren Gill as Ragdoll. Josh Hayward
said Post Malone as Tattoo Man. Kat Stevens
said Metallica as The Sinister Six. Luke Bradley
said Taylor Swift as Dazzler, Mason Thompson
said Childish Gambino as the Hypno Hustler,
and Mike Williams forgot to leave an answer.
But he called in anyway and we appreciate that.
But the winner of this week's No Prize is Judson
Batty, who said, Hi guys, Judson Batty here.
I know the chances are incredibly unlikely,
but I would cast Elton John as Arcade, the
X-Men villain. I think he's got the looks pretty
much on par. And it's not a very physical role,
so the older age wouldn't be much of an issue.
And I feel like Arcade's the sort of random
character who can get away with bursting into
song or any of that sort of stuff in a similar
way that Joker could. I think it would just
be a very funny thing to watch. Right. He got
cut off there, but this is the perfect answer
people. Yes. Elton John as the X-Men villain
Arcade. If you guys don't know who Arcade is,
he is a trickster villain for the X-Men who
sets up really elaborate video game and amusement
park death traps for heroes. And if you guys
have seen the sequel to Kingsman, which was
called Kingsman and the Golden Circle, you've
seen Elton John in that film and you know just
how perfect an answer this is because he was
fucking hilarious in Kingsman and he kicked
a whole lot of ass in that movie and he's a
great musician. So you gotta give it to him.
Yeah, Elton John is a very colorful character
and arcade creates very colorful and chaotic
environments for the X-Men. I think it totally
works. Plus, you know, when I think of arcade,
I think of evil ginger. And that's also what
I think of when I think of Elton John. What
do you have against gingers, man? Well, nothing
against gingers, just the evil ones. Oh, OK.
All right. That makes sense. I just want to
see the X-Men escaping a death trap. to the
tune of Tiny Dancer while we see Arcade singing
that song. Yes. MCU X-Men, get it done. Kevin
Feige, hope you're listening. Great answer
Judson, you win this week's note prize. If you
the listener want a shot at winning your own
note prize, stay tuned to later on in this episode
when we'll be asking another question of the
week. And now that that's done, onto the news!
Alright, just over a week ago we got the first
trailer for Marvel Studios' Thunderbolts asterisk
movie that's gonna come out in theaters in May
of 2025. And I thought this was a fantastic
trailer. It was pretty much exactly what we
saw from the D23 Thunderbolts presentation,
but with some additional footage toward the
end. And I thought that was one of the more
promising looks to come out of D23 was this
footage. So I'm really pumped for this movie.
Okay, I'm- Also really pumped by how cool this
trailer was. This looks like the Avengers,
but cooler to me. The Avengers are already really
cool. So I don't know what you mean by that.
But yeah, but I'm just talking about like the
cast of characters here. Like when this project
was first announced and they were talking about
the lineup, I was like, oh damn, like that's
a pretty damn cool lineup. Like you're essentially
just taking Marvel's coolest characters that
are like still alive and like putting them together.
But I'm also not gonna lie. When I first saw
this, I also thought, okay, I see what they're
going for. Fucking the Suicide Squad. First
of all, they're completely different concepts.
Like, the Thunderbolts is all about reformed
heroes actually working to do good. It's not
under threat of getting your head exploded
or something like that. That's fair. But can
you admit it? I want to see you admit it. That,
yeah, this looks like it's taking inspiration
from the Suicide Squad. I think that if this
was ripped off of Suicide Squad, it's going
to be a million times better than any iteration.
of the Suicide Squad anything ever was. Especially
that 2016 movie, right? You mean the Oscar
winning Suicide Squad 2016 movie? Fuck off.
All right, anyway, the trailer starts with
Yelena Belova visiting her surrogate father,
Alexei Shostakov, played by David Harbour,
who I think gives a great performance as the
Red Guardian. I love the moment where she knocks
on the door and he's trying to get things cleaned
up for her so that she could come in. And he
brushes his teeth with his finger and dish soap.
Like, just the whole character is just hilarious.
Sure, he's used for comic relief and sure, the
team already has like five different versions
of a super soldier, but I'm here for it. Oh,
yeah. No, David Harbour is fantastic as the
Red Guardian. He was one of the best parts to
come out of the Black Widow movie. I thought
I'm really glad that we're getting to see him
again. His comedic timing is so subtle yet
so good. I'm guessing that he's not with Melina
Vostokov anymore. played by Rachel Weisz in
the Black Widow movie. And that's why he's kind
of down and out here. She must've dumped him
or something. But Yulana talks about how she's
also depressed and she's been diving into her
work. One of her jobs puts her at odds with
John Walker, the US agent, Ghost from Ant-Man
and the Wasp, Taskmaster with a very different
costume here, and Bob Reynolds the Sentry.
Well yeah, Taskmaster and Ghost both have very
different costumes. Yeah, I like Ghost's costume.
She actually removes her mask here, which I
thought was interesting because Taskmaster
did not. I know Olga Korolenko is cast in the
film. I'm not certain why they're so afraid
to show her face though, considering we all
know who she is. Well, I don't know, maybe
some people who haven't seen Black Widow still
don't know that Taskmaster has been gender
swapped. I'm wondering if it's in fact the same
Taskmaster or if it's somebody else. Oh, that's
interesting. I don't know. That's hearsay, but
we'll see what happens. I am intrigued by the
fact though that Taskmaster never takes off
her mask. The fight between the group in that
warehouse bunker was fantastic. I thought it
was really cool to see how they can play off
each other even though they had never met each
other until this point. But they're so in tune
that they're able to counter each other's moves
as they're being made. It's pretty interesting.
Yeah, of course, and then the sentry pops out
of nowhere. Yeah, of course, that role was
originally played by Steven Yoon and I kind
of wish he was still in the role because I
think that would have been a f- Fascinating
character for him to play now. He's being played
by Lewis Pullman still pretty interesting here
I'm really interested in seeing where they
take the character and how faithful they will
be to the comics We do see in a shot later
on that he's being shot at by a group of guards
and all the bullets are basically Bouncing
off of him and not hurting him So he'll be a
cool character if you guys don't know much
about the sentry and want to learn more check
out our episode where? We put him against general
Zod. I wonder if these Thunderbolt characters
were sent in there to kill Bob the sentry or
if they were sent in there for him to kill them.
That's a great question. We don't know what's
really going on because we see Bucky attack
the Thunderbolts group later on at the end
of this trailer. So it seems like somebody's
trying to get these people killed but Bucky
joins the team, Sentry joins the team. It's
really interesting how this is all playing
out. And which of them is being manipulated
by the Contessa Valentina Allegra da Fontaine,
played by Julia Louis-Dreyfus, who apparently
has bought Stark Tower. and she's throwing
parties with like Loki Scepter in them and everything
like that. She puts together the Thunderbolts
and the MCU has been hinting at her involvement
in films like Black Widow and shows like Hawkeye
and the Falcon and the Witcher Soldier. And
Wakanda Forever. Oh yeah, that's right. She
was in that too. It'll be nice to finally get
that payoff of what her motives are and what's
all going on here. Fingers are still crossed
that she's Letharian. Yeah, if they like maybe
merge her character with Lucia von Bardis or
something like that, that could be pretty cool.
Again, Thunderbolts asterisk comes out on May
2nd, 2025. And speaking of that asterisk, that
asterisk though, that brings us to our question
of the week.
What is your theory as to what the asterisk
means in the Thunderbolts movie title? There
are a lot of rumors out there, some of them
more common than others, but we want to know
what your own personal theories are. Record
your answer at dynamicduel.com by clicking
on the red microphone button in the bottom right
hand corner of the screen, which will prompt
you to leave us a voicemail. Your message could
be up to 30 seconds long. And don't forget
to leave your name in case we include you on
the podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer.
and award that person a dynamic duel no prize
that will post to Instagram. Be sure to answer
before October 5th. Moving on to DC news, Kyle
Chandler has been set to star in HBO's Lanterns
series for the DC Universe. This will be produced
by both James Gunn and Peter Safran. Of course,
Chris Mundy and Damon Lindelof have been announced
as writers for the series. There's been some
speculation for a while now as to who was going
to be playing Cal Jordan. And we had A-list
talent in the running, including Josh Brolin
and Matthew McConaughey, Chris Pine, Timothy
Elephant. But ultimately it came down to Kyle
Chandler of Friday Night Lights fame. And I
gotta say, I'm not thrilled by the news, especially
considering the names we could have gotten
and the names that were being thrown around.
It's kind of hard to get excited about Kyle
Chandler. I feel kind of let down by that. I
think it's kind of funny. I think out of...
everyone you could have gotten. Nobody expected
Kyle Chandler to get the job. I mean, he'll
be serviceable. He's been in a few movies. He's
popped up in like Godzilla, King of Monsters,
and he was in the Neil Armstrong biopic First
Man. He's just not a household name. And I
guess I kind of assumed that Hal Jordan would
be considering the last actor to play him was
Ryan Reynolds. You know, we didn't get a version
of Hal Jordan in the Snyderverse. So I kind
of thought that they make up for the bad reception
of Ryan Reynolds film by casting someone really
big in the role to say hey Hal Jordan is still
really important to us he's still a really
big character so much so in fact that we got
this actor i guess that's not the case though
i shouldn't be that disappointed i mean after
all Kyle Chandler is an Emmy-winning actor
like you said he'll be serviceable considering
the talent behind the scenes i'm not too concerned
about the direction of the show I was just expecting
bigger names. It looks like from who's currently
in the running for Jon Stewart as well, like
that's not going to be a big name either. Currently
they're looking at Alan Pierre and Stephen James
to play the role of Jon Stewart. Of course,
Alan Pierre is the star of the Netflix thriller
Rebel Ridge and Stephen James was in films
like The Piano Lesson and 21 Bridges. Actually
he starred opposite Chadwick Boseman in 21
Bridges and I always thought that Stephen James
would have made a good Black Panther. after
Chad Oak Boseman's tragic passing. That said,
I'll be fine to take him for the DC Universe.
He's actually my favorite pick out of those
two for Jon Stewart. Yeah, same here. I'd like
to see him get the role. I think he could pull
it off and I think he'd be a great addition
to the DC film universe too, if they end up
putting Jon Stewart in a Justice League roster
down the line. Apparently they're looking to
make a decision for Jon Stewart sooner rather
than later. Maybe by the time we record our
next episode, we'll have our Jon Stewart. So
look forward to that. In other DC news, it looks
like James Gunn and Peter Safran are developing
a Bane and Deathstroke conjoined film that's
going to be written by Matthew Orton, the same
writer who wrote the upcoming Captain America
Brave New World movie. I have no idea what
that film would look like. Maybe it's just like
an Assassin's movie and there'll be other DC
like assassin or mercenary characters all going
for like a single target or something like
that. That sounds pretty cool. Or maybe Deathstroke
has to infiltrate Santa Prisca prison to eliminate
a target and he encounters Bane. I don't know,
it's all speculative right now. I think the
concept is the most intriguing bit of news to
come out of this though. So they never would
have assumed that they would have taken Bane,
who's a Batman villain, and Deathstroke, who's
primarily a Titans villain, and put them in
the same movie. Yeah, that's a pretty odd couple
there. I saw a rumor that said that the film
is potentially setting up a Secret Six movie.
Well considering that Deathstroke was not a
part of the Secret Six, I find that hard to
believe. Deadshot was in the Secret Six, so
people might be confusing him for Deathstroke,
but I don't know, it might be as good a guess
as any, but I find that hard to believe. As
James Gunn has said in the past, they're not
going to greenlight a film until the script
is completed, so who knows when this movie will
be released, if it will at all. But the fact
that they're developing it is just fascinating
in regards to what James Gunn has planned with
these films. Is there a plan? I'm gonna say
no. It's starting to look that way. Like it
may just be a shared universe with no overarching
story. So basically like they have to see you
right now. Oh, during the multiverse saga? Yeah,
kind of, but you see how that's going for them.
Yeah, yeah. I don't know. We'll see what happens
with this. We'll keep you guys updated if any
other news surrounding it develops.
That does it for all the news for this week,
so now let's move on to the main event of this
episode where we review season 1 of the Max
animated series, Kite Man. Hell yeah.
Hell yeah is a spin-off series of the critically
and fan-acclaimed animated max-exclusive series
Harley Quinn, for which we've reviewed two seasons
and a Valentine's Day special on this podcast.
Harley Quinn is a good series, with enough over-the-top
violence and raunchy humor to entertain its
mature audiences, but also a surprising amount
of heart and psychological insight into the
characters of Gotham that make it relatively
groundbreaking amidst DC's massive library
of animated fare. Now despite the success of
The Harley Quinn Show, I had mediocre expectations
for season one of Kite Man Hell Yeah, a series
based on a D-list Batman villain and minor,
albeit charming side characters from Harley
Quinn. The Harley Quinn Show already features
a pretty obscure cast of Gotham characters,
so would a show that scrapes even further into
the bottom of the barrel actually work? I'm
glad to say it did. I wouldn't go so far as
to recommend the show as must-see TV, but if
you're a fan of the Harley Quinn series, this
show is definitely worth your time, though I
wouldn't expect it to be as innovative. If
you're interested in watching the show but haven't
yet, skip this review for now and come back
after you've watched it as this review, like
all of our reviews, will contain spoilers.
Yeah, I'm not sure this show has any appeal
to people who aren't fans of the Harley Quinn
comedy, you might still find something here
to enjoy. The show is actually pretty different
from what I was expecting it to be. I thought
it was going to be much more of a sitcom, something
like Cheers, but it actually ended up having
more of an overarching story than I thought
it was going to have. For the most part, the
show is purely focused on laughs, though it
does revolve somewhat around the romance of
its two lead characters, Kite Man and his girlfriend
of 14 months, Golden Glider, an obscure Flash
villain. The two work well together, though
I'd say most of the laughs don't come from their
interactions. Rather, most of the show's humor
comes from the ensemble of recurring side characters
that frequent the bar Kite Man and Golden Glider
purchased in episode 1. This includes Bane,
a character from the Harley Quinn show and
my favorite of the bunch, Malice Vunderbar,
a trendy apocalyptic socialite forced to work
at the bar, Sean Noonan, the aloof former owner
of the bar who knows all of its secrets, The
Queen of Fables, also from Harley Quinn, now
just a decapitated head looking for a body.
Joe and Moe doubles, mobster conjoined twins
with two heads. Six pack, a lewd drunkard and
wannabe villain I think. And a random ass guy
named Gus. Now most of the ensemble works,
particularly Bane, Malice, and Noonan. Like
Bane's obsessive nature and Mack forgetting
himself into embarrassing situations are hilarious.
I thought Malice was going to be annoying when
we were first introduced to the character, but
she ended up being a fantastic foil for Golden
Glider, and her demonic cat Cheshire allowed
Malice to get involved in some of the show's
action scenes. Noonan was great as a loyal mentor
figure for Kite Man not only when it came to
running a seedy bar in Gotham, but also in navigating
relationships. Some of the cast, however, like
the doubles twins Sixpack and Daryl, were good
for maybe one joke the entire season. It's
always been interesting to see how some characters
are adapted in this quote-unquote quin-verse
like a character like Malice. And I would have
much rather seen other D-list villains frequenting
Noonan's than some of what we got here. Yeah,
actually going back to your idea that the premise
was going to be more of a sitcom where we see
a revolving cast of D-list villains showing
up at the bar, I was surprised at the lack of
cameos and stuff that we got from this show.
Yeah, we got Frank the Plant, we got Clayface,
we got Martian Manhunter just out of fucking
nowhere. But yeah, I thought we were going to
get a lot more villains. Now regarding the
humor, the show's irreverent gags are pretty
much nonstop, and most of the jokes land, especially
as the season progresses and continues to build
on past jokes. Like in Harley Quinn, there's
a touch of commentary in the humor, particularly
when it comes to one of the show's three villains,
Helen Villigan. who turned her themed bar, Villigans,
into an online Amazon slash Google-esque data
empire that spies on its user base in a send-up
of big tech and capitalistic excess. Usually
LexCorp fills that role in DC media, so I'm
not convinced that Helen Villigan was necessary,
especially considering Lex Luther already serves
as one of the season's villains. He was voiced
by Lance Riddick of John Wick fame. for eight
episodes before his untimely passing. Yeah,
for as ubiquitous as Villigans was in this universe,
you think that we would have seen Villigans
in the Harley Quinn show. We might have maybe
if they were setting this up, but I just don't
remember Villigans any time prior to this season.
No, I think she was made up for the show. Although
that's not entirely true. I was able to find
a character named Helen Helligan. I don't know
if they're the same though. You think they have
to be. Well, Helen Helligan is an FBI agent,
not a villain. Well, never mind then. Now, the
surprise villain for me was Darkseid, who we've
seen in past seasons of Harley Quinn. But, you
know, to make the central conflict of the season
revolve around the anti-life equation made for
some pretty lofty stakes for a show about D-list
villains. Considering the high stakes, I thought
the conflict would have been more appropriate
for a fifth season of Harley Quinn or better
yet, maybe like a Suicide Squad spin-off series.
that I think people would have been much more
interested in than Kite Man. Now seeing Kite
Man in the Suicide Squad would have been much
more interesting to me than seeing him run
a bar. That's just an idea, though. Like for
me, the premise of Kite Man running a bar is
almost like a web series at best. Right. But
it definitely has great potential in the sort
of sitcom style. Like you, I was hoping the
show would go a different route because. I
don't think we need another Harley Quinn series,
essentially. This show explored a lot of different
things, but I'm wondering how they're going
to incorporate what happened in this show into
the upcoming Harley Quinn season. If we're going
to see a lot of these characters jumping back
and forth, I think they're kind of basically
setting themselves up for a continuity nightmare,
especially in this universe which is so wacky
that almost anything can go from episode to
episode. Yeah, I definitely agree. To me, this
could have also just been a subplot within.
the next season of Harley Quinn. Like maybe
get rid of some of the minor subplots from
this series, like Queen of Fables looking for
a body to attach her head to or something like
that. And just, you know, get it streamlined
and insert it into the Harley Quinn show. I
think that could have worked. Exactly. And let
me just say this. It shouldn't have been Kite
Man who got his own spinoff show. For as funny
as Kite Man is, he didn't have as much to do
here as like Harley Quinn does in say her own
show. It's more about this whole cast of characters,
including Bane, who has probably just as much,
if not more, screen time than Kite Man does.
I think this should have been a Bane spinoff,
because to me, he's the standout from the Harley
Quinn show, not Kite Man. Yeah, he's the standout
from both shows, Harley Quinn and Kite Man,
I felt. I would love to see Bane get his own
show, and I agree he probably should have gotten
his before Kite Man did. Now, regarding the
romance of the series, it truly is the heart
of the show, as it is in the Harley Quinn series.
Kite Man and Golden Glider are great for each
other, but let's talk more about them and their
relationship in our character breakdown. Charles
Chuck Brown slash Kite Man was voiced by Matt
Oberg. I haven't talked too much about his
voice performance in past seasons of the Harley
Quinn series, but if it wasn't for Oberg's
lovable, loser-esque comedic take on Kite Man,
the character would not have been endearing
enough to sustain his own spinoff series. The
show owes a lot of credit to Oberg's charm.
which I think could translate into live action
if they ever want to put Kite Man in a Suicide
Squad film or something like that. For sure.
Yeah, that would be hilarious. The guy's delivery
is something special. I'll say that. It's more
than spot on. It's charming, it's pitiful,
it's comedic. It's all of these things in one
package. Yeah, it could go anywhere from super
heroic to super sad and everything in between.
And still be funny all at once. Kite Man's
arc this season revolves around self-acceptance,
and it's an arc that stems from his appearances
in Harley Quinn. He broke off his engagement
to Poison Ivy in that show because he had the
self-worth to not be with a woman he loved who
didn't love him on equal footing. Kite Man
and Golden Glider make a better couple in that
they're both fully committed to each other
despite their flaws. But Kite Man becomes insecure
during the show by his father's disapproval,
the appearance of a rival bar like Villigans
across the street, as well as Golden Glider's
mom, Rebecca Chen, telling him he's not good
enough for her daughter. So he makes the decision
to go to his rival, Helen Villigan, to gain
a superpower in order to be more than the loser
he suddenly feels he is. But by the end of the
season, he learns that he doesn't need a superpower
because his power all along had been his kindness
and friendliness that got him his dream girl
and bar from the very start. The superpower
of Beast Mode. Might be my favorite moment
with Kite Man. His douchebag power, it's just
so unbelievably wacky and hilarious. Oftentimes
I've been asked if you could have any superpower.
I think I kind of want douchebag superpower.
His power was telekinesis, which was activated
by him throwing up the middle finger, right?
But it would do things like wedgies and pull
people's pants down and titty twisters and
stuff like that. It was just hilarious. I think
that stemmed more from who Beast Mode was as
opposed to what his power was specifically.
Okay. It wasn't like his power was like randomly
doing these douchey things to them, I think.
But yeah, I would love that power in real life.
People who like cut me off in traffic, I just
like throw up the finger and then all of a
sudden their car would shut down or something
like that. That type of power does appeal to
me in a totally petty way. Was Beast Mode your
favorite Kite Man moment or did you have another
one? No, there were no like real standout action
moments or anything really heroic for him outside
of the whole Anti-life equation thing at the
end, but even that wasn't really an exciting
action moment for him true. Very yeah He didn't
really do anything like impressive with his
kite this season I felt which I was actually
really looking forward to considering our last
episode Which was a duel between kite man and
stilt man, you know all the different kite
gadgets that he has in the comics weren't really
on display in this show, except as random gags.
When he hit his belt and it would shoot out
a bunch of little kite throwing stars and stuff
like that. Yeah, you're right. That was it.
But you know, like Harley Quinn and Kite Man,
those shows really aren't about the heroics.
No, but there is a lot of action. So I would
have expected Kite Man to be more involved in
the action more frequently in his own series.
I think the biggest thing he did besides the
Anti-Life Equation thing was punch Baby Doll,
but that happened off camera. Well, you look
at Golden Glider, she got a whole lot of action
in this season. Oh, absolutely. Yeah. Lisa Snart
slash Golden Glider. She was voiced by Stephanie
Sue. I think she's a fantastic actress. She
was great as one of the leads in everything
everywhere all at once. And though I didn't
care for her performance at the start of this
season, I think that was more due to the writing
of the character because by the end of the
season, I was really happy with the character.
And I think a lot of that has to do. with Sue's
ability to deliver both comedy and drama. I
think at one point we were thinking about pitting
Golden Glider against Shadow Cat from Marvel
in a duel episode. And I am totally glad that
we didn't do that because Golden Glider seems
OP as fuck. Well, so this is an interesting
adaptation of Golden Glider because in the past,
Golden Glider was just a really fast skater.
But in the new 52, they re-imagined the character
to be almost like a ghost with blades that's
really fast. So they kind of did both for this
show and that she had this like astral projection
that could shoot out these ribbons that could
either like liquefy or cut people. I actually
think it was a pretty good adaptation of the
character and honestly I hope they adapt that
to the comics. She's a former member of the
Rogues? Yes, that's correct. We'll find a matchup
for her eventually somewhere down the line.
I think maybe Devin has already come up with
that idea, but I'll have to double check. This
is a much better adaptation of the character
from the comics than what they did on the Flash
TV show, which is just give her a gun that
turns things gold. Holy shit. That's so stupid.
Yeah, it was kind of ridiculous. But you know
what? I bet you Golden Glider in the Kite Man
show wished she had that power, though. I mean,
who wouldn't? I want that. Yeah, yeah. Now,
like Kite Man, Golden Glider's arc revolves
around insecurity. You know, her insecurity
around using her unstable powers. around her
relationship with Kite Man, around the new young,
caught-rich barmaid, her unresolved past, and
around the unrequited love from her mother.
The only thing that keeps her stable is the
shared love between herself and Kite Man, which
makes it all the more tragic at the end of
the season when the only way to seemingly save
the world from the anti-life equation is for
Glider to kill Kite Man. That ended up not happening
through a bizarre deus ex machina. But in the
end she admitted that she wouldn't have been
able to kill Kite Man anyway because she loved
him. And though she never overcomes her insecurities
in this season, at least she's supported by
a good partner who brings out the best in her
as she does for him. Hashtag relationship goals.
You know it's interesting that Kite Man and
Golden Glider make such a good couple considering
they're both highly insecure people. And neither
of them have like real secure attachments due
to their upbringing and stuff like that. And
usually you need at least one person to have
a secure attachment in a relationship in order
for the relationship to work. Otherwise, you
know, the insecurities compound and spiral out
of control. But yeah, they both seem like they
have anxious attachments to each other or something.
Well, Kymane is usually very secure, like almost
to a fault. Like he should not be as secure
as he is. It wasn't until this season that
he kind of started to feel like, oh, maybe he's
not good enough because, you know, he told
Poison Ivy straight to her face, like, I'm too
good for you. So, you know, that was never
really his problem until he started to get serious
with Golden Glider. That's true. That's very
true, actually. I didn't think about that, but
you're absolutely right. He kind of has delusions
of grandeur in his security. Exactly. But that's
kind of the appeal, right? He's a big loser,
but he doesn't necessarily know that he's a
big loser. Right. That's 100% the appeal of
the character. Because it makes you want to
root for him. He's the underdog. This whole
show is about underdogs. Him, Golden Glider,
Bane, everyone. No, my favorite moment with
Golden Glider was actually in the first episode
when she first showed her powers because that's
when I realized how they were adapting the character.
And I was like, okay, they're taking like a
mixture between, you know, pre-New 52 Golden
Glider and post-Flashpoint Golden Glider. The
funniest moments I think were actually, you
know, her naked fighting at the spa, but also
her getting her nipples pierced. when she thought
that her mom was going to get it done too,
only to find out that wasn't the case. Oh, so
all the raunchy stuff, okay. Yes. Regarding
the naked fight, that was pretty interesting
because the animators, it seemed like they
tried to Austin Powers the whole choreography
as much as they could in that they were trying
to hide her exposed bits for as long as they
could. But at some point they just said, fuck
it, and just decided to blur everything. Right.
And just let it in full view of the camera.
I thought that was pretty interesting why they
just didn't do that from the get go. But I
actually think it would have been more funny
for them to continue the kind of Austin powersing
of the nudity within the fight. That's fair.
Where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
DynaMic Podcast Network presents Console Combat,
where video game legends brawl every Monday.
Titans Smash every Tuesday, Max Destruction,
where TV and action heroes battle every Wednesday,
and Sendro World, where anime champions clash
every Thursday. Join us as we speculate on
the matches and, armed with the power of mathematical
simulations, discover who will emerge victorious.
Visit dynamicpodcast.com where we settle the
debate and settle the score.
Moving on to our story highlights, the first
episode was titled, Pilot Hell Yeah! With the
anti-life equation in his possession, Lex Luthor
reluctantly hires Kite Man as an aerial spy
to guard the Legion of Doom against the Justice
League due to the Legion's flying villains
being unavailable. Kite Man fails at his task,
so Luthor takes revenge by attempting to buy
Kite Man's hangout, Noonan's Bar, for $10 million.
Kite Man and his girlfriend Golden Glider strive
to raise the money first, but are unable to
borrow it from anyone. Harley Quinn and Poison
Ivy advise the two to rob from villains worse
than them. With help from former Legion member
Bane, the group attack the mansion of Kite Man's
father, Daryl, who willingly surrenders his
money as a reward for Kite Man finally standing
up to him. Luther's revenge is later revealed
to be a deception so that he can hide the anti-life
equation in Nunein's freezer, unaware that
Darkseid is also on the hunt for it. Do you
think they did Sinestro dirty in this episode?
They do so many villains dirty in the Harley
Quinn series and this show. I was not happy
with what they did to Sinestro. I was like,
okay, really Lex Luthor? I guess. I thought
that Kite Man's dad, Daryl, giving him the money,
I thought there was going to be some kind of
catch to it or something like that. He was going
to reveal like, This is your inheritance I'm
giving it to you now, don't ask me for anything
else in the future or something like that.
But the way he gave it to him was actually pretty
earnest, which surprised me considering how
he was kind of a big douchebag to his son. Yeah,
I think it was meant to be funny. I actually
think the show gets funnier as it goes. These
first few episodes I didn't think were that
great. Yeah, it was kind of weird the way he
just kind of gave it to him. I will say the
funniest part of this episode I thought. was
actually a setup for a gag that was recurring
throughout the rest of the season when Moe Doubles
was shot. And so his conjoined twin brother
is just like walking around with his dead brother's
head right next to him. Just like totally aloof.
Like it's not even a big thing. Yeah, that was
hilarious. I love that. Episode two was titled
Grand Reopening. Hell yeah. While preparing
for Noonan's grand reopening, Kite Man hires
Darkseid's entitled goddaughter Malice. as a
server despite Glider wanting to hire Bane
for the job. Meanwhile, Kite Man grows desperate
for Daryl to respond to his invite to the event.
Displeased with Malice's attitude, Glider invites
Luthor, among other notable Legion members,
to the party, unaware that Luthor is throwing
his own party to ensure Nuenans stays irrelevant.
The latter event is subsequently ruined by Malice's
cat Cheshire, who escapes and temporarily becomes
kaiju sized after eating several civilians.
unintentionally drawing attention to Noonans.
After realizing that he should focus more on
impressing people who actually like him, Kite
Man fires Malice, but Glider promotes her to
social media manager to make Darkseid happy
while Bane takes a job as bouncer. Elsewhere,
a goon named Gus takes the Queen of Fables
head in as his kindergartner's class pet where
she is forced to entertain his students before
stealing the body of one boy's mother after
being taken home. Now, I didn't know who Malice
was when watching the show, so I wanted to make
sure that I looked her up and she looks nothing
like her adaptation in the show. Yes, another
one of those instances of the Quinnverse really
doing a decent job of adapting the character
from the comics. In the comics, Malice is much
more like Baby Doll or Alice, and I think that
would have just been way too much if they had
done that with her character. I really like
what they did with Malice. Who is she related
to on Apocalypse? I have no idea who that is.
Okay. Yeah, he's like this Monocle general
type guy, kind of like Baron Shucker in Marvel.
Oh. Moving on to episode three titled, Villigans.
Hell yeah. Villigans, a themed chain restaurant
opens across the street from the bar, threatening
Newton's business. Meanwhile, Kite Man feels
that he is not moving fast enough in his relationship
with Glider and asks if they can move in together.
though she avoids the subject upon noticing
that he found her secret relationship spreadsheet
on her computer. Kite Man tries to reignite
their bond by discovering Villigan's intentions,
but proves reluctant to kill the manager as
he has never killed before. Meanwhile, Glider
accepts Villigan's offer for a free spa day
with the Queen and Malice. During this, she
confesses that she loves Kite Man and has been
ready to move in with him, but is afraid that
she might kill him due to her unstable powers.
The group later learn they stumbled onto a deathtrap
owned by Babydoll, who reveals her intent to
kill Kite Man and destroy Nunes with a rigged
gift basket. However, Kite Man throws the basket
at the last second, destroying Villigans. Kite
Man and Glider later reconcile and agree to
move in together. I thought one of the best
gags in the entire season was how Bane started
working for Villigans just by going there and
seeing how poor of a service the costumed Bane
there was giving. You're giving Bane a bad name.
He always finds himself in like the most embarrassing
situations, but he just has like the best heart
about it. So he just kind of always has to
deal with whatever is thrown at him. He's a
great character. Episode four was titled Portal
Potty. Hell, yeah. While moving above Noonan's,
Kiteman notices the lack of photos from Glider's
youth, but she refuses to discuss her background
with him. Meanwhile, Bane accidentally travels
back to 1986 after defecating in the apartment's
toilet, where he falls in love with Glider's
mother, Rebecca Chen. Through Glider's brother,
Captain Cold, Kite Man learns their alcoholic,
bickering parents frequented Newnans in 1986,
which is where Glider accidentally killed them
upon using her powers for the first time. After
falling out with Glider, Kite Man travels back
in time to prevent her parents' deaths, with
Glider following soon after. Glider's father,
Lawrence Snart, is killed in an explosion. Glider
ultimately decides to focus on the present
instead of the past, only to discover that Rebecca
is still not around in the present. Unbeknownst
to Glider, Rebecca ran away following Lawrence's
death before being trapped in a jail cell and
gassed by an unknown figure. A few questions
here. Who is Rebecca? Because she was very
prominent this season and I don't know if she's
from the comics at all. She's actually not
a major character in the comics. If anything,
the Snart Father is more of a major character
for his involvement in the origin of Captain
Cold. Well, by the end of the show, Rebecca
became like the evil queen in Fairy Tail Land
or something like that. Yeah, they made her
an evil fairy godmother, but like, that's not
really a character in DC. So I'm not sure what
that's gonna lead to. How did you feel about...
the year that they went back to being 1986,
because that would mean that Kite Man and Glider
were around their mid 40s by this point in
the present day. Doesn't that seem a little
bit old for them? They definitely look younger
than that, I would say. Just makes me feel like
I need to get my ass to the gym. Yeah, I know.
I'm starting to think that my potential superhero
days are over. But, you know, not if Golden
Glider's over here kicking ass at age 44. Right?
On ice skates, it's wild. Episode 5 was titled
Prison Break. Hell yeah. After returning to
the present, Bane learns Rebecca was imprisoned
in his old home, The Pit. He, Kite Man, and
Glider head there, where they discover Villigan's
owner, Helen Villigan, purchased the pit from
the League of Shadows, and is using brainwashed
prisoners as slave labor. Braving the workers
and various death traps, the trio rescue Rebecca
and bring her back safely. When she awakens
later, however, Rebecca is not enthused to
see Glider. Meanwhile, Malice closes Nounen's
early to prepare for the arrival of her immortal
boyfriend, despite the presence of a health
inspector. She asks everyone present to pretend
she does not work there, but the boyfriend kills
several patrons, leading to her telling the
truth and him dumping her. This causes her to
feel emotions for the first time. Through her
actions, Nounen's receives a D- from the inspector,
narrowly saving it from being closed down.
I'm kind of mixed on this episode. I really
liked the stuff. I thought that was hilarious,
mainly because, you know, Bane played a big
part of it and Bane is just fantastic. I hated
the whole Malice's boyfriend stuff and the health
inspector stuff. It was it was dumb. Like,
why was the health inspector immortal? It was
just out of nowhere. It was filler, of course.
I want to talk about I want to go back to Glider's
mom, Glider's mom, Rebecca, because a big portion
of the plot revolves around her. And we know
she didn't want to be a mom, that was her whole
thing, but we never really got a sense of why
she didn't want to be a mom and how that affected
Glider. There was no real closure there in terms
of that revelation and Glider's feelings on
it. Well, sort of. She told Glider straight
up that she never wanted to be a mom. But you
think there would be more of an emotional fallout
from that. They kind of just moved past it
right away. That's fair. I think I would be
much more emotionally distraught if my mother
told me that. But... You know, Rebecca was largely
out of the picture during that portion of this
season to begin with, so it didn't really bother
me that much. It was a non-satisfying side
story, for sure. I would agree with that, yeah.
Episode 6 is titled Mother Daughter Day. Hell
yeah. Glider attempts to reconcile with Rebecca
via a mother daughter day, with Malice tagging
along at Rebecca's insistence. Before leaving,
Rebecca tells Kite Man that he is not right
for her daughter, given his lack of prospects
and powers, which gets to him. Rebecca later
abandons Glider, confessing that she never wanted
a child and left because she did not want to
be killed by Glider's powers like Lawrence.
Angered, Glider tricks her into using the portal
potty to travel back to 1986. Meanwhile, despite
his crush on Rebecca, Bane reunites with Betty,
an old fling from Valentine's Day who convinces
him to give the relationship another chance.
Concurrently, at the suggestion of Noonan's
former owner, Sean Noonan, Kite Man separately
meets with Etchigan and Helen to get superpowers,
but is told by her that he must give up his
kite in exchange. He agrees and becomes Beast
Mode, gaining the ability to telekinetically
bully others, which costs him his relationship
with Glider. Satisfied that her plan is working,
Helen burns his old kite.
kind of switched to the side of Kite Man. We
see her throw the kite into the fire and she's
laughing, but we never see her pull it out of
the fire when she gives the kite back to him
later on in the season. It feels kind of cheap
that we never saw that transformation. It kind
of seems like the writers wrote themselves into
a corner and they didn't really know what to
do with the Helen Villigan character, so they
kind of just switched up her motivations a
little bit in order to make Darkseid the big
bad guy. Right. Yeah, yeah, it does feel that
way. I wonder why he had to give up the kite
to get the douchebag powers though. In a way
it was almost kind of like giving up his soul.
He loved kites ever since he was a young kid,
so for him to give up the things that he loves
as a way to gain powers, he was essentially
making a deal with the devil. Right, but why
did Helen need him to get rid of the kite?
It was like she was just fucking with him. Because
she knew it was the way that he was traditionally
most effective, and for the purposes that she
needed him for, he didn't need the kite. I
was really glad to see Etrigan and Betty from
the Valentine's Day special. I totally forgot
about them, so that was a nice reminder. I wish
Etrigan made more appearances. Betty and Bane
are meant to be together. I don't know what
he's doing around with this Rebecca girl. Right?
That's what I'm saying. Episode 7 was titled
Sexiest Villain Alive. Hell yeah! With Bane,
Luther, and Beast mode in the running for Sexiest
Villain Alive, Malice upgrades Bane's wardrobe
to increase his chances. containing the anti-life
equation that she found in Nunegan's freezer,
which she thinks is an accessory. Meanwhile,
Glider deduces that Helen can change Beast
Mode back into Kite Man, so she nabs Helen's
power controller with the help of Clayface,
but only the real Helen's eyes can bypass the
security. At the awards ceremony, the Queen
and Moe bring Toyman and Insect Queen as dates,
with the latter luring Moe back to her hive
to kill him. The Queen and Toyman follow to
warn him, only to stumble across the Queen's
old body preserved in honey. Helen has the contest
rigged in Beast Mode's favor, ordering him
to distract Luther with his insulting victory
speech while her Hummingbird drones hunt down
the equation, which Luther has also located.
The briefcase eventually lands in the possession
of Glider, who merges with the equation and
finally gains control of her powers. She forces
Helen to let her access the power controller,
restoring Kite Man, and the two mend their
relationship. I guess I want to know how Helen
knew about the anti-life equation, because
that kind of seemed to come out of nowhere,
where suddenly all these villain characters
are going after the same thing. Dude, Helen
knows about everything in the same way that
Google does. Or Jeff Bezos. Right, yeah. My
favorite moment in this episode, I think, was
when the Queen of Fables asked Toy Man if he
had a car, and he was like, sort of, and then
the next thing we see him like carrying her
head in a wagon. I don't know why. I thought
that was hilarious. I was kind of sad that we
didn't see a battle between Queen of Fables
in her new body and the Hive Queen. It was just
mentioned as something that happened off screen.
They should have shown that. Yeah, that was
weird. I love how enamored Kite Man's dad is
with this new version of him as Beast Mode.
Yeah, it was funny when the dad was like, let's
go to a titty bar, son. And Beast Mode was like,
I am the titty bar. And his dad was like, I
don't know what that means, but I've never been
more proud.
Everything was beast mode, I don't know why,
I just loved it. Episode 8 was titled, Just
Right. Hell yeah. Kite Man and Glider are on
the run after obtaining the Anti-Life Equation
and are allowed to hide out for one night at
a resort owned by Frank the Plant. Given his
recent experience with a superpower, Kite Man
is concerned that the equation is corrupting
his girlfriend and wants to get rid of it, especially
after she attacks random civilians out of paranoia
and insecurity. Glider is faced with visions
of Rebecca, who suggests that they can rule
the world together now that she has control
over her powers. Meanwhile, Bane is tasked
with babysitting and escaped Goldilocks while
the Queen is out enjoying her old body, though
Goldilocks' personality gets on everyone's nerves.
Bane takes Goldilocks to a meeting between
him, Lex Luthor, and Helen Villigan, who have
temporarily joined forces to track down the
equation. Though Goldilocks ruins their talk,
Bane decides that he should learn from her
high standards and leaves, though the equation's
location is outed thanks to a call from Frank.
Helen sends an army of robots to get the equation
back, though at Kite Man's insistence, Gleider
tosses it into a nearby nuclear plant, destroying
the robots as well as the resort and restoring
Gleider's personality. Ultimately, however,
the equation remains intact even after the
explosion. I loved the dynamic between Bane
and Goldilocks. Like if they made a Bane show,
I would want Goldilocks to be like his sidekick.
Or at least a recurring character from time
to time of someone that he's supposed to take
care of. Episode 9 was titled, To Get to the
Other Side. Hell yeah. To keep the anti-life
equation from Golden Glider, Luther, and Villigan,
Kite Man steals a chicken delivery truck and
keeps the briefcase in the back, which mutates
one of the chickens into a kaiju-sized carnivore.
Meanwhile, Malice is visited by Darkseid. who
offers to let her serve him an apocalypse for
her dedication at Nuenen's, though she is conflicted
about the proposal. When Sixpack lets slip that
Kite Man and Glider have the equation, she
tells him that Luther actually has it, which
adds to her guilt. Darkseid learns that he
was misled and sets out to find the equation
himself, unaware that Luther plans to recapture
it by holding Nuenen at gunpoint to lure Kite
Man back home. His attempt is thwarted by the
rest of the bar gang, including Bane. who unknowingly
sends Goldilocks to the portal potty to shield
her from the violence. After Cheshire fails
to subdue the giant chicken, Glider and Kite-Man
defeat it by making it cough up the briefcase,
dying to keep holding onto it. Back on Apocalypse,
Darkseid, determined to complete his search
for the equation, decides to confront Malice
about the truth using a tracking app that came
with Cheshire. I didn't love this episode.
The chicken largely felt like filler. Absolutely.
And I don't know if the... payoff was quite
there. No, it was definitely just, you know,
a stall tactic to get through another episode
for them to go right back to Noonan's. I also
thought the whole thing with them being on
the run just felt like filler. We haven't really
talked about the look of the equation yet.
I love that they made it like the Pulp Fiction
briefcase. Whenever I watch Pulp Fiction now,
yeah, I'm just going to think that, oh, that's
the anti-life equation. Yeah, that's my headcanon
now. Moving on to the final episode titled Hero
Stuff. Hell yeah. Helen captures Kite Man and
Glider and informs the couple that according
to her algorithm, the world population would
be fully destroyed no matter who handles the
anti-life equation except for Kite Man. They
are then spared since Helen wants their help
to keep her existing business. The couple hold
a meeting with those in Nuenens and decide that
Kite Man should commit suicide after absorbing
the equation like the Exorcist and Glider would
be the Mercy Killer. As they get ready on the
roof of Nuenens, Lex Luthor tracks down the
couple and arrives with the Legion of Doom.
Their friends defend them from the attack until
Darkseid shows up after learning Kiteman's
plan for Malice. Darkseid almost takes the equation,
but Helen's robots and Glider delay him until
Rebecca, who traveled back to the present upon
hearing stories from Goldilocks, grabs the
equation and jumps inside the Queen of Fairy
Tales book. The book is then taken far away
by Martian Manhunter, who has been disguised
as Gus since the group meeting. Lex retreats
sadly while Darkseid and Helen make peace with
Nuenen's group. As Kite Man and Glider enjoy
the blue skies ahead, Rebecca has killed off
the current evil fairy godmother and becomes
the new evil fairy godmother with the anti-life
equation. As she prepares for a future invasion
with the demonized storybook characters, Brainiac's
skullship approaches Earth from outer space.
And now I'm wondering if they're gonna address
Brainiac's arrival on Earth in the Harley or
if they're just gonna completely ignore it.
Yeah, is that a set up for season two of Kite
Man or is that set up for season five of Harley
Quinn? Not sure. I loved all the references
to The Exorcist. Like it came up so much more
than I thought it would, which is a spoiler
for The Exorcist for anyone who hasn't seen
it, by the way. I like how they turned it into
a verb where to exorcist yourself means to get
possessed by something and then kill yourself
to kill it. It's very convoluted, but it's kind
of funny the way they do it. I even love how
Darkseid knew about what happens in the movie.
Yeah. That's great. I really liked this end
battle. I thought it was cool to see the Legion
of Doom go up against Nuenen's bar people.
I thought it was a well planned out fight even
though it was fairly brief. I also liked this
episode overall just as a conclusion for season
one. Again, I'm not sure how the concluding
moments will set up future seasons, but it was
nice to see Kaiman and Glider just kind of
sail off into the sunset. I thought it was kind
of weird how Helen Villigan all of a sudden
had these simulation scenarios that she was
running, kind of like a Monte Carlo simulator
or something like that we use here. Yeah. But
she didn't have access to that information
in previous episodes, so it was just kind of
convenient that they introduced that idea in
this episode. Yeah. I am almost wondering if
Lance Riddick's death kind of threw a wrench
in everything, because he was the voice of Lex
Luthor for a majority of the series, except
for the last two episodes. You know, I thought
that exact same thing. Because... once they
got the new voice in there, his role seemed
substantially lessened. Oh, for sure, yeah.
And I'll say that the new voice wasn't nearly
as good. I agree. Not bad, but yeah, it just
wasn't the same. Noticeably so. But that does
it for the show. Overall, I had a good time
with season one of Kite Man, you know, with
laugh out load moments. raunchy romance and
high-flying stakes. It offered an entertaining
yet all-too-familiar look at Gotham's lovable
losers. It didn't break ground in the same way
that I feel the Harley Quinn series does with
its often introspective episodes. There's nothing
like that in Kite Man. I do think the show
has promise, though not as much promise as what
the show could have been if it was something
slightly different and slightly more unique,
I would say. I'm giving it 3 out of 5 stars,
a fresh rating on Rotten Tomatoes, though I
would mostly just recommend this to fans of
the Harley Quinn show. Yeah, I would agree.
The show doesn't really hold up to the main
Harley Quinn series, so it shouldn't be rated
as high as what we did for those reviews. We
gave the Valentine's Day special 3 stars, and
I think this holds up with that because I enjoyed
the Valentine's Day special for Harley Quinn.
And yeah, I think ultimately I would also recommend
the show, but again, to certain people. but
any sort of fan of comedy I think would enjoy
it. Are you excited for a season two? Not really,
no. I could actually take it or leave it. I
am excited for Harley Quinn season five though.
So I think that says a lot. Yeah, yeah, I don't
think we have a release date for that yet. I
could be wrong, but I am looking forward to
that as well. But that does it for this review.
AJ9K, help close us out. Thanks for listening
to Dynamic duel. Visit the show's website at
dynamicduel.com and follow us on Instagram
at dynamicduelpodcast. You can support the show
on Patreon at patreon.com slash dynamicduel
and joining a tier that works for you, or by
rating and reviewing Dynamic duel on Apple
Podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser or on our website.
Don't forget to listen to the other shows in
the DynaMic Podcast Network, including Max
Destruction, Senjow World and Console Combat.
In our next episode, we will be reviewing the
only DC theatrical film to come out this year,
Joker Folly Ado. I've been looking forward to
this for a couple years now, ever since it
was first announced. I think I might be seeing
it early at a critics screening, not sure yet.
Either way, we'll let you know everything we
thought about it in our next episode. We want
to give a big thanks to our executive producers
Ken Johnson, John Storosky, Zachary Hepburn,
Dustin Belcom, Megan Manson-Geehan. Brendan
Estergard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Austin
Wiselowski, AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Gil
Camacho, Adam Spies, Andrew Schunk, Dean Molesky,
Devin Davis, Joseph Kersing, and Josh Leiner
for helping make this podcast possible. We'll
talk to you guys next week. Up up and away,
true believers.