This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
Welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin brother, Marvelous
Joe. And in this episode, we are reviewing
X-Men 97. It's Marvel's first X-Men project
since acquiring the rights to the characters
from Fox. I remember watching this show in the
mid-90s as a kid. Was this 25 years worth the
wait? Yes it was and I can't wait to talk about
it later on this episode. Before that we're
going to break down the comic book movie news
from the past week of which it was a pretty
slow week. All we learned was that Vision Quest,
the upcoming television series for Disney+,
has gotten a 2026 release window and a showrunner.
Well to be fair we are recording this episode
a little bit early in lead up to the Memorial
Day holiday weekend. So there might be more
news that drops that we'll get to in the next
episode, if that's the case. As always, we
list our segment times in our episode description,
so feel free to check out the show notes if
you want to skip ahead to a particular topic.
Our artificially intelligent duel simulator,
AJ9K, has a quick message for our listeners,
so listen up. Why, hello there. Do you love
listening and chatting about Marvel and DC?
Then become a part of the dynamic duel community
on Patreon, where you can choose from three
tiers. The dynamic 2.0 tier, lets you listen
to this podcast without ads and gives you access
to its Discord chat group where you can chat
with Johnny DC and Marvelous Joe. The Fantastic
Four tier gives you that and more with two
bonus episodes each month, including bloopers
and top ten shows where Johnny and Joe count
down your favourite Marvel and DC subjects.
The X-Force tier makes you an executive producer
of Dynamic Duel, where every month you help
the host choose what to review and who to fight
against each other. And finally, the Dynamite
Podcast Network tier allows aspiring podcasters
to create their own battle-focused show using
this Monte Carlo simulator.
Thanks AJ9K, and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast. Be sure to tune into the shows
in the DynaMic Podcast Network this week, including
Max Destruction, which pitched your
The show is currently on a season break, but
hosts Ken and Scott are releasing bonus episodes,
and this Thursday they will be reviewing The
Matrix. On the Sendrow World podcast, host
Zachary Hepburn speculates on fights between
fan-favorite anime and manga characters. This
Thursday, we'll find out who would win between
Jura Nikus from Fairy Tail and Diane from Seven
Deadly Sins. On the Console Combat podcast,
Hosts John and Dean find out who would win
in fights between popular video game characters.
In yesterday's episode, they found out who
would win in a battle between Samanosuke Akechi
from Animusha against Ryu Hayabusa from Ninja
Gaiden. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com or click the
link in our show notes to listen to all of
the shows in the DynaMic Podcast Network. But
with that out of the way, quick! To the no
prize! A No Prize is an award Marvel used to
give out to fans. Our version, the Dynamic
duel No Prize, is a digital award we post on
Instagram for the person that we feel gave
the best answer to our question of the week.
Last week, we asked you guys, what celebrity
voice actor for a Marvel or DC animated film
would you like to see play the character in
live action? And this was coming off of the
news that Nicolas Cage will be starring in
a live action Spider-Man We got a lot of answers
for this question and they were all great But
let's break down our three honorable mentions
as well as the no prize winner Our first honorable
mention goes to Matt Estes who said Hey fellas,
Matt Estes here. Hey, this is probably the
easiest question y'all have ever asked for question
of the week It's gotta be Dove Cameron with
Spider-Gwen Yeah, Dove Cameron played the character
of Spider-Gwen in the animated Marvel Rising
movies And the actress looks exactly like Spider-Gwen.
I don't know what else there is to say about
that. She should definitely play the character
because she definitely has the look. But she's
also a really good actress. Actually, my daughters
are a fan of her from her working descendants.
She was on some Disney channel show where she
played like two different characters, twins,
I think. She has the acting chops. I was actually
rooting for her for a while to play Supergirl.
But yeah, Spider-Gwen would also work. She was
actually also in the Agents of S.H.I.E.L.D.
television show for a while as well. No one
cares! She's no stranger to Marvel, that's
all I'm saying. So this could definitely work.
Great answer Matt. Our next honorable mention
goes to Miggy Matagian who said, Hey what's
up guys, this is Miggy and I would love to
see Lou Diamond Phillips play Spectre in live
action. I mostly went with this because he's
half Filipino and I got to represent. But I
think he also has a good look for Jim Corrigan,
like a weathered, tired police detective. Some
other answers that I was leaning towards but
didn't go with is Jason Isaacs as Sinestro,
Bryan Cranston as Jim Gordon, John Noble as
Brainiac, and Jamie Chung as Cheshire. Thanks
guys. Yeah, all of those were great answers.
I especially loved Lou Diamond Phillips as the
Spectre for two reasons. One, Lou Diamond Phillips
does not get enough work. The guy's a good actor.
And two, the Spectre... is an awesome character.
Ever since I saw his DC showcase animated short,
I've always thought that the Spectre would
make for a really good film. For sure, and I
remember hearing his voice as the Spectre and
totally being blown away that it was even Lou
Diamond Phillips voicing him, because it doesn't
really sound like him, but if he can pull off
that voice for the character of the Spectre
as well, yeah, that's just great casting. Great
answer, Miggy. Our next honorable mention goes
to Cyrus Moore, who said, Hi guys, Cyrus Moore
here, and my answer would be either Shamar
Moore for Cyborg or Josh DeMoll from Batman
the Long Halloween. Those are two actors from
animated movies I would love to see in live
action. Shamar Moore does a great Cyborg voice,
but I do think he's a little too old to play
a Teen Titan personally. I do love Josh DeMoll
as Harvey Dent Two-Face though, because honestly
I thought he nailed the voice performance for
the character. And you know, he's a really good
actor in live action as well. So yeah, I think
that would just be. almost perfection. I don't
know if he's like that great of an actor as
you're claiming he is, but he's certainly solid
enough to pull off the role of Harvey Dent
and Two-Face, I agree. You make him sound like
freaking the next Daniel Day-Lewis or something,
the way you're describing him. Perfection, I
don't know. I don't think I implied that at
all. I didn't imply that. I just said he's a
good actor. No, he could totally pull it off.
I could totally see him in that role. And you're
right, his performance in... Batman the Long
Halloween was pretty impressive. He was almost
unrecognizable voice wise. So great answer,
Cyrus. We want to give a quick shout out to
the other answers. Brandon Estregard, who said
Matthew Gray Goobler should play the Riddler.
That's awesome. The twins, Travis Bailey and
Travis Herndon both gave answers. Travis Herndon
said Keith David should play Tombstone and
Travis Bailey said Hailey Steinfeld should play
Spider-Gwen. Gil Camacho chimed in and said
that Naji Jeter should play Miles Morales. Daniel
Alonso said AJ Locasio should play Gambit.
and Colby Hentges said that Laura Bailey should
play Lois Lane. Those are all great answers.
A lot of them didn't get picked because maybe
the voice actor wasn't a big enough name to,
we think, successfully pull the star power necessary
for that type of character in live action.
Yeah, great answers, guys. But the winner of
this week's no prize is Christopher Minotti,
who said, Hi, guys, Christopher Minotti. I know
a lot of people are probably going to say this,
but I want Jen Snackles as Batman. He does a
great voice for the character in the Tomorrowverse,
and he's a great actor as well, having starred
as Dean Winchester in Supernatural and Soldier
Boy in The Boys. I think he could do a great
job, and yeah, I just think I'd love to see
that. Not only do I think that Jensen Ackles
could pull off a convincing Batman and pull
in the crowd necessary for that type of role,
I'd also like to see him perform against David
Cornswat as Superman. Yeah, I mean, we've been
told that Robert Pattinson is not going to
be the Batman in James Gunn's DC Universe. And
I hear the name Jensen Ackles a lot for who
people want to see play Batman. And I would
not hate that at all. I think the Tomorrowverse
has proven that he has a good grasp of the character.
Yeah, he also played Jason Todd in Batman Under
the Red Hood. But now that he's a little bit
older, yeah, I think he's graduated into the
role of Batman for sure. Absolutely. So great
answer, Christopher Menotti, you win this week's
No Prize. If you, the listener, want a shot
at winning your own No Prize, stay tuned to
later on in this episode when we'll be asking
another Question of the Week. And now that
that's done, onto the news.
Alright this past week we learned that the Paul
Bettany Vision Quest series is still on and
that it now has a release date set in 2026.
Marvel has signed Terry Metalis to serve as
the showrunner for that series. Who has an impressive
resume, he's currently the executive producer
on Star Trek Picard which has gotten great reviews.
Now the last time we saw Vision was in WandaVision
and at the end of the series the vision manifestation
that Wanda created disappeared and the real
Vision, which had been rebuilt by Sword and
he was all white in color, he just kind of
disappeared to go, I don't know, figure shit
out. And this Vision series will allegedly
take place as he kind of comes back into the
fold. Yeah, it's kind of in a way a sequel
perhaps to Wanda Vision. Yeah, we don't know
what's going to happen, but one of the most
celebrated story arcs from the comics was written
by Tom King and is about how Vision tries to
create his own synthzoid family and try to live
the normal suburban lifestyle. And WandaVision
kind of touched on those themes, but it would
be kind of interesting to see the Vision Quest
series kind of continue that. If you guys haven't
read Tom King's run on Vision, I highly suggest
it. Yeah, won a couple of Eisner Awards, I believe.
Yeah, it was really good. Really dark. We've
been waiting for a release date for this show
for a while now, you know, ever since 2021,
when WandaVision first came out in the middle
of the pandemic. So it's nice to kind of get
that closure that the series is indeed happening
and it's happening relatively soon in terms
of movie and TV production time. Yeah, it's
one of the MCU's current loose threads that
people have definitely been interested in seeing
be picked up because he's an Avenger, not one
of the original Avengers, but he plays an important
part on the team. Yeah. The first sequel to
Wandavision that's coming out later on this
year though is Agatha All Along, which is the
true title of that series. None of the House
of Harkness or Covenant of Chaos bullshit is
just Agatha All Along. All those fake titles
were part of the marketing, I guess. Just kind
of showing like, oh, Agatha's being wacky, she's
messing with the titles, it was Agatha All
Along. Which I do think is a great name. I'm
hoping each of the episode titles actually
are like Covenant of Chaos and House of Harkness
and stuff like that. I'm hoping Kevin Feige
uses that show to explain all of the shittiness
that's been going on with MCU lately and all
the stuff that fans haven't been liking. You'd
be like, oh, blame Agatha. It was her all along.
First of all, you don't know what you're talking
about. But secondly, that would be funny. It's
like, oh, you don't like Secret Invasion. Blame
Agatha. Oh, you didn't like Modok. Yeah, it
was Agatha that did that one. Yep. Bow, the
god of dumplings. That was actually Agatha.
So good. Yeah, Agatha All Along premieres this
September, and again we'll wait a couple years
for Vision Quest. Actually, we don't even know
if the series is still called Vision Quest
because according to Variety, the series is
still unnamed. So it'll probably be called
Vision is what I'm guessing, but definitely
looking forward to it. And speaking of Vision,
that brings us to our question of the week.
Who is your favorite robot superhero or villain
from Marvel or DC and why? A lot of great robot
characters out there guys, let's hear your favorite.
Record your answer at dynamicduel.com by clicking
on the red microphone button in the bottom right
hand corner of the screen which will prompt
you to leave us a voicemail. Your message could
be up to 30 seconds long and don't forget to
leave your name in case we include you on the
podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer and
award that person the Dynamic Duel No Prize
that will post to Instagram. Be sure to answer
before June 1st.
But I think that does it for all of the news
for this episode. Now let's move on to the
main event, where we review the Marvel Studios
animated television series X-Men 97.
Okay, X-Men 97 is a Marvel television animated
series created by Bo DeMaio, the continuation
of the 1990s X-Men the animated series, which
ran from 1992 to 1997 and has long been celebrated
by fans as one of the greatest superhero cartoons
ever made. The long awaited questions we all
had, especially us 90s kids, was whether this
new effort could even hope to live up to the
original, which was known for being incredibly
faithful to the source material. and not being
afraid to tackle the more weighty themes of
prejudice and identity. Would this continuation
series carry on that level of quality, or would
it fall short of the lofty standards set by
its predecessor? Well, it brings me so much
unbridled joy to say that not only does X-Men
97 rise to the challenge, it clears the bar,
I think, for animated superhero television.
And here's your spoiler warning right up top,
this is a spoiler review for season 1, so don't
even th- think about continuing to listen to
this episode without watching the show. You
don't want to spoil all the greatness in store
for you, so I would suggest and even demand
that you watch the series before continuing
on. You won't regret it. The show is kind of
like the quintessential X-Men experience, I
think. Oh yeah, I wholeheartedly agree. I loved
the show. I remember watching it as a kid in
the mid-90s, back when I was still a Marvel
fan, and I don't remember... too much about
it. I definitely haven't seen all of the episodes,
but just watching this new season, I felt like
it went way harder than it even needed to because
I don't remember like any of the mature topics
back when I watched it as a kid. And I just
have to say, if it was as good and mature and
relevant back then as it is today, I would
not mind like going back and watching all of
those old seasons with my daughters. Yeah,
the first couple of seasons of the 90s show
were solid. It kind of dropped off a little
bit after that. In the series finale for the
90s show, Professor X gets shot by Henry Guyric
and he goes up into space. So this X-Men 97
series continues right where that one left
off, which was really nice. But yeah, you and
I were six years old when the X-Men animated
series first debuted and it was a huge influence
on us as children, you know, inspiring our
love of superheroes until the show ended when
we were 11. Like I remember turning on X-Men
every Saturday morning on Fox Kids with our
breakfast cereal in our lap. All the kids back
then watched the X-Men television show. And
I remember we used to play X-Men on the playground
with the other boys. The kid with glasses was
always Cyclops. And I liked pretending to be
Wolverine or Bishop or Gambit. And I think you
used to like to be Professor X because you
could just say like, I shut down your mind to
everyone no matter what. No, I was Colossus,
bro. I was classes. Okay. It's good times, though.
I completely tried to put aside all the nostalgia
while reviewing this series, although I will
say there was something magical about hearing
that opening theme once again for like a new
episode. It was just it was so bizarre, very
surreal with that nostalgia kick. Oh, yeah.
I didn't skip a single intro. Like it gave
me the option to skip intro and I was like,
no, I'm enjoying this. I will say that the
nostalgia wasn't that heavy though. I mean,
like the show certainly evokes a sense of nostalgia,
but like not as much as you'd think. Considering
this X-Men 97 series feels pretty modern and
upgraded from the animation styles we had back
in the 90s. It feels like there were two different
animation teams working on the show. You know,
one for the talking stuff and then one for
the crazy awesome action stuff with the dynamic
camera work and the hyper flashy visualizations.
I loved the action style of X-Men 97. This was
a perfect blend of both cerebral writing and
kinetic action. It was perfection. Well, I do
think that the animation could have gone even
further. They were largely constrained by the
animation style of the 90s show, but you could
tell they really cut loose during the action.
Yeah, for sure. But more than the action, I
really loved how the series seemed to be targeted
toward those that enjoyed the original show
30 years ago and are now grown-ass adults, like
us. You know, like not to say that kids couldn't
watch X-Men 97, but I would say that because
it doesn't really hold back in terms of violence
and death and you know, even adult relationships
compared to what you and I were used to seeing
back on the Fox Kids channel, I guess I would
be a little bit hesitant showing this to kids.
Like it's not TVMA or anything, I would place
most of the episodes at probably TV14 and maybe
some of the lighter ones at TVY7. I don't know
if people outside the US know what these ratings
mean, but I think basically anyone younger than
teenagers aren't probably going to get much
out of X-Men 97. It might even be put off by
parts of it. Yeah, again, I don't remember
the old show too much, but this definitely felt
more mature, and I don't know if that's just
because I understand more as an adult or not,
but I definitely do feel like this is the first
time I ever saw Wolverine cut into someone human
and them showing blood as a result. Oh for
sure, I mean, Wolverine was notoriously never
allowed to cut anybody in the 90s cartoon,
you know, he always had to go up against robots
and shit, but never really human beings, because
you just couldn't, it would be too violent.
You know, Stan Lee was famous for wanting to
gear his stories for more mature minds and you
know, John Byrne and Chris Claremont, the famous
X-Men writers, were right there with him. I
think the X-Men and Marvel in general, but
the X-Men in particular, were always a little
more weighty and intense than your standard,
you know, super friends fare. Oh, absolutely.
DC set the bar in terms of targeting children
for their animated fare. I don't think it was
really until Batman the Animated Series and
the X-Men Animated Series that things started
to get a little bit darker, I guess you could
say. Yeah, the writing just got better. Comparing
the writing of the previous cartoons with the
writing of an X-Men episode, both the 90s version
and this show, The X-Men episodes were always
inherently weightier than the other cartoons
because of the heavy themes of prejudice, discrimination,
identity, acceptance. You know, you have civil
rights in there, social justice, trauma. All
those ideas are baked into the concept of the
superpower team that fights for those that
hate and fear them. And that's on top of, you
know, other standard hero themes that you usually
get of power and sacrifice. But the X-Men have
always been more than a power fantasy. They've
always had this moral message. And that's what
makes the X-Men animated series and X-Men 97
so great is that they understand that. They
get that there is a lesson here. Yeah, no,
I absolutely appreciate that. I love stories
with messages. To me, that's what storytelling
is all about. And when it comes to this X-Men
show, like it just feels incredibly relevant
right now. As you know, like every day in the
news we're hearing about Russia and Ukraine
or Israel and Hamas or even, you know, Republican
versus Democrat. Lines are drawn and enemies
are declared. But the truth is that every group
in history has at one point or another been
victimized by another group. And what's great
about the message of the X-Men is that its
heroes inspire us not toward defeating those
we consider our enemies, but toward working
with them to build a tolerant future together.
I think everyone can relate with the X-Men
and that's why they're so incredibly popular
and relevant. Yeah, I mean, DC only wishes,
right? I'm sorry, there's no prejudice and the
DC Universe are better than that. I really
hope that however they tackle these X-Men stories
in the MCU in live action. I hope that the
filmmakers remember that the X-Men are more
than just a power fantasy. And, you know, this
X-Men 97 series gives me 100% faith that Marvel
knows what they're doing with the franchise
down the line. Absolutely. Holy cow. If the
X-Men movie that they make is not as good as
this show, I'm gonna kinda be disappointed because
they set a really, really high bar right out
the gate. Beyond the themes though... The X-Men
97 show, like its predecessor, has some of
the most badass, captivating dialogue I've ever
heard. Like usually the dialogue is the boring
stuff in these superhero cartoons, right? But
like when almost every line is written like
a profound piece of poetry, you yearn for the
boring stuff almost as much as the action.
Dude, it's like Shakespeare level good, right?
Right. Okay, maybe that's an exaggeration.
But it's really, really damn good. I love the
drama of everything. My wife, you know, she
caught snippets of this as I was watching it,
as I was just like riveted by it. And she actually
got into it as well. She was like, this is kind
of like a soap opera. I was like, hell yeah,
it is. Yeah. Like, yeah, I'll admit sometimes
the proceedings can get a little melodramatic,
especially the romantic relationship stuff.
But like as an adult, I don't care. Maybe as
a kid I would have cared, but as an adult I
don't. I'm like, give me that soap opera shit.
I crave the drama. Like when Gene caught Scott
psychically kissing Madeline in his bedroom,
I was like shoveling popcorn in my mouth. Like,
oh damn, I'm gonna be gossiping about this
at tea time tomorrow. This is some juicy shit.
For real, for real. But regarding the dialogue,
I just wanna go over some of my favorite lines
from the show. Kind of like a poetry reading.
I am trying to be better, do not make me let
you down. There is no love without sin, for
love is best measured in what we forgive. Every
moment is a new and shocking evaluation of
all we have ever been. Blood is blood, family
is a choice. Make them mind your weather, sister,
and them weather your mind. You best pray our
children read their textbooks more than their
Bibles, for only history could be conned into
forgiving us. Like who writes this? That's
all fantastic. And the best part is that somehow
it doesn't come across as overwritten either,
which shouldn't work for a seeming adolescent
cartoon, but it does. I'm not gonna lie, as
I was watching this, I was kinda hella jealous
about Marvel's animation.
This was way better. I think the only thing
that could kind of be compared to the X-Men
animated series that I know of, because I've
actually never seen the show, I might be talking
out of my ass right now, but what I've heard
about Young Justice actually comes pretty close
to this stuff. Like it also deals with like
weighty themes and stuff, right? Yeah, yeah,
I've seen Young Justice. It is really good,
especially thematically. But I wouldn't say
that the dialogue is as good because you're
right. It's written in a way that should feel
overwritten, but the performances were just
so good that they totally sold me on every
line that they said. There was not a single
line that I thought was delivered poorly. No,
for sure, and we should talk more about the
actors and characters in our character breakdown.
Starting with Cyclops, aka Scott Summers, played
by Ray Chase, who's not the original voice
actor from the 90s. That was Norm Spencer, who
died in the year 2020. But I think Ray Chase's
voice was spot on, I didn't even know it wasn't
the original voice actor when watching, so
kudos to Ray Chase. I loved seeing Cyclops front
and center with like a whole lot of screen
time as not only the team leader of the X-Men,
but as a character that was vital to the season's
narrative. After so many years out of the spotlight
in the X-Men movies, where he was largely relegated
as a side character, it was really nice to see
Cyclops have his time to shine. Yeah, Cyclops
is my favorite X-Men character. I know everyone
loves Wolverine. I've always been about Cyclops.
And yeah, it was really great to see Marvel
do the character justice in a way that they
have never been able to in the movies. Yeah,
I mean, like a lot of people will say Cyclops
is boring, but I think this season in particular
helped show how these Boy Scout characters
like Cyclops, you know, like Captain America,
and even Superman, they can still be complex
while adhering to a set of simple principles.
Cyclops, you know, he's not a brute like say
Wolverine, but that doesn't make him a pushover.
You know, he's still strong and assertive and
really his strength that is in his ability to
never waver in the face of adversity while
convincing other people to do the same and follow
his lead. Absolutely. Yeah, he is a great example
of leadership and a beacon for the rest of the
X-Men. What's also interesting is that he's
still trying to be fully on board with Xavier's
ideals himself. You know, Cyclops went through
a lot this season, dealing with the weight of
taking over the team, after the loss of his
mentor, trying to lead the X-Men to follow Professor
X's dream, while dealing with his own personal
beliefs, you know, his slight lack of idealism,
and his anger at humanity. You know, tie that
into becoming a father, and the emotional hardships
regarding his infected son, and his cloned
wife. Dude went through the emotional wringer
this season. But it was nice to see him come
out the other end, having connected with his
adult son Cable, and choosing to believe in
Xavier's dream of peaceful coexistence by extending
an olive branch to Bastion in the very last
episode. Yeah, what a fantastic arc. Really,
really solid. He's almost not a static character.
I guess he is, but he definitely still has a
journey that he goes through. Yeah, he kind
of discovers his own place amongst Xavier's
ideals and Magneto's realism, and The comics
explores that so much more, especially Cyclops
within the last decade of X-Men comics. And
it'll be interesting to see how the character
progresses with his arc in subsequent seasons
of this animated show. Let's go ahead and move
on to Jean Grey, who is played by Jennifer
Hale, who is new to the series. She replaces
the original actress, Katherine Disher, who
actually voiced Valerie Cooper in this season.
Now, Jennifer Hale did a good job here. She
did... previously voiced Jean in the Wolverine
and the X-Men cartoon, so she sounds pretty
familiar. Jean played largely a supporting role
to Cyclops Arc, though she certainly went through
a lot on her own, you know, discovering that
she was cloned and that clone bore a child
with her husband. Now, you could base an entire
season on that emotional conflict, but, you
know, as being part of an ensemble, surprisingly,
I still felt the weight of what Jean was going
through to the show's credit. In the end, she
chose to accept her circumstances, you know,
empathizing with Madeline Pryor and really embracing
Cable as her son, who in turn also embraced
Jean as his mother. And that all really came
full circle when she manifested the Phoenix
Force again when her son was about to be killed,
you know, reaching into the deepest part of
herself to protect her family, even though he
wasn't technically her son. Yeah, she went
through a really interesting dilemma. Her and
Scott and Madeline Pryor. It was a weird kind
of love triangle because like she was jealous
of herself in a way because she retained all
of the memories of Madeline Pryor even though
she didn't commit the actions that Madeline
Pryor did like give birth to Nathan. It's a
profound circumstance and I thought they did
a great job exploring it with the characters
of both Jean Grey and Madeline Pryor. Yeah,
you really felt for them. Really good stuff.
Let's go to move on to Magneto. aka Eric Lencher
played by Matthew Watterson who was also new
to the series. He takes over from original
voice actor David Hamblin who unfortunately
also died in 2020. I think Matthew Watterson
was spot on in terms of how he sounded. Like
again, I didn't even know this wasn't the original
actor until I looked it up. But the character
of Magneto was a massive player here taking
over the X-Men on behalf of Professor X, trying
to do things against his standard MO out of
respect for his seemingly late friend. He had
to kind of adopt a new perspective for a time
as mutants were starting to become more accepted
among humanity, only to have that illusion
shattered by Genosha's destruction, proving
to himself that he was right all along, and
having his initial belief system reinforced
that prejudice and otherism will always exist
within humanity. I'm not entirely sure that
he was right. despite the fact that Operation
Zero Tolerance was secretly backed by the UN,
because the UN had no real idea what Bastion
was up to. But the problem, I think, with both
Professor X's and Magneto's viewpoints is that
it's nearly impossible to describe humanity
in general terms. I would say that there were
enough Prime Sentinel volunteers to prove Magneto's
standpoint, and probably enough shock at Bastion's
actions to justify Xavier's hope. Yeah, Magneto
has always been one of the most interesting
Marvel villains. You know, people for a while
were saying Thanos was right in terms of what
he did in the MCU films. I don't know about
that. To me, I think Magneto has always been
a character whose actions are more, I don't
know about justified, but understandable for
sure. Yeah, it's just one of the great thought
experiments that the X-Men poses as a concept.
Everyone has the sense of justice within them.
And I think Magneto really speaks to that as
compared to Professor X, who speaks to a sense
of grace, I would suppose, that's probably
not as natural as the sense of justice. You
really have to fight for that and push for
that. So in a way, you could say Magneto is
more relatable than Professor X, but it would
be nice to be as idealistic as Professor X,
because it's just so much more hopeful. For
sure. Yeah. I remember in the comics in the
90s when Magneto went good for a while and
I think he went under the name Joseph. That
was a clone. Actually, I think that was a clone.
Yeah. But I love how this show adapts storylines
from the X-Men comics and it's always done
a great job at that. Yeah, there was definitely
a time when Magneto was in charge of the X-Men
when Professor X was thought to be dead. He
came around to lead the New Mutants characters
shortly after they were introduced. But let's
go ahead and move on to Bastion. aka Sebastian
Gilberty, played by Theo James. Theo James crushed
it, man. His voice was so unique and terrifying,
yet intelligent. I had no idea it was him. And
like with this performance, I could totally
honestly see him playing the character in live
action if the MCU ever goes with Bastion as
a villain. Dude, I didn't know this was Theo
James. I thought it was recognizable. Motivation-wise,
Sebastian is not terribly complex. He wants
to destroy mutants because he was born. part
sentinel, essentially, which is a change from
the source material where he's the techno-organic
fusion of Nimrod and Mastermold, but I actually
liked his origin more here because it made
more sense having him as a human-sentinel hybrid
than having him just manifest through a magical
portal. Yeah, I agree with that. Having him
grow up different in the same way that mutants
do, but also very much pro-humanities side was...
Very, very interesting. I think they did a
great job adapting that. Yeah, it was a dichotomy
that existed with his own mind because he hated
mutants, but he also struggled with humanity.
You know, he was seen as different by humans.
He had abilities. And he was even considered
for inclusion with the original X-Men, though
his mother denied it. Ultimately, he belonged
with neither humans nor mutants. And by the
end, he was content to destroy them all, given
that he probably already likely felt very alone.
He rejected the X-Men's offer for mercy at the
end, being far too cynical that he and mutants
would ever be accepted, essentially being proven
right in his last moments when the Magneto
protocols were implemented. You know, his last
lines were, humanity would rather die than
have kids like us. So he's just a tragic figure
who was just terribly fascinating. My major
gripe with this show was that they introduced
Bastion way too late. That's true. That's true.
I mean, he was like working behind the scenes.
but you're right, he wasn't introduced until
the latter half of the season. But I also kind
of like that, you know, he kind of came out
of nowhere to be this powerful influence. Yeah,
I mean, the show definitely didn't suffer from
any kind of lack of conflict throughout the
whole season, but I think I would have liked
to have felt Bastion's influence a little bit
earlier. Not just with the Sentinels, but him
specifically. Let's go ahead and move on to
Storm, aka Aurora Monroe, who is played by
Alice in Seelie Smith. Now she is the original
actress from the 90s show. And Alice in Seelie
Smith's take on the character was always more
grandiose and operatic than I ever thought
the character needed to be. And that's an issue
that I had with Storm's characterization even
from the 90s. You know, they really leaned heavily
into the goddess perspective where she was
once worshipped in Africa as a weather controlling
deity. But since her time with the X-Men, I
always read Storm in the comics as a little
bit more approachable, I guess. I just imagine
it would be hard to communicate with Storm from
the cartoon because she's so theatrical. Yeah,
I guess. Although I don't hate that interpretation
of her character, I think I certainly prefer
it more than the movie versions that we've received.
Oh, for sure. And, you know, you could argue
that she wasn't too hard to talk to considering
the relationship she had with Jean Grey, which-
I thought was great. They definitely seemed
like really close friends. Yeah, I think the
perfect storm lies somewhere in between this
cartoon version of Storm and the movie Storm.
There's got to be a balance there, I think.
She was definitely humbled this season. Oh
yeah, I liked Storm's arc here. It was basically
the life-death arc from the comics where she
temporarily lost her powers due to a weapon
created by Forge and she had to re-examine
and redefine herself as a human for a time.
It's a quintessential arc for her character
from the comics and you know it's an easy go-to
for character building. She basically learns
that she doesn't have to fear being a human
or a mutant and she can overcome her fear to
embrace who she is regardless. The scene right
after she lost her power when she's in her
room and she's frightened by a lightning strike
outside was so profound to me. Like that's
right she probably has never encountered weather
that she couldn't control. I don't know if
that scene was from the comics, but I loved
it. I don't know if it's from the comics, but
it was a quiet, profound moment that I really
loved for sure. And her letter to Jean was
so well written, too. Like the X-Men are incredible
writers. Let me just say, like Nightcrawler's
eulogy for Gambit. Oh, dude. Holy shit, man.
I just want a series of Nightcrawler performing
at like living funerals or something like that,
just breaking down all these heroes to their
core. and just explaining what makes them so
special and stuff like that. It was so touching
and yet still managed to incorporate so many
gambling and card playing terms. But I was
like, holy shit, get this guy a Pulitzer in
terms of like obituaries, because that was
a masterpiece. For sure. Yeah. All the X-Men
need to quit their day jobs and become writers,
I guess. See, if it was me, I would have just
been like, you got to know when to hold them.
You got to know when to fold them. Not Nightcrawler.
He's above that. Yeah. Let's go ahead and move
on to Rogue, AKA Anna Marie, played by Lenore
Zan. And she is the original actress here.
And that was very clear. It was like, oh, this
is just, you know, the older version of Rogue.
If anything, I think Lenore Zan's voice sounded
too old to me. I guess it didn't matter because
I did become more accustomed to it as the show
went on. But for a long time there, I was like,
Rogue really needs to stop smoking. Yeah. I
will agree with that. Although to be fair,
maybe she's older than we thought she was, considering
the fact that she did have a relationship with
Magneto, who also was like way too old to be
in the show if he was a Holocaust survivor.
Yeah, well you would think that he was born
in the mid-30s and this show takes place in
the year 1997, so he's got to be like mid-60s
here. And I'm guessing that when he and Rogue
had their thing, she must have been really young.
18, 19, late teens, maybe early 20s. That all
being said, Rogue had so much to do in this
season. You know, in the comics, like we said
earlier, Magneto had a clone named Joseph and
she had a fling with him for a time in the
books. I like how they brought elements of that
here, where she had the secret past with Magneto
and that instantly brought attention to her
relationship with Gambit, whom she loves, but
unlike Magneto, she can never touch. It just
drips with drama. And I'm here for it. especially
as she weighed her options in ruling alongside
Magneto. In her heart, she longed to make a
difference in that global way. But also in her
heart, she truly loved Gambit more. And in
the end, she did choose to be with Gambit right
before his tragic death, which, holy shit,
man, that was heartbreaking. I did not see that
coming. That really pumped up the stakes for
this series. I was like, holy cow, if Gambit
could die, is anyone safe? Yeah, anybody could
die. Yeah. Friggin' Leech! I know. How could
you kill Leech, man? He's such an innocent
character. And that's just part of the whole
tragedy of the attack on Genosha. Yeah, yeah,
that was super tragic. From that moment, Rogue's
arc was about revenge, which reaches its climax,
I think, when she seemingly kills Bolliver Trask,
which was shocking, but I wouldn't say it's
necessarily out of character for Rogue, considering
she used to be a villain. and she was acting
out of tremendous grief, having lost two men
she loved. And also, you know, Bolivar Trask
was about to commit suicide anyway. And also
he didn't really die because he was a prime
sentinel. But it was a fascinating character
moment in the moment. I that felt very out
of character to me. And I for a time was wondering
if she was being manipulated by Sinister or
by Bastion, but I guess not. I mean, it was
interesting to also get the reactions of the
X-Men. You had Nightcrawler who was completely
shocked and totally against what Rogue had
just done. And then you have someone like Wolverine
who was like, she just did what we were all
wanting to do, you know? Kind of ran the gamut
in terms of approval. But yeah, if you read
the comics, I think you'd find that it wasn't
necessarily too out of character for Rogue.
Again, she did used to be a villain. She was
raised by Mystique. She's no Boy Scout. We'll
say that. Okay. Let's go ahead and move on to
Wolverine, aka Logan, who was played by Cal
Dodd. the one and only Cal Dodd. He will always
be the voice in my head when I think of Wolverine.
Although he didn't get a whole lot to do here.
Outside of some awesome action scenes, he really
only served to add some additional drama to
the Gene and Scott situation. But you know
what? I liked that he kind of took a backseat
to let the other X-Men shine. Yeah, I think
fans of the character got what they wanted from
the character. It blew my mind that they incorporated
the fatal attraction story arc from the comics.
where Magneto ripped the adamantium from Wolverine's
bones. Yeah. I did not see that coming. In the
comics in the aftermath of that event, Wolverine
underwent this sort of physical trauma that
left him more feral looking. And of course,
you know, he had the bone claws and stuff like
that. I wonder if they're going to go with
that look for next season. I could see them
going with the bone claws. I'm not 100% sure
about the whole feral look because he looked
a lot like a shaved beast to me during that
era of the X-Men. Yeah. I didn't love it. Yeah,
it was an ass look. Let's be honest. It's like
Superman with long hair. It just is not right.
Let's go ahead and move on to Jubilee, aka
Jubilation Lee, who was played by Holly Chow,
who was a new actress taking over from Alice
in Court, who voiced the character in the 90s
series. Though Alice in Court did play a role
here. She played Epsisa, who is the future version
of Jubilee. I thought it was a spot on performance
by Holly Chow. I think she sounded just like
Alice in Court Jubilee's arc largely dealt
with her relationship with Sunspot. You know,
she spent most of the time trying to convince
him to accept his mutant self and teach him
what it means to be an X-Man. Beyond that,
she did get a nice half episode to herself in
Mojoverse, where she learned that life can't
be all fun and games, which was a good moment
of growth for her, especially on her 18th birthday.
I thought it was really cool how she saw like
the full potential of her power through her
future self. I think that definitely helped
in the end fight. And yeah, for a character
that's always seemed kind of weak with just,
you know, shooting fireworks this season definitely
showed how powerful a character like her can
be. I mean, we've all been shot with a Roman
candle, right? We've all had a firework go off
in our hands. Like Jubilee is not that powerful.
But when she does shit like that spiraling,
whirling firework that cut through the sentinel
and everything like that, that was pretty bad
ass. That was cool. She definitely got a power
upgrade. Yeah. Let's move on to Beast aka Hank
McCoy who is played by George Buzza who is
the one and only George Buzza. He's so good
in this role. He is the voice that I always
hear when I think of the Beast character. He
was a minor character too this season but like
everyone else he got his own moments in the
spotlight doing science stuff like determining
which gene was real or developing the headband
that stopped the Prime Sentinels. Beast is
a great character. Moving on to Gambit aka Remy
LeBeau. He was played by AJ Locascio, who is
new in the role, taking over from Chris Potter,
who actually did the voice of Cable. And Chris
Potter sounded exactly like Josh Brolin in the
role of Cable. So I thought that was pretty
interesting. Yeah. AJ Locascio was a great replacement.
I think he sounded a lot like the version of
the character in the 90s show. He also didn't
have a lot to do this season. But one could
also say that he had the biggest moment of the
season when he died saving Genosha. Yeah, sacrificing
himself. to destroy that giant three-headed
master mold was so unbelievably epic and touching.
I don't know what else to say about it other
than one for me and one for my homie. I didn't
actually spill something on the ground because
I don't want to ruin my floor. Well, that's
just incredibly insincere then. I think you
should actually spill something on your floor.
It's all right. It does look like Gambit's gonna
come back next season as Apocalypse's horseman
of death, according to the mid-credits scene.
that we had. What? Which is- There was a mid-credits
scene? Yeah. Fuck! You didn't see it? No. Yeah,
there was a mid-credits scene with Apocalypse
and he's going through the ruins of Genosha
and he is talking about how there was so much
death and he like emphasizes death as he's holding
one of Gambit's playing cards. Oh, dude. I
wish I would have seen that. I need to go back
and watch that because that just sounds awesome.
Yeah, it's great because Gambit actually was
the horseman of death in the comics for a time.
And you know, he's too good of a character to
leave dead. So absolutely. I'm super happy
he's coming back. Nice. Well done, Marvel. Holy
shit. Let's go to move on to Morph, AKA Kevin
Sidney, played by J.P. Karliak, who is new in
the role. He was previously voiced by Robin
Rubin in the 90s, who actually does the voice
of President Robert Kelly in the show. Morph
was an entirely different character this season
from the 90s, but I like how they based his
new look off of the Exiles comics version, which
was this more neutral looking figure. In the
original 90s show, Morph was based off of the
character of Changeling, but Morph was never
really in the mainstream Marvel universe until
the Exiles comic books. They made him non-binary
in the show, which totally I think makes sense
for Morph. He actually stood out more to me
in X-Men 97 than he ever did in the 90s show,
I think. He didn't have too much to do outside
of his friendship with Wolverine, but they have
a great friendship and that goes back to the
90s show. And I like how they gave a great moment
of closure with Morph and Mr. Sinister. I loved
seeing all of the different transformations
that Morph had throughout this season, not
only as different X-Men like Magic, but also
like the Hulk. That was wild. That was crazy.
Yeah, he was kind of like a cameo machine. He
played Archangel, Blob, Lady Deathstrike, Colossus,
Psylocke. Sabertooth, Quicksilver, Juggernaut,
like you said, the Hulk, Sauron. Oh, Mr. Fantastic
was the other one. That was outside of the X-Men.
It was awesome. It was really cool. For some
reason, I always forgot that he was able to
do that. So sometimes I would just randomly
see a character and be like, oh, where did they
come from? Only to realize it was more, it
was fun to watch. Let's go to move on to the
final character to discuss, of course, Professor
X, aka Charles Xavier, played by Ross from John
Kolikos who was another voice actor that died
in 2020. Dude, 2020 was a horrible year! Well,
for many reasons, but yeah, especially for
the X-Men voice actors. Ross Marquand has now,
I think, cemented himself as the greatest impressionist
of all time because holy shit, I didn't even
realize that was him. I thought it was the
original voice actor. Not only can Ross mimic
voices to near perfection, but he also retains
all the nuance and the depth of the voice through
his acting. It's incredible. Honestly, is this
the same guy who replaced Hugo weaving as Red
Skull? Yes, in Avengers Endgame. Damn crazy.
He's like a real life morph. Yeah, he is. He
probably could have done more of the voice,
too. But Professor X shows up later in the season,
abandoning his life in space to be with his
X-Men when they need him the most. I thought
it was nice that he was gone for a time because
it let the team grow in an organic way, especially
with their former sworn enemy, Magneto as the
new leader. But when he came back, I thought
it was just, it was epic. I often find Professor
X a little bit too idealistic for his own good,
but I will say that he is always inspiring.
You need someone like that, though. Yeah. I've
always loved the dichotomy between Professor
X and Magneto. You know, they're often compared
to Martin Luther King and Malcolm X, but I
also love that they're like best friends. Like
despite their ideological differences, Charles
will always fight for Magneto. They're just
iconic in that way. They're one of literature's
great characters, honestly. Yeah, I will not
disagree with that. What was nice this season
was that we finally got to see Professor X cut
loose with his powers. Like we did hear when
he took over Magneto's mind, that moment where
they're like clashing against each other face
to face, two Titans going head to head. I thought
that was just awesome. But that covers all
the main characters. So let's go ahead and discuss.
the episode highlights.
Our fantasies collide and heroes clash. One
Podcast Network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
DynaMic Podcast Network presents Console Combat,
where video game legends brawl every Monday.
Dynamic Duel, where comic books clash. Smash
every Tuesday, Max Destruction, where TV and
action heroes battle every Wednesday, and Sendro
World, where anime champions clash every Thursday.
Join us as we speculate on the matches and,
armed with the power of mathematical simulations,
discover who will emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
Episode 1 was called To Me, My X-Men. A year
after Professor X's assumed death, the X-Men
continue fighting for his dream of peaceful
mutant and human coexistence. Led by Cyclops,
the team save Sunspot from the Friends of Humanity
anti-mutant group who have acquired sentinel
technology. The team probes Henry Geirich's
mind to learn the location of Bolivar Trask,
the creator of the Sentinels. The X-Men travel
there and destroy all the Sentinels and Mastermold
and remit Trask into UN custody. Cyclops and
Jean Grey announce they're leaving the team
due to Jean's pregnancy, but they're interrupted
by Magneto, who reveals that Professor X left
him the Xavier Institute in his will. Uh, we
haven't talked about Roberto da Costa, but
damn he was annoying. I think we've talked a
few times when doing reviews about characters
who we know are heroes who spend a majority
of their runtime not wanting to be heroes.
That was definitely the case with Sunspot. It
was nice in the end to see him come into his
own in his battle against Bastion, but it took
a hell of a long time for him to get there.
Yeah, to me, he was really just there as someone
for the character of Jubilee to play off of.
I don't know if it needed to be Robert da Costa.
I think I would rather see him appear along
with the other new mutants at some point. Yeah,
I really didn't care for any time he was on
screen. I'll say, though, that his scene with
Jubilee dancing in the club was pretty surreal.
There were a few dance scenes within the course
of this show that went on for a while. They
were stylistic, but it felt very 90s, you know.
That being said, I always like when mutants
use their abilities outside of fighting bad
guys and, you know, letting off sparks while
dancing at a nightclub seems like a great use
of power for sure. Yeah, Jubilee could change
her name to Raver and that'd be okay. Dude,
the action scene at the end of this episode
when they're going up against the sentinels,
everything from when the blackbird gets destroyed
and they're all finding ways to land safely
on the ground, including Cyclops who uses his
optic blasts to cushion his landing and everything
like that. I squealed. I was so happy. It was
everything I've ever wanted to see, ever. I
was so pumped. It was a great scene. The only
thing that would have made it better is if it
was in live action. I still get the whole Cyclops
using his power to land safely. He was falling
really fast. Well, if you were holding a fire
hose and you were falling from the sky and you
shot the fire hose at the ground, would it
not slow your descent? Not enough to not die.
I still have to fight against gravity. Except
he can spread out his force blasts to cover
a wider area and it's more powerful than a
fire hose. So yeah, it would totally work. I
mean, I know that ties into his origin. when
his optic blasts first formed when he was falling
out of a plane and he used it to save him and
his brother Havoc from dying when they hit the
ground. So I appreciated that, but still seeing
it like in motion, I was like, I don't know.
It works. It works. It was cool. He had that
superhero landing. Then it was like to me, my
X-Men. And right after that was Storm just
like walking across the desert, just like turning
all the sand to glass. That was awesome, too.
It was incredible, the whole scene and like
how Beast took over one of the Sentinels. That
wouldn't be the last time that he does it this
season, but it was such a great way for the
character to fight the Sentinels, you know?
Yeah, absolutely. At this point in their superhero
careers, Sentinels are just like paper people,
and it's great to see superheroes just kick
ass in that way. Episode 2 is called Mutant
Liberation Begins. Magneto begins saving humans
as a way to prove to the X-Men that his intentions
are genuine. However, he is arrested by the
UN to face trial for his past crimes. Magneto
surrenders, however the trial is ambushed by
Friends of Humanity protesters led by Executioner
who tries to shoot Magneto with a power dampening
blast. Storm gets in the way of the blast and
gets depowered. Magneto peacefully stops the
assault by carrying Executioner and the UN Special
Committee into low orbit to help show his new
perspective. Magneto is pardoned and the mutant
populated island of Genosha is considered for
admission to the UN. Meanwhile, Jean Grey gives
birth to Nathan Summers. Storm leaves the team
and the group is surprised by a visit by another
Jean Grey. Great episode. My favorite moment
here was when Jean Grey was at the mansion and
she tells Wolverine he's here. And he's like,
who? Apocalypse? And sheaths his claws, you
know, she's like, the baby. He's like, oh no.
It's like a sitcom or something. Yeah. You'd
think in all of his years that Wolverine would
have encountered a situation like that before.
Justin can drive on sidewalks and stuff like
that. It was just comedy gold. Let's go ahead
and move on to episode number three, which
was called Fire Made Flesh. Running experiments,
Beast deduces that the new visitor is the real
Jean Grey, and the woman who just gave birth
to Nathan is a clone. To strut over the news,
Jean's clone is visited by Mr. Sinister, who
reveals himself as her creator, manipulating
her mind and turning her into the Goblin Queen.
She makes the X-Men experience frightening
telepathic hallucinations based on their worst
fears before leaving the mansion to give her
son to Mr. Sinister. Having been previously
manipulated by Sinister, Morph leads the team
to the Villain's lab where Sinister infects
Baby Nathan with a modified techno-organic
virus in an effort to make the child invincible.
The X-Men face off against the Goblin Queen,
including Jean Grey who convinces her clone
to save the baby. Though Mr. Sinister escapes.
Cyclops begrudgingly lets Bishop take the child
into the future to save his life from the techno-organic
virus, and the gene clone, now going by Madeline
Pryor, leaves the mansion for Genosha. Meanwhile,
Forge meets Storm at a bar. This was a fascinating
episode, how they merged the Inferno story
with the Mother Iscani story, substituting Bishop
for Mother Iscani. It was just a great streamline
of multiple story arcs in a way that completely
made sense. Oh yeah, I loved this episode.
It was one of my favorites. And I think I definitely
appreciated it more as an adult than I would
have watching it as a kid. As a father, I totally
related with Cyclops. Just, you know, that'd
be really hard to give up your kid to go to
a place where you don't even know where they're
going. And I loved all of the metal and prior
stuff, too. The battle scenes here with her
purple and green flaming depictions of power
was just really well animated. For sure. Yeah,
I agree how child endangerment stuff hits a
little bit different when once you become a
parent, I just felt so bad for that baby. But,
you know, we know he's capable now, so we knew
that he was in good hands anyway. The Goblin
Queen's visions that she induced in the X-Men
were borderline TVMA. Like I was like, what
the fuck? I thought this was a kids show. Yeah,
you know, you had Gambit's vision of rogue and
Magneto, like mostly nude fusing together.
That was horrifying when Jubilee and Sunspot
were watching TV. and the girl crawls out from
the TV and they slice her in half and like you
see her brain and shit. I was like, what is
happening here? Yeah, this was the moment when
I was like, oh damn, this is not my childhood
X-Men cartoon. And I'm here for it. Episode
4 was called Motendo. That was the first part
of the episode. The second part of the episode
was called Life Death Part 1. In the first
part, Jubilee wants to go to the arcade on her
18th birthday, but Magneto refuses. Sulk-ing
in her room with Sunspot, the two get sucked
into a video game console called Montendo,
which takes them to Mojo World, where Mojo forces
Jubilee and Sunspot to play out her previous
adventures with the X-Men in front of the spineless
ones, providing Mojo with ratings to feed off
of. The pair is saved repeatedly by a mysterious
hacker who turns out to be Epsisa, an older
digital version of Jubilee created by Mojo for
the video game's initial testing. Epsisa convinces
Jubilee that life is a grander adventure than
gaming. the two team up to take down Mojo.
Returning to the real world, Jubilee kisses
Sunspot. Meanwhile, Forge takes Storm to his
ranch and tests his power restoring machine
on her. It seemingly fails, and Forge reveals
to Storm that he was behind the mutant power
dampening tech that stole her mutant abilities.
Storm leaves in anger, but is brought back by
a demon known as the Adversary, which poisons
Forge. So this was probably my least favorite
episode. As much as I appreciated the callbacks
to the old X-Men arcade game, I did think Mojo
was pretty funny. I didn't really care for
the whole Forge storm adversary thing though.
I wasn't expecting to see the adversary here,
but I was totally blown away when I saw that
he made an appearance because he's always been
Forge's greatest. adversary, as it were. You
know, the adversary was the demon that Forge
summoned during his time in the military when
he thought he was going to die. He summoned
the demon to attack the enemy and the demon
actually ended up killing everybody and had
been haunting him ever since. I don't know if
you remember Forge's backstory in the duel
episode against Mr. Terrific, but Forge was
actually somewhat of a studied shaman before
he developed his mutant abilities which steered
him in the direction of science. And so, you
know, he had that kind of conflict at an early
age. But Magic and science has always been
an interesting mix for the character of Forge.
One thing I noticed about the voice actor for
Forge, the sound quality of his voice was not
as good as the other characters. So much so
that it was noticeable and distracting to me.
Yeah, it was a little bit more condensed, I
think. And also, it didn't really sound like
Forge to me, or would I imagine Forge to sound
like this voice actor sounded a little bit older
than I would think his voice sounded like.
That said, I am glad we got to see Forge, because
he is an interesting character. I love Forge,
yeah. Episode 5 is called Remember It. In it,
the UN formally admits the mutant nation of
Genosha, which Rogue, Gambit, and Magneto visit.
There, Magneto is asked by the Council to lead
the country as its Chancellor, and he agrees
on the condition that Rogue rules alongside
him. Meanwhile, Cyclops has an angry outburst
during a television interview after being asked
about his son, and telepathically confides in
Madeline Pryor, which Jean Grey finds out about
escalating tensions between her and Cyclops.
Rogue admits to Gambit her past with Magneto,
that his electromagnetic manipulation allows
her to touch him, and that she is considering
his offer. Dancing with Magneto at a celebration
gala, Rogue ultimately decides that she loves
Gambit too much to be with Magneto. Suddenly,
Cable appears and attempts to warn Genosha's
citizens of an impending attack by a wild mastermold
before being pulled away through time. Everything
turns to chaos as Magneto, Rogue, and Gambit
try to save as many people as they can. Enraged
at the apparent death of Magneto, Rogue attempts
to take Master Mold head on. Gambit prevents
her and saves her life. In the end, he is killed
when the Sentinel impales him, but he detonates
it in his last act, saving the remaining survivors.
Rogue weeps as she holds his body.
So the episodes from this season were released
week by week, correct? Yeah, I'm so glad I
did not watch the show that way because I would
have been devastated all week if I couldn't
immediately watch the next episode. I would
have been depressed. I would have been like,
don't talk to me, anybody. I'm just I'm destroyed.
If this episode doesn't win an Emmy, I would
actually be very surprised because the writing,
the drama, I thought was immensely palpable
throughout this whole episode. It deserves every
award it's going to get. Did you notice that
the Watcher was in the sky above Genosha right
before everything went down? No, I did not
see that. That was pointed out to me by people
on the Discord. That was really cool because
it insinuates, if you've seen the What If animated
television show, that Genosha's destruction
was an absolute point in history, which is something
that Beasts references in a later episode.
Basically something that couldn't be prevented.
Yeah, because Cable tried to prevent it 200
times. Yeah. I like the cameos that were in
this episode of all the mutants that were at
Genosha. You had Sebastian Shaw, you had the
White Queen, multiple man was there, Dazzler,
Leech, Pixie, Glob Herman. It was great to see
all those Easter eggs basically. But let's
go ahead and move on to episode 6, which is
called Life Death Part 2. Shiar Empress LeLondra
announces to her people her engagement to Professor
X, who was healed from his wounds with alien
technology. Meanwhile, Storm cares for Forge's
poisoned wound. when the adversary attacks
her. Forge uses shaman magic to expel the demon
and Storm confesses her love for him. Back
in space, Lelandra's sister Deathbird sees Professor
X as an unworthy consort due to his Terran
heritage and invokes the Rite of Amdasha, which
challenges him to erase all of his Earthbound
memories. Storm takes Forge to a cave to find
a cactus to heal his poison when she is confronted
by the adversary once again. Admitting that
it was more than the executioner's neutralizer
holding her powers back, but her fear of living
is a mutant once more, Storm abandons her fear,
restoring her mutant powers, and she saves Forge.
Back in space, Professor X refuses to give
up his memories of the X-Men and tries to teach
the Shi'ar about coexistence when he receives
a psychic vision of the attack on Genosha and
decides to return to Earth. Meanwhile, Mr.
Sinister tells Bolliver Trask that the attack
on Genosha was just the beginning. This one
was actually my least favorite episode, not
because it was bad, but it was strange going
through these plot detours after the devastating
previous episode. I wanted more answers about
what happened at Genosha. So I guess just sequencing
it after episode five fell off to me. Well,
I think they had to tie up some loose ends about
what was going on with these characters while
what happened at Genosha happened, because you
see Storm's reaction to what happened, you
see Professor X's reaction. And in a way, it
kind of made you relive the horror of what
you saw in the previous episode. I didn't mind
this episode. It was kind of a nice break from
the intensity that was the attack on Genosha,
I thought. Plus, it was just really interesting
to see that Professor X was still alive. I didn't
know that he was going to be in this show.
It was cool to see the Imperial Guard. It's
always cool to see the Shi'ar, I think. Eh,
they're just Legion knockoffs. I was not impressed.
Legion is superheroes, right? Not Legion, Professor
X's son. Yeah, no, you know what I meant. Episode
7 was called Bright Eyes. The X-Men hold a
funeral for Gambit, but Rogue skips it as she
angrily seeks out Bolivar Trask. She comes
into contact with Captain America, who helps
her find Henry Gyric in Mexico, but claims
he can't help her bring him in without causing
an international crisis. Rogue absorbs Henry
Gyric's memories to find Trask, but only gets
a glimpse, and Gyric is murdered later that
night. The X-Men travel to Genosha to help search
for survivors. and they find the White Queen
who is saved by her diamond skin secondary mutation.
The team gets a message from Bolliver Trask
who tells them to go to Madripoor. They pick
up Rogue on the way and discover a suicidal
Trask hiding at the UN secret Operation Zero
tolerance division. Rogue drops Trask off a
building in revenge for the Sentinels killing
Gambit and thousands on Genosha, but he comes
back as a Prime Sentinel. The team is rescued
by Cable who uses an EMP grenade and explains
that Mr. Sinister was behind the Genosha attack
along with a greater threat which is revealed
to be Bastion who has captured Magneto. My big
takeaway from here was that the Prime Sentinels
are far more scary in motion than they ever
were in the comic books. The way they were
presented in this show was almost like techno
zombies, which I absolutely love. In the comics,
Prime Sentinels just felt more like human sized
Mark 2 Sentinels, you know? Yeah, it's always
scary when a bad guy could be anybody. You know,
they did that with agents in The Matrix. They
have that with OMAX in DC Comics. And I remember
you mentioning Prime Sentinels in the Bastion
backstory from last week's episode. It was interesting
to actually see them. This show successfully
pulled off what Secret Invasion could not, which
was a feeling of tension and paranoia. Absolutely.
Especially in like a later episode when you
had people like the news reporter lady all
of a sudden become a Prime Sentinel. Yeah. And
Sunspot's Butler and stuff like that. It was
like, holy shit, who isn't a prime sentinel?
All these people are going to kill the X-Men.
And they were really cutting into them and there
were humans. That was wild to me. Yeah. What
did you think of the Captain America cameo?
I thought it was good. I loved Rogue's reaction
to Captain America refusing to take official
action with her in Mexico. She just fucking
yeeted his shield and it was like, fuck you.
And then peaced out. I think Captain America
deserved it. I think. in general, Marvel's other
heroes don't do enough to stand beside their
fellow heroes in the X-Men. That was something
the Avengers kind of came to terms with in
the comics when they formed the Avengers Unity
Division, which was a team of both Avengers
and X-Men. I'm just really hoping that Captain
America had like an apple tag on that shield.
He's gonna have to go find it. That's his lesson.
Again, characters like the Avengers should
be doing a whole lot more to stand alongside
the X-Men. Although, you know, this season
planted the seeds for a second season to incorporate
Avengers vs X-Men if they decide to go the
onslaught route for season 2. Oh that'd be sweet!
That'd be really cool. That'd be sick, yeah.
Episode 8 is called Tolerance is Extinction,
Part 1. Cable explains to the X-Men that Bastion's
Prime Sentinel program upgrades and evolves
humanity toward a future where mutants are
enslaved in a seeming utopia. Going off of one
of Cable's leads from the future, Cyclops and
Jean Grey visit Bastion's where they learn that
the time traveling sentinel Nimrod infected
Bastion's father with nanotech that resulted
in his wife giving birth to a son with the
powers of technopathy. After Valerie Cooper
and the rest of Operation Zero Tolerance express
concern with the Genosha massacre, Bastion explains
to them that the attack was only to buy time
and whittle the mutant population as he prepares
to activate the prime sentinels. Human volunteers
outfitted with Mr. Sinister's modified techno-organic
virus. They are activated around the world
and attack the X-Men and all mutants, burning
down the Xavier Institute. Valerie Cooper releases
Magneto from Beshyn's imprisonment, admitting
that Magneto was right. He flies to the Magnetic
North Pole where he causes a worldwide electrical
blackout that shuts down the Prime Sentinels.
Professor X returns to Earth and telepathically
summons the X-Men. This was a fantastic episode,
a great first act to the three part finale.
I thought it was really interesting how Operation
Zero Tolerance included members such as Dr.
Doom and Baron Zemo. Those were some sweet
ass cameos for sure. Yeah, that was interesting.
That I feel like even more so than like the
cameos from Captain America and stuff really
opened up the world that this X-Men cartoon
takes place in. I mean, I know they had like
a cameo with Spider-Man back in the 90s, but
it was cool to see all these different characters
pop up. I liked the part with Jubilee when
she was going shopping with Sunspot and she
got that like black wetsuit. Really that was
just a way to get her into her more modern look
from the comics because up until that point
she was still wearing her denim shorts and her
pink t-shirt. Yeah, they all went through look
changes in these last three episodes. Did they
go back to their 80s costumes? Most of them?
Yeah, they went back to the costumes they wore
when they had Muir Island as a base because
the X-Mansion was destroyed. So they had to
go to Muir Island off the coast of Scotland,
and they put on the costumes that they had stored
there. I like those costumes. Yeah, they're
great. Marvel Girls, not so much. I don't like
the Marvel Girl outfit. I prefer Jean Grey's,
actually I prefer the Phoenix outfit for Jean
Grey. Yeah, that's true. My favorite line from
this episode was when the Prime Sentinels invaded
the Axe Mansion and were about to kill Rogue
as she was comatose on the bed, and Wolverine
barges in, and the Prime Sentinel lady is like,
And he's like, lady, I got six reasons why.
And then all of a sudden Nightcrawler showed
up and he's like, no, my friend, nine. It was
like a great pun, great action scene, which
was followed almost immediately by the let's
show them why you don't mess with the summers
part where Cyclops blasts through the mountain
while Gene drives and Cable shoots the sentinels.
Yeah, so good. So good. Good writing. Yeah,
it's probably my favorite episode, I think.
Episode nine is called Tolerance's Extinction
Part Two. In it, the X-Men regroup in the destroyed
X-Mansion where they decide to split into two
teams, Blue Team and Gold Team, to deal with
both Bastion and Magneto. Beast and Forge develop
a headband to block Bastion's technopathy,
while Magneto restores his old Asteroid M base.
Magneto confronts the X-Men, telling them to
join him, which Rogue and Sunspot do. On their
old Muir Island base, the X-Men don their old
costumes and set upon their missions, Gold Team
going to Bastion's headquarters on the Galapagos
Islands, and Blue Team going into space. The
Gold Team fights Bastion-controlled Sentinels
as Mr. Sinister takes over Cable's mind, forcing
him to attack Jean Grey. She psychically reaches
out to Cyclops on Asteroid M, who prevents Professor
X from taking over Magneto's mind to restore
Earth's power. Wolverine impales Magneto, who
subsequently rips the adamantium from Wolverine's
body. There was a lot of buildup in this episode
until the big action-packed third act, but
I thought it was worth it. Gene fighting Mr.
Sinister was epic. And I think the show had
a lot of balls to go there with the Wolverine
versus Magneto stuff, where he got the adamantium
ripped out. I did not think that they would
go there. I actually kind of saw it coming.
Like right when he impaled Magneto, I was like,
OK, obviously Magneto is not going to die here.
What's going to happen next? The obvious. It
was quite the image, though, that the episode
finished on. Yeah, for sure. Episode 10 was
called Tolerance is Extinction Part 3. In it,
Professor X controls Magneto's mind, forcing
him to restore Earth's power and its magnetic
field. This reactivates the Prime Sentinels,
but Jean Grey, seeing Cable about to be killed
by Bastion, reaches out to the Phoenix Force,
who temporarily gives her the power to free
Cable. She places the headband that blocks Bastion's
connection to the Prime Sentinels on his head,
disabling the Prime Sentinels, and she removes
Mr. Sinister's stolen mutant powers, reverting
him to his centuries-old self. Bastion rips
off Cable's arm and technoforms it into a pair
of wings to fly to Asteroid M and try to crash
it down to Earth. In space, Rogue and Sunspot
intercept Bastion where they fight him in the
blue area of the moon, though Bastion fights
his way into the asteroid. Blue Team pilots
a sentinel robot to join the fight in space,
and the X-Men overpower Bastion, preventing
him from destroying the asteroid's gravity
core. However, Earth's leaders activate the
Magneto protocols to blast the asteroid out
of the sky and the missiles hit the gravity
core, creating a singularity that swallows
Bastion. Cyclops and Jean Grey telepathically
say goodbye to Cable as they try and stop asteroid
M from crashing into Earth, but Professor X
is able to restore Magneto's mind from his
earlier psychic assault in enough time for Magneto
to reverse the asteroid's fall and send it
back into space. At that moment, however, The
asteroid and the X-Men disappear through a
time portal that sends Cyclops and Jean Grey
into the future to raise their son Cable, and
the rest to ancient Egypt where they meet Apocalypse.
Bishop and Forge resolve to rescue the team.
In a mid-credit scene, present-day Apocalypse
finds one of Gambit's playing cards in the
ruins of Genosha. At the start of this episode
it seemed like they were totally setting up
onslaught, but by the end of the episode it
seems like they're definitely setting up Age
of Apocalypse. But either way, yeah, it's clear
that Gambit's coming back as the horseman of
death. Yeah, that's really cool. I love the
climax between the X-Men and Bastion. Again,
such a great message in how Cyclops decided
not to destroy his enemy, but to reason with
him. I think they did a terrific job with Bastion,
and you can almost see Cyclops and Bastion
almost having their own kind of Xavier Magneto
relationship. The characters were both just
so well done. Some of the characters were friggin'
fighting in space? Yeah, that was weird. Well,
I mean, you do have to remember that the bluer
area of the moon does have oxygen. That's where
the inhumans used to live. But like, Sunspot
taking Jubilee down to Earth from Asteroid
M didn't make any sense to me. He would have
brought back a corpse. Yeah, I did like the
fight against Bastion though. Rogue, Cyclops,
Sunspot, Jubilee, they all got their time to
shine. Beasts coming in and piloting the Sentinel
stomping on Bastion, I thought that took the
prize. I thought that was really great. I don't
know if I loved the time portal jump at the
end. You always kind of want to give the team
a little bit of breathing room between their
big adventures. It would have been nice to get
some kind of closure with the team celebrating
their win. But when it comes to the X-Men, they
rarely ever get a chance to breathe here. It's
being pulled into one adventure after the other.
And that was always the nature of the 90s X-Men
cartoon. Those seasons rarely ended with closure.
They were always setting up the cliffhanger
for the next season. Yeah, honestly, when that
time jump happened, I thought they were setting
up for something to tie in with the Deadpool
movie in some way. And maybe like that's how
they were going to get into the MCU universe.
Like it was this group of X-Men specifically
that were going to be our MCU X-Men. They were
just going to make the jump from animation
to live action. Obviously interesting. Didn't
play out that way. But right when that happened,
that's what I suspected. That would have been
cool. I was wondering who was behind the time
jump. My first thought was that it was Kang
because he played a role in ancient Egypt as
Ramitat and also maybe it was a mortis or something
like that. It could have even been someone
like Fitzroy who is Bishop's enemy and he's
able to drain life forces from people to create
time portals. I also wonder if it might have
had something to do with Bastion getting pulled
into the Singularity since he also had Cable's
arm with him which had the time sliding technology.
There's a lot of options here, I guess. Do you
hope Bastion comes back some way in the next
season? I don't think so. I think he was done
really well here. And I'd hate for them to
revisit that and make it feel repetitive and
not give another villain a time to shine. I
am really looking forward to Apocalypse. I think
that'll be cool to me. Apocalypse is sort of
like Super Bastion, just in terms of like his
techno morphing and stuff like that. So I think
it'll be exciting. But that does it for the
series overall. I. find little to no flaws
with this entire season. To me, it was the quintessential
X-Men experience. I thought the season perfectly
captured the complex themes and the characters
of the comic book series in a way that no other
project has. I'll be surprised if any forthcoming
X-Men movie comes close to touching this season.
I know that the show was certainly better than
what came previously with the Fox X-Men universe.
It just captured everything that I love about
the X-Men and was thought-provoking and action-packed
and everything good. I'm giving it five out
of five stars, a fresh rating on Rotten Tomatoes.
Yeah, honestly, I feel like by episode three,
I felt like this was going to be a five star
show because right off the bat, it was just
so phenomenally well made in terms of the visuals,
in terms of the writing, in terms of everything.
I was just insanely jealous, as I mentioned
earlier, you know. DC fans will often say that
DC has the edge when it comes to animation.
And I think that may be the case prior to the
Spider-Verse films. But I got to say, I think
I'm enjoying Marvel animation a lot more than
DC animation as of late, which is heartbreaking
to admit. But I have to. Well, the Tomorrowverse
isn't anything impressive, you know, so I can
see where you're coming from there. You know,
we usually reserve five star ratings for things
that. are transcendent and that they transcend
normal superhero tropes and trappings. Yeah,
or they're groundbreaking. Yeah, the X-Men in
themselves, I think, as characters are transcendent
in that they deal with so many more heavy themes
than most other comic book characters. It's
just inherent to the franchise. And when you
have a series that so perfectly captures the
essence of who the X-Men are and how their stories
go, then yeah, you have something that feels
transcendent. So while some people may balk
at the idea of this getting a perfect rating,
I think a lot of X-Men fans out there would
agree with this rating. It's just really well
done in a way that would be hard to surpass
if ever. Yeah, no, I wouldn't call it groundbreaking
in terms of bringing something new that we haven't
seen before. In a way, this took me back to
when I was a child. But I would call it groundbreaking
in that it was so unbelievably true to the
spirit of its creator Stan Lee, who wanted to
create content for not just kids, but really
smart kids who are growing into adulthood. And,
you know, they would have stories like this
to help them get there. I feel like a lot of
animated fare is either very kiddy for little
kids like, you know, Teen Titans Go, or it's
very mature, like, you know, some of... DC
stuff that they've put out. This to me was a
perfect blend of the two, where it wasn't too
kiddy and it wasn't too mature. It was perfect.
I really have no other way to describe it.
There were minor things that I didn't like or
were like, whoa, what's up with that? But ultimately,
I agree with you. It's the best X-Men project
that I've ever seen on screen. DC animation
fans beware, Marvel's coming for you. Yes, you.
Oh no. But that does it for this review guys,
let us know what you thought about X-Men 97
Season 1 by writing to us at dyna or by visiting
us on Instagram, which you can find a link to
in our show notes, or by going to our website
at dynamicduel.com. And on our site you can
also find a link to our Patreon page, where
you can join our Dynamic Duo tier and chat with
us and fellow listeners, our Fantastic Four
tier, which gets you bonus content each month,
our X-Force tier that makes you an executive
producer of this podcast, or our newest tier
that lets you join our Dynamic Podcast Network.
And please don't forget to rate the show on
Apple Podcasts or Spotify or Podchaser or on
our website. Our next episode is going to be
a X-Men tie-in where we pit Warpath, who was
a member of X-Force, against the Native American
DC hero Black Condor. But that does it for
this episode, we want to give a big thanks to
our executive producers Ken Johnson, Jon Strosky,
Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Balcom. Miggie Mathengian,
Brandon Essergard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yaiten,
Austin Wieselowski, AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho,
Gil Camacho, Adam Spies, Andrew Shunk, Dean
Mielewski, and Devin Davis for helping make
this podcast possible. And we'll talk to you
guys next week. Up up and away, true believers.
There is no love without sin. Cause I'm freaky
like that.