Hey Joseph, we all know you like Marvel, right?
I mean, if you haven't figured it out by now,
yeah. But like, what else is there to you? Like,
what else do you like? Well, I mean, I'm also
into Star Trek stuff and Harry Potter. I was
big into Game of Thrones. I try to stay on
top of the NFL and fantasy football. I like
long walks on the beach. Also, I'm a fan of,
you know, dressing stylishly. Well, you're in
luck, because we've partnered with cufflinks.com
to get our listeners 20% off. of everything
on their site all November long when you use
promo code DOOL20 at checkout. And by everything,
I mean EVERYTHING. Not just their Marvel and
DC fashion gear. We're talking Game of Thrones,
Star Wars, Star Trek, Harry Potter, NFL, NBA,
MLB, and more. Including jewelry with beach
sand. Wow. So whatever your passion is, odds
are cufflinks.com has turned it into a cufflink.
They also feature products from the world's best men's jewelry designers such as
Constantino, Deacon & Francis, and Jacob & Company.
Don't miss out on the software guys! Visit cufflinks.com right now and use code dual20.
That's D-U-E-L-20 to get 20% off any order.
And don't forget about their Marvel and DC Mystery Boxes,
where you get $200 worth of comic gear for just $50.
Get it for your loved ones this holiday season.
or ask them to get it for you as a gift. This
season, dress like a hero, save money, only
at cufflinks.com. On with the show.
Hi, welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters and stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin brother Marvelous
Joe. And welcome to episode 254! We're doing
a team duel this episode. We're going to pit
the Justice League Dark against Marvel's Midnight
Suns. We wanted to do this on episode 250. But
of course, we've had to do quite a few reviews
lately, and that pushed our big team duel episode
back by a month. Yeah, we were trying to get
to this before Halloween, but it just didn't
work out that way. But this team duel episode
ties into Halloween in that these teams that
were pitting against each other are Marvel
and DC's respective supernatural teams. These
are the guys that fight the things that go
bump in the night, the monsters, the demons,
the ghosts, the things like that. Yeah, I love
doing these team duels. Can't wait for the main
event later on in the episode. Before that,
we're going to break down the comic book and
movie news items from the past week, of which
it's all Marvel news once again, thanks to Disney
Plus Day, in which they gave us our first looks
at She-Hulk, Moon Knight, Ms. Marvel, and a
lot more. As always, we list our segment times
in our episode description, so feel free to
check out the show notes if you want to skip
ahead to a particular topic. Just a reminder
guys that only the four most recent episodes
of this podcast are available to the listening
public. If you guys want access to over- 250
episodes now of archived content including our
Justice League Dark review, Dr. Fate vs. Dr.
Strange, our Blade review, Zatanna vs. Scarlet
Witch, our Swamp Thing review, or Constantine
vs. Brother Voodoo. Be sure to subscribe to
this podcast on Spotify or Patreon, both of
which will provide you with an RSS feed to use
in your own podcast app. And on Patreon you
also get bonus
blooper reels, watch along parties and more.
It's only $2 a month to subscribe on Spotify
or Patreon and you could do so by visiting dynamicduel.com
slash subscribe, which is linked in our show
notes. I want to quickly reach out to one of
our executive producers who happens to be sick
with COVID at this time. Guys, stay safe out
there. We're definitely not out of this COVID
thing yet. Get vaccinated if you can and well
wishes to anyone who is currently sick out
there. Yeah, man, if you're listening, get well
soon. We're rooting for you. We also want to
give a shout out to patron Lizzie Dyer, whose
birthday was a few days ago. Happy birthday.
If I had to give you a gift from Marvel, I would
give you Hawkeye's quiver of trick arrows,
including, you know, his birthday candle lighting
arrows, which you know he totally has. Like
a lighter arrow? Yeah, yeah. He just, you know,
shoots across the wicks and it lights everything.
Interesting. Lizzie, if I could get you a gift
from DC, it would be Big Barter's Mega Rod.
Way cooler than a bag of arrows. Well, I mean,
if she doesn't like the gift, there's no receipt.
So, whatever. But with that out of the way,
quick, to the No Prize! A No Prize is an award
Marvel used to give out up until the 90s to
fans. Our version, the dynamic dual No Prize,
is a digital award we post on social media that
Jonathan draws for those who we feel gave the
best answer to our Question of the Week. Last
week's question coming off the news that Marvel
is going to do a Halloween special in 2022 based
on the werewolf by night character, we asked,
what's a cool Marvel or DC holiday special that
you would like to see? We got some awesome
answers for this one. Let's go ahead and run
down our honorable mentions as well as the
no prize winner. Our first honorable mention
goes to Michael Haggerty, who said, hello boys,
Michael Haggerty here. I want to see a Justice
League Dark Christmas Carol with Constantine
or Constantine based on your regional preference.
As Ebenezer Scrooge, there's already ghosts
in Just League Dark and there's ghosts in Christmas
Carol. So it kind of matches up perfectly.
The only question left is who would be little
Timmy? Who would be God bless us everyone?
What character would play that character? I
think that's the bigger question, but that's
my answer. All right, boys, gotta go, bye. A
Christmas Carol featuring John Constantine
is probably one of the most brilliant ideas
I've ever heard come out of a question of the
week. John Constantine is totally like a selfish
Scrooge. So for him to be visited by the ghosts
from his past totally makes sense. And as for
the Timmy character, that's obvious. Astralogue,
the little girl he tried and failed to save
at Newcastle from the demon Nurgall. Oh my
gosh dude, Michael Haggerty, you blew my mind.
I think a better Tiny Tim would be Damien Wayne,
Robin. That is a terrible idea. Why? Because
Constantine trying to save Astralogue in the
same way that Scrooge tries to save Tiny Tim
just writes itself. What about like Snapper
Car? Get the fuck out of here. That's rude,
you're like a screwed yourself. This story
needs to happen, I swear. Our next honorable
mention goes to Miggy Mathenkean, who said.
Hey, what's up guys, it's Miggy, and I would
love to see a Cinco de Mayo DC holiday special.
I think it would just be really dope to see
Jaime Reyes, Jessica Cruz, and Cisco Ramon
just like all, you know, get together, just
celebrate the holiday, and then maybe have
to team up against like Bain. Now to my knowledge,
they don't actually celebrate Cinco de Mayo
in Mexico. Yeah, it's much more celebrated in
America. But, you know, Cisco, Jaime, and Jessica
are all, you know, Latin American. So I think
it works. Are they all Mexican American? Well,
Blue Beetle is Mexican American. Cisco, I think,
is Puerto Rican. And I guess Jessica is half
Mexican, half Honduran. And of course, Bain
is from a Latin Caribbean country, right? Like
a riff on Cuba. Yeah, Santa Prisca. But you
know what? They still come together to celebrate.
Yeah, it's kind of just like a drinking holiday,
right? It's like... It's like St. Patrick's
Day, just an excuse to drink. It'd be cool if
they all got drunk and then tried to fight
Bane, who was also drunk. And then they all
come together to recognize the official meaning
of the holiday, which was the Mexican defeat
over the French on the 5th of May. Yep, there
you go. Our final honorable mention goes to
Michael Harald, who said, Hey guys, it's Michael
Harald. So I think the holiday special I'd like
to see would be Lego Batman in live action
with a Will Arnett and all them doing Mother's
Day and Father's Day to see them hamming it
up over not having his parents. or really just
any holiday. I think that could be pretty funny.
Yeah, maybe live action can work. I still love
Lego Batman in his animated form. I really
wish they would make a sequel to the first movie
because I really liked it. Well, Lego Batman
is pretty funny. I'll admit that I've always
wanted to see Will Arnett, who does the voice
for Lego Batman, dressed up in the bat suit
and do his shtick in live action. I think that
would be pretty cool to see. And considering
that Batman has no parents, it would be interesting
to see. him do a holiday special on Mother's
Day or Father's Day. Or in the case of Lego
Batman, who prefers to be called Padre, Padre's
Day. I think it would definitely build upon
the movie where we see Batman take Robin on
as a father. So you know, you can learn about
the true meaning of fatherhood. Before we announce
the winner of this week's No Prize, we want
to give a quick shout out to Corey Wooten, who
took the time to visit our site and record
an answer. Yeah, his answer of Santa Claus was
really good also. But the winner of this week's
No Prize... goes to someone who only identified
themselves as the man who said, Hello Marvelous
Joe and Johnny DC. Stan Lee here. How about
we get a holiday special featuring yours truly?
Just an idea. Thank you, true believers for
keeping the spirit of Marvel strong. Excelsior.
That impression, if it was an impression that
wasn't actually just Stan Lee speaking to us
from beyond the grave, that was so good. That
was incredible. I don't even understand how
an impression is possibly that good. It sounded
just like him. Not only did it sound like him
with like the cadence and everything, it sounded
like what Stan Lee would actually say. I'm
just blown away by this impression, and that's
why he gets this week's no prize. But also,
it would be really cool to see a Stan Lee holiday
special where he celebrates just any holiday
visiting his favorite creations from Marvel.
I've got chills. It's so spot on. There's got
to be like only a few people in the world that
can do an impression that good. If this guy
is not getting paid to do Stanley impressions,
he should be. Because my first impression to
hearing that was actually fright. You know,
I was like, oh my God, that was actually him.
And I really want to believe that it is. Well,
you know, maybe that reaction is appropriate
for this Halloween themed duel we have coming
up. You know, what's interesting, though, is
that Stanley actually died three years almost
to the day. so this episode is being done on
the anniversary of his passing. But congrats
again to The Man for winning this week's No
Prize. If you the listener want a shot at winning
your own No Prize, stay tuned to later on this
episode when we'll be asking another Question
of the Week. And now that that's done, on to
the news!
All right, this past Friday was Disney Plus
Day. I didn't even really know that was gonna
be a thing until like a few weeks beforehand.
But basically, it kind of served as a news
event for what the past year held on Disney
Plus as well as what's to come. Yeah, it was
kind of like a lame version of the DC fandom,
right? If by lame you mean better with more
news, then yeah, lame. I didn't mean that. We
got quite a few. Surprise announcements in
addition to first looks at some of the upcoming
shows that were announced a while ago Including
Moon Knight she Hulk and Ms. Marvel We'll go
over those first looks first starting with
Moon Knight Which is kind of turning out to
be way different than I thought it was gonna
be it looks definitely more mature than any
other Disney plus show that has come out so
far almost like a Netflix series looking show
It looks dark which is great because it's a
Moon Knight so it should seeing him just like
clobber some guy on the ground in this white
cape and hood was kind of frightening. Yeah,
the costume looks really good in the comics.
When you draw an all white costume, you can
still really hide it through shadow. But in
live action, he looks very immaculate, almost
priestly in his garb, which is, yeah, kind
of like haunting, you know, seeing him leap
across that night sky with the crescent moon
in the background was everything I wanted it
to be. It was so freaking cool. It's everything
I've ever wanted to see in a Batman movie. Well,
Batman can't leap across a whole city street.
What? He can leap across an alley, sure, but
he's not superhuman. He can grapple across
a city street. I mean, he could glide though.
That's true, that's true. But if you're aware
of the Moon Knight character, you know that
he has strength that waxes and wanes with the
phases of the moon, so it's apt here. I think
the thing that shocked me the most though was
Oscar Isaac's voices that he does for his different
personalities. Like his Mark Spector or maybe
Jake Lockley has a British accent, which was
interesting compared to his Moon Knight voice,
which is very dark and almost Batman-esque.
It was really cool. Kind of creepy, which again
is pretty good and pretty apt. We don't get
a lot of footage here, but the fact that Oscar
Isaac seems to be as confused with what we're
seeing as you know, we are is a good sign.
I think. Yeah. He's switching in and out of
his multiple personalities. The way the show
seems to be handling that looks fascinating.
Just like Fight Club, like how we describe
the character in our duel episode with him against
Batman. Oh, like Tyler Durden? Yeah, exactly.
I'm definitely looking forward to this one.
We don't have a release date, do we? No, we
don't have release dates for any of these. They
all say that they're just streaming soon. So
next year sometime. The next first look that
we got was of Ms. Marvel. We didn't get a look
at her costume or of her using her powers, really.
We do see this like purple energy emanate from
her. But it was the first live-action footage
we're getting from the show. We see her kind
of struggle with her identity as a hero, her
family praying as Muslims, and claiming that
heroes don't usually look like brown girls from
Jersey. The only costume that we really see
her in is when she's wearing her Captain Marvel
Halloween costume, which I think is what maybe
a lot of us would do as kids if we first discover
superpowers and we don't have any sort of like
tailor, you know? We'll just put on the superhero
costume of the hero that we admire the most.
I like that angle here as kind of a nod to her
origin in the comic books and the origin of
her superhero name. We do get to see her like
running across the sky, which I thought was
interesting. I'm really curious to see how they're
going to depict her power. Yeah, it's not going
to be stretching really like how it is in the
comics. Essentially, it looks like her bangle
that she wears on her wrist, which she wears
in the comics as an heirloom, that's going
to be the source of her superpowers. It emanates
like this personal energy field around her.
that she can manipulate in a way that is akin
to stretching, like enlarging her fists or
stretching her legs out or something like that.
It's gotta be like Kree technology or something,
right? Perhaps. It's an interesting take. I
think they're doing it, one, for special effects
reasons, two, to make it so that Mr. Fantastic
is the first elastic hero within the MCU, and
three, to make all of the Marvel's characters
in the upcoming The Marvel's film all energy-based,
including Captain Marvel, Ms. Marvel, and Photon.
Makes sense. The next first look we got was
of She-Hulk, and this was our first glimpse
of the logo, which I thought was pretty weird.
It almost looks something like the practice
or Ally McBeal or something like that. Like
Nip Tuck. Yeah, Nip Tuck, yeah, that was interesting.
It looks very like 90s legal drama. And I wonder
if that's the vibe that the show is going for,
because toward the end of this teaser, which
starts off with Jennifer Walters introducing
herself, and then we see a glimpse of her in
her She-Hulk form, at the end. She's like breaking
the fourth wall like the character does in
the comics, speaking to the audience and saying,
don't make me angry, you wouldn't like me when
I'm angry. And that setting in which she does
it looks very 90s. I was gonna say 70s. Yeah,
could be 70s. Anywhere between like the 70s
and 90s, I would say. Okay. I wonder if it's
gonna be like a lawyer commercial or something
like that. Yeah, I don't know. I don't know
what's happening there. It's really strange
that like Bruce Banner was just kind of...
standing still in the background. I wonder if
like everybody freezes in the show as she speaks
to the audience in the same way like saved by
the bell or something like that. I never knew
that She-Hulk broke the fourth wall in the comics.
That seems so weird to me. Yeah, she used to
do all the time way before Deadpool was doing
it. It does look like they're gonna go the
CG route with She-Hulk just like the Hulk and
not just like paint her skin green. I hope
the special effects on Tatiana Maslany are as
good as they are on Mark Ruffalo. I'll be really
interested to see like the facial expressions
on this character design. Timeline-wise, it
appears like this may take place in between
the events of Avengers Endgame and Shang-Chi
because we see the Hulk here in his Professor
Hulk form. But I can't be certain on that.
Maybe Mark Ruffalo can still change back and
forth while still retaining his personality.
I was gonna say that this takes place before
because the Hulk's arm isn't like scarred and
broken and damaged. Yeah, that's a great point.
That's a great point. We'll see when the show
comes out next year. So that was really it for
the first looks. We did get a brief glimpse
of Samuel L. Jackson's character as he's going
to appear in Secret Invasion, in which he has
a longer beard and isn't wearing the eye patch,
which is interesting. Makes me suspect he's
a Skrull. Right off the bat. We also got announcements
that they're coming out with a season two of
What If, which we already knew. But we did get
new announcements of shows that were not announced
previously by Disney Plus, including Echo, which
will be a spinoff of the Hawkeye series. Marvel
Zombies, which might be an animated spin-off
of What If? Agatha House of Harkness, which
is definitely a spin-off of WandaVision. And
most surprisingly, a show called Spider-Man
Freshman Year, which will be animated, perhaps
voiced by Tom Holland or maybe the actor who
did Spider-Man's voice in What If? But basically
it looks like it's going to recount Spider-Man's
origin story within the MCU. Which is really
cool, because we never got to see that. Yeah,
I'm excited for this, for sure. They also announced
that they will be doing more X-Men cartoons,
like the 90s version of the X-Men. I was surprised
that they put the Marvel Studios banner above
that one, considering it's not part of the MCU
though. No, it's like an alternate universe
X-Men, kind of. It's great that they're bringing
that back though. Hopefully with better animation
and fingers crossed it's the same voice cast.
This will be Marvel Studios first X-Men project,
which is also exciting. Oh yeah, so much to
look forward to. Way better than that fan dome
crap, who needs that when you have Disney Plus
Day? Oh gosh. Yay logos! Yay for logos. Marvel
fans always excited by them logos. I mean, we
didn't even get a logo for Blue Beetle or Batgirl.
So how about that? No, we got to see concept
art of them in costume. Oh, concept art. Yay.
Whatever, dude. All I'm saying is I got way
more pumped from this news than I did at the
fandom. I'm sorry. What's your name again? Marvelous
Joe? OK, that makes sense. I can't wait till
we get dates on all of these. It looks like
next year is going to be just as big of a year
as 2021 was. Lots to look forward to. Lots to
review. Too much Marvel stuff to watch. Ugh.
But regarding all the news to come out at Disney
Plus Day, that brings us to our question of
the week.
What was your favorite news to come out of Disney
Plus Day and why? Record your answer at dynamicduel.com
by clicking on the red microphone button in
the bottom right hand corner, which will prompt
you to leave us a voicemail. Your message can
be up to 30 seconds long, and don't forget
to leave your name in case we include you on
the podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer
and draw that person a Dynamic Duel No Prize
that we'll post to social media. Be sure to
answer before November 20th. But that does it
for the news for this episode. Let's go ahead
and get a word from our sponsor, HBO Max. Bruce
Wayne may appear to be a wealthy playboy, but
beneath his facade, his true identity is that
of the Batman waging an endless war against
crime. Join the caped crusader in Batman, the
audio adventures, the first scripted audio
original featuring Batman and his villainous
rogues gallery in a world premiere story of
life and death in Gotham City, debuting exclusively
on HBO Max. Starring Jeffrey Wright as Batman
and a who's who of incredible Saturday Night
Live alums, this rollicking adventure, told
across 10 episodes, is written and directed
by Emmy winner Dennis McNicholas, includes
devilishly delightful original music by Doug
Bossie, and performances by Rosario Dawson,
John Leguizamo, Chris Parnell, Melissa Villaseñor,
Seth Meyers, Jason Sudeikis, Brooke Shields,
Fred Armisen, and many, many more. Go to HBOmax.com
slash Batman Audio Adventures for more and
stream Batman The Audio Adventures only on HBO
Max. Thanks to HBO Max for sponsoring this
episode. Now let's go ahead and get into our
main event where we find out who would win
in a fight between the supernatural teams of
DC's Justice League Dark and Marvel's Midnight
Suns.
Okay, Justice League Dark versus the Midnight
Suns. These are both DC and Marvel's most prominent,
supernatural super teams. Though I gotta be
honest, I only learned about the Midnight Suns
like earlier this year. Well, yeah, I told you
about them when we were trying to come up with
our next team duel episode. I thought it would
be really cool since Episode 250 was gonna
land around the same time as Halloween to do
a kind of Halloween themed team duel. Right.
It's a little disappointing that we're two weeks
past Halloween now, but that's just how the
episodes fell. Basically, we didn't want to
skip a review because then we'd be pushing
back all of the review episodes that we were
going to do. But to me, it was never the end
of the Halloween season until we got to this
episode. I'm going to get right back into it.
Just jack-o-lanterns and black cats and autumn
leaves falling in the dead of night. That's
where my mind is at right now. Yeah, the duel
is supposed to not take place in any kind of
environment. But that's the environment I'm
going to be imagining for this matchup. Now
the only prime exposure I have to Justice League
Dark is the movie that we reviewed a couple
years ago, the animated film Justice League
Dark, and its sequel, Justice League Dark Apocalypse
War. Yeah, that wasn't quite a sequel specifically
to Justice League Dark. I'm not sure why they
called that film Justice League Dark Apocalypse
War. It probably should have just been like
Apocalypse War. But yeah, both of those films
featured characters from Justice League Dark.
Back when we started this podcast too, We were
talking about how Guillermo del Toro was supposed
to make a Justice League Dark movie. I think
he was calling it Dark Universe at the time,
and that seemed like it was really cool. Still
waiting for that to materialize. But I guess
that JJ Abrams is working on bringing some of
those characters to the screen for HBO Max,
like as we speak. So that's exciting. Yeah,
and sometime in 2022, we're supposed to get
a Midnight Suns video game, which I think will
be the primary exposure of that team to the
world at large. It is spelled S-U-N-S, which
the developer did to make the team seem more
inclusive. And in that video game, the team
is actually named after a rare astronomical
event, during which time the demon character
Lilith attempts to resurrect C'thun, the Elder
God of Chaos. So I actually think that's pretty
cool. I think the name reads cooler with S-U-N-S,
and I do think that Marvel will follow suit
with the next incarnation of the team. So the
title of this podcast will use that newer spelling.
S-U-N-S? Yeah. Well, I can't wait to learn
more about them. If you've never listened to
one of our duel episodes before, the way we
determine a winner for these two teams is by
running 1000 Monte Carlo simulations using
their statistics. And actually it's more than
1000 when we do team duels, we're actually
comparing matrices of data. Yeah, between each
character, so it's 49,000 Monte Carlo simulations
technically. Friggin' crazy. It takes a long
time. Now if you're wondering what a Monte
Carlo simulation is, It's a probabilistic model
used to determine outcomes through random sampling.
And in our case, it randomizes statistics along
a normal distribution, which is a bell curve
as a way to simulate the many variables that
can occur during battle. The stat parameters
we use are based on the official Marvel Power
Grid, and we use that criteria to extrapolate
the DC character stats. We've included some
additional stat categories of our own, such
as range, damage potential, versatility, and
perception. in order to create a more complete
and robust simulation. Running these 1000 simulations
gives us a percentage of wins for each team,
and we declare the team with the higher percentage
to be the ultimate victor considering that
they're more likely to win any given battle.
No characters ever win 100% of the time. Comics
have shown that there's always a way for Batman
to defeat Superman, so we feel our method falls
in line with the precedents that have been established
in the comic book stories. And we used this
method because it was the least subjective,
most unbiased way to determine who would win.
Of course, we are both heavily biased toward
our respective allegiances, and instead of
debating these matches forever, we just let
the math decide for us. So there's no fan votes
here, and no relying on just feats. Before we
run the simulations though, we like to break
down each team's histories and rosters, before
improvising a scenario on how we imagine one
of these simulations would play out beat for
beat. It's been a while since we've done a
duel episode. Yeah, I think not since Manbat
vs Morbius, like almost a month. It's crazy.
It's crazy. So many reviews. But I think it's
my turn to go first with the DC backstory,
so let me tell you all about Justice League
Dark. Now, though the most recent iteration
of the team is known as Justice League Dark,
the Magic-based group is much less renowned
than the popular superteam, the Justice League,
which you can learn more about in our 100th
episode, Justice League vs Avengers. Justice
League Dark actually has its roots in a team
known as the Sentinels of Magic, which emerged
in the Day of Judgment storyline where the
demon Etrigan tricked the hostless spirit of
vengeance known as the Spectre to bond with
the fallen angel Asmodel in Hell. With his new,
nearly limitless power, Asmodel caused Hell
to freeze over and unleashed hordes of demons
on Earth as well as powerful, evil spirits
such as the Enchantress. With the Justice League
and Justice Society overwhelmed, magicians,
sorcerers, and occultists from around the world
joined together, namely Zatanna, the Phantom
Stranger, Madame Xanadu, Deadman, Raven, Ragman,
Faust, Doctor Occult, and the Green Lantern,
Ellen Scott, in order to stop Asmodel and find
a new host for the Spectre. After slaying the
Enchantress to reignite the fires of Hell, the
Sentinels helped the who you can learn more
about in our Green Lantern vs Nova episode.
Eventually, Hull Jordan was separated from
the Spectre's spirit, which was manipulated
by the spirit of wrath known as Eclipso, into
destroying all magic. You can learn more about
this in our Spectre vs Galactus episode. Now,
after the Spectre destroyed the Rock of Eternity,
an incapacitated sorcerer is powerful enough
to stop him, such as Dr. Fate and Madam Xanadu,
several other magic users banded together to
take a stand against the Spectre, including
a resurrected Enchantress, Blue Devil, Ragman,
Nightmaster, Nightshade, and Detective Chimp,
forming a team known as Shadow Pact. Though
Zatanna wasn't an official member of the team,
she and other magical heroes did help them
reform the Rock of Eternity. Shadow Pact was
unsuccessful in stopping the hostless Spectre,
whose threat to magic was
by Heaven after the Spectre killed the powerful
ancient wizards Shazam and Naboo. Shadow Pact
remained together, operating out of the Oblivion
Bar, which existed in a pocket dimension accessible
to magic users, and taking on new members such
as the angel Zareel, who you can learn more
about in our Zareel vs Archangel episode. Together,
they defeated magical threats to Earth from
groups such as the Pentechol and the Congregation,
and they stopped villains like Dr. Gotham.
In post-Flashpoint continuity, DC's premier
Magic team became known as Justice League Dark,
a team initially consisting of John Constantine,
Zatanna, Deadman, Shade, Mindwarp, and Madame
Xanadu, the latter of whom brought the team
together to stop the succubus Enchantress after
she became unbound to her host, June Moon, and
defeated the Justice League. Constantine was
able to re-bind Enchantress to June Moon, and
the team disbanded for a short time before
coming together again, sans mind warp, to fend
off Kane and his legion of vampires. Joined
by the vampire Andrew Bennett from the series
I, Vampire, the team defeated Kane, drawing
the attention of the government agency Argus,
who actually gave the team the name Justice
League Dark. Argus commissioned the League to
stop the sorcerer Faust, who planned on taking
control of all magic using the Books of Magic.
That's a clever name. That was the name of
the Timothy Hunter book written by Neil Gaiman
for Vertigo. Now after accidentally unleashing
the Demons III, a trio of powerful demons under
Faust's control, the team discovered Faust
was actually working for Nick Necro, the mentor
to both Constantine and Zatanna. With the help
of Black Orchid, Frankenstein, Amethyst, and
the boy sorcerer Timothy Hunter, Nick Necro
was defeated. During the Trinity War storyline,
Wonder Woman approached the League in order
to help determine how a mystic artifact known
as Pandora's Box was able to manipulate Superman
into killing. The Box, Constantine discovered,
was actually a gateway to Earth-3, home to
the Crime Syndicate and the likes of evil Justice
League doppelgangers like Ultraman, Superwoman,
and Owlman, who broke through Pandora's Box
and trapped all the members of the Justice
League, Justice League of America, and Justice
League Dark. Constantine, however, was rescued
by the Justice League Dark's base of operations,
the sentient and interdimensional House of
Mystery. With the help of Nightmare Nurse, Swamp
Thing, the Phantom Stranger, Pandora, Zareal,
and Deadman, the latter of whom also escaped
capture, Constantine located Zatanna, and together,
they stopped Nick Necro and Faust again, who
had partnered with the Crime Syndicate, but
this time, they stopped him in Nandaparbat.
which you can learn more about in our Dead
Man vs. Magic episode. Their battle there eventually
awakened an evil old god of Nandaparbat, Pantheon,
whom the Justice League Dark managed to defeat.
When their House of Mystery merged with Nick
Necro's House of Secrets to form the House of
Wonder, the League was forced to destroy it
since it had become powerful enough to conquer
the planet. After the events of Dark Knight's
Metal resulted in a break in the Source Wall,
Magic was thrown into flux. and Wonder Woman
formed a new Justice League Dark Team in response.
This team initially consisted of Wonder Woman,
Zatanna, Detective Chimp, Manbat, and Swamp
Thing, though it wasn't long before Constantine
got involved in a battle against the hostless
spirit of Naboo, as Dr. Fate, who was trying
to destroy the chaos of magic by summoning the
Upside-Down Man and the other kind to devour
it. Wonder Woman was able to fend off the Upside-Down
Man, however, thanks to a burgeoning magical
ability that she later learned was derived from
the Greek goddess of magic, Hecate. After Hecate
corrupted and took control of Wonder Woman and
several other magic heroines, including Black
Orchid, Manitou Dawn, and Witchfire, Wonder
Woman used the Upside-Down Men to devour Hecate
and free the women from her curse. After Detective
Chip inherited the Sword of Nightmaster, he
was able to transfer many heroes to the Mystic
Realm of Myrrah. including Swamp Thing, Etrigan,
and Deadman, where they would be safe from being
devoured by the upside down man and his other
kind. Naboo and the other Lords of Order, however,
were able to invade the realm and began stripping
the citizens there of magic. Zatanna and Wonder
Woman, meanwhile, were transformed into Lords
of Chaos for a time by the Chaos Lord Mordru,
and the League defeated the Lords of Order
with Wonder Woman bringing magic back to the
world. With Wonder Woman's arch-nemesis Cersei
now in control of Hecate's magic, Cersei formed
an Injustice League Dark villain team, in which
she allowed herself to be possessed by Eclipso
and teamed up with Floronic Man, Clarion the
Witch Boy, Papa Midnight, and Solomon Grundy.
Thanks to help from the Upside-Down Men and
the other kind, the League was able to stop
the Injustice League Dark. Recently, the Injustice
League Dark team became more closely partnered
with the Justice League, became a new official
member of the team as the most powerful and
dangerous sorcerer, Merlin, was resurrected.
And that's the team's history so far. Now there
are a ton of magic-based superheroes in DC,
many of whom have been members of the Justice
League Dark and its previous incarnations.
One character that has been in almost every
iteration of the team, however, is Zatanna.
So she was a no-brainer, as was Constantine,
who's not the biggest team player, but a powerful
and popular figure in DC's world of magic. Like
Zatanna and Constantine, Deadman was an original
member of the first Justice League Dark team,
so he's in, as is Swamp Thing, who was also
there early on thanks to his ties to Constantine.
A lot of these characters so far have had their
own Vertigo titles, so in keeping with that,
I wanted to include Black Orchid on the team
since she was a more prominent member of the
initial team than characters like F- Frankenstein
Amethyst or the Vampire Andrew Bennett. Since
what Roman took over the team, both Detective
Chimp and Manbat have become mainstays, though
of the two, I opted for Manbat due to his versatility.
And finally, I chose my seventh team member
to be Etrigan. He's only been a member of the
Justice League Dark for a short time, but Jason
Blood is often depicted as being on the team
in other media and alternate timelines, including
the and even Guillermo del Toro's Justice League
Dark script. So that's my team. Yeah, that makes
sense. What do you think of the name Justice
League Dark? Because you mentioned their previous
incarnations as like the Sentinels of Magic
and stuff. I think that's way better and less
derivative. Yeah, it's named Justice League
Dark so that it sells, but I would much prefer
a team name of like Shadow Pact or something
like that for sure. Or even like Constantine's
like old band name, Yookus Membrane. I'm sure
he would have voted for that over Justice League
Dark. Yeah, I think when it comes to the names
of these teams, Midnight Suns is just way better.
And actually, they're just a better team in
general when you think about it. And I think
our listeners agree when they compare the Justice
League Dark backstory to the Midnight Suns backstory.
Okay, let's hear it. So the story of the Midnight
Suns goes back hundreds of years, beginning
as an ancient secret order of protectors with
the mission of stopping supernatural threats
to humanity. Their ranks included members that
were reputed to have a taste of damnation, those
with some measure of exposure to the darkness
of paranormal, mystical, and hellish evils on
Earth. Their greatest feat among battling the
likes of Dracula was the defeat of Lilith, the
mother of all demons and former wife of the
devil himself. The Midnight Suns cast her and
her children, the Lilin, to a dark dimensional
prison called the Shadow Side. though it was
prophesied among the Order that she would one
day return and that nine of their own would
stand against her. That day came hundreds of
years later when Doctor Strange, the Sorcerer
Supreme, detected a rift in the Shadow Side
and that Lilith would soon escape and come back
to Earth. He knew that he couldn't face her
himself because the magical energies that would
stem from the battle would weaken the dimensional
barriers between the two realms, and so he would
have to gather the nine together that were
foretold in the prophecy. Doctor Strange reached
out to his occasional ally, Johnny Blaze, who
was host to Ghost Rider, the vengeful demon,
and his brother, Ketch, who was host to the
Spirit of Vengeance, both of whom had also seen
a vision of Lilith's return. On their motorcycles,
the brothers traveled to gather Doctor Strange's
recruits, including the reluctant pseudo-vampire
Morbius, and the group known as the Nightstalkers,
who were Hannibal King, the self-loathing vampire
detective, Frank Drake, a descendant of Dracula,
and the daywalker, Blade. the Vampire Hunter.
The last of their recruits were three experts
on the occult and the Darkhold, a book of black
magic. They were Victoria Montessi, Sam Buchanan,
and Louise Hastings, together known as the
Darkhold Redeemers. Dude, the Books of Magic
is a way better name than the Darkhold. I noticed
you can't help but hide that smile as you say
that. That's right. The prophesied nine collectively
battled and killed four of the Lilin, and who
managed to escape, though she was severely
weakened. Though the nine heroes fulfilled the
prophecy and sealed the rift in the Shadowside,
they knew that Lilith would soon sire more children
and try to conquer Earth's realm again. They
maintained a loose connection, though one day
Blade, in his desire to obliterate all vampires
from existence, tried to use a spell from the
Darkhold to do so. This backfired, transforming
him into the possessed Switchblade, who went
on a supernatural killing spree. He murdered
many of the prophesied Nine, though the Darkhold
Redeemers were able to use the book to counter
the spell and undo the damage that Blade had
caused. Reunited, the group of Nine learned
that Lilith had partnered with the demon Xerathos,
who had opened a portal to the Shadow Side
within Salem Field Cemetery. Xerathos is the
Ghost Raider? Yeah, this demon was not connected
to Johnny Blaze at the time. Okay. The prophesied
Nine traveled to the cemetery to try to stop
Lilith and her Lilin again, though they were
overwhelmed and had to flee with the help of
the Caretaker. They regrouped at Dr. Strange's
Sanctum Sanctorum, where it was discovered
that Morbius was a traitor to the Nine due to
an infection with Lilin blood. They were overrun
again, leading Dr. Strange to cast a spell that
magically detonated his Sanctum, killing the
Lilin inside. They helped Morbius fight off
his infection, and traveled back to the cemetery
and used a magic medallion provided by the Caretaker
to send Lilith back to the Shadow Side. They
also defeated Xerathos and his followers using
a mystic sword, though throughout the whole
ordeal, several members of the Nine fell in
battle. With Lilith finally gone for good,
the surviving members, including Ghost Rider,
Strange, Blade, and Morbius, underwent a ceremony
in which they were branded with the mark of
the Midnight Suns, a flaming dagger that resembles
a small cross, officially making them members
of the ancient order. Years later, a zombie
virus infiltrated Earth's realm through the
nexus of all realities, located in the swamp
where the creature known as Manthing lived.
Morbius saw the need for a supernatural fighting
force to return and formed a new Midnight Suns
group consisting of himself, Jennifer Kael,
who is Ghost Rider's cousin, Hellstorm, the
son of Satan, Jack Russell, the werewolf by
night, and Manthing. Though Morbius' zombie
cure failed, the team was able to mystically
transfer the virus into one person named Simon
Garth, aka Zombie, a man who was already undead
due to a voodoo curse. Later, the city of Las
Vegas was burned down and sent to hell during
a takeover by the criminal organization Hydra.
The city was resurrected using magic, but while
it was in hell, Mephisto had created a casino
called Hotel Inferno. It was brought to earth
with the rest of Vegas, where gamblers could
bet- their very souls. Holy crap! Doctor Strange
made a deal with Mephisto where if Strange won,
the casino's souls would be set free and Mephisto
and the Hotel Inferno would return to hell.
If Strange lost, Mephisto could claim his soul.
Notified of the wager, Strange's assistant,
Wong, summoned the Midnight Suns again, including
Blade, Ghost Rider, and Man-Thing, with new
recruits Brother Voodoo, Moon Knight, Iron
Fist, Scarlet Spider, and Elsa Bloodstone. Together,
they traveled to Vegas and fought Mephisto's
Demon Army. Ghost Rider fought Mephisto head
on, who killed Johnny Blaze and sent him to
Hell. There, Blaze and the Spirit of Vengeance
freed the Casino's captured souls from their
vault and usurped the Crown and Throne of Hell,
cutting Mephisto off from his power. The rest
of the team then defeated the Demon Lord and
saved Doctor Strange's soul. That's the comics
team history. I did want to note that the upcoming
video game that renames the team to Midnight
Suns with a U does recruit other Mystic heroes
such as Niko Minoru, a former Runaways character,
and the new mutant member known as Magic. Which
makes sense. Yeah. For this team duel, I chose
seven members to represent the Midnight Suns.
Doctor Strange, who is Marvel's foremost Magic
hero and who was the initial recruiter for this
present-day incarnation of the Order. Ghost
Rider. first gathered the team and is also a
supernatural heavy hitter. Blade and Morbius,
both original members with vampiric abilities.
Man-Thing who is recruited into Morbius's team
and whom I've always thought was pretty creepy
and cool. And lastly Brother Voodoo and Bloodstone,
both newer recruits but also characters I think
are badass and really grew to love during their
individual duel episodes that we've done. Yeah
if you want to learn more about the individual
characters on each of our teams we've done duel
episodes with all of them so... Definitely
go back and check out the catalog. It's only
$2 on Spotify. I would have included characters
like Moon Knight and Iron Fist, but of course
they were in our last team duel where we pit
the defenders against the Suicide Squad. So
you have like two sorcerers in Doctor Strange
and Brother Voodoo. You have two vampires in
Morbius and Blade. You have a swamp monster
in Man-Thing, a monster hunter in Bloodstone,
and I guess a fiery demon in Ghost Rider. Bring
them on, I'll take them. I'll take them all
on. Haha so cocky, we'll see how this plays
out. Because now that we've gotten their histories
and abilities out of the way, we're going to
speculate on how one of the simulated matches
will go. The winner is determined by simulations,
not the speculation, but it is fun to imagine
how this fight could play out. We don't set
any rules for this match, other than the characters
don't know anything about each other going
in, except that the other team is a threat that
needs to be put down. And we say that each
team starts off about 50 meters apart. in an
environment that has no bearing on the match
itself because we don't take stats for the environment.
Yeah, plus certain characters have advantages
in some environments over others, and we want
these teams to win on their own merit. So let's
get into it. Justice League Dark and the Midnight
Suns meet on the battlefield. Who goes first?
I could guarantee you right away that Constantine,
he's just gonna look at this whole situation
and be like, oh bloody hell, and then just like
make himself disappear from the situation.
Where does he go? He just... Turns himself invisible.
All right, so Dr. Strange, he's gonna use his
Eye of Agamotto. You know, he's gonna fly into
the air and the eye is gonna glow and shine
an eye symbol onto the foreheads of each of
his teammates on the Midnight Suns, which is
gonna grant them the Eye of Agamotto's sight.
Right, so that means that throughout the course
of this match, they can see through any illusion
or hidden being, including Deadman and the
now hidden Constantine. What? I feel like that's
cheating. Swamp Thing, he's gonna start things
off just by shoving his hands like into the
ground and he's gonna cover the floor beneath
the Midnight Suns with foliage and branches
before they even get a chance to move, right?
And he's just gonna grab their ankles and hold
them in place. While Etch again, he's gonna
breathe out a blast of hellfire that just sets
that foliage ablaze and he just burns the shit
out of the Midnight Suns where they stand with
hellfire. You know that like half this team
is like immune to fire, right? What do you mean?
I guess it's just- Ghost Rider and Brother
Voodoo. But actually, you know what? Brother
Voodoo, not only can he control fire, he can
also control plant life. So what Brother Voodoo
is gonna do is he's just gonna handle this.
He's gonna release the team from the branches
that they're stuck in by commanding them to
let go, and then he's just gonna manipulate
the Hellfire so that it extinguishes before
it burns anyone. So like, Dr. Voodoo was the
ultimate defense against this attack. And with
the team free, the Midnight Suns are just gonna
rush forward and charge Justice League Dark.
The fastest one on the team out of anybody here,
I think, is Ghost Rider. So on his motorcycle,
he's going to be the first one across the battlefield.
He's just going to ride right over to Swamp
Thing, who's like the biggest guy on the Justice
League Dark, and he's going to wrap Swamp Thing
up in his Hellfire chains and just burn this
plant man to a crisp. Is it like Swamp Thing?
He goes up against fire guys all the time. I
feel like he's just going to slough off the
burnt parts, right? So he's probably just like
a pair of legs right now, but he'll regrow.
It's fine. So like the rest of the Midnight
Sun's approach, the Justice League Dark. Zatanna,
she's just gonna summon forth magic armor for
her entire team. She's just gonna be like Kegum
Ram-ra-poo. What is that? That's magic armor
up. What kind of armor is this? I don't know,
it's like medieval kind of chest plate and shoulder
armor and a helmet that's like made of light.
Okay, even for Deadman? Who's not physical?
Everyone except for a Deadman, alright? But
Deadman, he's gonna fly into the body of Man-Thing,
alright? And possess his body becoming Deadman-Thing.
And in this body, he's going to be attacking
Blade, just taking him by surprise, grabs his
arm, and just burns it with a sulfuric acid
touch. Well, Blade wears a jacket, you know,
it's like a thick, durable, heavy leather jacket.
So, you know, that's going to protect him a
little bit from this Man-Thing touch. But Blade
is going to be surprised, yeah, and he's going
to like slice off Man-Thing's arm as it's grabbing
him. And he's going to like spin around, yanking
off his jacket before the acid burns his flesh.
I could totally see that into Wesley Snipes'
like, twirl. Yeah, and he's gonna finish off
the twirl by slicing Man-Thing right in half
at the waist. Which, you know, won't kill Man-Thing,
but you know. Yeah, Man-Thing, he just regenerates,
right? Exactly. So, Blade is probably gonna
mouth like, What the fuck? Hahahaha! Just with
like, what was the blood god's name? Like, yeah,
from the movie. Yeah. So meanwhile, nearby
Man-Bat, he's gonna unleash this debilitating
scream at Elsa Bloodstone specifically. just
dropping her to her knees. And as she's disoriented,
he's gonna grab her with his talons, just swoop
high above the battle, and just let her go,
just drop her straight down. Okay, um, all
right. As Elsa Bloodstone is falling, she's
gonna throw up a dagger that sticks right into
Manbat's leg, because she's just not pleased
with what he just did to her. And right before
she hits the ground, Doctor Strange is gonna
save her by slowing her descent using the winds
of Watomb. So she's fine. and man bats like
bleeding out from his leg. Oh, awesome, okay.
Meanwhile, Morbius, he'll have snuck behind
Zatanna at this point, and he's gonna attack
her, biting her in between her helmet and shoulder
armor, sinking his teeth into her neck. And
this is gonna turn her into a vampire. So her
skin turns white, her eyes glow red, nose flattens,
fangs grow, and she'll now be known as Batanna,
the pseudo-vampiris. Who is basically on the
side of the Midnight Suns against her own team
since she's like a familiar of Morbius I was
gonna say, oh thanks for just leveling her up
with like vampire powers But you're saying
she's now under Morbius's command? Not under
his command, but on his side So what she's
gonna do is she's gonna yank Constantine out
of his cowardly hiding spell and from her hat
She's gonna pull this like army of vampire rabbits
that just freaking pounce on Constantine and
feast on him They're like biniculas. Yeah, exactly,
like binicula. She pulls out an army of biniculas
from her hand now that she's a vampire. That's
kind of cool. But like Constantine, he has
demonic blood, which actually makes him immune
to vampire bites. So these rabbits, they're
just going to like explode upon biting him,
all right? And he's going to pull out this
like vial from his pocket, which is like an
anathema for vampirism. And you're just going
to throw it at Zatanna's feet and it's going
to emit this smoke, like a smoke bomb. that
transforms her back into her normal self. I
mean, would he really have an anathema for
pseudo vampirism? This works on, like, vampirism
of any form. He's prepared for shit like this.
Okay. Meanwhile, Black Orchid, she's going to
be going up against Brother Voodoo, and she's
going to emit these pheromones that control
him into shooting a magic blast at Ghost Rider,
just knocking him straight off of his hell cycle.
Right on his ass. Okay, so it's a lot of teammate
turning on teammate here, huh? Yeah. Well, Brother
Voodoo is, you know, easily manipulated by
external forces because within him resides the
spirit of his brother. So Daniel, his brother,
he flies out of his brother and like shakes
him out of this daze that he's in. And brother
Voodoo is able to prevent further pheromone
control on him by using this like special Voodoo
herb mixture that counteracts the pheromones.
And then Daniel the spirit is going to go off
and freaking tackle Deadman thing which pushes
Deadman out of the body. And those two are
just going to start fighting as ghosts. Okay,
okay. And as payback for manipulating Kim,
Brother Voodoo is gonna in return manipulate
Black Orchid. Since she is part plant and he
can command plants, he's gonna like freeze her
in place where she stands as he just strikes
her in the head with his staff of legba. Oh,
you mean he strikes her in her magic helmet?
Oh yeah, that's stupid magic armor. It's still
around, I gotta get rid of that. Edrigan meanwhile,
he's trying to attack Dr. Strange, just slashing
through. His magic shields laughing and rhyming
about how he's gonna feast on his entrails,
you know? Jesus. And finally, he's gonna break
through Dr. Strange's defenses and shields,
alright? And Etrigan, he's just gonna bloody
Dr. Strange with his teeth, claws, and superior
strength. Because Etrigan's like Hulk strength,
remember? With magic. Okay, yeah, I think that
would mess Dr. Strange up if he started getting
like pummeled by Etrigan. So he's probably gonna
be near death, but he's gonna raise up his
hand, and he's gonna call upon the Spear of
the Seraphim. to just fall from the sky and
impale Edrigan where he stands, like right through
his armor and everything. And since it's from
the Seraphim, you know, Seraphim are angels.
So it's just gonna freaking cause Edrigan to
explode in this bright, holy light that exercises
the demon and sends him back to hell, leaving
just the human, Jason Blood, in his place. And
this holy light explosion is gonna be so powerful
that it's also going to demolish the magic armor
that everybody's wearing. What? Conveniently.
Like what, shatter? Yeah, it's like a angelic
light spear, you know, it carries a big punch.
I feel like that's a really random way to get
rid of the armor, but okay. It's magic. No
question it. Okay. Uh, but by this time Swamp
Thing, he's regrown his body and he's going
to see the vampire Morbius and he's going to
turn his hand into like this wooden stake and
he's just going to quickly stretch out his arm,
running the wooden stick right through Morbius'
heart as he was gliding through the air. That
doesn't work on Morbius. He's not a real vampire.
It's. Stakes through the heart don't actually
do anything, nor do holy water or garlic or
things like that. I'm pretty sure getting impaled
would do something to Morbius. I mean it would,
like he'll be out of commission for a bit as
he regenerates his heart using his healing
factor. But you know, he's not out of the match.
And suddenly, like swamp thing, his head freakin'
explodes into shredded lettuce. Because Bloodstone
is gonna unleash two Goliath rounds from her
shotguns at him point blank. Goliath rounds?
Yeah, it's like getting hit with a bus. I guess
it's a good thing that Swamp Thing doesn't really
care about that. He'll be fine. Meanwhile,
Manbat, he's gonna dive bomb right into Manthing
at full speed, just splattering him into canned
spinach. Like all over the battlefield. Oh,
really? Yeah. You do know that Manthing is
full of like, sulfuric acid. So he's like splattered
all over Manbat, meaning Manbat essentially
is just burning himself alive. I take it back!
That was a really dumb move. And then- and
then Man-Thing, he's gonna reform from the splatter,
and Manbat's like, he's done for. He's burned
all over his body, like his flesh is burning
off all over his body, and he's just gonna
finish Manbat off by ripping off Manbat's Manbat-Thing.
What? He's done, he's out. Manbat dies. He
can't survive that. What a way to go. That was
literally like the worst death we've ever had
in any of these team duels. That was so dumb.
Manbat is dead now, but- Meanwhile, Deadman,
using his superior agility, he's gonna evade
this Daniel brother voodoo ghost, and he's
gonna leap into Bloodstone's body, and he's
gonna use her red gem to blast Daniel, like,
out of existence. Okay, yeah, I mean, it's a
magic blast. I think he could do that, yeah.
And then, he's gonna take one of her knives
and use it to slice her own throat, like cutting
off the Bloodstone, which causes Morbius to
become, like, overwhelmed with blood drink
her dry, removing bloodstone from the match.
That's messed up. Well, I mean, like Morbius
was regrowing a heart at this time. But I guess
the sight of seeing bloodstone bleed from her
neck would compel him to gather his strength
to go feast on that because he can't help himself.
But the bloodstone makes her blood toxic to
vampires. Yeah, it doesn't matter. Dead men
cut that off when he slit her throat, too. So
OK, so Morbius takes out bloodstone, which
is fucked up and like Blade is going to be like
really pissed off. You know, he's not having
any of that shit. That's everything that he
stands against. So Blade would at this point
probably kill Morbius for killing Bloodstone.
This is an interesting turn of, I'm gonna allow
this. I'm gonna allow this. I mean, it's what
would happen. I think, so he's gonna chop off
Morbius' head, pick it up and like shove it
in front of Dead Man's face since he can see
him, you know, due to the Eye of Agamotto spell.
So Morbius' vampiric eyes, they're gonna mesmerize
Dead Man giving Doctor Strange enough time to
freaking cast Deadman into like the dark dimension.
Deadman's gone. Wait, so Blade decapitated Morbius,
but used his vampiric gaze from his head to
stun Deadman? Yeah, yes, yes. Like, uh, Perseus
did with Medusa. I just recently watched Clash
of the Titans. That may be where I'm getting
this from. Okay, Deadman's gone, but meanwhile,
Constantine and Jason Blood, they're gonna be
working together on exercising Xerathos. from
Ghost Rider, who I imagine is back on his bike
and you know is pretty hard to capture, alright?
Yeah. Now Dr. Strange killed Etrigen, but that
just sends Etrigen back to hell, where Jason
Blood can resummon him. So as Constantine is
distracting Ghost Rider, that's what Jason
Blood does. He's like gone, oh form of man.
No, no, no. Before he can even finish this.
First of all, the spirit of the Seraphim didn't
just banish Etrigen back to hell, it fucking
destroyed his ass. What? But second of all,
it doesn't matter regardless because... Before
Jason Blood can even finish performing this
transformation incantation, he just gets run
over at full speed by Ghost Rider's motorcycle.
He's like, one, two, cheese! It's cold! So
freaking Jason Blood is dead. Wow. And as Ghost
Rider rides past Constantine, he's gonna yank
him by his collar while he's riding. You know,
he's gonna like stand up and surf on his bike
as he's holding onto Constantine, and he's just
gonna peer into his eyes and do the pen and
stare on Constantine, forcing him to relive
all the pain that he's ever caused on others.
For Constantine, that's a lot. So the Hellblazer
is just gonna go out in a blaze of glory, going
to hell for all the shit that he's done, finally.
Yeah, that pen and star would absolutely destroy
Constantine. But it's a good thing that's not
Constantine, I guess. Because instead of exploding,
Constantine's skin just like sloughs off like
dead leaves. It was actually Black Orchid pretending
to be Constantine. The real Constantine is actually
nearby, having finished like an exorcism spell
that causes Ghost Rider in his entirety to get
sucked into this tiny vial in Jon's hands with
the Seal of Solomon on it. Boom. Ghost Rider
is out of the match. You just got conned! Why
would the Pennanesther work on Black Orchid?
She's a hero. She's not a criminal. Well, no,
she's done some shit in her past. She's very
mysterious, right? But like even in the comics,
like when she was taken over by Hecate, like
she destroyed the Parliament of Tres. She's
done some shit. You can't say she hasn't. But
I mean, that's not really her sins. Like, I
don't think the Pennanesther would actually
kill Black Orchid. No, no, she's not dead.
But but she is likely overcome with the fear
and the pain that she's inflicted. And so Man-Thing
is gonna capitalize on it. Since she feels fear,
Man-Thing is just gonna burn her and tear her
to shreds. So Black Orchid's now out of this
match. That's right, because he's attracted
to fear. Well, he's not attracted to it. It
makes him uncomfortable, so he tries to get
rid of it. Okay, so RIP Black Orchid. Meanwhile,
Zatanna and Swamp-Thing, who by this point
has regrown his head, are going toe-to-toe with
Dr. Strange. Now Swamp-Thing, he creates these
duplicates of himself, and together, They manage
to bind Dr. Strange's hands, which allows Zatanna
to hit him with this massive energy blast. Well,
Dr. Strange has, like, magical blast resistance,
as it were, you know? So, this magic blast,
I'm gonna say it's not gonna kill him or anything.
If it's really that strong, it'll probably knock
him unconscious. But before he loses consciousness,
he's going to eject his astral form. And he
can still do magic in his astral form. And
in his spirit mode, he's going to recognize
that swamp thing... is essentially also an
astral form just inhabiting this massive plants.
So he's gonna pull out Swamp Thing's spirit.
What's Swamp Thing's real name? Alakolland.
But Swamp Thing isn't actually Alakolland.
It was an entity that thought it was Alakolland
for a time. Well he's gonna pull out that entity
and he's gonna take him up onto the astral plane
where Dr. Strange turns into like this giant
fiery beast that just burns Swamp Thing and
all of his incarnations and the green itself.
It's just all gonna burn. Dude! Dr. Strange
just fucking killed everybody. If the green
is gone, there's no more plant life. Yeah, just
in the DC universe. That's fine by me. Well,
so in the battlefield, no one knows really what's
going on, but the swamp things just disintegrate.
And Dr. Strange's astral form goes back into
his unconscious body. I think Constantine would
have seen what happened, you know, on the astral
plane, because he's psychic, right? So before
Dr. Strange's astral form could return to his
body, Constantine's just gonna perform this
spell that banishes Dr. Strange's astral form.
to hell, like preventing him from returning
to his comatose body and eliminating him from
the match. First of all, Dr. Strange would
go to heaven. So he's trapped in heaven. No,
he went to hell. That's where Constantine sends
people. So essentially, Dr. Strange is in the
afterlife now. He's out of this match. Right.
But it would take time for Constantine to invoke
this spell, right? So right after he finishes,
he finds that a glaive has just decapitated
him. Thrown by Blade. What? Yeah. So Constantine's
head falls off. and the glaive returns to blade
like a boomerang and he just catches it like
a badass and like removes his sunglasses and
is like some motherfuckers always trying to
ice skate uphill
Okay, I did not see Constantine being taken
out with a sword or a glaive, but his trench
coat is demonically possessed All right So upon
Constantine's death it's gonna fly off of his
body and just wraps around blades face and neck
Just smothering and strangling him. Well blade
could just cut that jacket off. No big deal
No, because as blade is trying to cut it off
Zatanna causes all of blades weapons to transform
into like liquid which allows blade to get
strangled and he's out of the match What's the
spell for turning blades into liquid? Oh gosh.
Take your time. Nort-ot, do you kill? Something
like that. Okay, so Blade is gone. He's been
smothered to death. But Man-Thing appears behind
Zatanna and just slashes her across her back,
leaving these painful burning slash marks. Okay,
but Zatanna, she's gonna turn around and just
compress Man-Thing's matter into like this crystal
ball. And then she's gonna like lock this crystal
ball in a magic chest that just appears. And
then wrap that chest in like magic chains.
And then just cause the whole chest to disappear.
Presto, chain Joe. That was like a pretty elaborate
elimination. She had to get rid of him. And
I think I only have one guy left. Yeah, actually
it's just Zatanna and Brother Voodoo now, I
believe. I wasn't even keeping track. So if
it's Brother Voodoo versus Zatanna, of all the
magics that Zatanna is well versed in, I bet
you one of them is not necromancy like Brother
Voodoo is. He's gonna raise all of his fallen
comrades, including Blade, Morbius, Bloodstone,
Dr. Strange. They're all gonna come back in
zombie form under Brother Voodoo's command.
What? So really, it's Brother Voodoo and the
Marvel zombies against Zatanna. And they're
all just gonna freakin' dogpile on her and
feast on her flesh. I mean, she could just set
them on fire before like, any of them even
get close though. That's not how you kill a
zombie, fool. All you did was just turn him
into fire-covered zombies. They're still lurching
forward, they're still tackling, they're still
feasting. Well, little did you know though,
that Zatanna was actually possessed by Deadman
at the time of her death. Because he could teleport
between planes of existence. So when Doctor
Strange banished him, he just came right back
in the nick of time. And since these zombies
have been given new life, Deadman, he's gonna
duplicate himself and take control of each
one. Brother Voodoo no longer has any control
of these guys. So they turn on him. Well then
at this point brother Voodoo would just blast
all the zombies heads off and be the last survivor
No, no, cause Deadman is an acrobat He's gonna
use his superior agility to dodge like any
magic blast that brother Voodoo may send at
the zombies to defend himself Acrobatic zombies?
What is cooler? So the dead man zombies are
just gonna tear brother Voodoo apart and give
Justice League Dark the win I disagree I think
brother Voodoo kills the zombies and then destroys
dead man using Voodoo giving Midnight Sons the
win Well, let's take it to the stats and see
what happens Alright yeah, either Dead Man Zombies
feast on Brother Voodoo, or Brother Voodoo
vanquishes Dead Man. We'll run the simulations
and be right back with the results.
Alright, that was a spooky good time. I always
enjoy these team duel matches. This one got
pretty interesting because I felt like there
were a lot of possessions and like forcing
other people to do things through magic and
stuff. Yeah, yeah, it got pretty crazy. I think
that's why I kind of lost track of who was still
alive and who was dead. So we ran the simulations.
Basically, when it comes to team duels, we don't
run sets of data against each other. We run
matrices. So it's all seven of the Justice League
Dark characters against all seven of the Midnight
Suns characters. Yeah, I was pretty surprised
to see how these stat totals added up. The
teams were pretty even, even though I would
say that these teams specifically, probably
more so than any of our other previous team
duels, had a pretty wide range between like
really powerful characters and really weak characters.
Well, that was also the case for our JSA vs.
Fantastic Four duel, but yeah, same here. Now,
for purposes of balance, when we determine
who's going to fight in these team duels, we
kind of pair characters up against each other.
So the pairings for Justice League Dark vs Midnight
Suns were Zatanna vs Doctor Strange, Constantine
vs Brother Voodoo, Swamp Thing vs Man Thing,
Echigan vs Ghost Rider, Black Orchid vs Bloodstone,
Man Bat vs Amorbius, and Dead Man vs Blade.
But that's just for balance. Every character
is fighting every other character. Looking at
the results, Doctor Strange was definitely
the most powerful character out of both teams.
He won a whopping 84%. of all of his fights.
Yeah, he was definitely the most powerful character
out of both teams. But Swamp Thing wasn't too
far behind him as my most powerful character,
winning over 75% of his matches. I only had
a total of three characters on the Midnight
Suns who had a win rate above 50%. Besides
Doctor Strange, that was Brother Voodoo and
Ghost Rider. Justice League Dark had a few
more people with an over 50% win rate, including
Swamp Thing, Zatanna, Constantine, and Ettrichin.
But you had the lowest win rates as well. Yeah,
Deadman had the lowest win rate, honestly,
because his stats... He's a ghost, his stats
aren't that great. So he only had a win rate
of like less than 15%. And considering he's
going up against a bunch of like magicians
and sorcerers and stuff like that, it kind of
makes sense. And Black Orchid and Manbat didn't
fare too much better either, with their win
rates both in the 30s. Your weakest character
was Bloodstone. It was either Bloodstone or
Manthing, they were also both in the 30s. They
were almost tied, basically. Manthing, even
though he's seemingly a powerhouse, he's just
not... very impressive statistically given that
he doesn't really have a mind, you know? But
I have the final results between these two teams
Justice League Dark and Midnight Suns. Who
do you think came out on top? I'm gonna say
I'm gonna say Midnight Suns because both teams
have a large disparity in terms of power levels,
but Dr. Strange is the most powerful statistically.
And plus the Midnight Suns didn't have anyone
as low as Deadman. So since I have the most
powerful and you have the least powerful, I
think I got this. Even though freaking Instagram
doesn't agree On our Instagram poll, two thirds
of the voters, 67%, said that they think Justice
League Dark is gonna win. But I think that's
because the Midnight Suns aren't very popular.
Right, they haven't had a movie like Justice
League Dark has. And their game hasn't come
out yet. Well, let's see how close our Instagram
followers were. The winner of the matchup between
Justice League Dark and the Midnight Suns is
Justice League Dark. No. Yes, psych. They won.
52.3% of the team matches. Wait, how much? 52.3.
523 of the 1000 matches between both teams.
So, Midnight Suns won 477. Yes, yeah. I mean,
that's pretty close. I mean, it's like the
least close team duel we've ever done so far,
actually. The rest of them have been closer
than this. Your mom has been closer than this.
That's stupid. That doesn't sound right to
me. Dr. Strange, he's got a... find more powerful
Marvel characters to add to his team next time.
Because although Dr. Strange was the most powerful,
you know, the combined might of Zatanna, Constantine,
Swamp Thing, and Etchigan was just too much
for your team to handle. Yeah, I guess Man-Thing,
Bloodstone, Blade, and Morbius were a little
bit lower on the spectrum. But I thought Dr.
Strange could compensate for that. Yeah, I guess
he's the Sorcerer sub-prime. Well, the Justice
League Dark are the Justice League dorks. I
fucking suck. That was bad. That wasn't bad.
I'm pissed off. I got nothing. I'm actually
heartbroken right now because I love Marvel's
supernatural characters. But whatever, I'll
get you on the next team duel. Yeah, that'll
be in April and we're gonna be doing our very
first villain team duels. We're gonna be pitting
Batman's Arkham villains against the Sinister
Six. Right, yeah, and this is gonna piggyback
off of the Spider-Man No Way Home movie, which
we suspect will feature the Sinister Six. So
that'll be a fun one. We're talking like Joker
vs. Green Goblin, Scarecrow vs. Mysterio, Penguin
vs. Vulture, Mr. Freeze vs. Electro. Clayface
vs Sandman, and Bane vs Kraven the Hunter.
Yeah that's gonna be an awesome matchup. I can't
wait for that one. But that does it for this
duel. Let us know what you guys thought about
Justice League Dark vs Midnight Suns by writing
to us at dyna or by visiting us on Facebook,
Instagram, or Twitter. You can find links to
all of our accounts by checking out our show
notes or visiting our website dynamicduel.com.
And on our website you can also find a link
to our Patreon page where we offer bonus content
including bonus episodes and duels. monthly
live movie watch alongs, collectible pinsets,
and access to our Discord server. Check it out
right after this episode, our lowest tier is
only $2 a month, which is also the cost to subscribe
to the show on Spotify. Subscribe now to access
over 200 archived episodes of this podcast.
And don't forget guys to also use code dual
20 at cufflinks.com to get 20% off any order
and to listen to Batman the Audio Adventures
on HBO Max. Our next episode, next week's episode
is going to be another review. This past week
we got the last episode of Doom Patrol Season
3, so we're going to be reviewing that. Yeah,
it's another review, but luckily Doom Patrol
is a good show. Definitely check it out on
HBO Max if you haven't already. But that does
it for this episode, we want to give a big
thanks to our executive producers, John Spees,
Ken Johnson, Jace Crump, John Storosky, Zachary
Hepburn, John Beccinina, Mitchell Phipps, Dustin
Belcombe. Salvador Hernandez Contreras Jr.
and Levi Yeaton for helping make this podcast
possible. And we'll talk to you guys next week.
Up up and away, true believers.