This is a Dynamike Network podcast.
Welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin brother, Marvelous
Joe. And in this episode, we're doing a duel
between two evil Superman-type characters from
alternate dimensions, Ultraman against Hyperion.
Hyperion's not evil. What are you talking about?
It wasn't he like a bad guy for a while. No,
he's like he's misguided sometimes. We'll just
say that. But he's a hero. Pretty sure in supreme
power, he was bad. That was the even Marvel
continuity. Those Marvel Max. OK. Anyway, Hyperion's
a good guy, and he's going to beat the shit
out of Ultraman. That's all you need to know.
And all you need to know is I got I don't know.
I got nothing. I'll think of something later
on in this episode. Before that, we're going
to break down the comic book movie news from
the past week, of which we have some casting
news. Millie Alcock has been cast as Supergirl
in the DC Universe, and Geraldine Viswanathan
and Lewis Pullman have been cast in the MCU's
Thunderbolts. As always, we list our segment
times in our episode description, so feel free
to check out the show notes if you want to skip
ahead to a particular topic. Our artificially
intelligent dual simulator, AJ-9K, has a quick
message for our listeners, so listen up. Why
hello there. Do you love listening and chatting
about Marvel and DC? Then become a part of
the dynamic dual community on Patreon, where
you can choose from three tiers. The dynamic
two-o tier lets you listen to this podcast without
ads and gives you access to its discord chat
group, where you can chat with Johnny DC and
Marvelous Joe. The Fantastic Four tier gives
you that and more with two bonus episodes each
month, including bloopers and top ten shows
where Johnny and Joe count down your favourite
Marvel and DC subjects. The X-Force tier makes
you an executive producer of Dynamic Duel, where
every month you help the host choose what to
review and who to fight against each other.
And finally, the Dynamite Podcast Network tier
allows aspiring podcasters to create their own
battle-focused show using this Monte Carlo
simulator.
Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone who supports
the podcast. Guys, be sure to tune into the
Max Destruction Podcast which is part of the
Dynamike Podcast Network which pits your favorite
action heroes from film and television against
each other This week hosts Ken and Scotty,
you're gonna find out who'd win in a fight between
Robocop and Wolfcop. And on the Send Your World
podcast, hosts Zachary Hepburn speculates on
fights between your favorite anime characters.
This week, we'll find out who would win between
Fire Forces Takihisa and Hinawa versus Blue
Exorcists Yukio Okumura. And on the Console
Combat podcast, hosts John and Dean find out
who'd win in fights between your favorite video
game characters. In yesterday's episode, they
continued into round three of their tournament
speculating on who would win between Assassin's
Creed's Ezio Auditore vs. Sonic the Hedgehog's
Tails and Metal Gear's Revolver Ocelot vs.
Mortal Kombat's Scorpion. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com
or click the link in our show notes to listen
to all of the shows in the Dynamike Podcast
Network. But with that out of the way, quick
to the no prize! A No Prize is an award Marvel
used to give out to fans. Our version, the
Dynamic Dual No Prize, is a digital award we
post on Instagram for the person that we feel
gave the best answer to our question of the
week. Last week we asked, who is your favorite
villain from a Marvel or DC television series
and why? And this is coming off the news that
Wilson Bethel will be returning as Bullseye
in the Daredevil Born Again Disney Plus series
next year. We got quite a few answers. So let's
break down the honorable mentions before revealing
this week's no prize winner. Our first honorable
mention goes to... Miggy Mathengian, who said...
Hey what's up guys, it's Miggy. My favorite
DC TV villain is Eivartan from The Flash Season
1. I think his motivation was pretty unique
because he just wanted to get home, so you
can sympathize with that while still disliking
his methods. Also his relationship with the
protagonist was also very unique because it
started out out of pure resentment, but it
evolved into a love-hate mentorship. Thanks
guys. Yeah, Eobard Thawne was the reverse Flash
antagonist in the Flash CW series. Now the character
was played by multiple actors over the course
of the series, namely Tom Kavanaugh and Matt
Letcher, but every time he was on screen, he
was a force to be reckoned with. He was just
pure evil in how much he wanted to bring down
the series protagonist Barry Allen. Yeah, I
never watched The Flash show, but it seemed
like Reverse Flash was the best out of all the
villains that were on all the seasons. Yeah,
I didn't watch the whole thing, but I did watch
the final battle of the final episode and that
was pretty cool. It was really cool to see the
Reverse Flash and all the other speedsters
that The Flash had gone up against throughout
the series in that episode. Great answer, Miggy.
Our next honorable mention goes to Travis Herndon,
who said, Hey guys, Travis here. So my answer
would have to be Bushmaster from Luke Cage Season
2. I think he was an amazing villain, had a
tragic backstory, an interesting power set.
I really love him as an antagonist and a villain
and seeing that fight, that main fight between
him and Luke Cage was cool as well as them
teaming up really makes me wish that he could
have stayed as sort of a new partner for Luke
Cage in Season 3, but hey, what will he do?
Yeah, Bushmaster in season two of Luke Cage
was incredible. He had a great backstory and
he was quite the formidable challenge for Luke
Cage. Like he totally whipped his ass early
on in that season. And then, you know, Luke
Cage had to grow as a character in order to
finally face him again. The Luke Cage television
show had some great villains across its two
season run. Like in the first season, you had
Cottonmouth and Black Mariah. Although you also
had Diamondback, which really sucked. But like
season two had no such villain problem. because
Bushmaster was just phenomenal. And Black Mariah
was phenomenal too. Yeah, Luke Cage season two
is like one of the most underrated, I think,
seasons of superhero television in existence.
I feel like not enough people saw that, and
it was really good. In part, thanks to Bushmaster,
fantastic villain. Great answer, Travis. Our
next honorable mention goes to Judson Batty,
who said. Hi guys, Judson Batty here. I think
that the best villain from a Marvel or DC project,
show is Deathstroke from Arrow season two.
He was played incredibly well with subtleties
that made the performance never get boring.
He was recognizable as the character from the
comics and made a hero as selfless as Green
Arrow for his own life and not just that of
those around him, which is quite an impressive
feat. Yeah, Deathstroke has been the villain
of a number of television seasons, including
like Titan season two. but he was never more
frightening and more effectively used than
in Arrow Season 2. The fact that you set up
this character of Slade as being an ally of
the main character Oliver Queen throughout Season
1, only to see that relationship deteriorate
in the Season 2 flashbacks, and just see the
consequences of everything that happened on
the island in the present day, it was terrifying.
He was like a great monster movie character,
almost like Michael Myers or something like
that, but like... smart and just deadly and
fast, really wicked, really awesome, fantastic
answer. We want to give a quick shout out to
Colby Hentges and Scott Camacho for taking the
time to visit our website and leave their answers
as well. But the winner of this week's Snow
Prize is Alex Fowler who said, What is up,
gentlemen? This is Alex Fowler, huge fan, been
listening for a long time. My favorite depiction
of a villain in a Marvel or DC series. I'm a
DC fan, but I've got to say. Vincent D'Onofrio's
depiction of Kingpin in Daredevil is just great.
He's complex. You understand why he is the
way he is. He's depicted intensely. He's just
great, guys. You know what? You guys are doing
a great job. Keep up the great work. Huge, huge
fan. Take care. Bye-bye. Yeah, I mean, this
is the answer, right? Vincent D'Onofrio's Kingpin
so epitomizes the character and I think even
enhances what everybody's perception of him
was from the comics. You know, Kingpin was
always the fat bald guy who for some reason
could go toe to toe with Spider-Man. I think
watching Vincent D'Onofrio's intensity as he
plays the character, not only in Daredevil
seasons 1 through 3, but also I think in the
recent Echo television series, the character
is so believable, so threatening. Vincent D'Onofrio
is phenomenal. Yeah, I'm a DC fan just like
Alex, and even I admit that Vincent D'Onofrio
was like born to play Kingpin. It's a sight
to behold. And there's not much more to say
about it than that. Great answer, Alex. You
win this week's No Prize. If you the listener
want a shot at winning your own No Prize, stay
tuned to later on this episode when we'll be
asking another question of the week. And now
that that's done, onto the news.
Okay, so a few weeks ago we learned that the
finalists for the casting of Laura Zor-El,
aka Supergirl, in James Gunn's DC Cinematic
Universe was down to McDonaldi from some Disney
zombie TV show and Millie Alcock from HBO's
House of the Dragon. And it's been revealed
that Millie has won the role of Supergirl, beating
out McDonaldi. Not gonna lie. I was actually
rooting for McDonaldy for the role. And this
is probably because my daughters have watched
that zombie Disney television series. So I was
familiar with her. I haven't seen House of
the Dragon yet, but now I know I definitely
need to because I've heard great things about
Millie Alcock's performance in that even though
she's only in two episodes of the series. But
yeah, she's our super girl. And all I want to
know is how the heck did like this eight year
old get this part? Right. Not going to lie.
That was my first reaction to. Apparently though,
she's 23 years old. She looks 12, but she's
23. She's 5'5". You know, I've seen some fan
art, some better than others, where she looks
fairly decent as the character. Not as good
as McDonnelly, but I'm not gonna hold that against
her, because again, she's supposedly a fantastic
actress. And I like the fact that James Gunn
would choose the better actress over the more
comics accurate depiction, I guess you could
say. She's like the female Will Poulter. She
looks exactly like Will Poulter. You know who
you look exactly like? You? That's fair, I
shouldn't say anything else then. Ha ha ha.
To be fair, I stole the Will Poulter line from
Meggie on the Discord channel. That's what he
said and it cracked me up because it's true.
She just does not look like Supergirl to me
and I'm really thinking that we may need to
realign our expectations for this role. She
may not look like Supergirl. but she may act
like Supergirl. And according to some of the
scans I've seen from the woman of tomorrow
trade paperback, the character is a total badass.
Oh yeah, Supergirl in that comic series is
a very hard edged character. And maybe Millie
Alcock has that hard edge to her that the other
actresses did not. Ultimately, she's the lead
in a film that is probably gonna be really,
really expensive to make. So I hope they put
their chips in the right hand. But I'm optimistic
because so far the rest of the other casting
in the DCU has been spot on. Yeah, Millie Alcock
might be all, you know, 5'5 and look like she's
a teenager, but I will also admit that she
also looks feisty and like she could kick some
ass if she needs to. We've recently seen Supergirl
in quite a few projects as of late, including
the Supergirl television series and the Flash
movie. So Millie Alcock has some big shoes to
fill. And that brings us to our question of
the week.
Who has been your favorite Supergirl actress
across film and television, and why? Record
your answer at dynamicduel.com by clicking on
the red microphone button in the bottom right
hand corner of the screen which will prompt
you to leave us a voicemail. Your message could
be up to 30 seconds long, and don't forget to
leave your name in case we include you on the
podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer, and
award that person a Dynamic Duel No Prize that
we'll post to Instagram. Be sure to answer before
February 10th. In Marvel News, we learned this
past week that the Thunderbolts has cast two
new roles in the film, including Geraldine
Viswanathan. We're not quite sure who she's
playing yet, but it appears that Lewis Pullman
has nabbed the role of Robert Reynolds, aka
The Sentry, taking over the spot that was left
behind by Steven Yeun. Now Lewis Pullman is
an actor that I'm not too familiar with other
than his parentage. He is the son of Bill Pullman.
who we all know as the badass president from
Independence Day, and also while you were sleeping.
And a bunch of other great stuff. Bill Pullman's
a great actor. His son, I'm hoping, is great
as well. He was in Top Gun Maverick, and he
was also in Bad Times at the El Royale, and
recently Lessons in Chemistry with Brie Larson.
I saw parts of all three of those, and I don't
remember him. Well, you're gonna remember him
now that he's playing the Sentry. He looks the
part, you know, he looks the part of Bob Reynolds,
I should say, maybe not necessarily the Sentry.
It will be interesting to see him bulked out
with like golden flowing hair and stuff like
that. But you know, he has time to bulk up
if he needs to. I don't know if they're going
to go for like the drug addict Rob Reynolds
look or the totally shredded sentry, but we'll
see. Whatever actor was going to play the sentry
needed to convincingly convey both a light and
a dark side, considering the sentry's dark
shadow self is the void. So it's really a dual
role here. Do we know what character Geraldine
Viswanathan is going to play? No, but she did
replace Ayo Adabiri, who had to depart the
project due to scheduling issues, just like
Steven Yeun. Cool. This is like the most boring
casting announcement ever. It's like a whole
bunch of people we don't know playing roles
that we aren't sure about. What are you talking
about? We know who the Sentry is. Yeah, but
I mean, the Sentry is not that cool. Do you
want to die? I mean, we all die someday.
Sentry is badass, you don't know what you're
talking about. And I think this is pretty interesting
news. I'm looking forward to seeing how Lewis
Pullman plays the character. You know what
we need? We need like some fucking costume tests.
Like we're getting casting news without costume
tests. I wanna see these people in the roles.
Kevin Feige and James Gunn, come on. Well,
maybe we'll get some news at this year's San
Diego Comic-Con. I bet this year's Comic-Con
is gonna be so cool. Like I'm looking forward
to it more than I have in a long time. It's
because there's only a few movies coming out
this year. So there's a lot more to look forward
to in the coming years than there is this year.
Yeah, the sooner we get through this year,
the better, man, for real. Let's just fast forward
2024. Just have a ton of fun because time flies,
apparently. No, I'm looking forward to Deadpool
three. Better be lots of fun. It will be. We
all know it will be.
But I think that does it for all the news for
this episode, so let's go ahead and move into
our main event where we find out who would win
in a fight between the Crime Syndicate's Ultraman
versus the Squadron Supremes Hyperion.
Alright, Ultraman versus Hyperion. Ultraman
of course is the evil Earth 3 counterpart to
Superman and Hyperion is the Superman, one of
many Superman counterparts in Marvel. You've
got Hyperion, you've got Gladiator, you've got
the Sentry, you've got a whole bunch of people
because Marvel's a big ripoff company. I mean
not really though if you think about it. I
just did and I just revealed that was true.
Now Hyperion is cool. He's the leader of the
Squadron Supreme, who is a team that had a fantastic
run in the mid-1980s, even before Watchmen
came out, that really started to break down
and deconstruct the superhero mythos. And really
what Marvel was doing was they were trying to
tell the story using these DC character archetypes
to explore what would it be like if they were
more authoritarian and really do things that
DC couldn't really do with their IP at the time.
And really, it was a huge influence, I think,
to Alan Moore's Watchmen, who told a similar
story, but those characters were more analogs
to the Charlton characters, but fantastic stories.
You know, I knew about the Squadron Supreme
legacy as being something like that. I didn't
realize it came before Watchmen, though. I'll
have to read it. It's good. It's really good.
I'll definitely go into major spoilers about
that story within my Hyperion background, but
I hope it'll convince a lot of people to check
it out. Yeah, there's... several versions of
Hyperion, right? Correct, yeah. So there was
the original Hyperion from the Squadron Supreme,
there was Hyperion from Squadron Sinister,
which was an evil doppelganger version of Squadron
Supreme, then there was also Supreme Powers
Hyperion, which was a line in the Marvel Max
imprint, and then two other Hyperions found
their way to the Marvel Primary 616 universe.
I don't think we've mentioned this yet, but
this is actually a multiversal duel. That's
the whole reason why we're doing this. Oh yes,
so of course Ultraman was in the recent Justice
League Crisis on Infinite Earths Part 1 animated
film. We were supposed to review that after
Echo, so this is a tie into that. But also,
you know, between Crisis on Infinite Earths
and Madame Web, we were looking to do these
multiversal duels. So this is one of them. Yeah,
we've done several multiversal duels over the
course of this show, including Batman Beyond
vs. Spider-Man 2099, Cosmic Gross Rider vs.
The Batman Who Laughs, and we've done Kingdom
Come Superman vs. Maestro. So it's always neat
to explore these universes outside of the primary
Marvel and DC continuity. Yeah, and we'll do
so in the characters' backstories. Before that,
let's go to our sentient duel simulator, Alfred
Jarvis 9000. AJ 9K. Tell our listeners how you
go about determining a winner in our dual matchups.
Yes, of course, sir. The way I determine a winner
between the contestants is by running 1000
Monte Carlo simulations using the characters
statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation is a probabilistic
model used to determine outcomes through random
sampling. In this case, I randomize the statistics
along a normal distribution as a way to simulate
the many variables that can occur during battle.
The stat parameters are based on the official
Marvel power grid. from which the DC characters'
statistics are extrapolated. Additional stat
categories are included, such as range, damage
potential, versatility, and perception, in order
to create a more detailed and accurate simulation.
The results of the 1,000 simulations provide
a percentage of wins for each character. The
contestant with the higher percentage is declared
the victor, as they have a higher probability
to win any given battle. In an equitable pairing,
neither character should win 100% of the matches.
The comic book stories have shown that there's
even a way for Batman to defeat Superman, so
the confidence rate of my method falls in line
with the precedents that have been established
in the source material. My mathematical simulations
are without subjectivity or bias. Feats are
not the sole consideration, nor are fan votes
tabulated for determination of the winner.
Thanks AJ9K, before we run the simulations though,
we'd like to break down each character's histories
and abilities before improvising a scenario
on how we imagine one of the 1000 simulations
would play out beat for beat. And I believe
it's my turn to go first with the Marvel backstory,
so let me go ahead and tell you all about Hyperion.
Beyond the Earth-616 mainstream Marvel universe,
an adjacent reality known as Earth-712 was the
home of a team of superheroes called the Squadron
Supreme. The team was led by a hero named Hyperion,
who was the last surviving member of a race
of Eternals whose planet had died. Sent to live
on Earth as a baby, Hyperion was raised by
a loving family who named him Mark Milton, and
instilled a strong moral code. Growing up as
the hero Hyperion, he moved to Cosmopolis, where
he worked at a newspaper as a cartoonist, and
fell in love with reporter Lonnie Latimer. During
his career as a superhero, he befriended fellow
adventurer Nighthawk, aka Batman, and the two
joined forces with Power Princess, aka Wonder
Woman, Amphibian, aka Aquaman, the Blur, aka
Flash, Dr. Spectrum, aka Green Lantern, and
the Skrull hero Skymax, aka Martian Manhunter,
to form the Squadron Supreme. Together, they
were the world's finest protectors, rising to
fight and defeat any threat to planet Earth.
In one adventure, The elder of the universe
known as the Grandmaster created an evil duplicate
of the team and called it the Squadron Sinister.
In a cosmic wager against a variant of the
villain King the Conqueror, the Grandmaster
pit the Squadron Sinister against Earth-616's
Avengers in a contest of champions. The Avengers
won the battle. Like, super easily mind you.
Bullshiiiit. And though the Grandmaster and
King's bet was over, The Avengers later found
themselves accidentally transported to Earth-712,
where they met the Squadron Supreme. After
a brief misunderstanding where they confused
them for the Squadron Sinister, the two teams
eventually joined forces to defeat a mutant
villain named Brainchild, before the Avengers
returned to their home reality. Later, the Squadron
became mind-controlled by an evil entity known
as Overmind, and the team ravaged the United
States into an apocalyptic state. However,
Earth-616's Defenders team were able to travel
to their dimension and free the Squadron and
combine their might to defeat Overmind. The
Defenders then returned to their home reality,
but Earth-712's America was left in chaos. You
can learn more about King the Conqueror and
his duel against Professor Zoom, more about
the Avengers and their duel against the Justice
League, and more about the Defenders and their
duel against the Suicide Squad. With the United
States falling apart, Hyperion and his teammates
decided that with their combined knowledge
and power, they could restore the country and
transform it into a utopia. The team declared
martial law and usurped the US government, implementing
a series of sweeping changes that included
a behavior modification program to inhibit the
criminal instincts of prison inmates. They
also destroyed all firearms and replaced them
with personal force field devices, and developed
medical cryogenic technology to preserve those
who were near death until such time they could
be restored to health. Though the squadron's
reforms successfully turned the planet into
a paradise without crime, poverty, and sickness,
their new system of order was not without its
setbacks. The hero known as the Golden Archer,
aka Green Arrow, was removed from the team
after it was discovered he was using the behavior
modification process to brainwash his teammate
Lady Lark aka Black Canary, to fall in love
with him. Nuke, aka Firestorm, went on a crazed
rampage after learning the radiation from his
body had killed his parents, forcing the Squadron
to kill him. Several members left the Squadron
after becoming disgusted with its methods,
including Amphibian and Nighthawk, the latter
of whom created his own team of heroes and
former villains called the Redeemers who would
rise to oppose the Squadron. The two groups
clashed in a brutal fight in which several members
on each side were killed. When Hyperion saw
Nighthawk perish in the battle, he became horrified
at what was happening and realized that his
late friend was right. That although their intentions
were good, the Squadron Supreme had become
dictators in a totalitarian state of their own
creation. They surrendered control of the US
back to the government and the team disbanded.
Shortly after, Hyperion recruited the remaining
members of the squadron to save Earth-712 from
the Nth Man, aka Phantom Stranger, who was
inadvertently nullifying dimensions he was traveling
through. Several members of the squadron died
trying to stop him, though they ultimately were
successful. Hyperion, however, ended up stranded
alongside several other squadron members in
the Earth-616 reality for a time, where he
ended up occasionally partnering with the Avengers.
Eventually Hyperion and his fellow teammates
found a way back to their home reality, where
they found that in the absence of the Squadron,
the world governments had formed a global directorate
that were using the technology of the Squadron's
old Utopia project for themselves. The founding
members of the Squadron Supreme banded together
once again, along with the son of the original
Nyhawk and a team of dimension-hopping heroes
called the Exiles. Together they battled and
defeated the global directorate, returning
freedom to the world, and allowing society to
progress democratically and without superhuman
involvement. Unfortunately, all of Earth-712
came to an end, however, when realities in
the Marvel multiverse began colliding and destroying
each other in a series of cataclysmic incursions.
Hyperion became his universe's only survivor,
floating in the void left where his dimension
was destroyed. There, he was discovered by AIM
scientists from Earth-616 who held him in captivity
until he was rescued by the Avengers and joined
their ranks for a time as they tried to stop
the incursions. After the events of the secret
wars that rebuilt the multiverse, Hyperion
formed a new squadron supreme composed of heroes
who had also survived their own universe's
destruction. And that's his backstory.
capable of absorbing cosmic radiation and channeling
it like a nuclear reactor for a variety of
effects. This includes vastly enhanced durability
and strength, able to lift well in excess of
100 tons. He can fly and move at hypersonic
speeds, and has superhuman senses including
hearing, smell, and sight, able to see in all
wavelengths of the electromagnetic spectrum
like infrared and x-rays. He can also fire beams
of intense radiation from his eyes called atomic
vision. In addition to his physical attributes,
he is a capable leader and an experienced combatant.
He has only one weakness, and that is to Argonite,
a substance native to his birth planet. Which
is named Argon? It's never named actually. I
guess you could assume that his birth planet
was Argon or Argo. Friggin no shame. How are
you with the fact that you're essentially using
a DC character in this match? I don't know what
you're talking about. I hope it feels good.
How do you figure? Hyperion is basically a DC
character. I don't see it. Cosmopolis, Argonite,
Atomic Vision. You totally lost me, man. Alright.
Well, let me move on to Ultraman. Within the
DC multiverse, there exists a universe that
is a dark reflection of DC's Prime Universe,
in which heroes became villains and villains
became heroes. In this universe, the planet
Krypton never exploded, The infant son of the
Kryptonian criminal, Jir-Lil, was rocketed
from the planet to Earth, encountering Kryptonite
adrift in space along the way, which empowered
the infant in this universe rather than weakening
him. Gaining new powers each time he encountered
the smallest fragment of Kryptonite, the Kryptonian
grew to become a superpower despot known as
Ultraman. During his conquest and destruction,
he encountered four other powerful and tyrannical
beings, Overpowering and Johnny Quick and together
they joined to form the Crime Syndicate of
America Able to overpower any resistance the
Crime Syndicate conquered most of the world
with Ultraman gaining new powers Every time
they encountered new stashes of Kryptonite
on Earth Eventually Ultraman gained a new type
of supervision that allowed him to see into
other universes Setting his sights on Earth's
one and two the home dimensions of the Justice
League and Justice Society, respectively. You
can learn more about the Justice League and
Justice Society in their team duel episodes
against the Avengers and Fantastic Four. Eager
to test the strength of the crime syndicate
against the champions from these other worlds,
Ultraman and his allies nonetheless proved themselves
incapable of overpowering the combined might
of the heroes from Earths 1 and 2. Ultraman
himself fell after the heroes of Earth 1 exposed
him to a chunk of kryptonite so large, his body
went into a paralytic shock after the acquisition
of so many new powers. which eventually wore
off. Ultraman and the crime syndicate were
imprisoned by Green Lantern in an interdimensional
prison between universes, though they eventually
escaped and Ultraman was rescued by Lex Luthor
and Alexi Luthor of Earths 1 and 2 in order
to kill the supermen of their worlds. With the
help of Alexander Luthor Sr. of Earth 3, a
hero, the supermen were able to defeat and
Eventually, a wave of antimatter tore through
the DC Multiverse, destroying entire universes.
Though the Crime Syndicate teamed up with Alexander
Luther Sr. and other heroes of Earth 3, nothing
they did was able to stop the wave. Resigned
to fight to the very end, Ultraman charged
the oncoming wave at full force and was instantly
erased from existence, just before the rest
of his universe also vanished. After the Crisis
on Infinite Earth's event concluded with the
destruction of the multiverse and the creation
of a single universe, the villain's psycho
pirate revealed years later the ability to psychically
manifest any being from the former multiverse
from his mask, known as the Medusa Mask, which
was revealed to contain Ultraman. Years later,
it was also revealed that Ultraman's mind was
rescued prior to its destruction by the antimatter
wave by the Legion of Superheroes villain, Saturn
Queen. a powerful psychic from the future who
attempted to use Ultraman to take over the bottled
city of Kandor in the present, though her plan
was thwarted by Supergirl. While the Multiverse
had collapsed during the Crisis on Infinite
Earths, there did still exist an antimatter
counterpart to the Positive Matter Universe,
home to another antimatter version of the Crime
Syndicate and a new version of Ultraman. This
antimatter version was formerly a human astronaut
named Lieutenant Clark Kent, whose spaceship
exploded in hyperspace, and his body was rebuilt
by aliens using anti-cryptonite radiation in
an effort to build the ultimate weapon. Clark
gained control of his new powers that he had
developed before the aliens could control him,
however, and Clark returned to Earth. His mind
now warped and used his powers to take over
the planet. Anti-Matter Ultraman was revealed
to be married to Superwoman, the Anti-Matter
Lois Lane, though she was having an affair
with Anti-Matter Owlman. Ultraman's powers were
contingent upon exposure to Anti-Cryptonite.
Though Anti-Matter Lex Luthor attempted to save
his Earth from the Crime Syndicate's rule,
with help from the Positive Matter Universe's
Justice League, his plan ultimately failed,
as the Anti-Matter Earth recognized the Crime
Syndicate as their legitimate leaders. Eventually,
the Crime Syndicate grew bored with Earth's
collective Stockholm Syndrome and decided to
attack the antimatter planet of Kord, home to
the Weponeers that created the very first yellow
power ring. Their battle ended up creating a
positive matter wave that spread throughout
the antimatter universe, altering its reality.
In an attempt to better understand what was
going on, Ultraman and his allies visited the
positive matter universe disguised as their
counterparts and eventually decided to stay.
Though they were fought back to their dimension
by the Justice League, only to learn that now
everyone on their Earth hated them. When 52
new universes were created during the Infinite
Crisis, Earth 3 was reimagined. This time,
Krypton was destroyed by the Anti-Monitor. and
the young Cal Ill's father sent him from the
dying planet into space to grow in power and
eventually get revenge. After landing on Earth,
the infant Cal forced two alcoholic drug addicts
named Jonathan and Martha Kent to adopt him,
only to later murder them when he turned seven
years old. He eventually became Ultraman and
formed the Crime Syndicate, once again taking
over the world only for it to be destroyed
by the Anti-Monitor just like Krypton. It was
at this time that Darkseid on the Prime Earth
gained the anti-life equation, initiating the
final crisis, and allowing the Crime Syndicate
to escape Earth-3, though they became trapped
in an interdimensional limbo, save for their
versions of Alfred and the Atom, who managed
to escape to the new Prime Continuity established
after the Flash reset DC's timeline. After the
Earth-3 Alfred and Adam orchestrated a clash
between the Justice League, JLA, and Justice
League Dark Teams, a portal was opened that
unleashed Ultraman and his allies in the Prime
Universe while also trapping many of its heroes.
The crime syndicate was eventually stopped by
Earth's villains, primarily by Lex Luthor,
with Ultraman as the syndicate's only survivor.
Imprisoned by the Justice League upon their
return, he was eventually set free during a
war between Darkseid and the Anti-Monitor to
help stop them. Ultraman put up his best fight
against the Anti-Monitor, but was easily killed
by him in an anti-matter energy blast. The Earth-3
universe eventually healed itself, and Ultraman
and the Crime Syndicate were reborn, and eventually
encountered by Superman's son, Jonathan Kent,
whom Ultraman imprisoned and eventually confessed
to that he had no real friends. Ultraman and
the crime syndicate joined Perpetua, the creator
of the multiverse, when she and Batman from
across the Dark Multiverse attempted to destroy
it. Owlman, feeling betrayed that he was not
one of the Dark Multiverse Batman and seeking
revenge against Perpetua, shot and killed Ultraman
and Superwoman with a gun from Kord. Your deal
destroyed and recreated Earth-3, whose new
version of Ultraman obtained a device that allowed
him to traverse the multiverse and kill any
Superman that he came across. Though Val Zod,
the black Superman of Earth-2, and Jonathan
Kent tried to stop him, Ultraman banished Val
Zod to the Phantom Zone, and though Jonathan
nearly defeated Ultraman, Ultraman was killed
by the Superman from the Injustice Universe,
Earth-49. And that's his backstory. Powers-wise,
Ultraman's physiology allows him to gain vast
power from the radiation of his native planet,
Krypton. Though he can store that radiation
in his body, the presence of Kryptonite strengthens
him even further. He possesses vast strength
and durability, ultra-speed, and flight. He
also has ultra-senses, such as hearing and
sight, and he can emit heat vision from his
eyes. His one weakness is that his powers will
diminish over time without access to kryptonite
and this accelerates when exposed to solar
radiation. He's more powerful in the dark. DC
has no shame. Like, how dare they rip off a
hero- Themselves? His beloved and popular as
Ultraman. What? The true Ultraman, which is
the Japanese Ultraman.
Actually, I think our Ultraman came before that
one. Do you know that for sure? Yes, I do.
The Japanese Ultraman came out in 1966. And
the Silver Age version of Ultraman came out
in 1964. So boom, damn it. Everyone copies DC,
gosh.
But now that we've got their histories and abilities
out of the way, let's speculate on how one
of the 1000 simulated matches will go. The winner
is determined by simulations, not this speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how this fight could
play out. AJ9K, what are the rules of our speculation?
Well, I should say there are no rules, other
than the characters have no prior knowledge
of the other going into the fight. All they
are aware of starting out is that the other
character is a threat that needs to be eliminated.
For the speculation, the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a non-descript
environment that will have no bearing on the
match itself, as no environmental statistics
are considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. Alright
then, let's get into it. Ultraman and Hyperion
meet on the battlefield. Who goes first? Alright,
I'm going to say that since Ultraman is more
evil and unhinged than Hyperion, he's going
to go first. He's gonna start by crushing a
kryptonite rock that he had and just snorting
that thing off the back of his hand. So now
that he's more powered up, he's gonna ultra-speed
dash over to Hyperion and just like crush his
neck in his bare hands. Where did he get this
kryptonite rock from? He has a stash of kryptonite
that he keeps around him. He knows he needs
it. Alright. Alright, well Hyperion sees Ultraman
do this line of kryptonite crack and Hyperion's
against it. He's like, drugs are illegal and
bad. So he's going to hold out his hand as Ultraman's
flying at him. And he just catches Ultraman's
fist in his palm and uses that momentum to slam
Ultraman into the ground, just creating this
massive crater that shakes whatever planet they're
onto its core. OK, I mean, that's fine. Ultraman,
you know, he's going to ultra spin his body,
just drilling deep into the ground before he
explodes back out right beneath Hyperion, just.
pushing him into space while heat visioning
his face off. Okay, well as Hyperion's being
carried into space, he's gonna counter Ultraman's
heat vision with his atomic vision. And like
the two eye beams are like canceling each other
out and Hyperion is gonna grab Ultraman by the
head and then he's just gonna head butt the
shit out of him, sending Ultraman crashing back
into the ground from space. And then Hyperion
with his eyes still glowing. He's going to fly
down and slam into Ultraman with this badass
superhero landing pose. Except that Ultraman
sees Hyperion speeding down toward him, and
he's going to use his ultra breath to freeze
Hyperion, causing him to just shatter once
he hits the ground. So now there's blood and
ice everywhere. Yeah, Ultraman's blood. What?
Because he just got freaking decimated by a
Hyperion ice missile. Like, ice isn't really
going to hurt. Hyperion like he wouldn't freeze
through that fast considering his body is built
like a nuclear reactor Fine, I guess Ultraman,
you know has the wind knocked out of him or
something. He could withstand nuclear bombs
Okay. All right. So while Ultraman is winded
Hyperion yanks him by the cape and swings him
around and around and around Choking Ultraman
by his collar and then Hyperion let's go the
cape Tossing him like a hammer throw and sending
Ultraman crashing right into a nearby moon.
On moon? Okay Uh, so Ultraman, you know, he's
gonna grab that moon and just hurl it right
back down toward Hyperion, just annihilating
him and the planet he's on. Is he strong enough
to do that? Yeah, uh, actually Ultraman had
to move the moon between the sun and the Earth,
so that the Earth was in a constant state of
eclipse, and so he wouldn't be degraded power-wise.
Oh, interesting. Okay, well, Hyperion sees
that this moon is gonna crash down onto him.
I don't think he would have any choice but
to, like, meet it head on by flying through
it, kind of like a bullet through a bowling
ball type situation, which is, you know, it's
going to hurt him. Like a bullet is not going
to go through a bowling ball unscathed. The
same goes for Hyperion. You know, it's going
to hurt him. He's going to be drained pretty
badly, but he is going to be angry and he's
going to be like, you throw another moon at
me. I'm going to lose it. So Ultraman throws
another moon at Hyperion. What? For where? I
don't know. But. The thing is, this one randomly
happened to be filled with kryptonite. Who knew?
Oh my God. Basically, when it explodes upon
hitting Hyperion, it's going to turn Ultraman
into like a god and now he's like this reality
warping telekinetic and he's going to mentally
explode Hyperion's atoms across the universe.
Just with a thought. Boom. Dude, that's environmental.
You can't say the moon has kryptonite in it.
Like who's to say? I mean, I do. I just I just
said that. Like you're the one who brought
the moon into it. Well, most planets have a
moon like that seems fairly easy to assume.
But also, like you said in Ultraman's bio that
too much kryptonite exposure paralyzed him
because he like developed too many powers at
once or something. Well, that's a silver age
version. I don't care. I want to say instead
of killing Hyperion, Ultraman's like, eh, it's
too much power and he's going to go into a coma,
at which point Hyperion. It's gonna take this
opportunity and he's just gonna fly Hyperion
into the nearest sun, which is just gonna render
Ultraman powerless and like ultra dead. Alright,
that would definitely kill Ultraman. So yeah,
we'll leave it there. Either Ultraman is killed
by being thrown into a sun and just losing
his power from the solar radiation, or he gets
ultra powered up from a whole bunch of kryptonite
around him and just erases Hyperion from existence.
Yeah, sounds pretty good. Let's go ahead and
enter the character stats, run the simulations
and come back with a winner. AG9K, hit it!
Inputting data, running calculations, processing
results, simulations complete. Okay, so these
characters are both Superman, analogs, ripoffs,
whatever you may want to call them. They're
basically Superman. So it's not surprising that
their stats were basically equal to Superman's.
Yeah, they had the same speed, evasiveness,
durability, strength, damage level, fighting
skill, range, versatility. They were pretty
much a match. Which is pretty rare. Like, we
don't come across that too often. We try not
to. Right. Because if we know the character
stats are the same, we run into a situation
where it's a guaranteed coin flip, you know,
50-50 on who wins. But you know, it could still
be anybody's fight. According to our Instagram
poll takers, they believe that Ultraman is ultimately
going to come out on top in this match. Sixty
two percent of those who voted in Ultraman's
favor. And I'm going to chalk that up to them
thinking it was the Japanese Ultraman. There's
a photo of Ultraman on the pole. I don't really
know anything about the Japanese Ultraman, so
I don't know what his powers are, but I'm still
going to say he's more popular. Well, let's
find out who the winner is. H.E. 9K, the results,
please. Hey, you are, sir. All right. The winner.
between the Crime Syndicate's Ultraman and
the Squadron Supreme's Hyperion is... Hyperion!
Really close though, almost a coin toss, Hyperion
won 517 matches out of the 1000 simulations
whereas Ultraman only won 483. So Hyperion's
51.7% over Ultraman's 48.3%. And I knew this
was gonna happen once I realized that I had
to concede Ultraman's intelligent stat. He's
definitely not as smart as Superman, so we
figured he's not as smart as Hyperion. Yeah,
Hyperion's not the sharpest tool in the shed,
you know. He was the one who thought that it
would be a good idea to essentially become
a dictator over an authoritarian state, but
he's also not so stupid to think that he can
punch an antimatter wave and have that be okay.
Yeah, that was kind of humorous when I read
that. So, I mean, I guess I can't be too bummed.
The good guy won, even if it is a Marvel guy.
Still a rip off, though. Essentially, you could
say Superman wins in the end in this match.
No, I period would beat him to what? No, no,
he loses just on originality points alone.
Like that needs to be a new stat originality.
DC is going to top out Marvel every time in
that stat. As we've said many times on the show,
it's not about who does it first. It's about
who does it better. And if there was a quality
stat, Marvel would be higher because their
characters are just better. So it would even
out. If you're arguing that Hyperion is better
than Superman. Yes. I would have fucked. Duh.
Obviously. Next time I see you, when's the
next family dinner? Be prepared. I'm not afraid
of you. Well, I guess that does it for this
duel. Let us know what you thought about the
results by writing to us at Dynamic Duel Podcast.
at gmail.com or by visiting us on Instagram,
which you could find a link to in our show
notes or by visiting our website at dynamic
duel.com. And on our site, you could also find
a link to our Patreon page where you could join
our dynamic two tier and chat with us and fellow
listeners are fantastic for tier, which gives
you bonus content each month, our X force tier
that makes you an executive producer of this
podcast, or our newest here that lets you join
our dynamic podcast network. Please don't forget
to rate the show. on Apple podcasts, Spotify,
Podchaser, or on our website. Next week's episode
is gonna be another duel, another multiversal
duel, where we pit two characters outside of
the main Marvel and DC continuity against each
other. This time we're going to find out who'd
win in a fight between Rocket, who is the sidekick
to Icon. Yeah, from Milestone Comics. Versus
Spider-Gwen, who everybody knows is a popular
Spider-themed multiversal character. And of
course, that episode is in lead up to Madam
Web, which we'll be reviewing the week after.
But that does it for this episode. We want
to give a big thanks to our executive producers,
Ken Johnson, John Storowski, Zachary Hepburn,
Dustin Belcombe, Miggy Mattenkian, Brandon Estergard,
Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yaton, Nick Abato, Austin
Wazilowski, AJ Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Adam
Spies, Andrew Shunk, and Dean Molesky for helping
make this podcast possible. And we'll talk to
you guys next week. Up up and away, true believers.
Watch me lean and watch me rock Superman that
hoe.