This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
Welcome to the dynamic duel podcast a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC By comparing
their characters and stat-based battle simulations.
I'm marvelous Joe and I'm his twin brother Johnny
DC And in this episode we're going to find
out who would win in a fight between Sandman
the Wesley Dodds version of the character against
Madame Webb the Julia carpenter version of the
character Yeah, there's multiple iterations
of these characters with the same names, but
these two specific characters are pretty badass.
They wear trench coats. They have premonitions.
They knock other people unconscious. We thought
it was a pretty good match up. And this, of
course, is in lead up to our next episode,
which is a review of the Dead Boy Detectives
on Netflix, which takes place in the Sandman
universe. A different Sandman. Right. But Wesley
Dodds is like Sandman adjacent. It's... Don't
worry about it. You'll learn all about it later
on. Yeah, I mean, and also the Madame Web movie
came out a few months ago. So this is kind of
timely. Yeah, I guess I forgot all about that
movie. Before we get into that duel where we
input the character statistics and run 1000
simulations to find out who would win, we're
going to break down the latest comic book movie
news that came out this past week, of which
there were two items, both DC animation related.
We got the official trailer for My Adventures
with Superman season two. and a teaser for
Justice League Crisis on Infinite Earths Part
3. As always, we list our segment times in
our episode description, so feel free to check
out the show notes if you want to skip ahead
to a particular topic. Our artificially intelligent
duel simulator, AJ9K, has a quick message for
our listeners, so listen up. Why hello there.
Do you love listening and chatting about Marvel
and DC? Then become a part of the dynamic duel
community on Patreon, where you can choose
from three tiers. The dynamic 2-0 tier lets
you listen to this podcast without ads and
gives you access to its Discord chat group,
where you can chat with Johnny DC and Marvelous
Joe. The fantastic four tier gives you that
and more with two bonus episodes each month,
including bloopers and top 10 shows where Johnny
and Joe count down your favorite Marvel and
DC subjects. The X-Force tier makes you an executive
producer of Dynamic duel. where every month
you help the host choose what to review and
who to fight against each other. And finally,
the Dynamite Podcast Network tier allows aspiring
podcasters to create their own battle-focused
show using this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny
and Joe will help you develop your show, provide
graphic support and consultation, and get you
simulation results to announce on your show.
Pitch the twins your show via email at dyna
or by reaching out to them on social media.
Check it out at patreon.com slash dyna your
pip cheerio.
And on the Senjou World podcast, host Zachary
Hepburn speculates on fights between fan favorite
anime and manga characters. This Thursday, we'll
find out who would win between Gabimaro the
Hollow from Hell's Paradise and Rekka Hanabishi
from Flame of Rekka. On the Console Combat
podcast, hosts John and Dean find out who would
win in fights between popular video game characters.
In yesterday's episode, they found out who would
win between Knuckles from the Sonic the Hedgehog
games and Donkey Kong. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com
or click the link in our show notes to listen
to all the shows in the DynaMic Podcast Network.
But with that out of the way, quick to the
no prize! A no prize is an award Marvel used
to give out to fans. Our version, the Dynamic
duel No Prize, is a digital award we post on
Instagram for the person that we feel gave
the best answer to our question of the week.
Last week as a tie-in to the Deadpool and Wolverine
trailer, we asked... other than Wolverine, what
Fox X-Men character do you most hope appears
in Deadpool and Wolverine and why? And we got
three answers so let's go ahead and run down
our two honorable mentions as well as the no
prize winner. Our first honorable mention goes
to Judson Batty who said, Hi guys Judson Batty
here. In the last episode you called me a Brit.
I'm actually Australian but whatever. I would
say that the Fox X-Men character I want to
come over the most is Caliban from Logan because
I feel like he could really fit. the theme
of the movie. He could help them find a character
or a place that they need to do because that
is pretty much what he does. And I feel like
it would really be a way to tie film back into
Logan. We do have two important corrections
to make from Judson Batty's answer in the last
episode. The first correction is that, I don't
know what I was spoken. Sean Connery is not
alive anymore. I said he was still alive, but
he actually died in 2020, and apparently I'm
still in denial. So, sorry about that. Also,
apparently Judson Betty is not from Great Britain,
but is in fact Australian. Oh, Guten Tag! Let's
go skiing in the Australian Alps! Listen to
Mozart's music in Vienna, the capital city of
Australia. But no, Caliban was in the Logan
movie played by Stephen Merchant and he was
fantastic in that role. He did unfortunately
die, but that doesn't mean we couldn't see a
variant of him show up in Deadpool and Wolverine.
And like Judson said, probably direct them to
a specific goal or location since his whole
mutant power is the ability to track and detect
the location of other mutants. Yeah, I totally
forgot about this character in Logan. I would
love to see him return to the role. Oh, yeah,
for sure. He played the character way better
than the guy who played him in X-Men Apocalypse.
That was just weird. Already blocked it. Great
answer, Judson. Let's go ahead and move on
to our next honorable mention, which goes to
Corey Wooten. Who said? Hey, guys, Corey Wooten.
I'd like to see Alan Rickson as Sabretooth with
an aesthetic more like with the correct aesthetic
more like the original X-Men, but also with
the ability to think, speak, and deliver lines.
Yeah, Sabertooth would be fantastic to see go
up against Wolverine and Deadpool. Alan Richson
never played the character, but he would make
a fantastic Sabertooth. He was played in the
original movies by Tyler Maine and then, of
course, by Leif Schreiber in the X-Men Origins
Wolverine movie. Yeah, my vote is for Tyler
Maine to return. I would love to see that.
And maybe we will. It would be cool to see Sabertooth,
Wolverine and Deadpool in a fight considering,
you know, they're all slashy, heely guys. They
would just tear each other to bits and like
nothing would happen. They just fight endlessly.
That'd be really cool to see. So great answer,
Corey, but the winner of this week's snow prize
goes to Travis Herndon, who said, What's up,
Dynamic Dudes? Travis here, shout out to my
other twins. So my answer would have to be
Mystique, particularly Rebecca's version of
the character. It would be cool to see that
actress come back to reprise her role as Mystique.
Also, you could make a little joke that Deadpool
or something brings up the fact that she's been
running around naked in all three of the X-Men
movies she was in. only for her to maybe shade
shift into her comic book accurate suit and
give him the middle finger. So yeah, that's
my pick. I love this answer. I think it would
be so cool, yeah, to have Rebecca Romaine as
Mystique show up in the void at the end of
time. And like no one just comments on the fact
that she's essentially naked. And Deadpool's
like looking around like Wolverine is not saying
anything. And Deadpool's like, is seriously
no one going to say anything? Lady, put your
fun bags away. This is Disney now. It's family
friendly. And then like she just beats his ass
or something like that. I would love that.
If this doesn't happen in the movie, I'm actually
going to be a little bit disappointed. It will
still exist in my headcanon if it's not in the
film. Yeah, I always preferred Rebecca Romaine
to Jennifer Lawrence for Mystique. I hope we
get a return of Rebecca Romaine for this movie.
And going off of what Travis said, yeah, it
would be cool to then see Mystique shape shift
into her more comic book accurate costume with
the white dress. Yeah, because we've never
seen that on film. That'd be awesome. Yeah,
and I hope that's what they do for the MCU
version of the character. So congrats to Travis
Herndon. Fantastic answer. You win this week's
No Prize. If you're the listener, want a shot
at winning your own No Prize. Stay tuned to
later on in this episode when we'll be asking
another question of the week. And now that
that's done, on to the news.
Alright, so last week we got our first look
at the second season of My Adventures with
Superman, an animated series that's premiering
on Cartoon Network, but also showing on the
Max platform. Of course, we reviewed My Adventures
with Superman season one last year. It was
a really, really well done modern anime version
of the Superman mythos. And the way it ended,
it set up season two. So I've been really looking
forward to this first trailer. and it didn't
disappoint. No, it looks like it continues everything
that made the first season so well done. And
not being, you know, a DC or a Superman guy
myself, I really enjoyed the show and it's,
yeah, modern take on the character of Superman.
The way they adapted all of these characters
to kind of fit in with Kryptonian technology
and stuff like that, I thought was really fascinating.
And they really left that first season on quite
the cliffhanger with Brainiac and General Lane
and all that stuff. So yeah, this is gonna be
exciting. Yeah, definitely more of the same,
which is great to see the opening shot of the
trailer. It looks like Lois Lane and Jimmy
Olsen are encountering a Kryptonian, although
I'm not sure who it is, whether it's General
Zod or someone else, maybe. I guess we'll see.
It looks like the trio of Clark Kent, Lois
Lane and Jimmy Olsen are getting up to their
wacky hijinks as they have in the past. It
was a fun reminder that Jimmy Olsen is now a
millionaire. So, you know, he's. talking at
this conference, that's gonna be interesting
this season. But what I thought was really
cool was to see the return of Lex Luthor, who
we got like a tease of in the first season,
but it looks like it's officially him. He was
Ivo's assistant or something like that. And
it makes sense that with Ivo out, Lex Luthor
may be taking over the tech space and competing
with Jimmy Olsen. I thought it was cool how
we got our first looks at characters like Metallo,
Parademons, and of course, Supergirl. Oh yeah,
Supergirl was a huge surprise. She, of course,
is in the poster for the upcoming season. And
I was really happy to see that she'll be here.
Clark Kent does encounter a baby version of
her at the very end of the trailer, although
I'm not sure if that's just like a flashback
to the past when she was also, you know, rocketed
off of Krypton before it was destroyed or not.
I guess we'll find out. Another villain we
get to see in this trailer is Brainiac. And
it's gonna be really interesting to see his
dynamic with Zod, because it looks like a lot
of the Kryptonian tech is powered by Brainiac.
I think we also get our first look at John Henry
Irons' steel in this trailer too. It's more
like a prototype mech suit. I'm not quite sure
if it's steel, but that would be cool if we
got him in this season too. Yeah, I would love
that. I imagine they would kind of take the
same route they took with his origin in the
New 52, tying him into Metallo. At least I
hope they do. But it looks like this season
kicks off at the end of this month on May 25th
on the Cartoon Network. The shows will be then
showing up on MAX the following day. We're
definitely going to review this upcoming season
and I can't wait to do so. I can't wait to
see all the cool new villains that they adapt
for this show. Yes, definitely one of the more
interesting aspects of the show. But speaking
of villains, that brings us to our question
of the week.
Who is your favorite Superman villain and why?
This is going to be a tough one, there's a
lot of great Superman villains out there. Really
dig deep on the why portion of your answer.
Record your answer at dynamicduel.com by clicking
on the red microphone button in the bottom
right hand corner of the screen, which will
prompt you to leave us a voicemail. Your message
could be up to 30 seconds long, and don't forget
to leave your name in case we include you on
the podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer,
and award that person a dynamic duel no prize
that we'll post to Instagram. Be sure to answer
before... May 11th. In other DC animated news,
we got the first official teaser trailer for
Justice League Chrysalis Infinite Earths Part
3. Of course, we reviewed Part 2 in our last
episode. Spoiler alert, it wasn't that great
and it really didn't get me too pumped up for
Part 3. And I can't say this official teaser
did either. It's very much a tease. And primarily
it's a tease that Lex Luthor in the whole crisis
mix although it's unclear as to which version
of Lex Luthor this is. The teaser kind of makes
it seem like he's a bad guy but if this is Lex
Luthor from Earth 3 and maybe he survived that
universe's destruction somehow then he could
be a huge asset to defeating the Anti-Monitor
without anyone realizing it. Of course we get
to see the Anti-Monitor in this trailer and
he looks terrible. I just gotta say it. He looks
nothing like he does in the comics. I wish
he was more comics accurate because this is
a weird look for the character. This is a little
bit generic. He's just this figure all in black
with red eyes. And that's it exactly. That's
it exactly. Lame. I often boast about how good
the character design is in the tomorrow verse,
but this makes me embarrassed of the tomorrow
verse. Just this design. It was interesting
to see the Batman animated series, Batman and
Joker. It seems like we're doing a lot more
universe hopping, including the DC animated
universe, which incorporates like Superman
cartoon, the Batman cartoon, the Justice League
cartoon. That's pretty interesting. That was
very interesting. I'm wondering how many other
different animated universes are going to pop
up. Like Teen Titans go? No idea. That would
be weird. They've already had their own crisis
on their show, so I would be surprised, but
You know, anything's possible, honestly. I
really do hope that this is good. I really do
hope that this brings closure to decades of
DC's animated media, maybe going all the way
back to like Superman's Max Fleischer cartoons.
That would be really cool. And I think really
give us a good setup for maybe James Gunn's
new universe. That would be awesome. Do you
mean Creature Commandos, the animated series
that's coming out later this year? Yes, exactly.
That's scheduled to come out in late 2024.
as part of the whole Gods and Monsters chapter
of James Gunn's DC Universe. I'm not sure if
that's still the case though. I have a feeling
that might get pushed back to after Superman.
Or at least I wouldn't be surprised if it did.
There's no release date for this film yet.
At the very end of the trailer it just says
it's coming soon. I imagine sometime in the
fall. And when it does, we'll review it. Fingers
crossed it's good.
Alright, I think that does it for all the news
for this episode, so let's go ahead and get
into the main event where we find out who'd
win in a fight between Sandman, aka Wesley
Dodds, and Madame Webb, aka Julia Carpenter.
Alright, Sandman vs. Madame Webb. This is the
Wesley Dodds and Julia Carpenter versions of
the characters respectively. They're both kind
of pulpy characters in that they're terribly
mysterious and they wear trench coats and vaguely
similar power sets as well. Yeah, and that
their main ability is to incapacitate others,
you could say. But they also get premonitions
of the future and they both have kind of like
cool face gear, like Madame Webb wears these
glasses because she's blind and Sandman wears
this gas mask. which makes him look extra pulpy.
Wesley Dodds is a fantastic character. Yeah,
he's really cool. I'm a really big fan of the
character, especially the way they re-imagined
him in Sandman Mystery Theater, which was a
vertigo tie-in to the Sandman series. Speaking
of that, Jonathan, what's the difference between
the Wesley Dodds version of Sandman and the
Morpheus version of Sandman? They could not
be more different. So one of them is a detective
of sorts who uses sleeping gas. And the other
one is essentially the god of dreams or the
embodiment of dreams, you could say. Right.
The latter of which had a series on Netflix,
but the former of which, the guy with the sleeping
gas gun, he has played a part in the adventures
of the dream god version of Sandman. Yes, tangentially.
He's a character that has appeared in the Sandman
comics. And of course, everybody knows Madame
Webb. She is world famous now that she's had
her own film. Now in that movie, the character
was Cassandra Webb, who in the comics is an
old woman in a chair. She eventually passed
her powers down to Julia Carpenter, who was
played in the Madden Webb film by Sidney Sweeney.
This is all very complicated, but hopefully
the characters' backstories that we get into
later will help clear things up. But to explain
the methodology behind our duels, let's go
to our sentient duel simulator, Alfred Jarvis
9000. AJ and IK tell our listeners how you
go about determining a winner in our duel matchups.
The way I determine a winner between the contestants
is by running 1000 Monte Carlo simulations using
the characters statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation
is a probabilistic model used to determine outcomes
through random sampling. In this case, I randomize
the statistics along a normal distribution as
a way to simulate the many variables that can
occur during battle. The stat parameters are
based on the official Marvel power grid from
which the DC characters statistics are extrapolated.
Additional stat categories are included such
as range, damage potential, versatility and
perception in order to create a more detailed
and accurate simulation. The results of the
1000 simulations provide a percentage of wins
for each character. The contestant with the
higher percentage is declared the victor as
they have a higher probability to win any given
battle. In an equitable pairing, neither character
should win 100% of the matches. The comic book
stories have shown that there's even a way
for Batman to defeat Superman. So the confidence
rate of my method falls in line with the precedents
that have been established in the source material.
My mathematical simulations are without subjectivity
or bias. Feats are not the sole consideration,
nor are fan votes tabulated for determination
of the winner. Thanks AJ9K! Before we run the
simulations though, we like to break down each
character's histories and abilities, before
improvising a scenario on how we imagine one
of the 1000 simulations would play out beat
for beat. And I believe it's my turn to go
first with the Marvel characters backstory,
so let me tell you guys all about Madame Web.
Now the story of Julia Carpenter's transformation
into Madame Web begins with the story of her
predecessor, Cassandra Web, the original Madame
Web. Born in Salem, Oregon, Cassandra suffered
from a condition known as myasthenia gravis,
which left her blind and a quadriplegic confined
to a wheelchair. In spite of her physical handicap-
She developed a strong mind into her later
years that was able to tap into the web of life
and destiny, which is a five-dimensional construct
of all reality, past, present, and future. This
endowed her with psychic abilities, which she
used as a medium telling people's fortunes in
New York City, calling herself Madame Web.
It was in New York that Cassandra was first
visited by Peter Parker, who was shocked to
learn that she knew of his alternate identity
as Spider-Man. Cassandra assisted him in solving
several mysterious criminal cases, and she became
a valuable asset to Spider-Man's crime-fighting
career. You can learn more about Spider-Man
in his duel against Blue Beetle. Meanwhile,
a couple of decades prior to Cassandra meeting
Spider-Man, Julia Cornwall was born and raised
in Los Angeles, California to Walter and Elizabeth
Cornwall. She grew up and married her college
boyfriend Larry Carpenter, and the pair moved
to Denver, Colorado, where they had a daughter
named Rachel. Larry became a politician and
Julia joined a PR firm. Five years later, however,
the pair got a divorce and Julia was awarded
custody of their child. While living as a single
mom, Julia ran into her college friend named
Valerie Cooper, who was the chair of the U.S.
Commission on Superhuman Activities, a government
committee involved in dealing with the country's
growing number of superhuman beings. After several
failed attempts to control existing superpowered
beings, the Commission decided it was time to
create its own hero. To that end, they began
recruiting potential candidates for a classified
athletic study, and Chair Valerie Cooper enlisted
her friend Julia to take part in their experiment.
The Commission injected Julia with a formula
of rare spider venoms and plant extracts found
in the Amazon rainforest, which ended up gifting
her with an enhanced physiology and the ability
to produce strands of telekinetic energy that
manifested like webbing. As the sole success
of their experiment, Julia was dubbed by the
commission Spider-Woman, and they sent her into
the field as a superhero government operative.
Juggling her top-secret identity with being
a mother, Julia struggled in both her personal
life and with her activities as a secret agent,
receiving orders that occasionally put her
in conflict with other heroes such as the X-Men
and the Avengers. After helping the Avengers
escape the vault prison after they were arrested
on false treason Julia became a wanted fugitive
from the government. Exacerbating the situation,
Julia also found herself in a custody battle
over her daughter Rachel with her ex-husband
Larry, who eventually won due to Julia's absence
and moved to California. Still on the run, Julia
evaded authorities with help from Iron Man,
and she relocated to California to be closer
to her daughter. There, she joined the West
Coast Avengers branch, which ended her fugitive
status, eventually gaining back custody of
Rachel, as she balanced being a mom and an Avenger.
At this time, she revealed her superhero identity
to her daughter and her parents, who were initially
supportive but soon felt that her powers made
her unfit as a mother. After the West Coast
Avengers disbanded, Julia and her daughter
moved back to Denver, where she fought crime
and served as a reserve Avengers member. Eventually,
the stories of Cassandra Webb and Julia Carpenter
would cross when Cassandra's Granddaughter
Charlotte Witter began stealing the powers of
other spider-powered heroes, including Maddie
Franklin and Jessica Drew, the latter of whom
you can learn more about in our Queen Bee vs
Spider-Woman duel episode. The women teamed
up with Cassandra to defeat Witter, and eventually,
Julia had her powers restored by a recreated
spider formula and returned to crime fighting.
When the U.S. Congress introduced the Superhuman
Registration Act, which forced heroes to register
with the government or face prosecution, Julia,
now going by the code name Arachne, sided with
Iron Man's pro-registration side, but secretly
helped unregistered heroes evade capture, as
she privately disagreed with the legislation.
Julia was ultimately caught, however, and was
forcibly arrested in front of her daughter Rachel.
She was offered a pardon for her crimes, however,
provided she serve on the Canadian government's
new superhero team, Omega Flight, which was
a spinoff of the country's renowned Alpha Flight
team. Both Julia and Cassandra were kidnapped
by the family of Craven the Hunter, who planned
to sacrifice spider-powered heroes in an attempt
to resurrect Craven through an occult ritual.
The family slit Cassandra Webb's throat, who
psychically transferred her ability to mentally
access the Web of Life of Destiny into Julia,
making her the new Madame Webb. Spider-Man was
able to rescue Julia from being sacrificed
as well. though the Craven family was successful
in bringing Craven back from the dead, which
you can learn more about in our Vixen vs Craven
duel episode. And though Julia was now blind
due to her new insight into the past, present,
and future, her clairvoyance played a crucial
role in helping Spider-Man overcome threats
to New York, and she even saved his life on
multiple occasions. When she experienced a vision
of Spider-Man's death at the hands of Mephisto,
an elder demon of hell whom you can learn more
about in his duel against Sandman, Julia formed
a team of spider-powered heroes called the Order
of the Web, who fought to protect Spider-Man
and fight other supernatural threats. Powers-wise,
Madame Web has the combined power sets of her
former Arachne identity and the original Madame
Web. This grants her enhanced physicality,
including increased strength able to lift around
10 tons, increased agility, speed, and durability.
She can emit strands of telekinetic energy for
a variety of effects, including strands which
she can manipulate at will to swing from, ensnare
opponents, and use to bind herself to surfaces
in a wall-crawling effect. She can send out
these psionic strands to use as invisible feelers
to detect the environment around her and warn
her of impending danger for a spider sense
effect. Mataweb has access to see into the web
of life and destiny, which she can use to get
visions of potential futures, other locations
in the present, and the past. She has limited
telepathy, able to read minds and project her
thoughts into the minds of others, allowing
them to see her as an astral projection. She
is also an adept hand-to-hand combatant due
to her training from the Commission on Superhuman
Activities. Her one weakness is that she is
blind, but her psychic perception of her environment
makes this barely a handicap. And that's Madame
Web. So she's like a mixture between Daredevil
and Spider-Man. Uh, with a little bit of Professor
X thrown in there too. Okay. I'm not going to
lie. A little scared, a little scared, a little
bit. You should be. But I will argue that Wesley
Dodds is just the cooler character because
you really don't get cooler than Wesley Dodds.
He's so noir and like that pulpy kind of like
the shadow comes in. Avenger Spider-Man or no,
no. Fuck that guy. That guy's that guy's a
poser. Wesley Dodds is the real deal. Let me
get into his backstory. Now Wesley Dodds was
born in the 1910s to a Jewish couple, Edward
and Marina Dodds, though Marina died in 1917
while Wesley's father served in World War I.
Raised by his military father, Wesley traveled
the Orient, where he acquired various skills
such as herbalism and martial arts. After graduating
from college, Wesley briefly served as a pilot
for the US Navy until his father died.
Wesley also took on the same career as his father
had before the war, an investor. Wesley became
a wealthy socialite, though at night he was
plagued by nightmares of crimes, murders, and
a mysterious figure in a strange mask. Unbeknownst
to Wesley, the lord of the dream world, Morpheus,
had been imprisoned by a British occultist named
Roderick Burgess, causing many individuels
around the world to have strange sleeping patterns,
Wesley being one of them. After realizing the
events in his dreams were coming true, Wesley
decided he needed to do something about it
and created a secret laboratory in his basement
where he experimented with various herb and
chemical mixtures to craft a formula for a powerful
sedative whose vapors could put people into
a deep sleep. Initially using a WWI gas mask
to protect him from his own sleeping gas, Wesley
became a fedora-wearing vigilante known as the
Sandman. knocking out the criminals and serial
killers they had seen in his dreams. Early in
his crime-fighting career, he encountered another
masked vigilante, the Crimson Avenger, who Wesley
thought was a criminal, but turned out to be
his old college friend, the Travis. Lee gave
Wesley a design for a gas gun, which Wesley
crafted and perfected over the years, along
with various other gadgets, including a grappling
gun.
Wesley had met and fallen for Diane Belmont,
the daughter of New York City's District Attorney,
Larry Belmont. Within a year, Diane deduced
Wesley's alter ego as the Sandman and began
aiding him in his missions, often feeding him
information from her father's files and acting
as his getaway driver. When America became involved
in World War II, President Franklin Roosevelt
recruited Wesley and various other mystery men
to form the Justice Society of America. a team
of superheroes that you could learn more about
in our Justice Society vs. Fantastic Four episode.
While Wesley was away with the JSA, Diane decided
that for one sabotage case she had been working
on to don one of Wesley's Sandman outfits and
ended up being shot and killed by a Nazi agent.
Devastated, Wesley began wearing a new, more
colorful and superheroic outfit that Diane
had designed for him to fight crime. Wesley
also adopted Diane's young nephew. an orphan
named Sanderson Hawkins. Sandy idolized Sandman
and trained hard to be like him one day. Wesley
soon revealed his Sandman identity to Sandy,
and Sandy became his crime-fighting sidekick,
aiding him in their World War II adventures
with a new expanded wartime superteam known
as the All-Star Squadron. Hoping to improve
his crime-fighting abilities, Wesley engineered
a silicoid gun. which would have used irradiated
silicon to create constructs of sand and glass.
The device exploded upon its first use, however,
bombarding and infusing the radioactive particles
into Sandy, transforming him into a raging sand
monster. Though Wesley was able to sedate and
capture Sandy, he was unable to cure him, so
he kept him sedated and hidden in a glass chamber
in his basement. Wesley retired from superheroics,
as by this time, many of the Justice Society's
members were forced into retirement when the
US government began requiring all masked Avengers
to reveal their secret identities and operate
strictly under government orders. Wesley spent
decades in retirement trying to find a cure
for Sandy when an earthquake broke Sandy's
glass prison and caused him to go on a mad rampage.
Wesley donned his Sandman outfit once again.
and successfully stopped his former protege,
only to learn that Sandy had regained his lucidity
shortly after his imprisonment and had been
conscious all these years. Guilt-stricken,
Wesley retired once again, even going so far
as to get a psychiatrist named Dr. Raymond
Baxter to hypnotize him into forgetting he ever
was the Sandman. Wesley eventually remembered
his past, however, and along with other retired
former JSA members, came out of retirement
seemingly one last time to help the Norse gods
prevent the end of the world in Ragnarok in
a continuous and eternal loop within the realm
of Limbo. After the Crisis on Infinite Earths
event merged the multiverse into a single universe,
the JSA members eventually returned from Limbo,
and Wesley retired once more, dream free, and
now with Diane, who had never died in the new
timeline.
The two decided to liquidate all of their assets
and travel the world. She died shortly after
the two arrived in Tibet, and Wesley had one
final dream that predicted not only his own
impending death, but the location of who the
next Doctor Fate would be. After sending this
information to his old JSA allies, Wesley was
confronted by the evil
Rather than reveal Dr. Fate's location through
torture, Wesley threw himself off of a mountain
cliff, killing himself. He and Diane were buried
in Valhalla, a cemetery for superheroes, and
Sandy gave the eulogy. After the Flash reset
DC's continuity, Wesley Dodds was the commander
of a gove teleporting paramilitary force known
as the Sandmen on Earth-2. In DC's Prime Universe,
however, Wesley remained dead until Deadman
brought him back to life as a zombie detective
in order to help him in an unresolved case involving
a nigh death cult that Wesley had encountered
decades prior. You can learn more about Deadman
in our Deadman vs. Magic duel episode. Though
Deadman offered to return Wesley back to his
grave, Wesley agreed to help Deadman until
the case was finished. Sandman is cursed with
prophetic nightmares, though he is also a trained
martial artist, an expert chemist, and an accomplished
inventor, having devised several gas formulas
that include a powerful sedative and a truth
serum. He's also engineered a gas gun, a grappling
gun, an experimental silicoid gun, and a gas
mask that not only filters his breathing, but
also allows him to see through the gas and even
breathe underwater. That's the Sandman. Now,
I'm not gonna lie. I'm actually a really big
fan of DC's Sandman. He's probably my favorite
DC Comics character if I had to boil it down,
being a Marvel fan, you know? I just really
like the look and the pulpiness of the character.
You know, as iconic as someone as Ghost Rider's
look is, I think Sandman's look is just as iconic
with that gas mask and everything like that.
He's really cool. Oh yeah, just seeing like
those glowing eyes in the mist. like walking
through the fog with his fedora and trench coat.
It doesn't get cooler. It's weird, though,
that there are so many characters in Marvel
and DC named Sandman. Like you have the Spider-Man
villain who's made out of literal sand. You
have the God of Dreams Sandman, and then you
also have this Sandman who puts people to sleep.
And I just want to state that even though I
think the Wesley Dodds version of the Sandman
looks the coolest out of the three, Marvel
Sandman is still the better character. And you
can learn more about him in our Sandman versus
Red Tornado duel episode. where you'll find
out that he is in fact not the best of the
three characters. Judge for yourself is all
I'll say.
Where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
Dynomic Podcast Network presents Console Combat,
where video game legends brawl every Monday.
Dynamic Duel, where comic book titans smash
every Tuesday. Max Destruction, where the world
is at its limit. TV and action heroes battle
every Wednesday, and Sendro World, where anime
champions clash every Thursday. Join us as we
speculate on the matches and armed with the
power of mathematical simulations, discover
who will emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
Well, now that we've got their histories and
abilities out of the way, let's speculate on
how one of the 1000 simulated matches will go.
The winner is determined by simulations, not
this speculation, but it's fun to imagine how
this fight could play out. AJ9K, what are the
rules of our speculation? Well, I should say
there are no rules, other than the characters
have no prior knowledge of the other going into
the fight. All they are aware of starting out
is that the other character is a threat that
needs to be eliminated. For the speculation,
the contestants will begin approximately 50
meters apart in a nondescript environment that
will have no bearing on the match itself, as
no environmental statistics are considered
in my simulations. The contestants must earn
victory on their own merit. Alright then, let's
get into it. Sandman and Madame Webb meet on
the battlefield. Who goes first? I'm going
to say that Madame Webb goes first, and she's
going to get a premonition of her winning this
match. And she's like, I got this. No, because
Wesley already went first last night when he
choked about this match and how he wins. And
it all starts with Wesley whipping out his
gas gun and just flooding the environment with
sleeping gas. Madam Webb, she's going to fall
asleep. So match over. No, she's going to perceive
the gas cloud coming at her. And so she's going
to leap into the air. and generate this psionic
web and she just walks along it like a tightrope
walker above the cloud of gas and the gas isn't
gonna hide Sandman like she's still gonna be
able to perceive where he is through her psionic
web feelers. Well feel this! Sandman sees Madame
Web hovering over the gas cloud so he draws
his harpoon gun and fires it right at her and
that harpoon's gonna stick in her shoulder and
she's just gonna get yanked down into the gas
toward him like a fish on a hook. No, she- but
she has her own version of Spidey Sense, right?
So she's gonna detect this harpoon gun being
fired at her. She's gonna leap out of the way
off of her tightrope, and she's gonna swing
over to an area of the environment that isn't
filled with gas, but like 15, 20 meters away,
and she's gonna use her psionic webbing to
ensnare Sandman and yank him out of the gas
cloud toward her. And she's just gonna roundhouse
kick him to the floor. No, actually, all she
kicks is a trench coat. because he slipped
it off once he started getting pulled by her
webbing. And when she kicked the coat, she
actually broke a gas capsule that he had in
his pocket. So she just doused herself with
his sleeping gas and put herself to sleep. All
right. But as she's, you know, feeling herself
being sedated at the last second, she's going
to expel her astral form from her physical
body, which is now sleeping on the floor and
her astral spirit. is gonna reach out into
Sandman's mind so that he can see her. And he's
gonna be super confused as to like how she's
both sleeping on the ground and in front of
him. And she's gonna swing a punch at him.
And you know, he's gonna dodge it because he
doesn't know that she's actually incorporeal,
but she's gonna keep attacking him to buy her
time to wake up. Okay, well, I mean, to an
outside observer, Sandman's probably just swinging
wildly at the air. But he's a trained martial
artist, so he'd catch on over time when he realizes
that neither his or her attacks are landing,
right? So that's when he's gonna rush over to
Madame Webb's real body, you know, still on
the ground, and... I don't know, he's just gonna
start kicking the shit out of her unconscious
body? Well, if he's beating the shit out of
her on the ground, that's gonna snap her out
of her sleep, you know? Plus she's like really
durable, so Sandman kicking her, it's not gonna
hurt her as much as he'd probably like. So she's
gonna wake up and immediately she's gonna wrap
him up from head to toe in psionic webbing.
So like he can't move his arms, his legs, like
they're just completely ensnared. So he's gonna
fall over and she's gonna return the favor
by kicking the shit out of him while he's incapacitated.
And her kicks hurt a lot worse. All right,
well, I mean, little did Madam Webb know, though,
Sandman had a like maximum potent gas capsule
hidden in his sleeve, which he crushes, causing
a cloud of smoke to surround him. And when
Madam Webb breathes that in as she's bidding
the shit out of him, it's going to place her
into a lifelong coma that she never wakes up
from. Match over just as Sandman predicted.
He has capsules that can put people in comas.
Uh, yeah, lifelong comas. He actually has only
used this once, but yeah, it's a thing. Okay,
shit. Uh, well, I mean, that's how one potential
scenario could have gone, according to Madam
Web's precognition, you know? So she gets this
vision of how that all went down, and she realizes
that if she just rips off Sandman's mask at
the start, then, you know, he can't do shit.
So she does that. You know, she rips off his
mask with her web ink back. at the start of
this match, and Sandman instantly puts his
own self to sleep and matches over before it
ever really began. Dude, that- the real timeline
that matters is the one we started with, not
this new bullshit one. It's not multiple timelines.
No, everything that happened that we just described
was just a vision of a potential timeline and
what actually happened is Sandman put himself
down for night-night- No, cause Sandman dreamed
about Madam Web- having a premonition about
that potential future, and he just made sure
to pack a backup mask. Okay, but Sandman's dream
of Madam Web's vision altered her vision, so
the new vision incorporates the second mask,
so he's gonna need to bring infinite masks
if he wants to win this thing. Nah, because
he saw that coming too. Man. I don't even know
how we leave this off. Like... What actually
happens here? Either Sandman puts Madam Web
into a lifelong coma or none of that ever happened
and Madam Web just steals his mask and he's
screwed. Exactly. One of those scenarios is
gonna happen. We'll go ahead and find out which
one by inputting the character stats, running
the simulations and coming back with the winner.
AG9K, hit it.
Processing results. Simulations complete. All
right, this is a pretty fun matchup. It gets
a little bit crazy when characters can perceive
future events. And it quickly spirals into
infinity real quick. Regarding the stats though,
the characters were not very similar at all.
I mean, they were both equal when it came to
things like versatility, fighting skill, and
their range, but they had very little else in
common. Yeah, we said that Sandman came out
on top when it came to evasiveness and intelligence.
We said he was smarter than Madame Webb. But
we said that Madame Webb was much more perceptive
because not only does she have precognitive
visions like Sandman, but she also has her spider
sense. She's also a lot stronger and therefore
can do more physical damage than Sandman. She's
also faster. Yeah, physically, she was definitely
more impressive than Sandman. But does that
really matter when he's smarter? It's kind
of like a brain versus brawn scenario we have
here. I think enough brawn can just beat the
shit out of a brain, for sure. That's what people
with no brains think. Well, Jonathan, considering
these stats, who do you think is going to win
this fight when we get the results? I have
to root for Sandman. He's such an awesome character.
Madame Webb sucks. And those who voted in our
Instagram poll agree. 66% of them said that
Sandman would beat Madame Webb. So about two
thirds. I think those people are just hating
because of the Madame Webb movie and they're
not giving her credit where credit is due. That's
my assumption. Yeah, that's probably fair.
But let's find out who really won. AJ 9K, the
results please. Hey, Yuasa. All right, after
running 1000 simulations, the winner between
Sandman and Madame Webb is Madam Web. Psych!
No, it wasn't even really that close. Out of
1000 simulations, Madam Web won 743 matches,
whereas Sandman only won 257. She kind of beat
his ass. But her movie sucked! Uh, I mean this
version of Madam Web had both the psychic powers
and the Spider-Man powers, so... She doesn't
suck as much as, you know, the movie might have
you believe. She's actually pretty badass.
You know, I was looking forward to this match
because Wesley Dodd's Sandman is like my hero
and I am not going to lie. I'm super disappointed.
I do have to say, though, I'm still proud of
the guy, even though he lost by a lot. At the
end of the day, Madame Webb will always be
remembered as the character having the shitty
movie. And Wesley Dodd's will always just have
that classic iconic noir vibe to him that you
just can't take away. It's like he's so cool,
he can't lose. That just sounds like a pathetic
coping mechanism for the fact that your boy
got humiliated by Madam Webb. Oh yeah, 100%
is. I do not deny that. Which is fine by me,
your disappointment and humiliation is like
my sustenance. I live for that shit. More copium,
straight to the vein. That does it for this
duel guys. Let us know what you thought about
the results by writing to us at dyna or by visiting
us on Instagram, which you can find a link
to in our show notes or by going on our website
at dynamicduel.com. And on our site, you could
also find a link to our Patreon page where you
could join our dynamic 2-0 tier and chat with
us and fellow listeners, our fantastic 4 tier,
which gets you bonus content each month, our
X-Force tier that makes you an executive producer
of this podcast. or our newest tier that lets
you join our DynaMic Podcast Network. And guys,
please don't forget to rate our show on Apple
Podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser, or on our website
directly. As we mentioned earlier, in our next
episode, we will be reviewing the Netflix series
Dead Boy Detectives, which is a spin-off series
of The Sandman, also on Netflix's Terrific Show.
Yeah, my only experience with the Dead Boy
Detectives was their guest appearance on the
Doom Patrol TV series, but that was a fantastic
episode. So, semi-looking forward to the show.
I haven't started it yet, but I've actually
heard good things. I remember I did not like
the trailer, but here's hoping it's as good
as they say. We'll find out next week. That
does it for this episode, we want to give a
big thanks to our executive producers Ken Johnson,
John Strosky, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Balcom,
Miggy Mathengian, Brandon Estregard, Nathaniel
Wagner, Levi Yeaton, Austin Wazilovski, AJ
Dunkerley, Scott Camacho, Adam Spies, Andrew
Shunk, Dean Molesky, and Devin Davis for helping
make this podcast possible. We'll talk to you
guys next week. Up up and away, true believers.
I'm getting a premonition right now. In my pants.