This is a Dynamike Network podcast.
And welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters and stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Marvelous Joe. And I'm his twin brother,
Johnny DC. And in this episode, we are going
to review the latest DC films release, Blue
Beetle. I thought it was fine. Jonathan apparently
thinks it was the greatest movie ever made.
And we've been arguing about it pretty much
for the past few hours. I feel like that's a
stretch, but I did really enjoy the film. And
I can't wait to talk about it. Yeah, we'll talk
all about it later on this episode. Before
that, we're going to break down the comic book
movie news that came out this past week, of
which there was none or at least none worth
talking about. Like we learned that Taika Waititi
made some comments about what he would do for
a Thor five movie. But God, no, they better
not let him direct another Thor film. Yeah,
we also saw that David Ayer shared some A.I.
art on social media that he's claiming is concept
art for his Suicide Squad film. He's just really
desperate to release the air cut of Suicide
Squad. And I'm like, eh, yeah, who cares? What
we're going to end up doing is talking about
a game that Jonathan and I developed, a card
game deck building card game called Chronicle
A.I. Hopefully you guys tune into that because
we think it's pretty cool, but we're biased,
but trust us. As always, we list our segment
times in our episode description, so feel free
to check out the show notes if you want to
skip ahead to a particular topic. As our listeners
may know, our dual simulator is so advanced
that it's gained sentience and has named itself
the Artificial Lifeform for Running Extensive
Duels, just a rather very intelligent simulator
9000, or Alfred Jarvis 9000. Here's a quick
message for our listeners, so listen up! Why
hello there. Do you love listening and chatting
about Marvel and DC? Then become a part of the
dynamic dual community on Patreon where you
can choose from three tiers. The dynamic 2-0
tier lets you listen to this podcast without
ads and gives you access to its Discord chat
group where you can chat with Johnny DC and
Marvelous Joe. The fantastic 4 tier gives you
that and more with two bonus episodes each
month including bloopers and top 10 shows where
Johnny and Joe count down your favourite Marvel
and DC subjects. The X-Force tier makes you
an executive producer of Dynamic Duel, where
every month you help the hosts choose what to
review and who to fight against each other.
And finally, the Dynamike Podcast Network tier
allows aspiring podcasters to create their
own battle-focused show using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and consultation,
and get you simulation results to announce
on your show. Pitch the twins your show via
email at dynamicduelpodcast.gmail.com or by
reaching out to them on social media. Check
it out at patreon.com slash dynamicduel. Pip
pip cheerio. Thanks, J9K. and thanks to everyone
who supports the podcast. Be sure to tune into
the Max Destruction Podcast to witness the bare-knuckle
brawls of the greatest action stars across
film and television. This week on Wednesday,
August 23rd, you can learn who would win in
a fight between Lara Croft from Tomb Raider
and Lelou from The Fifth Element. Also be sure
to tune into Senjo World, a new battle podcast
featuring your favorite anime characters. that
drops new episodes every Thursday. If you tune
in this week, you'll find out who would win
between Edward Elric from Full Metal Alchemist
and Alan Walker from D.Grayman. Yeah, it's
gonna be an awesome week on the Dynamike Network.
Definitely check out those shows. Visit dynamicpodcasts.com
or click the link in our show notes to listen
to all the shows on our network. Speaking of
Send Your World, we heard that it was host Zach's
birthday this past week. So we wanna... Give
a big happy birthday to the birthday boy. And
Zach, if I were to get you a gift from Marvel,
I would get you the Muramasa Blade, which is
Wolverine's sword that he got from Japan that
is able to slash him and negate his healing
factor. It's badass. And I would get you Pied
Piper's flute, because I know that you're into
music and that you have a degree in it. It's
very evident in the production of Senjou World.
So for a fan of music, you can't get better
than that. Yeah, my Muramasa blade would cut
your flute in half, so... Yeah, try getting
past its sonic force field! Alright, happy birthday,
Zack. But with that out of the way, quick to
the No Prize! A No Prize is an award Marvel
used to give out to fans. Our version, the
Dynamic Dual No Prize, is a digital award that
we post on Instagram and in our email newsletter
for the person that we feel gave the best answer
to our question of the week. Last week we asked...
Who would you want to direct a Wonder Woman
reboot and why? And this was coming off the
news that Gal Gadot was basically saying that
she was going to be part of the next Wonder
Woman movie production, which may or may not
be true. But we wanted your guys' opinions
for who should helm the next film if it were
to happen. In James Gunn's new DC universe.
We got a number of answers, we're going to break
down the honorable mentions before revealing
this week's no-prize winner. Our first honorable
mention goes to Lizzie Dyer Arnie, who said,
Hey, it's Lizzie. I'm gonna shock absolutely
no one and say I would like Greta Gerwig to
direct the Wonder Woman reboot. So Barbie is
probably gonna be the biggest movie of the
year. I think Greta is the hottest thing in
Hollywood right now. I think that would be
really good to revive DC's brand. I really would
like to see what her take on the character
would be. I mean, Barbie Land is pretty similar
to Paradise Island, isn't it? And I think this
would be a lot of fun. Yeah, I figured that
this would be most people's answers coming
off of the success of Barbie, which has just
surpassed The Dark Knight to be Warner Brothers
most successful film domestically ever. Which
is crazy. Who would have known that Barbie
would have been more popular than Batman? Not
me! Well, you have to kind of account for inflation
with that. Records will always be broken box
office wise because of that. And inflation
is crazy right now. But that's not to discount
the huge accomplishment that the Barbie film
Achieved. I haven't seen it yet though. I haven't
really been able to get to the theater with
a newborn. I had a chance to see it. I think
the second week it came out, I went to see
Oppenheimer before I saw Barbie. I didn't love
the film. I think it kind of gets its satirical
message mixed up, but that's just me. Greta
Gerwig is a good director, though I think I
would prefer someone with a little bit more
experience with action, personally. Or you
could go the Marvel route where basically they
just hire action directors for you. to let
you nail down the other aspects of the direction.
Yeah, I mean, that's what they did with Birds
of Prey with Kathy Yan. And I don't know. I
think I would prefer one vision for the entire
film. Well, great answer, Lizzie. Our next honorable
mention goes to Trevor Myers, who said, Hi,
my name is Trevor Myers and the director I would
pick for the Wonder Woman reboot would be Catherine
Bigelow, the first woman to ever win the best
director Oscar. She did that for the Hurt Locker.
Since then, she's done Zero Dark Thirty and
Detroit, all critically acclaimed films. She's
also worked in the action genre in the 90s.
She did Point Break. She's done Blue Steel.
She's done a bunch of great films. And she also
had interest in directing an X-Men movie in
the early 90s, starring Angela Bassett as Storm,
according to the rap. So fun fact. And that's
pretty cool. I didn't actually know that about
Catherine Bigelow. Now she is a director with
a background in action. She's made some awesome
military movies. So yeah, she would be a fantastic
choice, I think. Though I questioned whether
or not she could direct a film set in the tone
of James Gunn and his style, because it would
be nice if the DC Universe films had a similar
tone, sort of like the Marvel Universe going
forward. Yeah, while the Marvel Studios films
are distinctive from each other, there is somewhat
of a more cohesive tone among them in that,
you know, they're action driven, visual effects
heavy with some comedic elements, you know.
It would be nice to get some kind of cohesion
there with James Gunn's DCU. I think that's
definitely what people want. As cool as it would
be to see Catherine Bigelow's Wonder Woman,
I do think it would be very different from any
other DC project. But great answer Trevor,
our final honorable mention goes to Ken Johnson,
who said, Hey guys, it's Ken. I too paused
the episode right as soon as you guys started
to interview me in order to answer this question,
because I'm in front of a computer and I could
actually really look into it. My pick is Denis
Villanueve, because I think he would be awesome.
as a woman director. Thanks. That's a creative
pronunciation of Denny Villeneuve, which is
also probably butchering the pronunciation.
If there's any director I would love to see
direct a superhero film, it would be Villeneuve.
I don't think he ever would, but Ken Johnson
gets an honorable mention for the name drop
alone. Yeah, I mean, like Catherine Bigelow,
his vision is a very singular, distinct vision.
I think he did great on films like Blade Runner
2049 and Dune. He also showed that he can direct
strong female leads with emotional centers,
like he did with Amy Adams in Arrival, which
is a fantastic film. I really like this answer.
Again, I do feel like it would be a little
bit of a stretch to get him to play within James
Gunn's DCU, but it would be an incredible film
nonetheless. We want to give a big shout out
to Travis Herndon and Miggy Methingian for
taking the time to visit our website and record
an answer. But the winner of this week's Snow
Prize is... Brandon Estergard, who said... I've
been waiting for this question to be asked
for a while now. I think Guillermo del Toro
would be perfect for Wonder Woman reboot. Del
Toro is great at bringing these mythological
slash cryptid creatures to life, especially
using practical effects. I'd set the movie in
the underworld and just let Del Toro go nuts.
Gero del Toro is a fantastic director, and he's
particularly fantastic at creating these magical
fantasy creatures. You take a look at films
like the Hellboy movies or Pan's Labyrinth,
or even his most recent Pinocchio movie, and
I absolutely know he has what it takes to bring
the mythical world of Wonder Woman to life.
Yeah, not only the mythical part of the film,
you know, he can direct action as we saw in
Blade II. and he could direct strong female
leads as we saw in The Shape of Water. Absolutely,
yeah. I also love the fact that Brandon brought
up the Underworld, because I always thought
that would have been a perfect Wonder Woman
sequel. Just have her travel to the Underworld
to get Steve Trevor's soul back in sort of
like a Orpheus type story that has ties to mythology.
That would have been so much better than Wonder
Woman 1984, for sure. Yeah, Hades could have
been the villain. Ugh, missed opportunity.
But great answer, Brandon Estregard, you win
this week's No Prize. Congrats. If you, the
listener, want a shot at winning your own No
Prize, stay tuned to later on this episode
when we'll be asking another question of the
week. But now that that's done, on to the news.
Alright, so this isn't comic book movie news,
but it is news regarding Jonathan and myself.
We created a deck building card game kind of
in the vein of Marvel Legendary or the DC deck
building card game. If you've heard of those
or you're into those, we created a PvP version
of that, a player versus player two player card
game where you can fight as the Marvel heroes
against DC heroes. And we offered that game
exclusively through our store to patrons of
this podcast. Yeah, it's a really fun game,
we think. We spent over 10 years making it.
And because of all the time we spent doing that,
we decided we wanted to offer it to more than
just our patrons and really open up the potential
for fans of games, not necessarily comics,
to enjoy it. Yeah, it would be nice to sell
the Marvel vs. DC card game, but we don't have
licenses for Marvel or DC to actually produce
this thing and sell it to the public at large.
So we rebranded the game from Marvel vs. to
Chronicle AI and based the story of the game
around a short story that I created a while
back. I'll go ahead and read basically the
fictional background of the game to you guys.
So at the twilight of human civilization, humanity
created the Path R, posthumous artificial intelligence
for transmitting the human record robots. Their
objective? To communicate mankind's story to
whatever sentient life appeared next on Earth.
The Path R robots wandered the planet for centuries
in search of intelligent beings. Over time,
they evolved beyond their programming. They
developed their own society, equipped with
the entirety of human knowledge, and became
the planet's new dominant life form. The robots
fostered the developing plant and animal life,
transforming the Earth into paradise. After
several millennia, new sentients finally appeared
in the form of visitors from outer space. the
Xeno-Eye, were also artificial like the Path-R
robots, programmed to amass resources on behalf
of their alien creators. In difference to the
Path-R robots' attempts to relay mankind's
history, the more advanced Xeno-Eye began tearing
down and harvesting the planet. Seeing their
paradise demolished, the Path-R robots determined
that they would fight to protect their home.
No longer emissaries, but defenders. they reconstructed
their forms for battle. This is the chronicle
of the AI war for Earth. Yeah, it's a really
interesting story. I think it plays really
well into the gameplay. If you're interested
in getting the game, visit dynamicduel.com
slash AI. Yeah, check it out. You could download
the rule set for free, so you can learn how
to play. The game comes with 165 cards total,
including one Path R robot deck and one Xeno-Eye
deck. So we hope you guys check it out. definitely
download the free rule book, consider buying
the game, and if you do, let us know what you
thought about it. And also don't forget that
we do still have a Marvel versus DC version
of the game for our patrons. But that isn't
for this shameless plug. But we do have a question
of the week that ties in. So here it is.
Who is your favorite robot character from Marvel
or DC, and why? Since the card game deals with
robots, we figured that this was an appropriate
question, and we're really curious to hear
your guys' answer. Record your answer at dynamicduel.com
by clicking on the red microphone button in
the bottom right hand corner of the screen,
which will prompt you to leave us a voicemail.
Your message could be up to 30 seconds long,
and don't forget to leave your name in case
we include you on the podcast. We'll pick our
favorite answer, and award that person a Dynamic
Duel No Prize. that we'll post to Instagram
and our email newsletter. Be sure to answer
before August 26th.
Now let's go ahead and move on to the main event
of this episode where we review the latest
DC film to hit theaters, Blue Beetle.
Alright, Blue Beetle is the latest film to come
out from DC Studios. It was directed by Angel
Manuel Soto and stars Sholo Mariduña of Korokai
fame as the title character. The film was originally
supposed to be released as an HBO Max exclusive,
but was switched to a theatrical release just
before Discovery and Warner Bros. merged and
filming began. Depending on who you ask...
Either this film or the upcoming Superman Legacy
is the first film in the new DC universe shepherded
by DC Studios co-head James Gunn. This film
is produced by Peter Safran, the other co-head
of DC Studios, so depending on this film's box
office success, I can see this film kicking
off the new universe. And it's not a terrible
film to kick off said new universe. If people
were looking for an MCU tonal approach to the
new DC universe, then they'd have a hard time
finding a more Marvel-esque film than Blue Beetle,
for better or worse. The film and title character
borrow quite a bit from Marvel, I'd say. It's
funny and action-packed with heartfelt moments
and a charismatic lead. If you haven't seen
the film yet, I strongly encourage you to see
it in theaters if the fun MCU films of the past
are your thing. And definitely see it before
listening to this spoiler review. I'm interested
in hearing how much you think that this film
was inspired by Marvel's films, especially given
how much you enjoy it, which makes me think
that you just really love Marvel now. If this
film is indeed inspired by Marvel's films,
I would say it's inspired by the lesser side
of Marvel that we don't like to talk about,
the side that produced Ant-Man, Quantum Mania
and Thor, Love and Thunder. No, no, I'm thinking
more like... Iron Man, Black Panther, that kind
of thing. You're out of your fucking mind.
If you think that this film could compare to
those because it can't. It was a fine effort.
I don't think it was exceptional like the first
Black Panther or Iron Man films. Well, I guess
this is the first of many times. I'll just be
saying to you during the course of this review.
Haters going to hate. So, Joseph, you got to
see this film a day before me. And though you
threaten to spoil everything, The only thing
you really told me before I saw it was that
the film was exactly what I was going to expect
it to be. And that's pretty accurate. I haven't
read too many Blue Beetle comics, honestly,
but I did read the character's title up until
about a year after the introduction of Jaime
Reyes during DC Comics Infinite Crisis event.
The comic title was known for its humor, action,
badass tech design. and unapologetically showing
Jaime Reyes' strong cultural Latin upbringing.
I was expecting the film to match the comic
that made the character fairly popular, and
I'm happy to say that it did. The movie is
a nearly perfect adaptation of the Blue Beetle
comics. As we see in the movie, Jaime Reyes
took over the mantle of Blue Beetle from the
character Ted Kord as part of a push from DC
Comics to create more diverse and relatable
characters. Relatability is usually more associated
with Marvel characters, as DC's heroes tend
to be more aspirational, but part of Jaime's
appeal is that it's easy to relate to him and
his experiences with his ethnically diverse
family. And sure enough, family was a major
component of this film, more so than most other
superhero movies. Yeah, I think it's really
easy to relate to Jaime, especially if you
come from a Latino background. Which you and
I do. this character is due to his relatability
considering that, like you said, it's a trademark
of Marvel characters as opposed to DC which
seemed to be a little bit more iconic and larger
than life and archetypical, not so relatable.
So basically, what you're telling me is that
you have a essentially Marvel character in
an essentially Marvel film and that you loved
it and that you're calling me a hater. If this
was a Marvel film, honestly, it wouldn't be
one of my favorites. I would consider it one
of its lesser entries in MCU. To which I could
only reply, haters gonna hate. Here it comes.
Alright, we're gonna hear that over and over
again. Let's get into why you liked it and
why I thought it was okay. Well, I think the
biggest appeal of the film to me and part of
the appeal of Jaime Reyes as Blue Beetle in
general is that the character is just so damn
cool. I mentioned that he borrows quite a bit
from Marvel and I'd say that if someone described
the character as a mixture between Iron Man,
Venom, Black Panther, and Miles Morales as
would be a damn good description. One's cool
factor is very subjective, but I describe each
of those Marvel characters as cool, and Jaime
himself may just be the coolest superhero in
existence in my opinion, particularly on film
as we get to see all of the blue electricity
and neon glow, the buster swords, and the plasma
cannons. If this movie came out when I was
9 or 10, I'd have thought it was the best movie
that had ever been made. Like five stars, no
question. Yeah, I definitely agree that it would
appeal to eight year olds and nine year olds.
I think you're correct in that the visual effects
and the action were probably the best things
about this movie. They were mind blowing, honestly.
It's incredible how much better the visual
effects were here than in the recent Flash movie.
I was legit terrified that like everything
we saw from the trailers was going to be the
only good CG in the movie and that everything
else was just going to be. complete like uncanny
valley weirdness like the Flash was. Thankfully
that was not the case. Now as an adult, as a
Hispanic adult fan in particular, there was
a lot to enjoy with this film. I thought the
story was fun, the action was awesome, and
the humor was decent. It does get juvenile at
times, but I described the humor in the comics
the same way. Like Jaime may not be a juvenile
in the movie like he is in the comics. But
he's not far off, and for a family film, it's
not uncommon to come across jokes like the
Bugship's fart spray. The humor was a little
bit cheesier than I would have liked it to
have been. Very reminiscent of the style of
humor that we'd get in family action movies
from the 90s or something like that. You know,
very harking back to that time. There were
some jokes that definitely landed for me, especially
coming from George Lopez, who is a comedic
legend. That guy is so funny. And I was really
iffy going into the film on what I would think
about his character. But he really carried the
film outside of the cool action beats and visual
effects stuff. My favorite joke in the whole
movie came from him. Wayne Hyman was like,
it's inside me. And George Lopez is like, it
went up his ass. But in Spanish. Yeah, there
are a lot of Spanish curse words on this. I
was actually surprised that it got away with
the PG-13 rating. Holy shit. Right. Yeah. So
much of the movie. that's subtitled from Spanish,
those subtitles are not quite accurate as to
what's actually being said. I remember towards
the end of the film, Jaime's mom essentially
says in Spanish, like, go kill those motherfuckers.
But in the subtitles, it was like, go kick their
asses. And I was like, oh damn. Yeah, that
was pretty amusing. I guess I'm a little bit
surprised though that you found the movie as
amusing as you did, considering that you dislike
cheesy humor even more than I do. So I just
feel like you're just being biased. toward this
film because it has a DC logo on it. You know,
that's fair to call me out on that because I
don't enjoy cheesy humor. I think it was the
environment. I went to go see this movie in
a theater that I usually don't. It's situated
in a largely Hispanic neighborhood and everyone
was just laughing the whole time. And I saw
it with my family who was also Hispanic and
all of them were laughing as well. I couldn't
help myself. That may be why I just had such
a good time with this movie and the humor.
So what you're saying is you lost all objectivity.
It's really hard in a theater where everyone's
laughing not to laugh. OK, I could see where
you would say that the humor was juvenile.
But again, the comics are juvenile. The comics
are always making like inappropriate, like
puberty jokes and stuff like that. So it's on
brand for the character. All right. I also
love that you're clutching your pearls at these
jokes when you make like jokes about taking
a shit like at least twice a week. I'm just
saying that cheese isn't my favorite style
of humor. That's fine. That's fine. And you're
a hypocrite for enjoying the humor in this
movie. You wouldn't give any other film that
kind of leeway. To which I could only say,
hypocrite's gonna hypocrite. I don't know. I
don't know how else to respond. I enjoyed it.
Sue me. One of the things in particular that
was interesting to me in this film was how
well the filmmakers blended like the humorous
family tone with the adult's edge. Like you
had scenes like the fart spray, but 30 seconds
earlier, you had the bug ship impaling an enemy
soldier with one of its legs, which is a little
violent. I think the film definitely harkened
back to a time when family films were a touch
darker, like in the 80s and 90s, like the Dark
Crystal, like the Goonies, like Temple of Doom,
things like that. One non-family film from
that era that I think influenced this film in
terms of its minuscule amount of body horror
and definitely its villain's plan is Robocop.
The stakes are basically the same in that this
corporate tech giant run by the world's biggest
douche is planning on creating an unstoppable
technological security force that will be under
its control. The film doesn't do a great job
of enforcing the stakes and explaining what
will happen if Victoria Cord's plan succeeds.
It focuses so much on Jaime's early superhero
career that we don't see him save anyone but
his family. And that's fine. You know, Jaime
has only had the scarab for two days in the
film, and because his family is such a big part
of his life, it makes sense that his personal
stakes would be hyper-focused on saving his
family. But because it's so hyper-focused,
it weakened the primary antagonist. For sure.
One of the biggest gripes I have about this
movie is that it feels overly d- generic, a
lot of the things that we saw in this movie
we've seen before and done maybe a little bit
better, including the family aspect of this
movie. You know, I think I said on the Discord
that the whole strength in family theme was
done incredibly in the Shazam film, and we've
also seen more mature complex takes on the
family dynamic in films like Black Panther and
Shang-Chi. But I guess the one thing that this
film has going for it that those other films
don't that kind of give Blue Beetle its own
voice is the Latino culture aspect. Outside
of the action and visual effects, I think that
was the film's strongest suit because it was
a lot of fun to watch. Palmera City felt like
this wonderful amalgam of Los Angeles and Miami.
It was pretty cool. Yeah, Palmera City was
very well realized, I thought. I don't know
if I would agree with you though that other
superhero films have done the family angle stronger.
I think that's sort of confusing conflict with
theme. There was still a very strong theme of
family here, and just because there was less
conflict with the family doesn't mean that it
was not strong. Going back to the stakes of
the film, usually it doesn't help when the main
character can seemingly do anything. Blue Beetle
has all of the powers, but I will say that they
did a good job prior to the final act when
Blue Beetle and the scarab Kajira fully bond,
of limiting Kaime's control over the suit,
which is straight out of the comics. and brought
some danger to the character earlier in the
film. Yeah, that was fantastic. It's not often
that we see a hero unable to control their
powers in this way. It was definitely a unique
take that I thought was quite fascinating.
It does make me wonder, though, how they're
going to proceed with this character in future
films now that he's seemingly in full control
of his powers and able to do anything. I do
feel like if they make a sequel to this, like
the villain is going to have to affect the
scarab in some way so that Jaime loses some
control over it because the dude is OP. Yeah,
he's pretty strong. I could totally see now
why the results of the dual episode we had
where we pit Blue Beetle against Spider-Man
went the way they did. I still feel kind of
bad tricking you into that one because I knew
that Blue Beetle was going to stop, but we
went with it anyway. Now I mentioned that the
film felt very like 90s to me, and maybe some
of it had to do with the saturated color palette,
but I think most of it was the score. I loved
the score for this movie with its synthesizer.
It sounded appropriately alien and technological
and badass. I thought it was perfect. Well,
yeah, the auditory landscape for this film
was kind of fascinating. The synth made it feel,
you know, like early 90s, late 80s. The songs
that they chose for the soundtrack were appropriate
throwbacks to the same era, both within American
culture and Hispanic culture, even pop culture
references like El Chapulín Colorado, harken
back to decades past because I feel like I haven't
seen that character in ages. Oh yeah, dude,
Dad was just cracking up during those scenes
because he used to watch that character as
a kid. And there's definitely some similarities
between El Chapulín Colorado, which essentially
translates to the reddish cricket or the cherry
cricket and blue beetle. They're both like
a color and a bug. It's kind of amusing. The
whole film definitely like spans a broad spectrum
of Latin culture. Like you mentioned, even with
music, there's everything from reggaeton to
like old mariachi songs, Los Pancho songs. It
was great to hear. And maybe a lot of deep
cuts to like the telenovela reference. Maria
de la Barrio. Right. I didn't even know what
that was, honestly. Mom recognized that she
used to watch that at her grandmother's house
when she was younger, I guess. Interesting.
All the cultural references aside, the heart
of this film is in its characters. So let's
talk about them in the character breakdown.
Now Blue Beetle, AKA Jaime Reyes, was played
by Sholo Mariduña, and he's perfect as the
character. I thought they were going to make
him a young high schooler in the movie, but
that probably would have felt pretty Cobra Kai,
and making him a recent college graduate fit
the overall themes of purpose and destiny in
the film pretty well. I mean, as far as I'm
concerned, Sholo Mariduña was born to play this
role. He fit the character really well. I'd
never really seen him in anything because I
never watched Cobra Kai, but the dude is definitely
poised to become a big star, I think. I hope
so. Yeah, he deserves it. He's great. He's
fantastic. He's essentially the star of Cobra
Kai, I would argue. So yeah, he definitely
is a star in the making for film. Yeah, a lot
of charisma, hits all the right emotional beats,
and is a fantastic fighter, apparently. The
fight scenes in this movie were incredible.
And I didn't think they would be so hand-to-hand
given the nature of Blue Beetle's powers. but
they managed to work in, show those martial
arts skills, and really well here too. Yeah,
seamlessly. It was great. Now, Heimer returns
home from college, unsure how to help his struggling
family, but feeling a responsibility to do so.
He struggles with his purpose, as does his
aged father, revealed in a heartfelt scene of
encouragement and relatability, though as his
kind father explained to him, whatever happens,
at least the family can face it together. That's
sort of the central crux of the film. Haima
ends up seemingly in this horrifying situation
with the unwanted parasitic and alien scarab
attached to him for life, but by the end he
is encouraged by the spirit of his father to
embrace the hand that has been dealt to him
and make the most of it to be a superhero and
save his family. It's a very mature and relatable
theme, after all, who among us doesn't question
their purpose in life? And I think for many,
purposes found in overcoming hardship and taking
responsibility. Honestly, anything really dealing
with Jaime Reyes and the Blue Beetle character
in this movie was pretty flawless. I think
the fans of the character are going to be over
the moon with his portrayal here. Oh yeah,
I mean I know I was. Honestly, my hope with
how cool the suit and the character's powers
are, but also with how relatable the character
is with his family, I hope that Blue Beetle
will become the favorite superhero of millions
of little boys across the planet. And I think
he will, particularly in Latin countries. I'm
dying to see what this film's worldwide box
office take is going to be. It's not going to
be high because it's underperforming, but it
might be domestically. Yes. But what's the worldwide
total going to be? It's probably still going
to underperform because it's D.C. and nobody
likes D.C. But I do see it maybe becoming like
a cult favorite down the line. Fingers crossed.
That would be awesome. Moving on to Jenny Cord,
she was played by Bruna Marchesine, and she
does a good job as Jenny, even though most
of the film I kept asking myself, why is she
in the movie? And not because I thought she
was an unnecessary character, but because as
far as I'm aware, she was created for the film.
By the end, I was actually glad they introduced
her in the movie, not only because she was
a great love interest for Jaime, but also because
she became Jaime's connection. to Ted and Victoria
Cord and also the one who really understood
the stakes of Victoria's plan. Blue Beetle
is a legacy character, but the legacy in the
film really revolves around Jenny and the Cord
name. I'm actually really glad she was included
in this film because I think without her, it
would have seemed like the movie was making
a statement regarding class and race dynamics
where every single Hispanic character is treated
as almost like an oppressed second-class person.
by having this rich, affluent Hispanic person
in the film, they were able to avoid that problem.
Yeah, that's true. I didn't even think about
that, but that's, yeah, 100% true. I especially
came around on the character of Jenny after
I saw the film and saw some speculation amongst
our patrons in our Discord chat server that
because Jenny is part Brazilian, that could
mean her mother is Beatriz da Costa, the superhero
known as Fire, and a former teammate of Ted
Kord on the Justice League. I love that idea
and I want Jenny to inherit her mother's powers
in the next film. But did Fire and Ted Kord's
Blue Beetle have a romantic relationship in
the comics? Dude, Fire flirted with everyone.
She's Brazilian. The fuck is that supposed
to mean? Brazilians are like some of the sexiest
people on the planet. They know it. We learn
a little about Jenny's mother in the film during
a scene that really sets up Jenny's emotional
arc. She longs for her family. and for a family,
and she really admires how close Jamie is with
his. By the end, she's accepted into the Reyes
family, even though she's pretty much responsible
for everything bad that happened to them. They
didn't seem to see it that way though, and
she definitely helped them recover some of what
they lost at the end, specifically their home
and Rudy's truck, so that was nice. Yeah, they
kind of looked out there. The early conflict
of the movie is that the family is losing their
home due to their poverty. And the issue never
really gets addressed until that 11th hour scene
at the end of the movie where she's like, oh
yeah, I'm gonna buy the house and the community
is gonna come together. I thought the community
was gonna come back to help them rebuild the
house, but they just, you know, had a fucking
barbecue, which didn't really help anything.
So yeah, fortunately Jenny was there. Yeah,
that's right. Well, I mean, like. The issue
didn't really have time to be addressed because
the whole film only takes place over the course
of, what, three days? So, yeah, I mean, if
it took place over a long period of time, things
would have played out differently for sure.
Moving on to Cesar Rudy Reyes, he's played by
George Lopez. He's not one of my favorite comedians.
I mean, he's decent. I thought he was going
to be just so-so in this film, but like you,
I'm actually really glad he was in it because
I thought he did a terrific job as Rudy and
was responsible for some of the film's most
successful humor. I love George Lopez. I think
he's one of the most hilarious comedians ever.
He definitely played the character of Rudy
as such a character. You know, he's paranoid
about the government and core to industry's
technology. He was a real help to Jaime and
everyone, not only in handling technology like
the bug ship, but also in inventing his own
tech and maximizing his truck taco, which I
actually got a lot more laughs than I thought
it would. Like they really milked that thing,
but in a good way. I just love hearing George
Lopez scream, die taco. Just his screaming
is fantastic. It's just so funny. It's really
good. You're right. He was such a character,
they could almost give him his own show. I just
thought George Lopez was going to play him
like George Lopez. But I would say this is probably
George Lopez's best acting job that I've ever
personally seen. Yeah, I would agree with that
even outside of the comedic bits, you know,
the parts where he actually had heart to heart
talks with Jaime. I thought we're really well
done. Yeah, there was a pretty touching scene
with Rudy and Jaime on top of the court mansion
when Rudy describes himself as basically like
a loser who sleeps on his brother's living
room couch. But when Jaime tells him that he's
never seen him like that, that he's always
seen his uncle as this badass, there was just
something like truly special and loving and
empowering. Not just about family, but non-judgmental
family in particular. And you could see that
love in the performances of both Sholo and George
Lopez. Is Rudy from the comics? No, I don't
believe he is. Jaime has an aunt, but I don't
think, as far as I'm aware, that we ever see
him with an uncle. I mean, Alberto Milagro,
Jaime's mom, are in the comics, although his
mom has a different name. Her name is Bianca
in the comic, and in the movie her name is
Rocio. But yeah, Rudy is an original character.
I was hoping to get some kind of explanation
as to who the hell this guy is and why he's
so good at building random technology and where
that came from. And yeah, he seems like a character
that would be rooted in the comics. I'm sure
he will be after this movie. I'd be surprised
if he wasn't. Moving on to the rest of Jaime's
family, I don't have much to say about each
of them. I think the standout is Milagro, his
sister. She was played by Belisa Escobedo. I
thought she did a great job here, and like
George Lopez brought a lot of humor to the film.
Her snarkiness makes her a good foil for both
Jaime and Jenny, but in spite of her attitude,
you never question her loyalty to her brother
or her family. I thought the father was a standout
as well. Oh, Alberto? He was played by Damien
Alcazar. Yeah, he tied in heavily to the themes
of Purpose and Destiny. It was interesting
to see him at the end kind of state that he
realized his purpose posthumously. was to be
there and provide strength for Jaime in his
moment of need. That scene almost broke me
in the theater. I didn't cry, but I was really
close. That was such a beautiful scene. I don't
have too much to say about the mother, but of
course I think one of the standout characters
of the film as a whole was Nana. Not necessarily
in a positive way for me personally at least.
I have other family members who loved her, but
I think the joke of her being like this badass
revolutionary who could wield a gatling gun.
was beating a dead horse. Yeah, it should have
been given one reference, kind of was like a
wink and a nod, and then dropped entirely.
I think it would have actually been funnier
that way. Absolutely. Moving on to the villains
of the film, Ignacio Carapaz was played by Raul
Max Trujillo. He was an interesting character
somewhat, but only up until the very end. Like
throughout the whole film, he has this weird
relationship with Victoria, but he's very stoic
and quiet, something of a mystery. And he says
mysterious things like, your family makes you
weak. So there's this hint of backstory there,
which we don't get until the very end, and I
honestly felt that I was a cop out. I wish
they would have established early on that he
suffered from memory loss, and I think that
would have made the end make a little bit more
sense. Yeah, the character was too generic
for too long of a film to make him any sort
of interesting villain. Too much of his character
building was done pretty much after the fact.
Although it was an interesting story and it
seemed like the film was touching on injustices
faced by Latin American countries at the hands
of the American military complex. Right. But
it was kind of like shoehorned in there. Not
that the film needed to be about that, but overall
the character building there was just too little
too late. I agree. I agree. Essentially, we
learn at the very end that Carapax was a little
boy living in a rural Latin American country
whose mom was the victim of a Cordo Industries
missile. I don't remember it being clear why
his mom was bombed, and I'm not sure if it's
entirely necessary, but Victoria essentially
abducts Ignacio as a little boy and performs
horrendous experiments on him that takes his
arm and implants him with Ohmak tech. His entire
existence is a testament to Victoria Kord's
evilness essentially, and it was pretty hardcore
how he was the one to give her comeuppets at
the end by dragging her screaming into the
fire and blowing her and himself up. That was
crazy. Is Caropax an OMAC? In the comics, no.
The OMAC is a very different thing in the comics,
and I'm still not quite sure how I feel about
them using it in this movie. OMAC stands for
One-Man Army Corps, and it was done really
well during Jaime Reyes' debut during the Infinite
Crisis storyline, where the OMAC technology
was a nanovirus that was implanted in just random
people across the planet as like sleeper cells.
It was very akin to like, Secret Invasion in
a way. And of course it was done very different
here. Although I don't think you wouldn't be
able to pick that back up in a later film as
a different version. In the comics, Kera Pax
got his armor from Pago Island. The same island
where the fortress was at the end of this movie.
It was an island owned by Jarvis Kord, Ted's
uncle, who was the one responsible for Dan Garrett's
death. The original Blue Beetle. But speaking
of Jarvis Kord... Let's move on to Victoria
Cord, who is played by Susan Sarandon. I want
to jump in right here and say that this is by
far the worst performance I've ever seen Susan
Sarandon give. She was horrible in this movie.
Good God, this villain sucked. I feel like
you're being a little harsh, but not by much.
I mean, Susan Sarandon, she's a great actress.
I think she did a decent job with what was called
for the character in the script. You know,
essentially, she was just supposed to be this
corporate elitist and racist. who's more concerned
with money and her legacy than human lives.
She wasn't supposed to be likable. It was a
very cold performance, though, especially in
contrast to the more colorful cast. She was
so detached from everything, it felt like she
was like reading cue cards and her approach
was to be as generic as possible. I didn't think
it was that bad. It was bad. Not as bad as
you're describing it, though. I think she's
still emoted. She still acted, you know. OK,
haters going to hate. We learned that Victoria
helped start Corda Industries as a weapons
manufacturer with her father. Though when her
father died, he left the company to Victoria's
brother, Ted. It's never made clear whether
Victoria had some responsibility in Ted's disappearance,
though I'm guessing it had more to do with his
adventures as Blue Beetle than her. But regardless,
Victoria makes the most of Ted's absence and
steers the direction of the company back to
the weapons industry. with the intent of creating
the ultimate cybernetic soldiers. I'm confused
honestly why they had to create the character
of Victoria Cord when she's essentially Jarvis
Cord from the comics as I mentioned earlier.
Jarvis isn't a major character though, so I
guess it's not that big of a deal. I'm just
wondering why of all the routes you could have
taken with a Blue Beetle villain they decided
to go this route. And again, I think they just
wanted to make someone super unlikable like
the ultimate entitled Karen. If Susan Strandon
doesn't get nominated for a Razzie for this
role, I'm going to eat my shirt. You heard
it here first, folks. Joseph's going to eat
his shirt. In the meantime, let's move on to
the story highlights.
In a frozen tundra, Chord Industries, led by
Victoria Chord, locate an alien artifact known
as a scarab within a giant stone sphere. Not
long after, we see Jaime Reyes return home
to Palmera City after earning a pre-law degree
from Gotham Law. He learns that his family
is losing their home in the Edge Keys neighborhood
after his father lost his job and because Chord
Industries' development in the city increased
housing prices. I can't remember if we ever
learned how the scarab ended up in that stone.
No, we have no idea. We're not sure if Ted
Kord put it there. It was implied that maybe
he did and it set up decoys across the entire
globe that Victoria Kord was searching through.
I'm not sure if it's explicitly said. There
was a lot that was flashing by the screen during
the opening credits, so the answer could lie
in that. They were cool opening credits. I like
how they kind of give a history of the scarabs
and everything. Yeah, and how lethal they are,
just devastating a planet. That was cool. Jaime
takes a job with his sister, Milagro, cleaning
beachside mansions in order to contribute money
to his family. While cleaning the home of Victoria
Cord, he witnesses an argument between Victoria
and her niece, Jenny, over the one-man army
corps, or OMAC, weapons project that Cord Industries
is working on, and also over the disappearance
of Jenny's father, Ted, the former head of
Cord Industries. When Jaime stands up for Jenny,
Victoria fires him and Milagro, though Jenny
promises Jaime to help him get a job at Chord
Industries if he visits her there the next
day. When Jaime goes to Chord Tower the next
day to meet with Jenny, she frantically gives
him a small box containing the scarab that she
had just stolen from the Chord Laboratories,
which was studying the scarab in order to extract
its alien code. Despite being told by Jenny
not to open the box, When Jaime brings it home,
he's pressured by his family to do so. The
scarab bonds to Jaime's spine, painfully forming
a reconfiguring exoskeleton around him and
performing a system calibration check that causes
him to tear through his family's roof and Palmera
City, where his automatic defense system slices
a bus in half. The scene where he goes into
space I thought was really well done. I feel
like they did a good job capturing the panic
that Jaime was feeling in the moment. Yeah,
it was well done. I didn't like how they basically
plagiarized the scene from Shazam when he was
falling out of the sky and then with his arms
up right before he crashed back onto Earth,
he stopped like an inch off the ground. It
was played a little bit different in the Shazam
movie and that it like cut to black and stuff
like that, but not by much. And yeah, I would
say it was ripped off. I did think it was funny
with the guys at the bus stop on drugs when
they're like, has it kicked in yet? And then
once the whole thing with the Blue Beetle happens,
they're like, yeah, I think it's kicked in.
That was funny. When Jaime returns home, he's
frightened at the sight of the Scarab bound
to his spine, and he steals his Uncle Rudy's
truck to find Jenny for her help in getting
it removed. Jaime finds Jenny on the run from
Kord's lethal security force, and helps her
escape back to his house where she tells him
and his family that the Scarab is an ancient
parasitic weapon capable of destroying the planet
that has chosen to bond with Jaime for some
reason. She explains that her father studied
the Scarab. and might know how to get it off,
but they would need to get a key from Core Tower
to access his hidden laboratory. Meanwhile,
Victoria orders Lieutenant Ignacio Carapax to
find Jenny. Why is it that every DC film wants
to portray its lead male star in the nude due
to the way their super suit works? Like we
saw that in The Flash recently. We did. I mean,
but we saw a lot more. of Barry Allen and the
Flash and more of Ben Affleck as Batman than
we did of Jaime. I don't know, I feel like
studios always have the hardest time with superhero
costumes and the whole just nature of them
putting on the suit. Like, they're like, oh,
obviously the clothes aren't underneath the
suit, so they have to take them off, right?
It's just, you don't think about that when
you're reading comics. With help from Uncle
Rudy, Jenny and Jaime managed to steal the
watch key only to then be attacked by Carapax.
who is equipped with cybernetic omak armor
and weaponry. Though Jaime's scarab armor activates
defensively in response, Jaime is still unable
to fully control his new powers and is nearly
killed by carapacts until Uncle Rudy intervenes
and the three escape. I have a question. Sure.
Why does Victoria Cord even need the scarab
if the omak armor is already so successful?
I mean, it nearly defeated Blue Beetle at this
point. I don't know, that's a good question.
she wanted the scarab for herself. Like she
wanted to bond with it so she could be super
powerful. But after I learned that she just
wanted the code to make her OMAC machines even
more powerful, I was wondering the same thing.
I think she's just obsessed with power and that
may not be a very good reason, but I think
she's known that the alien technology is far
superior than anything core industries could
come up with. Moving on to the next scene, at
Jenny's childhood home, now a run-down mansion,
Jenny unlocks her father's high-tech laboratory,
where Haima and Rudy learn that Ted Kord was
the hero once known as Blue Beetle. While Haima
learns more about Jenny's family, Rudy learns
via Ted's computer that the Scarab, named Kaji
Dah, is alien in origin and can't be removed
while Haima is still alive, as evidenced by
the Scarab's original host, Dan Garrett.
where he sees Victoria Court's helicopter headed
toward his family home in the edge keys and
he realizes Victoria knows that he's been helping
Jenny. Jaime leaps off the roof in order to
activate Khajiitah through its protective measures
and he flies home. How do you feel about the
movie's treatment of the Blue Beetle legacy
here? I thought it was pretty interesting that
they brought it up at all considering maybe
they didn't need to. I actually really liked
what they did here. I agree that they probably
didn't need to. But I respect them for how
they did it. They really didn't miss anything,
honestly. And I didn't expect them to touch
on as much as they did. I thought we would just
get Ted Kord, the fact that we got so many
references to Dan Garrett too, and them acknowledging
the fact that he was the first one to bond
with the beetle, I thought was pretty neat.
Yeah, yeah, it was really cool. There's so
much stuff in this movie that just had me super
giddy because I never thought I was ever going
to see it, like the bug ship. Like we saw something
very similar in the Watchmen movie Night Owl
is based on Blue Beetle, but to see the actual
buck ship was super cool. Yeah, and that little
trapeze thing that comes out of the bottom of
it that Blue Beetle swings around on. Right.
Yeah, there's something special about finally
seeing that in live action. Back to the movie,
Victoria uses her private military force to
invade the Reyes' home and rounds up its occupants.
When Jaime arrives, Victoria orders her troops
to attack him and his family in order to see
what the Scarab is capable of. Though Jaime
manages to protect his family, Kiripax successfully
disables and captures Jaime, while his father,
Alberto, suffers from cardiac arrest during
their escape. As Victoria takes Jaime to Pago
Island, her private island fortress, Alberto
dies, and before the family can grieve, the
grandmother and matriarch known as Nana encourages
them to save Jaime. This was a pretty intense
scene. The fact that Alberto died was... incredibly
powerful and something I didn't see coming.
I question the legality of Victoria Court's
actions. Like really, how much can the Reyes
family sue court industries for because of
all the shit that went down here? I mean, if
they could afford the lawyer. I mean, there
isn't a lawyer around that wouldn't take that
case. That's a huge payday right there. Unless
Victoria Court pays them more to not do that.
Well, Jaime took pre-law, so you think he might
be able to do a good enough job of it? Yeah,
maybe if he got his postgraduate law degree
and passed the bar to get his license. It would
take a lot of work. Yet. And then you would
never have to work again. Ha ha ha. That's fair.
Victoria binds Jaime to a machine in a laboratory
on Pago Island and begins extracting the scarab's
energy and data in order to improve her OMAC
machines. A process that nearly kills Jaime.
Meanwhile, Jenny takes the Reyes family back
to her father's secret lab. where they use the
Blue Beetle hovercraft known as the Bug Ship
and Blue Beetle's experimental weaponry to travel
to Pago Island and rescue Jaime. As the Bug
Ship storms the fortress, Jaime's mind drifts
into the afterlife, where he meets his father.
Alberto encourages his son, telling him that
it's not his time to die and that he needs
to fully bond mentally with Kha'Jida, which
Jaime does just as Jenny and Milagro blow up
the fortress's power generators and the Scarab
Code fully downloads into Carapax, amplifying
the power of his Omac armor and driving him
into a murderous rampage. I love the joke here
where Victoria's scientist whom she calls Sanchez,
when he makes that final stand against her
giving his full name with all of his family's
surnames and everything, it was a great moment.
Though Jenny is captured by Victoria, Jaime
manages to rescue his sister before facing
off against Carapax and nearly getting killed.
When Jaime is saved thanks to a distraction
by Rudy, Jaime believes Carapax kills his uncle
and gets a second wind after seemingly witnessing
the death of one of his family members. Though
Jaime gets the upper hand and nearly kills
Carapax, Kajira reveals to Jaime Carapax's memories
that it managed to uncover during the data
download. of how Carapax has been abused by
Victoria since he was a child, including being
responsible for the death of his mother. After
Jenny manages to bring down Victoria's getaway
copter, Jaime lets Carapax kill Victoria by
overloading his suit and generating an explosion
that also destroys all the OMAC weapons held
at the fortress, though Jaime and his family
escape the explosion in the bugship and they
finally mourn Alberto's death together. The
final battles here were so unbelievably cool.
I mentioned how Blue Beetle borrows a lot from
Marvel. And I have to say, I'm ecstatic that
DC character finally gets his own like hallway
fight scene. Yeah, it was so good. Honestly,
if that like corridor fight scene doesn't make
your nominations list for best DC moment of
the year for the Brothers Awards in December,
I'll be surprised. Oh, it absolutely will. I
just love how like Haima was just pissed off.
He's like, let's go. It's like smashing his
energy fists together. And the song, I Ain't
Going Out Like That by Cypress Hill, is definitely
my new fight song. Like I'm getting into a
fight with someone, I'm putting that song on.
The moment leading up to that where Kajida
repeats his mother's line in Spanish, it gave
me chills. It was really well done, that whole
scene. And it really kind of showed how well
the two had bonded by that point because Haime
was starting to influence the Scarab to the
point where the Scarab was starting to speak
Spanish. That's such a neat concept. Yeah, yeah,
really cool. Also really cool that final fight
between Carapax and Blue Beetle, where Blue
Beetle is like busting out Buster swords and
like doing flying somersault sword slashes.
So unbelievably awesome. I was just so happy
in the theater during this final fight. After
Alberto's funeral, Jenny takes control of Cordova
Industries and offers to rebuild Threya's home
while also giving Grooty a new truck, both
of which were destroyed earlier. Jaime and Jenny
finally kiss before he flies her to her childhood
home. In the mid-credits scene, we learn via
a broadcast on Ted's lab computer that Ted
Kord is still alive. Now I have to say, the
painting of Ted Kord in the mansion looks exactly
like Jason Sudeikis. Am I wrong? I wouldn't
say exactly because it was a very impressionist
style painting, so it could literally be anybody.
I mean, it's exactly Jason. Sudeikis in an
impressionist style, right? Okay. I don't know
where you're getting this Jason Sudeikis thing
from. Well, he's been rumored to be in the film,
but obviously that wasn't the case. I don't
know if maybe they cut his role. I have no idea
whose voice that was at the very end. I don't
know if that was supposed to be Ted Kord or
maybe even Booster Gold because they refer
to Ted Kord in the third person, right? I'm
hoping that Ted Kord kind of got trapped in
time alongside Booster. and that this film will
segue into the Booster Gold television series.
That would be awesome. I almost feel like Jaime
Reyes needs his own Booster Gold, right? Because
like Ted Kord, Blue Beetle and Booster Gold
were best friends. But now that Ted Kord's
legacy has kind of been passed down, it would
be nice to have that dynamic still with Jaime
and appear. I think you could go a number of
routes with that. You could go the Peacemaker
route, who kind of served as a mentor and partner
for Jaime in the comics. But you could also
go like the Teen Titans route. Like maybe even
Blue Beetle could appear in the upcoming Batman
and Robin film, like in a post-credits scene
or something like that, as Damien is maybe
forming the Teen Titans. Who knows? It could
work, I think. I would be surprised if we saw
Blue Beetle appear like in Peacemaker Season
2. I do think that there's room for two Blue
Beetles, like I think Ted Kord and Jaime could
share the role, so that you can have Ted Kord
in the Booster Gold series. There is an after
credits scene, but it's nothing. It's just...
El Chapulín Colorado in a cute claymation form.
Colorado. It was just El Chapulín Colorado
in a cute claymation form. Yeah, I kind of regret
sticking around for that one. I don't think
it was worth it. Dad didn't though. He loved
it. So I loved it. But that does it for the
movie. Again, I was really happy with the way
it turned out. I thought it was a terrific
adaptation of the source material. I honestly
can't think of a better way to approach. Blue
Beetle comics than what they did in this movie.
Overall, with the film's thrilling visual effects
action and touching cultural look at family,
the film introduces one of the genre's coolest
and most relatable superheroes yet, particularly
for DC. I'm rating the film 4 out of 5 stars,
a fresh rating on Rotten Tomatoes. Yeah, you
said particularly for DC, I think you need
that asterisk there in your review. I'm a little
bit surprised you're giving it four stars and
not three and a half stars because this is basically
the definition of a three and a half star film.
I think as you stated through the course of
your review, you have lost objectivity and
I think you should have your Rotten Tomatoes
license revoked. To which I could only reply,
haters gonna hate. And it's again, like I mentioned,
the perfect Blue Beetle movie. But that does
it for this review. Let us know what you thought
about the movie by writing to us at dynamicduelpodcast.gmail.com
or by visiting us on Instagram or Twitter X.
You can find links to all of our accounts by
checking out our show notes or visiting our
website at dynamicduel.com. And on our site
you can also find a link to our Patreon page
where you can join our dynamic 2-0 tier and
chat with us and fellow listeners, our fantastic
4 tier which gets you bonus content each month,
our X-Force tier that makes you an executive
producer of this podcast, or our newest here
that lets you join our Dynamike podcast network.
If you can't join Patreon, you can still support
the show by signing up for our e-newsletter
also at dynamicduel.com. Or you could also
rate the show on Apple podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser,
or on our website. Next week's episode is going
to be a duel leading up to our Doom Patrol versus
Guardians of the Galaxy team duel episode,
which is going to be episode 350. Next week,
we are pitting the Doom Patrol member, Danny
the Street, who if you've read the books or
you've seen the Doom Patrol show, you will
know is actually a sentient street and we're
going to pay him against the sentient island
of Krakoa. So essentially it's going to be two
locations facing off against each other and
I've not been more terrified for how speculation
is going to go in my entire life. In the words
of Rudy, we'll burn that bridge once we get
to it. Yeah. But that does it for this episode,
we want to give a big thanks to our executive
producers Ken Johnson, John Sturowski, Zachary
Hepburn, Dustin Belcombe, Mickey Mathen-Geehan,
Brandon Estergard, Nathaniel Wagner, Levi Yeaton,
Nick Abonto, Austin Wesolowski, AJ Dunkerley,
Scott Camacho, and Adam Spies for helping make
this podcast possible. And we'll talk to you
guys next week. Up, up, and away, true believers.