This is a DynaMic Network podcast.
Hi and welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast,
a weekly show where we review superhero films
and debate the superiority between Marvel and
DC by comparing their characters in stat-based
battle simulations. I'm Marvelous Joe. And I'm
his twin brother Johnny DC. And in this episode,
we're going to find out who'd win in a fight
between the Sorcerer characters Eclipso versus
Malekith. Now why are we doing Eclipso this
episode? Because yesterday was an eclipse.
That is correct. And really there's no other
reason to it. These are great characters though.
Malekith is a Thor villain, and actually he
was the villain in the Thor the Dark World
movie. And Eclipso, I believe, is a JSA villain.
Oh, he's like JSA, Spectre, but also recently
an Amethyst villain. Amethyst, interesting.
Yeah. Well, it should be a magical good time
later on this episode as we input the character
stats, run simulations, and find out who'll
win. Before we get into that, we're gonna break
down the latest Comic Quick movie news that
came out this past week. of which there was
just one news item and that is that the Fantastic
Four film has cast Julia Garner as the Silver
Surfer. As always we list our segment times
in our episode description so feel free to check
out the show notes if you want to skip ahead
to a particular topic. Our artificially intelligent
Duel simulator AJ9K has a quick message for
our listeners so listen up. Why hello there.
Do you love listening and chatting about Marvel
and DC? Then become a part of the dynamic Duel
community on Patreon, where you can choose
from three tiers. The dynamic 2-0 tier lets
you listen to this podcast without ads and
gives you access to its Discord chat group,
where you can chat with Johnny DC and Marvelous
Joe. The fantastic 4 tier gives you that and
more with two bonus episodes each month. including
bloopers and top 10 shows where Johnny and Joe
count down your favorite Marvel and DC subjects.
The X-Force tier makes you an executive producer
of Dynamic Duel, where every month you help
the hosts choose what to review and who to fight
against each other. And finally, the Dynamite
Podcast Network tier allows aspiring podcasters
to create their own battle-focused show using
this Monte Carlo simulator. Johnny and Joe will
help you develop your show, provide graphic
support and consultation, and get you simulation
results to announce on your show. Pitch the
twins your show via email at dynamic Duel podcast
at gmail.com or by reaching out to them on
social media Check it out at patreon.com slash
dynamic Duel pip cheerio Thanks a j-9k and
thanks to everyone who supports the podcast
Be sure to tune into the shows in the dynaMic
podcast network this week guys including Max
destruction which pits your favorite action
heroes from film and television against each
other this week 11 from stranger things is
facing off against Matilda And on the Senjoworld
podcast, host Zachary Hepburn speculates on
fights between fan favorite anime characters.
This Thursday, we'll find out who would win
between Sanji from One Piece against Mic Guy
from Naruto. And on the Console Combat podcast,
host John and Dean find out who would win in
fights between popular video game characters.
In yesterday's episode, they found out who would
win in a fight between Scott Pilgrim and Toon
Link. Want to give a big shout out to all three
of those shows? I think we had a fantastic
crossover event for April Fools where collectively
we found out who would win in a fight between
Godzilla and Ultraman. Super proud of those
guys. Be sure to check out their shows. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our
show notes to listen to all of the shows in
the DynaMic Podcast Network. But with that
out of the way, quick to the no prize. A no
prize is an award Marvel used to give out to
fans. Our version, the dynamic duel no prize,
is a digital award we pushed on Instagram for
the person that we feel gave the best answer
to our question of the week. Last week we asked,
what is your favorite anime and why? Um, we
did not get a lot of answers for this one. Yeah,
in fact, we got only one answer from Travis
Herndon. So I just want to give a slow clap
for our listeners. Yep. And listen to him as
Travis Herndon. This clap is for you. And if
your name is Travis Herndon, it's also for
you, but it's meant non-sarcastically. So let's
go ahead and hear his answer. He said, What's
up, dynamic dudes? Travis here. So my favorite
series would have to be Berserk. If I had to
describe Berserk to you, I would think of it
as sort of Game of Thrones meets Dark Souls.
Just the fact that it's dark, it's gritty, the
characters are real, the main characters is
tragic. person that like overcomes like great
hardships and everything. If you're a fan of
dark fantasy, I would definitely recommend Berserk
to you. So I've never seen Berserk, but I have
learned about it through the Syndrome World
podcast and it seems like a pretty dope show.
Yeah, the backstory to the main character Guts
seems pretty intense and crazy, but it looks
like an epic show for sure. Zach on Send Your
World did do a Duel episode with the character
of Guts. So if you want to learn more about
Berserk, I would recommend listening to his
episode and also watching the anime. Congrats
to Travis for winning this week's No Prize.
If you the listener want a shot at winning your
own No Prize, stay tuned to later on this episode
when we'll be asking another Question of the
Week. And now that that's done, on to the news!
Alright, this past week we found out that the
Fantastic Four film has cast the Silver Surfer
in the movie. The character will be played by
Julia Garner, who is a three-time Emmy winner,
who won for her role in the Netflix series Ozark,
and she also got a nomination for Inventing
Anna. I've never seen any of those shows. I've
heard Ozark is fantastic. I really don't know
anything about Julia Garner, but according to
a sizzle reel I saw on YouTube, she's actually
quite talented. The big news here is though
that You know, Julia Garner is not a dude and
Silver Surfer is a dude. So what the heck is
going on? So I keep seeing posts online like
apologists were like, guys, it's not the Noren
Rad version of the character. It's the shallow
ball version of the character. Right. Yeah.
Shala Ball is Noren Rad's love interest back
on Zen Law when he was living on that planet
prior to his servitude as a herald of Galactus.
The only time Shalabal has ever been the Silver
Surfer was in an alternate future timeline
in the Earth X-Books, which is actually my favorite
story. In that universe, the real Galactus
died and Silver Surfer, finding himself without
purpose, turned his former lover Shalabal into
a Silver Surfer and they soared the spaceways
together. There's not a whole lot of precedent
for Shalabal being the Silver Surfer. And my
initial reaction to this news was pure rage,
I will say. I was pretty upset. you know, Julia
Garner's acting skills notwithstanding, because
I do have faith that she will turn in a stellar
performance regardless of the character's gender.
But I went on to Reddit to see what everybody
else was saying about it, and somebody brought
up a great point. So it's well established that
the Fantastic Four film is largely going to
take place in another universe within the multiverse.
And further evidence of this fact was on display
on the April 4th. poster that Marvel Studios
released saying, Happy 4-4 Day. In the background
of that poster, we see this very futuristic
non-Earth city, basically. So if the Fantastic
Four are spending the movie in an alternate
universe, it's highly likely that this will
be an alternate universe version of Silver Surfer,
where instead of Norrin Radd sacrificing himself,
it was Shala Ball who did it. And while I would
always prefer to see Norrin Radd as the character,
The reason I'm coming to terms with this news
a little bit better is because I don't think
when we finally do get introduced to Norrin
Radd as the Silver Surfer, we're going to want
a rehash of what's happening in this alternate
universe. It makes sense for things to be different
if the Fantastic Four movie is not in the main
timeline. I don't want to see Silver Surfer
here and then see that story just redone again
in the 616 timeline. Well, you're assuming
that we're going to get an origin story for
the Silver Surfer in the Fantastic Four movie.
Um, even if we don't. I think they're trying
to stick with an alternate cast of characters
for this alternate dimension. That way things
don't feel rehashed when they finally come
to the main earth. You know when I first heard
the news, I was just laughing my ass off. Not
only at the casting choice, but also in seeing
Marvel fanboys trying to justify the choice.
But I do think that the justification is there.
Who the hell cares if this is an alternate
world? It's an alternate universe, Silver Surfer.
They don't want to do the rehash. You don't
have to rehash it! Only tell it once! If you
see the Silver Surfer's origin story in this
Fantastic Four movie, and it was Noren Rad,
and then they come to the main timeline, and
then you have a new Silver Surfer who's being
introduced to the team all over again. No!
Have him be the same Silver Surfer and have
him be upset that he can never make it back
to his home world and the other universe. It's
that fucking simple. You haven't seen the script.
I don't need to see- why would I need to see
the script? Maybe wait to judge until you see
the movie. Yeah, you don't know how it's gonna
go. It may make perfect sense. Or it didn't
need to be done in the first place. Well, I
haven't seen the script, so I wouldn't know.
Oh my gosh. It doesn't matter how good the script
is. What matters is that Norin Rad is the Silver
Surfer, and they're changing it. It doesn't
matter how good that reason is for why they
changed it. Yeah, Norin Rad is the Silver Surfer
in the primary Marvel universe. They go into
another dimension in the movie. How do you know
that? How do you know they just don't start
off in an alternate dimension and then make
their way to the 616. The source was a scooper,
Daniel RPK, who's had legit scoops in the past.
And it's highly suspected that's the reason
they've been out of the MCU this whole time.
Still not a good enough reason to me. They
could have gone to another dimension where they
found the Silver Surfer, who was Nora and Rad,
who eventually could have come back with them
into the 616. Or they could go into an alternate
dimension where they see alternate versions
of familiar characters that they will be encountering
in the 616 universe. That works too. That's
dumb. I guess. I don't know. I'll have to wait
and see. I'm not going to judge until I see
it. I guess I'm the true Marvel fan here, guys.
Joseph has given up on Marvel. He's just like
accepting everything they throw at him and
not being passionate about Marvel at all. I'll
be mad for him. I'll accept changes made to
an alternate universe for sure. So we'll go
ahead and move past this topic and move on
to our question of the week.
What would be your favorite out of left field
casting choice for an alternate universe Marvel
or DC character? Record your answer at dynamicduel.com
by clicking on the red microphone button in
the bottom right hand corner of the screen,
which will prompt you to leave us a voicemail.
Your message can be up to 30 seconds long, and
don't forget to leave your name in case we
include you on the podcast. We'll pick our favorite
answer, and award that person the Dynamic Duel
No Prize that we'll post to Instagram. Be sure
to answer before April 13th.
But I think that does it for all the news for
this episode. So let's go ahead and move on
to the main event where we find out who'd win
in a fight between the sorcerers of Eclipso
and Malachit.
Alright, Eclipso vs Malekith. This is a sorcerer
duel that we're getting into in homage to the
eclipse that happened yesterday. We'd actually
been thinking about doing this duel for a while.
It was thought up by one of our executive producers.
I can't remember which one offhand. Brandon
Essergard. That's right. And once I heard it,
I thought it was going to be a really cool
matchup. We haven't reviewed Throw the Dark
World. It's one of the MCU films that we have
not talked about yet. Of course, Malekith is
the primary antagonist in that film. So people
are pretty familiar with him. But I also think
people are somewhat familiar with Eclipso as
well. He is a pretty powerful villain in DC
Comics. He hasn't been in any movies, but he
was the primary villain of Stargirl Season Two,
if anyone's seen that. The version of Malekith
that was in Thor the Dark World is not really
akin to his comic book counterpart. The backstory
to Malekith is actually quite interesting, so
I can't wait to get into it. But to explain
the methodology behind our duels, let's go to
our sentient duel simulator. Alfred Jarvis
9000. AJ and Ike tell our listeners how you
go about determining a winner in our Duel matchups.
Yes, of course sir. The way I determine a winner
between the contestants is by running 1000
Monte Carlo simulations using the characters
statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation is a probabilistic
model used to determine outcomes through random
sampling. In this case, I randomize the statistics
along a normal distribution as a way to simulate
the many variables that can occur during battle.
The stat parameters are based on the official
Marvel power grid from which the DC characters'
statistics are extrapolated. Additional stat
categories are included such as range, damage
potential, versatility and perception in order
to create a more detailed and accurate simulation.
The results of the 1000 simulations provide
a percentage of wins for each character. The
contestant with the higher percentage is declared
the victor as they have a higher probability
to win any given battle. In an equitable pairing,
neither character should win 100% of the matches.
The comic book stories have shown that there's
even a way for Batman to defeat Superman, so
the confidence rate of my method falls in line
with the precedents that have been established
in the source material. My mathematical simulations
are without subjectivity or bias. Feats are
not the sole consideration, nor are fan votes
tabulated for determination of the winner.
Thanks AJ9K! Before we run the simulations though,
we'd like to break down each character's histories
and abilities. before improvising a scenario
on how we imagine one of the 1000 simulations
would play out beat for beat. And I believe
it's my turn to go first with the Marvel character,
so let me go ahead and tell you all about Malekith
the Accursed. Malekith the Dark Elf was born
in the realm of Svartalheim, the 13th son of
a 13th son, whose father and brothers were
slain as soldiers in a war with the rock trolls.
Malekith's mother promised her only remaining
child that he would not have to die as a soldier,
and she sold him into slavery. where he would
work in turmoil as a corpse burner for a group
of Undertakers. After years of disposing bodies
from the war's battlefields, young Malekith
was captured by the Rock Trolls who imprisoned
him. One of his fellow prisoners was an old
Dark Elf wizard, who used magic to help the
two escape the Trolls, and Malekith became the
Sorcerer's apprentice. He trained in magic
over the years, and was noted by the old wizard
as one of the most gifted spellcasters he'd
ever seen. perhaps strong enough to end the
war. In response to his mentor's request to
unite the Dark Elf clan and bring about peace,
Malekith stabbed the wizard repeatedly, telling
him that the Elf's strength is forged from the
tragedies of war. The old sorcerer, with his
dying act, cast a curse on Malekith's face,
marking half of it in black for the rest of
his days. Returning to his childhood home, Malekith
fed his mom to her pack of hunting dogs. claiming
his clan's title as the Lord of the Wild Hunt
and going on to become the King of the Dark
Elves due to the fear he instilled in his people.
For his frequent acts of war and aggression,
Odin, the Allfather of the Nine Realms banished
Malekith to Limbo, where he remained for centuries.
However, in the present day, the Dark Elf King
struck an alliance with Loki, the Norse god
of mischief and brother to the mighty hero Thor.
You can learn more about Loki in his duel against
Ares. and more about Thor in his duel against
Wonder Woman. Escaping to Limbo with Loki's
help, Malekith made his way to Earth, where
a powerful artifact known as the Casket of
Ancient Winters was being hidden. Malekith unearthed
the casket, and though Thor was able to defeat
him, the Dark Elf managed to shatter the artifact.
This unleashed massive blizzards across the
world, which the Avengers had to contend with
as Thor imprisoned Malekith back on Asgard.
Previously, Malekith forced the strongest dark
elf in his army, Algrim the Strong, to don
a powerful armor that would make him virtually
indestructible, and Algrim became a cursed
warrior known as Curse. Seeking revenge against
Malekith for how he was treated, Curse infiltrated
Asgard to seek him out in prison. However, Malekith
had escaped Asgard's prison by taking on the
form of Thor's friend named Baldr the Brave,
who at the time was about to be crowned the
Lord of Asgard when Thor denied the role. Kursk
saw through Malekith's disguise though and
seemingly killed his former leader. Years later,
it all turned out to be a ruse for Malekith's
escape when the dark elf was discovered to be
alive. Malekith would later go on to use Kursk's
hatred for him to achieve his own ends when
he cast a spell that made Thor appear as Malekith,
inciting Kursk to recruit a band of mythical
monsters to go up against the Thunder God.
In the end, Thor won out with the help of his
friends Sif, Heimdall, Volstag, and the Pogon,
Fandral, and Beta Ray Bill. Malekith even manipulated
Hela, the goddess of death, into the fray,
but she was able to clear Chris's mind to break
Malekith's spell, and she took Malekith with
her back to her domain of hell. He later escaped
and stole the casket of Ancient Winters, which
had been reforged. Malekith used it to summon
a demon made of ice to seek out Asgardian blood,
then froze the golden city of Asgard with a
coldness that spread even into the realm of
hell. As Malekith attacked Odin, who at the
time was resting in the Odin's sleep, Thor
was able to successfully defend his father after
obtaining an artifact from Odin's vault called
the Gem of Infinite Suns. With it, Thor defeated
Malekith and the Ice Demon and returned the
coldness back into the casket, which he then
sealed closed. Malekith later set out to conquer
all the realms by amassing his Dark Elf army,
allying with the Frost Giants, and killing
anyone who didn't pledge their allegiance to
him. This forced Thor to assemble a League
of Realms, uniting warriors from every land
to stop Malekith's army. This included Sir
Ivory Hunnyshot of the Light Elves, Auggie the
Mountain Giant, Ud the Troll, Screwbeard the
Dwarf, and Lady Wazirah of the Dark Elves. Together,
their band defeated Malekith's army, but the
Dark Elves refused to let their king be imprisoned.
From his throne, Malekith later plotted to
steal the ten rings of the Chinese villain known
as the Mandarin, whom you'll learn more about
in our Abra-Kadabra vs. Mandarin episode. This
led to Iron Man taking the fight to Malekith
in Spartalheim, wearing a suit made of literal
iron, which was the Dark Elf's only weakness.
For a time, Thor became unworthy of wielding
his Uru Hammer Mjolnir, an opportunity Malekith
sought to take advantage of. Coming to Midgard,
aka Earth, the Dark Elf easily overtook Thor,
slicing off his left arm in battle.
was able to wield Mjolnir and used it to defend
Thor, becoming the new God of Thunder. Malekith
was able to disappear with Thor's arm though,
and burned it to ash. Soon after, Malekith
started a War of the Realms, where it was revealed
that he had formed his own League called the
Dark Council. This included himself, Ulic the
Troll, a nameless lava being from Muspelheim,
King Lofi of the Frost Giants, a Minotaur, Loki,
and the Asgardian known as Enchantress, whom
you can learn more about in her duel against
DC's Enchantress. This sorceress manipulated
Queen Elsa of the Light Elves into marrying
Malekith, uniting the realms of Svartalheim
and Alfheim, and making his Dark Army unstoppable.
He began taking over the other realms one by
one, including Asgard itself, until only Midgard
remained. His forces besieged Europe, which
Malekith dubbed New Svartalheim, where he used
dark magic to wield the Venom symbiote. adding
to his power. It took all of Earth's heroes
dividing up into strike forces to defend the
rest of the planet, and four variants of Thor
himself to take on Malekith. In the end, Thor
was able to wield Mjolnir once again, using
it to separate Malekith from the symbiote.
In a last ditch effort, Malekith, as the Lord
of the Wild Hunt, tried to summon a legion
of supernatural dog wolves to devour Thor, but
his control over the beasts was broken by his
fear, and they devoured their master instead.
Malekith's soul was then sent to hell, where
Hela had him crucified with his eyes sewn open,
forced to watch for all eternity the innocent
childlike portion of his soul untainted by war,
playing with his former hounds. Powers-wise,
Malekith is a dark elf, possessing innate physical
enhancements, including strength enough to
lift 10 tons. Increased with magic, he can improve
his physicality to lift up to 90 tons. He also
has enhanced speed, durability, agility, longevity,
and and healing speed. As the most powerful
dark elf sorcerer, he can wield magic energies
to cast all manner of spells. This includes
but is not limited to shapeshifting, illusion
casting, teleportation, matter transmutation,
hypnosis, telekinesis, and the conjuring of
eldritch energy blasts and shields. He is also
a skilled swordsman and as the lord of the wild
hunt, he wields a hunting horn that lets him
summon a legion of supernatural dogs. that can
track and devour his opponents. Finally, Malekith
is an experienced strategist and master manipulator.
Like all dark elves, he has one major weakness
and that is to iron, and that's Malekith. Wait,
you weren't kidding when you were saying that
the version in Thor the Dark World is different
from the comics version. The comics version
is so much cooler. Yeah, I really like the heavy
fantasy element that Malekith brings to the
world of Thor comic books. You know, given that
he is a dark elf from one of the nine realms.
In the movie, the dark elves were almost like
sci-fi guys. They had like guns and lasers
and stuff like that. It was a little bit weird.
The movie definitely took a weird turn with
the character. And also Christopher Eccleston's
characterization was not really accurate either
because Mallekith is like a very boastful, talkative
braggart type of character. He's not like quiet
and brooding like Eccleston's performance was.
And I'm not gonna lie, I actually kinda liked
Melikith in Thor the Dark World. I don't hate
that movie as much as other people do, but
now I kind of don't like it. So you ruined the
movie for me. Well, I mean, we'll talk about
the movie next week in our next episode. All
right. Well, moving on to my character's backstory,
which is way cooler even than that. Let me tell
you all about Eclipso. In the beginning, God,
AKA the presence in DC Comics. created the heavens
and the earth, and appointed various angels
and spirits to represent various aspects of
himself in the material world. One of these
aspects, Galeed, became the embodiment of God's
divine wrath. It wasn't long before Galeed
became corrupted by power, as his wrath was
not tempered by vengeance or a sense of justice.
The presence chose a new embodiment for his
wrath, a former fallen angel who sought redemption
The Spectre, who you can learn more about in
our Spectre vs Galactus episode. The Spectre
split Galeed in two, imprisoning one portion
in the deepest crater on the dark side of the
moon and the other within a massive black diamond
known as the Heart of Darkness that had been
mined from the planet Apocalypse. The Heart
of Darkness attracted evil and so was hidden
for most of human civilization, though it was
eventually discovered in the late 1890s. by
an explorer named Henry Gordon, within an ancient
temple deep in the African jungle. The diamond
corrupted Henry, who killed his companion, a
university professor, once they found it. Henry
took the diamond to a jeweler, and tasked him
with dividing the diamond into 1,000 identical
gemstones within one year's time. When Henry
returned for the diamonds, he had the jeweler
killed by two thugs, who stole all but one of
the diamonds from Henry. and sold over 100
of the gemstones before Henry found them a week
later and killed them. The splitting of the
diamond weakened the prison-like nature of it,
which allowed the spirit of Galeed, now referring
to itself as Eclipso, to influence anyone in
possession of one of the black diamonds if
they were angry, or to possess them outright
if they were violent in nature, though Eclipso
could easily be banished from his host when
exposed to sunlight. One of the gemstones eventually
found its way back to the African jungle and
came into the possession of a tribal sorcerer
named Mophir. When a solar energy scientist
named Bruce Gordon traveled to the jungle to
view the solar eclipse, a possessed Mophir attacked
Bruce, scratching him with his diamond before
falling off of a cliff. Bruce took the diamond
back with him to America, where, anytime there
was an eclipse, he became possessed by Eclipso.
now a frequent foe of the DC superhero community.
Unaware of the nature of the Diamond, Bruce
simply believed that Eclipso was an alternate,
superpowered evil persona of his, though when
he learned the nature of the Diamond, he was
able to prevent himself from becoming the villain
through solar-powered technology. It was later
revealed that Henry Gordon was Bruce Gordon's
time-traveling son. who traveled to the past
intending to destroy the Heart of Darkness and
prevent his father from being used by Eclipso,
but was corrupted by the Diamond instead. Eventually,
the time traveling hero known as Mon-El discovered
a fortress that Eclipso had erected on the dark
side of the moon and became possessed by the
other half of the spirit while investigating.
This allowed Eclipso to merge both halves of
his spirit and managed to possess all of Earth's
heroes whom he brought to the moon. Bruce Gordon
was able to free everyone, however, alongside
a team of scientists who wielded solar weaponry
that Bruce had designed. In an epic battle against
Eclipso on the moon, the villain was seemingly
destroyed by a solar bomb. But because the Heart
of Darkness still existed, so too did Eclipso's
spirit. He next appeared in the fictional South
American nation of Peridot, where he possessed
a drug and eventually possessed the country's
president, allowing him to take control over
the entire nation and its army. Seeking vengeance
against Bruce Gordon, Eclipso attacked Bruce's
fiance's father, resulting in Bruce gathering
several allies, including his fiance Mona,
a fellow scientist named Cave Carson, and the
Creeper, who you can learn more about in our
Creeper vs. Nightcrawler episode. Bruce and
the others ventured into Peridot, only to be
captured by Eclipso, and force-fed black diamonds
before being set free. The ordeal stirred Amanda
Waller and other heroes to action, though U.S.
forces suffered major casualties as a result
of warring with Peridot's forces. Amanda Waller,
Bruce Gordon, and others were put on trial
by the UN for attempting to overthrow a sovereign
nation, and Eclipso threatened to nuke the
planet if they weren't found guilty. As heroes
around the world prepared to take on Eclipso,
The Phantom Stranger and the Spectre united
to fight the villain, managing to gather all
of the black diamonds around the world and reforming
the full Heart of Darkness, imprisoning Eclipso
once again. At one point, when the Spectre lost
faith in God, Eclipso managed to break free
of the diamond and possess the specter. The
specter was eventually able to overcome and
retrap Eclipso in the Heart of Darkness before
he crushed the diamond to dust. The fragments
of the Heart of Darkness were eventually gathered
by a man named Alex Montez, however, who was
enraged over the death of his cousin caused
by Eclipso. Save for a single shard, Alex liquefied
the diamond and injected it into himself. body
and occult glyphs and symbology, Eclipso was
trapped within Alex, who took up his moniker
and power as a new version of the villain.
Though Alex later became an anti-hero and ally
of the Justice Society and Black Adam, he was
eventually injured with part of his tattoo skin
Damage, which broke the glyphs and freed Eclipso,
who killed Alex's girlfriend, which caused Alex
to
Superboy Prime, who teamed with Alexander Luther
Jr. of Earth-3 to restore the multiverse in
the Infinite Crisis event. Superboy Prime gave
the gemstone to Jean Loring, the ex-wife of
Ray Palmer, the Atom. Jean, as Eclipso, manipulated
the specter into destroying magic, which he
nearly successfully did. As the sorcerers and
magicians of Earth fought back, one of them,
an anti-hero known as Nightshade,
where Eclipsa would be trapped and tormented
by the light. Due to his connection to Bruce
Gordon Eclipso eventually made his way back
to Earth and took possession of Bruce once
again, though Bruce found he was able to control
Eclipso as long as he controlled his temper.
When Eclipso managed to kill Bruce's wife, Mona,
he was able to take full control of Bruce's
body and wage another campaign against Earth's
heroes, revealing to the angelic hero Zahriyel,
whom he defeated, that his ultimate goal was
to kill God. You can learn more about Zahriyel
in our Zahriyel vs. Archangel episode. After
killing the specter and absorbing all of his
power, Eclipso destroyed the moon, just before
attempting to destroy the Earth and its inhabitants'
love for God. With the combined might of all
of Earth's heroes, however, Eclipso was defeated.
In post-Flashpoint continuity, Eclipso long
ago possessed Lord Kala, a scion of House Onyx
and House Diamond in the fantasy dimension of
Neela, aka Gemworld. of Niela, but was defeated
by Lady Shandra of House Amethyst, who trapped
him in a gem called the Black Diamond, which
was banished to Earth's realm. Powers-wise,
Eclipso possesses a vast amount of dark, magical
energy that grants him vast strength and vulnerability,
immortality, telekinesis, and telepathy. He
can emit this energy, often by focusing his
gaze through a fragment of the Heart of
darkness and from his light right eye paralyzing
bursts of black light. He can alter his size
and can also manipulate the environment around
him to create thunderstorms, floods, and other
phenomena often attributed to God's wrath. He
can fly or teleport through shadow and he can
influence or possess others, particularly if
they are in contact with a fragment of the
Heart of Darkness. Since part of his spirit
is confined to the Heart of Darkness, Destroying
it can weaken him and he's also vulnerable to
bright light and that's Eclipso. If only Malekith
could summon bright light, which I don't think
he can as a member of the Dark Elves. Yes!
But, I don't know if Eclipso can summon iron
so I hope he can't. Oh, one more thing he can
do I forgot to mention is not summon iron, but
he can create constructs of shadow and gemstone
as of recent comics. Oh interesting, that's
pretty cool. That's a cool visual. They need
to put Eclipso in a bigger movie or something
than just, you know, Stargirls season two.
Although he was freaky as hell in Stargirls
season two. Like there was some horror movie
type shit. Really? I feel like I gotta check
that show out sometime. It's not bad, we should
have reviewed it, honestly. Well, that's, I
blame you for that one. I'll take the blame.
where fantasies collide and heroes clash, one
podcast network rises above the rest. Prepare
yourself for the ultimate showdowns in comic
books, video games, movies, and anime. The
Dynomic Podcast Network presents Console Combat,
where video game legends brawl every Monday.
Dynamic Podcast Network. Comic Book Titans smash
every Tuesday. Max Destruction, where TV and
action heroes battle every Wednesday. And Sendro
World, where anime champions clash every Thursday.
Join us as we speculate on the matches and armed
with the power of mathematical simulations,
discover who will emerge victorious. Visit dynamicpodcast.com
where we settle the debate and settle the score.
Well now that we got their histories and abilities
out of the way, let's speculate on how one
of the 1000 simulated matches will go. The winner
is determined by simulations, not the speculation,
but it's fun to imagine how this fight could
play out. AJ and IK, what are the rules of
our speculation? Well I should say there are
no rules, other than the characters have no
prior knowledge of the other going into the
fight. All they are aware of starting out is
that the other character is a threat that needs
to be eliminated. For the speculation... The
contestants will begin approximately 50 meters
apart in a nondescript environment that will
have no bearing on the match itself, as no environmental
statistics are considered in my simulations.
The contestants must earn victory on their own
merit. Alright then, let's get into it. Eclipso
and Malekith meet on the battlefield. Who goes
first? I think Malekith is going to see Eclipso
and conjure a blade, like a Chris sword type
thing, you know like a, it's a sword with like
a wavy blade. Right, right, yeah. He's gonna
see Eclipso and probably assume that the guy
is cursed just like him since they have similar
face marks and Malekith is gonna be like let
me fix the other side for you and from his sword
He's gonna shoot out an eldritch flame blast
right at Eclipso's face. Just melting that shit
right off Okay, I mean so as this fireball
is coming at Eclipso He's gonna generate a shield
made of gemstone to block it then he's gonna
hold up a shard of the heart of darkness to
his right eye, flashing this burst of black
light that's gonna paralyze Malekith. All right.
So Malekith is paralyzed. And by the time he
even realizes what's happening, Eclipso has
already moved right over to him and created
his own sword of crystal and shadow that he's
just going to plunge right into Malekith's
chest. No, cause Malekith teleports, you know,
he disappears in this green flash. and Eclipso
doesn't see him anymore. All he hears is Malekith's
laughter just echoing from all directions.
And it's like, it'll start off quietly at first,
but it's gonna get like louder and louder,
just like deafening Eclipso as Malekith suddenly
appears, knocking Eclipso's sword out of his
hand and then catching it and then using both
of the swords, like scissors to lop off Eclipso's
head. Wait, he took Eclipso's sword? Yes. Okay,
well, as Malekith is holding Eclipso's shadow
sword. Before he could decapitate Eclipso, the
shadow blade moves like liquid up Melikith's
arm and across his body before disappearing
into his ears. So now Melikith is possessed
by Eclipso with like an eclipse symbol over
his face and Eclipso is going to force Melikith
to cut off his own head. Well I mean if Melikith
sees this like liquid shadow moving up over
his body, that's gonna give him time to come
up with a counter spell pretty quick. And you
know, like as a dark elf, he's familiar with
shadow magic, so he's gonna take control of
this shadow, lift it off of himself, and like
reshape it into the form of like this raven
that is gonna fly at Eclipso and snatch the
black diamond that he's carrying away from
him. Okay, well Eclipso, he's gonna quickly
grow to like three stories and just snatch
the bird before it can fly away with his diamond.
And Eclipso's gonna just look down at Melikith
and slam his fist down right on him. Just crushing
his body into the ground. Okay, but you know,
Eclipso's tall and a little bit slow. So as
his fist is coming down, Malekith summons the
Casket of Ancient Winters artifact from out
of thin air. And he uses it to freeze Eclipso's
arm right through. What? Dude, he can't do that.
What? Why not? How is that allowed? Why does
Eclipso get the Heart of Darkness and Malekith
doesn't get the Casket of Ancient Winters,
like in his back pocket? Because Eclipso always
has a shard of the Heart of Darkness. Yeah,
and like the casket of Ancient Winters is small
enough to be portable, you know? It's smaller
than it was in the movies, in the first Thor
movie. Really? Yeah, it's tiny. It's like the
size of a small jewelry box kind of thing. Oh.
Meh. So this works, you know, Eclipso's fist
comes down and his whole arm just shatters right
off with, you know, Malekith protecting himself
with a magic energy shield, smiling and then
hiding the casket again. Dang. So, Calypso's
pissed off right now. So, as he shrinks back
down to his normal height, you know, his eyes
just glowing red, he's gonna conjure this violent
thunderstorm that rains lightning across the
environment and zaps Malekith like numerous
times until he's literally fried. Malekith
deals with lightning all the time when he fights
Thor, you know, he's no stranger to a lightning
attack. All he's gonna do here is transform
his body into like this mist cloud and that's
gonna sink into the earth below them and therefore
the lightning is just you know gonna strike
the ground no big deal but then all of a sudden
the ground shakes like there's an earthquake
and a group of rock trolls are gonna rise from
the ground and just beat the shit out of a
clip so with their rock clubs oh dang wait so
is the clip so in the rock trolls or he just
conjured them malekits still in the ground in
his missed form and he just conjured the rock
trolls okay so eclipse those Storm like vanished
as soon as Melikith did so the Sun is probably
shining right now and right when the rock trolls
emerge Eclipso is gonna telekinetically slam
them all together to form a single like giant
stone ball But he levitates into the sky to
cast a shadow upon the environment an eclipse
that increases his power So wherever Melikith
is right now Eclipso is gonna telekinetically
pull his mist body into his grasp and hold
him and blasting Melikith point blank with this
dark energy blast that's so powerful it's gonna
send Melikith crashing through the rock troll
moon and all the way to the sun where he dies.
That's not even a real eclipse, how does that
count? It's counted before in the comics where
like things could block the sun it's like oh
it's an eclipse! Okay. I'm gonna say that when
Eclipso does summon Malekith into his grasp,
he's holding onto his hunting horn. And as
he blows into it, he's gonna summon the Wild
Hunt, which is this pack of supernatural dogs,
and also a winged white tiger, and they're all
just gonna devour Eclipso whole. And Eclipso's
gonna be like, Oh god, they're killing me! And
Malekith is gonna be laughing and having a
good time. Match over. Okay, so three things.
One, uh... That tiger is super random. Two,
Eclipso's not gonna be saying anything if this
happens. And it's not gonna happen because
three, yeah, that wild hunt is gonna follow
Malekith's ass into the sun because he's already
there by the time he blows that horn. Well,
one, don't knock the white tiger because it's
bad ass, you know, it has wings and Malekith
rides it and it looks awesome. Two, you're
wrong. And three, let's run the stats to see
which of these scenarios happens. Sure. Okay,
so either Bella Kith gets blasted into the sun
or he blows his horn in time to have the wild
hunt devour Eclipso. We'll go ahead and input
the stats, run the simulations, and come back
with a winner. AJ9K, hit it! Inputting data.
Running calculations. Processing results. Simulations
complete. Alright, this is a pretty fun matchup.
It's always really hard. speculate on matches
between wizards and sorcerers and like magical
entities and stuff like that because they can
almost do anything so you have to be really
creative and make sure that all of the spells
are in keeping with the themes of the character
and stuff like that but that being said I think
we did a pretty good job with that speculation
it was a lot of fun yeah both characters are
really powerful Malekith ended up being more
powerful than I anticipated I thought Eclipsa
was gonna totally take this considering You
know, he's pretty much the equivalent of the
specter, but uh, Melikith definitely held his
own. Yeah. Melikith goes, you know, toe to
toe with Thor and obviously Thor can beat the
specter, so there you go. Uh, Galactus couldn't
even beat the specter. Spoiler alert. Spoilers.
Come on, man. Come on. Everybody go listen
to the specter versus Galactus Duel episode
now, but not before you get the results here.
Stat wise, Eclipso was more durable and stronger
and could seemingly do more damage with less
effort. The dude is really powerful. But Malekith,
we said, has him on fighting skill because
he does a lot of swordplay, especially when
he was wielding like the Necro Sword in the
comics. He was able to successfully best Thor
in sword combat by chopping his arm off. And
Eclipso hasn't really been shown to do that
kind of stuff too much. Well, he actually is
shown to do a lot of sword fighting, but he
also tends to lose a lot of those sword fights.
Because of Eclipso's strength He seemingly tends
to tank a lot of attacks directed at him, whereas
Malekith avoids most attacks that are directed
at him, either by transmuting his form into
a mist or by pulling up a Eldritch shield or
something like that. Teleporting, so we said
Malekith had a slight edge over Eclipso when
it comes to evasiveness. But both these guys
are super versatile. They're pretty smart and
strategic. Yeah, and they're both really fast
and they can both teleport. So all that said,
Jonathan. Who do you think is going to win
this and why do you think it's Malekith? I don't
think it's Malekith. I think it's Eclipso.
I think it's going to be closer than I thought
it was going to be, but I still think Eclipso
is going to take the lead here, as do our Instagram
followers, 68% of whom said that Eclipso was
going to take the win. I don't think it's going
to be a win percentage that high in the simulation
results, but I think Eclipso is still going
to get the win. I'm honestly surprised Eclipso
beat Malekith in the poll. considering I tend
to think of these things as popularity contests.
And since Malekith was in Thor the Dark World,
I thought more people would actually vote for
him. But I think it just kind of goes to show
how much people really don't like Thor the
Dark World. Well, let's see if these people
are right. AJ9K, the results please. Hey, Yuasa.
Okay, the winner between Eclipso and Malekith
is... Don't act like you're frozen. It was
Eclipso. Yes. Yeah. Eclipso out of the 1000
matches won 531 battles over Malekith's 469
wins. So it was 53.1% over 46.9%. See, that's
actually closer than I thought it was going
to be, but I'll still take the win because Eclipso
is dope. I think Eclipso is lame. I think Eclipses
in general are lame. You know, it's just a,
just a big shadow. get over it people who cares.
I think you're lame Jonathan big time and I
think we should wrap this shit up. Don't be
a sore loser. People wanted Eclipsa to win the
people got what they wanted. We should all
be happy. I am people. Yeah, but you don't you
don't count Marvel fans aren't real people.
Anyway, what are you talking about? Of course,
we're real people. We have real feelings. They
get really hurt when we lose these Duel matches.
Okay. Punch us, we bleed. Okay, don't actually.
All right, that does it for this episode, guys.
Let us know what you thought about the Duel
results by writing to us at dyna or by visiting
us on Instagram, which you can find a link
to in our show notes or by visiting our website
at dynamicduel.com. And on our site, you can
also find a link to our Patreon page, where
you can join our Dynamic 2.0 tier and chat
with us and fellow listeners. Our fantastic
4 tier, which gets you bonus content each month,
our X-Force tier. that makes you an executive
producer of this podcast, or our newest tier
that lets you join our Dynamic Podcast Network.
And please don't forget to rate the show on
Apple Podcasts, Spotify, Podchaser, or on our
website. And actually, if you've made it this
far into the episode, please subscribe to us
on YouTube. Our numbers are abysmal there.
Most of our listeners actually come through
our podcast RSS feed. So yeah, if you wouldn't
mind, just go ahead and subscribe. In our next
episode, as we mentioned earlier, We will be
doing a throwback review of the film Thor the
Dark World. I think it will be interesting
to revisit this film after a lot of terrible
Marvel projects like the Marvels have come
out. Watch your language. OK, words mean things.
You can't just call the Marvels terrible when
it was in fact not terrible and, you know, adequate.
That's how you could describe the Marvels.
OK, if you want to talk about terrible, look
at a movie like Catwoman. OK, that's a proper
word for that movie. All right. But that does
it for this episode guys, we want to give a
big thanks to our executive producers Ken Johnson,
John Sturowski, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Belcombe,
Miki Mantengian, Brandon Estergard, Nathaniel
Wagner, Levi Yatin, Austin Wasilewski, AJ Dunkerley,
Scott Camacho, Adam Spies, Andrew Shunk, and
Dean Molesky for helping make this podcast
possible. We'll talk to you guys next week.
Up and Away, true believers. Once upon a time
I was falling in love, now I'm only falling
apart. There's nothing I can do. A total eclipse
of the fart.