Welcome to the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly
show where we review superhero films and debate
the superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle simulations.
I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin brother, Marvelous
Joe. And in this episode, it's a duel episode
where we're pitting Sinestro against Magneto.
And of course, this ties into our Dark Phoenix
review from our last episode. Right, yeah. I'm
really looking forward to see who'd win in
this match because they're both insanely powerful
villains who have like really... compelling
character arcs from the comics. I know some
people were expecting us to pit Magneto against
Dr. Polaris, I think his name is, but those
guys are so similar that I feel like it wouldn't
be an interesting fight because what you'd end
up getting is like a Hawkeye versus Green Arrow
situation where the characters are identical
and the match ends up being like a coin toss.
Yeah, that's so fun. This is going to be much
more interesting. Yeah, because it's characters
with similar power levels, but with different
power sets all together. Yeah, we'll get into
more of why we think this is a good matchup
later on in the episode. Before that, we're
going to break down the news items from the
past week, of which there is not much news.
No, kind of slow. Yeah, Lobo is getting his
own spinoff show on the Syfy channel from Krypton,
which is also on that channel. And the Avengers
are getting their own video game. Yeah, we
don't usually comment on video game news, but
I feel like this is a big thing to talk about.
It was a pretty decent trailer, so there is
a big lead up to it for sure. I think it just
kind of disappointed everyone. What? Really?
I guess that's the word on the street, huh?
Yeah. We'll get into it. Yeah. But as always,
our segment times are in our episode description.
So feel free to jump right to whatever topic
you want to listen to. Right before we get
into the news, we want to give a big, huge shout
out to those who have rated us and reviewed
us on the Apple Podcasts platform. As you know,
we're trying to get to 200 reviews because
at that point we become eligible to become critics
on Rotten Tomatoes and have our reviews of
the Marvel and DC movies count toward those
films official tomato meter. Yeah, we don't
have any new ratings. We're still at 110. but
we do have a few bladed shout outs to people
who have given us reviews. Yeah, we want to
give thanks to NRA 413 for leaving us a review,
as well as Circus Loving and his sons, Harry
and Tasker. You guys get a special shout out.
Typically, we say that this show is geared toward
adults because of the language that we just
can't help ourselves from saying. It's so hard.
Kids know these words nowadays, right? They
should it. It's not what Superman would do.
This episode for you, Harry and Tess, I'm going
to try my hardest not to say any swear words.
Yep, this is for you, too. It's going to be
especially hard considering that this is a dual
episode. Yeah, it's always when I get the most
frustrated. So it's going to be a huge challenge.
Yeah. Instead of the F word, I'm going to say
Frick. And instead of the A hole word, I'm going
to say butthole. And instead of the S word,
I'm going to say snap. Oh, snap. Exactly. So
yeah, thank you guys for leaving us reviews
again. And remember Harry and Tasker, Marvel
is better. What? They don't cook to the no
prize. A No Prize is an award Marvel used to
give out up until the 90s to fans. Our version,
the dynamic duel No Prize, is a digital award
that we post on social media that Jonathan
personally draws for those who we feel gave
the best answer to our question of the week.
Last week's question was in regards to the news
that the DC Universe app might be going under.
Yeah, it was. Would you prefer to have a DC
Universe app subscription or a WarnerMedia
app subscription that only has some DC content?
The television stuff, not the comic books.
Right. We got a lot of answers, a lot of great
answers. Yeah. Honorable mention goes to Jace
Crump for his answer that he would prefer to
just have the WarnerMedia app because it has
more content than the DC app and would have
a bigger audience. Iranagami gave the answer
DC Universe because he enjoys the apps, comic
libraries and animated shows, provided that
the quality is better than the CW. Honorable
mention goes to Dustin Balcom, who said he'd
prefer to have the DC Universe app because it
pays for itself. If you just read four to five
comics a month, And plus it has those extra
shows. Jeremy Orr said that he would prefer
the Warner Media app because it has a larger
audience pool and therefore the price can stay
low. Plus getting anime and other great content
is just awesome. Honorable mention goes to
James Cole III who prefers the DC Universe app
because it has fantastic original content,
over 22,000 digital comics on all your devices
and television. It sounds like an advertisement.
I think James Cole III works for DC Universe.
I'm sold. Joel Seagrave also gave the answer
DC Universe. But he would prefer it to be on
the PS4 and he feels that a Warner Media app
would be too expensive. Honorable mention goes
to Jonathan Hazelton who said he would prefer
subscribing to the DC Universe app because he
doubts that there will be comics on the Warner
Media app. Ken Johnson also said he wants the
DC Universe app. There's so many DC Universe
app people here. I know, right? I'm like really
happy about that. There's so many DC fans.
It's so weird. Yeah, it's awesome. I didn't
think any of them existed. So amazing. Ken
Johnson wants the DC Universe app. But he wants
them to open up all of the DC film and television
content instead of, you know, just putting out
different things each month. And also he wants
all of the episodes for the television shows
to be released at once. That's a huge aspect
to why I think the DC universe is not as successful
as it could be. I agree. If I could binge Swamp
Thing like in one weekend, I would much prefer
that to having to wait, you know, 10 weeks,
especially because I know it's not going to
continue. So like, what's the incentive? Right.
Exactly and the hype's all gonna die by the
time the show ends. Right. Anyway, honorable
mention also goes to Jeremy Hoyt, who said he
would prefer the DC Universe app because he
wants access to all DC content, including that
terrible Green Lantern movie. What? Which I
think makes sense. The final honorable mention
goes to Caleb Elbers, who said that he only
wants content that's good and therefore wants
a dynamic dual streaming service with film
commentaries. and shorts of the duels. Yes,
I would totally pay for that. Like animated
shorts of the duels? Yeah. Or even live action.
Even live action. They do that with the Bat
in the Sun productions. What is that called?
Like superhero showdown or something like that.
That's right, that's right. Shut up and take
my money. I would totally pay for that. That
was a very flattering answer. Flattery will
get you everywhere. But it won't give you the
no prize this time for some reason. Because
as cool as a dynamic duel streaming app would
be, I don't think it would be nearly as cool
as Gaby Mai's answer who said, they would prefer
the DC Universe app, but only with DC Universe
Online, the game, and other DC games. I didn't
even think about that. DC has so many great
video games. So he wants the app to have the
comics and the television shows and the movies
and the video games. Yes. I think a lot of
people would switch to the DC Universe app if
it came with those games too. Yeah, like the
Batman Arkham games? Absolutely. Yeah, yeah.
Congrats again to Gavi Mai for your answer
this week. You win the no prize. And if you,
the listener, want to win your own no prize,
go ahead and stay tuned to later on this episode
when we will be asking another question of
the week. With that all out of the way, onto
the news.
Okay, so last week, like just hours before his
debut on the Krypton season two opener, Syfy
announced that Lobo will be getting his own
spin-off show. Is it gonna be like TVMA? Oh,
I hope so. I hope so, why not? It's Syfy channel.
I think they could do TVMA content on there.
If they don't, Lobo should be the first one.
Now I haven't actually seen the episode because
I don't have the Syfy channel, but I have seen
clips from the episode and he just looks ruthless,
man. He looks like he's gonna be a really good
Lobo. Really? And I love the character of Lobo.
Like I still remember getting really excited
when they said that Danny Trejo was gonna be
Lobo on the Flash television series. What? Yeah,
that ended up not happening. Really? But it
would have been so perfect. Is this the first
live action version of Lobo that we've seen?
Yes. Yeah. Wow. He looks a lot like the character.
It's pretty well done. Yeah. I've always thought
he was kind of a crazy character, kind of in
the same vein of like Deadpool and how wacky
and inappropriate he is, how like un-kid friendly,
you know? He's a great character for Harry
and Tasker, you know Because he doesn't say
cuss words, you know, he instead of the f-word
He says frag and he says like bastitch a fast
itch. Yeah, those are safe curse words, right?
I guess I they don't sound like it but you know
Technically, that's true. I guess the show
is gonna be written and produced by Krypton's
same showrunner Cameron Welsh I've only seen
like the first four episodes of Krypton and
it was fine Like, I'm still not too invested
in the story of Superman's grandfather. Yeah.
But, like, the production value is decent.
Well, it's kind of like Gotham, where in that
show, all these Batman villains are popping
up, like, prematurely. Yeah. In the Batman universe.
Right. And in this one, it's like all Superman's
villains are popping up prematurely in the Superman
universe. But it's guys like Brainiac, you
know, who, of course, they were around before
Superman. Uh-huh. So. And Doomsday was too,
I guess. Yeah. Can you tell us a little bit
about Lobo, for those who might not know about
him? Well, he was a character created in the
80s, which makes sense. I think he started
off as like a minor villain for the Omega Men.
He was a space biker. Yeah, right. He's like
Deadpool, but like cranked up to 11. Deadpool
mixed with the Ghost Rider. Yeah, kinda. I
guess you could do that. He's the last of his
race. He like accidentally killed everyone
else on his planet when he was like just a boy
with like a science experiment. It's pretty
wild. He's meant to be like an over the top
character. and he's insanely strong, like Superman
level strong. Who do you think we could pit
against him in a duel episode? We've already
used Ghost Rider against Etrigan and we've already
used Deadpool against Deathstroke. Yeah, I
don't think those would be good matches anyway.
Really? I don't know, Marvel, you tell me who
would be a good match. Maybe like the Silver
Surfer, although I want to pit him against
Orion. Yeah. So I don't know, someone like Beta
Ray Bill or something, some crazy eighties
alien like that. I don't know, I'll have to
think about it. Okay, yeah, we should definitely
do a duel episode with Lobo, maybe next year.
There's no release date for when his show will
be out. It might still be a few years away.
We'll do a dual episode with him soon. Cool.
Moving on to video game news, we got a trailer
for Marvel's Avengers video game that's coming
out. It was shown at E3 this past week. And
you know what? I feel like it's getting a lot
of hate out there, but I didn't mind it. I hate
it. I think a lot of people are expecting maybe
different gameplay, maybe something like open
world. Yeah. Like Arkham. It's freaking 2019.
I almost said the bad word. It's 2019. It's
like, come on. This game does appear to be
more mission-based than anything else. Right.
And I also noticed that the character design
was getting a lot of flack because the characters
don't resemble the movie counterparts. Which
is fine. Like the movie counterparts don't look
exactly like the comic characters. Right, and
it's not a movie-based game. So I don't mind
that the likenesses are different. What bothers
me is not so much the likenesses, but the graphics
quality. It looks like something that could
have been on the GameCube. Yeah, these actors
faces are a little bit uncanny valley-y. Absolutely.
They're a little bit frightening, honestly.
Especially Tony Stark. I don't know why. And
the writing. The writing just seems so generic.
It is really bad. OK, really bad. Let's start
from the beginning, though. So we get narration
from whom I'm assuming is Kamala Khan, because
this seems like her voice style. And Kamala
Khan, of course, is Ms. Marvel. And it sounds
like she's meeting the Avengers on this big
event known as A Day, where they're celebrating
the team. But. I guess there's some kind of
attack on San Francisco's Golden Gate Bridge.
So Cap sends the team out and the action looks
super cinematic. I think it looks pretty damn
cool. All the footage used in this trailer was
in game footage using the game's engine, but
it wasn't gameplay footage. I think some of
it was some of the behind the back stuff. I
really think some of it was gameplay footage,
although we don't know what the gameplay necessarily
is going to be like. If these are just like
quick time events or if those characters are
actually being controlled at this point, you
know, right, right. The Spider-Man video game
that came out for PS4 was similar in its cinematic
style and was a mixture of Quick Time Events
and actual open world. Yeah, yeah. Like the
Arkham games. Right. How cool would an open
world Avengers game be though? That would be
so much better than what it looks like whatever
this is. So as the Avengers are taking on the
threat on the Golden Gate Bridge, we get some
dialogue between the characters and there's
a weird moment where Thor's like, there are
civilian hostages and tiny men with guns. And
then Iron Man like stops everything that he's
doing and is like, did Thor just make a joke?
I think Thor just made a joke. And no, he didn't
make a freaking joke. That was not a joke. You
know? And then Iron Man gets blasted out of
the air from like a repulsor tank. It's so poorly
written. But it's so much more than just that
moment too. It's like, oh, this looks interesting.
And like, they played us. And just like, who's
writing this? Black Widow's voice sucks. I have
to say I really- All of their voices are kind
of off. I want Black Widow to have a Russian
accent. Please give her a Russian accent. It's
who she is. I mean, and obviously she's a spy.
She can speak multiple languages. She can easily
hide her accent, but I don't think that she
would. She doesn't need to. Right, not when
she's just being herself. So anyway, we have
Iron Man blasting some tanks. We have Hulk
blasting some tanks. It looks like the main
villain of the scene is Taskmaster, I wanna
say, because he has like a skull face and a
hood. It might be, you know, an alternate design
of the Crossbones character that we saw in Civil
War. Oh yeah, yeah. But he looks pretty formidable.
There's a part where he's flying around the
bridge on a jetpack and Black Widow's like
hitching a ride and attacking him at the same
time. That looks pretty cool. The camera work
is pretty impressive, I have to say. But apparently
Captain America dies when the shield helicarrier's
core explodes or something like that. I don't
know what that fragment crystal was within
the ship's core. It could have been like isotope
8, which is an element that they tend to use.
in these Marvel games that's used to like power
up your character essentially. Huh. Like these
RPG kind of elements. Yeah. But I don't really
think that Cap's dead. They make it seem like
Cap's dead, but I'm pretty sure he would survive
a crashing helicarrier into the water, you
know? It's water. It's just water. It doesn't
hurt. He was trapped in ice, which is harder
than water. Exactly. But yeah, the game really
makes it seem like there's some kind of fallout
from this incident where the Avengers have kind
of disbanded and then they have to unite once
again to take on this new threat. So in all,
this trailer has been kind of like a mixed
bag with some interesting action bits, but also
some really poor graphics and dialogue and
story elements too. Would you buy it? Well,
yeah, I absolutely would buy it if I had a
platform to play it. That's one of the reasons
why we don't comment on gaming news too much
on this podcast is because neither Jonathan
nor I are gamers anymore. We used to be, but
we kind of dropped off after the Wii era, I
guess. Yeah, I just sold my Xbox One S. Really?
Yeah. I was thinking about getting a Switch
for the Ultimate Alliance Marvel game that's
coming out exclusively to that platform. Yeah,
that's interesting. I'm still wondering why
that's a Switch exclusive. I'm not sure. In
all, I'd be really interested in hearing what
our listeners think about this trailer. Those
who are gamers and, you know, are a little
bit more knowledgeable on the subject of modern
gaming. But speaking of gaming, this brings
us to our question of the week.
What has been your favorite DC or Marvel video
game and why? Post your answer to our Instagram,
Twitter, Facebook, or email us at dynamicduelpodcast
at gmail.com. We'll pick our favorite answer
and draw that person a dynamic duel no prize
that we'll post to social media. I think that
does it for all of the news for this episode.
So with all that done, let's go ahead and move
on to the main event where we find out who'd
win in a fight between Sinestro and Magneto.
Are you scared? No. You should be. I'm not.
Okay, Sinestro versus Magneto. Now you might
be asking yourself, why these two characters?
And actually, this was sort of inspired by the
internet, just by looking at what people thought
would be good matches between DC and Marvel.
I saw this one and I was like, well, that's
an interesting match. I have no idea who would
win. They're both great, fascinating characters.
They kind of skirt with like being really evil
and, you know, semi-heroic. Sinestro is heroic?
Well, yeah, he started off as a Green Lantern.
Oh, that's right. That's right. But also, I
think what appealed to me for this particular
episode is that there's not too many people
who could go up against a Green Lantern powers
wise. They're just so powerful and energetic.
But I think Magneto is absolutely one of those
characters. He's not only one of the most powerful
mutants in the Marvel universe, he's one of
the most powerful characters in general. His
electromagnetic energy powers are just off the
charts. So I think Magneto is more than a match
for Sinestro in this particular duel. More than
a match. Yes. We'll see. So the way we determine
the winner between these two characters is through
statistics. We take their statistics and we
run them through a simulation known as a Monte
Carlo simulation. And what that does is it
takes those stat numbers and it randomizes them
along a normal distribution which is in the
shape of a bell curve. And that randomization
simulates all the variables that take place
during the course of battle. Now we compare
these randomizations against each other 1,000
times to simulate 1,000 battles. And from those
results we get a percentage of wins for each
character. Right, and the character with the
highest percentage of wins is the one that
we declare the winner because they would win
most of the time. Right, because no one character
ever wins 100% of the matches. That's never
happened. Right. There's always a way for Batman
to beat someone like Superman. Do we try not
to be that lopsided in our matchup pairings?
We try to pick matches that we think will end
up as close to 50% as possible. and then are
just super excited when that doesn't happen.
If that doesn't happen. Right, right. So again,
because Joseph and I are so biased, we've chosen
this approach because it's the most objective
scientific approach that we could find. It used
to be done by Spike TV on their old television
show, Deadliest Warrior. Right, it's objective.
There's no fan votes. We don't consider it
like outlier feats. It's just base statistics.
which are all based on the official Marvel
Power Rankings grid. Right, and from Marvel's
criteria, we extrapolate the DC character statistics,
as well as add our own stat categories in order
to make a more robust, accurate simulation.
Things like evasiveness and range, things that,
you know, would play a factor in an actual
battle. Right. So before we run this Monte Carlo
simulation with these character stats, we'll
go over Magneto's and Sinestro's histories and
powers, so you're more familiar with the characters.
I think I go first this time, so let me tell
you all about the character of Magneto, who
I have to say is one of my favorite villains
of all time. Because is he a tyrannical madman
or a righteous zealot? He does take extreme
measures to fight for mutant equality, but
have extreme measures not been taken also by
humans to suppress mutants? Do the ends justify
the means when striving for a noble cause, and
who decides which cause is noble? These are
just some of the fascinating questions that
arise when analyzing Magneto. Now Magneto's
real name is Max Eisenhart. Max Eisenhart was
born to a middle class Jewish family in Germany
during the rise of the Nazi regime. He and his
family were persecuted by Nazi soldiers and
beaten nearly every day and they ended up fleeing
to Poland. There they escaped to the Warsaw
ghetto to avoid extermination but were eventually
captured and killed in a firing squad. Max
unknowingly used his powers for the first time
to avoid being shot and was the only member
of his family to survive. though he was soon
found and imprisoned in Auschwitz. There he
was forced to clean out the furnaces of the
crematoria where he would discover the bodies
of friends who had been picked for death, some
of them horribly disfigured by the experiments
of geneticist super villain Mr. Sinister. He
reunited with an early childhood crush named
Magda in the extermination camp and saved her
from the gas chambers before the two escaped
and fled to a Carpathian mountain village where
Max changed his identity to Eric Lencher. They
stayed there until the war's end. got married
and had a daughter named Anya. Yeah, it's not
his name was Eric Linscher. In the movies, that's
what they refer to him as, but that's actually
more of a gypsy name. And in the comics, they
didn't quite decide whether or not they wanted
Magneto to be Jewish or gypsy for a really long
time. So what they did is they gave him a Jewish
name that he later changed to a gypsy name.
Okay. Because he married Magda, who was part
Romani. Right. So after they had their daughter
Anya, Eric moved his family to a Soviet Union
city where he got a job as a carpenter. There,
he consciously used his mutant powers for the
first time as he magnetically hurled a crowbar
at his boss for not paying him. As he arrived
home that evening, he saw his home burning down
with his daughter trapped in her room. He tried
to save her but was held down by KGB goons who
had been called by Erik's boss to start the
fire and beat him up. As Anya burned alive in
front of him, Erik killed the men who held
him and the entire crowd watching and he destroyed
a portion of the city itself. Holy cow. Magda
fled in grief at the loss of her daughter and
out of fear of her husband. Eric traveled to
Israel, where he worked as an orderly at a psychiatric
hospital for Holocaust survivors. There, he
first met Charles Xavier, who was volunteering
at the hospital. The two became friends and
would often discuss the subject of the budding
mutant race and its coexistence with the human
majority. The two eventually revealed their
powers to each other as they fought Hydra to
save a kidnapped friend. Realizing kids and
Charles' views were incompatible, Eric stole
Hydra's Nazi gold and went on a journey hunting
Nazi war criminals around the world. He developed
a notorious reputation and was nicknamed Magneto.
He witnessed the persecution of mutants first
hand in his travels around the world and seeing
parallels with the persecution of Jews in Nazi
Germany, decided to establish a group to fight
for mutant rights. He created an orbital space
station to use as a base called Asteroid M and
recruited his alleged children Quicksilver
and Scarlet Witch as well as Toad and Mastermind.
This was the original Brotherhood of Mutants.
He led the group in acts of genetic terrorism
and were often stopped by Charles Xavier and
his rival team of mutants called the X-Men,
who fought for peaceful mutant and human coexistence.
He would also end up clashing with the likes
of the Fantastic Four, the Sub-Mariner, Thor,
and the Inhumans. Eventually, Quicksilver and
the Scarlet Witch left the team to join the
Avengers, and you can learn more about them
in our Flash versus Quicksilver episode and
our Zatanna versus Scarlet Witch episode, where
they find out. that they're not actually Magneto's
children. Dumb. After many years of attacking
humans with various incarnations of his brotherhood
team, Eric was de-aged a few decades into his
younger self's body during an encounter with
the alien Shi'ar race. Occasionally, Eric would
find himself fighting alongside the X-Men when
external threats to mutant kind would show up,
such as William Stryker's purifiers, and during
the secret wars event. That was when the godlike
being known as the Beyonder transported Marvel's
heroes and villains to Battleworld to do battle.
Eric was transported to the villain side, but
he rejected them and fought alongside the heroes
instead. Later, he even led the X-Men and the
new mutants teams when Professor X had to be
taken off-world to be treated for an attack
by Hydra. Though Eric thought he could manipulate
the teams into his belief of mutant superiority,
the reverse happened and he began questioning
his own methods. However, over time the pressures
of keeping the teams safe got to him and he
became an overbearing and tyrannical team leader.
He ended up leaving the X-Men and returning
to his old ways, after seeing his students
oppressed time and again. He stated that the
world should focus on just him as the mutant
threat, and that by being the major quote villain,
he could help protect other mutants. His goal
was no longer human conquest, but rather the
creation of a haven for mutant kind on Asteroid
M. The United Nations Security Council deployed
satellites that disrupted Erick's powers on
Asteroid M, and he deactivated every electronic
device on Earth in retaliation. He fought the
X-Men again, once again led by Professor X.
and in the process extracted the adamantium
from Wolverine's skeleton. You can learn more
about that in our Hawkman vs. Wolverine duel
episode. In the aftermath, the United Nations
ended up ceding governmental control of the
small island nation of Genosha to Erik to use
as his mutant haven. Its population grew in
the tens of thousands, but the island was eventually
attacked and destroyed by Mega Sentinels, an
event during which Erik was presumed dead. As
he rose from Genosha's rubble and recovered
his powers, His alleged daughter, the Scarlet
Witch, rewrote reality to one where Eric ruled
over a mutant-dominated world called the House
of M. That version of reality came crashing
down, however, when the heroes realized the
truth, and the Scarlet Witch ended up restoring
reality, but not before stripping most of the
Earth's mutant population of their powers,
including Eric's. Broken and disillusioned,
Eric went into hiding. He worked with a high
evolutionary, the scientist that granted Quicksilver
and Scarlet Witch the powers, and was able
to regain his powers through his technology.
though the machine could only be used once.
Of course. Eric made it his mission to try and
restore the mutant populace's lost powers,
which brought his attention to the first mutant
born after the events of House of M, named
Hope Summers. He joined the X-Men on their new
island base called Utopia, which was actually
Asteroid M resurfaced from the ocean's depths.
During the Avengers versus X-Men event, the
Phoenix Force returned to Earth. Magneto sided
with the X-Men, but attacked Cyclops when his
Phoenix powers grew out of control. Hope Summers
and the Scarlet Witch were able to use the
Phoenix to restore the lost powers of Earth's
former mutants, fulfilling Eric's mission.
He later tracked down the Red Skull after learning
that the villain was using Genosha as a concentration
camp for many of these newly restored mutants,
and he beat him to death. However, Schmidt
was soon resurrected in the psyche of Red Onslaught,
whom Eric helped defeat alongside the X-Men
and the Avengers. Though Earth's mutants were
restored, many of them started dying due to
exposure to the Terrigan Mists' released in
the atmosphere by Black Bolt, whom you can
learn more about in our Shazam vs Black Bolt
duel. This forced Eric to again try and protect
the mutant race through any means necessary,
establishing a new asteroid M and a new Brotherhood
of Mutants. Isn't that the Brotherhood of Evil
Mutants? Um, it was initially called the Brotherhood
of Evil Mutants in the comics, yes, but that's
kind of been retconned, because it wouldn't
make sense for Magneto to refer to his own team
as evil considering that he views his cause
as righteous. Right, right, I was thinking the
same thing. Okay. Although there was a theory
in the Earth-X graphic novel where the Watcher
surmised that Magneto called his brotherhood
evil in order to force Charles Xavier to take
a moral stance basically. Interesting. Yeah,
which, I don't know, still doesn't make sense
to me. No. Anyway, Magneto's powers are to
control the fundamental forces of electromagnetism,
and he is one of the Earth's most powerful
mutants. With his power, he has complete molecular
control of metals, with effects that range
from being able to control a person's blood
flow. using the iron in their hemoglobin, or
he can move mountains, or he can even manipulate
the planet's electromagnetic field. Wouldn't
that like destroy the planet? Yes. Maybe. I
don't know. But he can fly, he can create impenetrable
force fields, and fire electromagnetic blasts
and pulses. Now, can he control all metals
or just iron? All ferrous metals. Okay. Basically
any metal that can be magnetized. Okay. Although
he can also magnetize non-magnetic elements,
so, you know. Just metal, just think metal,
okay? Okay. Magneto can also reinforce the metal
fibers of his outfit to be near the strength
of adamantium. In addition, he also has telepathic
resistance through his helmet, and he also
has a genius level intellect. And that's the
character. I mean, I guess that's impressive.
I mean, not as impressive as like a ring that
can allow you to create anything you can imagine.
I mean, Magneto can create anything he imagines
out of metal, so. Well, let's hope there's
some around. Let me get into Sinestro. Thal
Sinestro is from the planet Korugar in space
sector 1417. He was an orderly anthropologist
on his planet until one day the green lantern
for 1417 named Praul Gasgatha crash landed near
Sinestro, injured and apparently dying from
a battle with a weaponer of Qord, which is a
planet from DC's antimatter universe. Gasgatha
gave up his ring to Sinestro. whom the ring
deemed to be fearless and honorable, and despite
not knowing what the ring could do, Sinestro
was able to destroy the Kordian attackers in
pursuit of Gasgatha. When the dust settled,
Gasgatha was still alive. Realizing he could
recover with the aid of his Green Lantern Ring,
Gasgatha asked Sinestro to return it, but Sinestro,
disgusted by how easily Gasgatha gave up that
power, left Gasgatha to die. and became Sector
1417's new Green Lantern. Dang, that's not very
honorable. That's true. That ring was stupid.
The Guardians of the Universe, whom I'll refer
to as the Owens, and whom you can learn more
about in our Green Lantern vs. Nova episode,
were the creators and leaders of the interstellar
peacekeeping force known as the Green Lantern
Corps. They never found out about how Sinestro
let Gosgotha die, and instead lauded him for
his competence with the ring. Doesn't the ring
have its own sentience and wouldn't it tell
on him? It didn't. In his prime, Sinestro was
the greatest green lantern in all 3600 sectors
of the universe. Under his vigilant protection,
Sector 1417 was almost entirely devoid of crime.
He mentored and befriended many other green
lanterns, including the alien Abin Sur of Sector
2814, where Earth resides. Sinestro and Abin
Sur became such close friends Sinestro married
Abin's sister, Erin, and together they had
a daughter. Abin Sur had learned from an alien
named Atrocitus of a prophecy known as Blackest
Night, a time when darkness would rise up in
the universe and extinguish all light. Atrocitus
was the leader of a prophetic terrorist gabal
against the Owens, and as Abin Sur was taking
the captured Atrocitus to the prison planet
of Yismalt for his crimes, Atrocitus killed
Abin and the two crash-landed on Earth. Sinestro
attacked Atrocitus while on Earth and recaptured
him with the help of Abansur's successor, the
human Hal Jordan, whom Sinestro initially deemed
unworthy. As he was imprisoned, Atrocitus taunted
Sinestro with a personal prophecy about the
chaos and deadly coup that would lead to Sinestro's
fall from grace within the Green Lantern Corps.
and began crossing ethical lines in order to
maintain order within his sector, eventually
dominating each planet as a dictator who ruled
by fear. Recognizing Sinestro's dark turn and
fearing for their daughter's life, his wife
Erin secretly gave their daughter away and
fled, dying soon after from a suicide bomber
who had intended to kill Sinestro, which only
bolstered his tyranny. The Owens ordered Sinestro
to train Hal Jordan, who, despite his recklessness,
Sinestro eventually befriended. During their
training, Hal traveled to Sector 1417 with
Sinestro to quell a rebellion that had arisen
during Sinestro's absence. During this time,
Hal realized Sinestro was using his ring to
rule over his sector. Guilt stricken for helping
him stop the rebellion, Hal kept Sinestro's
secret and instead imprisoned both of them
on Earth. The Owens sent Manhunters, the emotionless,
energy-draining android precursors to the Green
Lanterns, to Earth to capture both Green Lanterns
and put them on trial. Hal testified against
Sinestro, who was imprisoned in the Anti-Matter
universe, and swore revenge against Hal and
the Owens. While there, he met the Weaponers
of Chord, who hated the Owens as much as he
did. They fashioned him a yellow power ring
and sent him back to the Positive Matter universe,
where he became the Green Lantern Corps' most
powerful nemesis, due, at the time, to their
ring's inability to affect the color yellow.
Eventually, thanks mostly to Hell Jordan, Sinestro
was imprisoned in the Green Lantern Corps' central
power battery, which powers the rings of each
member of the Corps. While in the battery, Sinestro
discovered that the Green Lantern's weakness
to yellow came from an entity known as Parallax,
the yellow embodiment of fear in the universe
that the Owens had also imprisoned in the battery
millions of years prior. Sinestro influenced
Parallax into manipulating Kal Jordan and driving
him insane when Hal's hometown of Coast City
was destroyed. Hal went on a rampage, killing
the rest of the core in order to drain their
energy, and made his way to the planet Oa to
absorb the central power battery. The Owens
released Sinestro from his prison to confront
and defeat Hal, but Sinestro taunted Hal into
killing him and the Owens. bringing Hal fully
over the edge and allowing Parallax to fully
possess him. It was later revealed, however,
that the Sinestro who died was an energy construct
made by Parallax and puppeteered by Sinestro,
who went into hiding once the core was destroyed,
biding his time until Parallax was powerful
enough to power his yellow ring. Parallax had
been destroyed but was slowly regaining his
energy through Hal Jordan in his new form as
the Spectre. who you can learn more about in
our Spectre vs Galactus episode. Hal Jordan
re-emerged as a Green Lantern once again, now
free from Parallax's influence, and he and
Sinestro fought, resulting in Sinestro's yellow
ring to be destroyed and him being instantly
teleported back to the antimatter universe.
With the help of the universe-destroying entity
from the antimatter universe known as the Anti-Monitor,
Sinestro formed the Sinestro Corps, a team
of frightful beings from across the universe.
who wielded yellow power rings to combat the
reformation of the Green Lantern Corps. With
the Green Lantern's universal entity of courage
and willpower, a being known as Ion, captured
by the Sinestro Corps, the Owens rewrote the
Green Lantern bylaws to allow Green Lanterns
to use lethal force, which was Sinestro's plan
all along, making him victorious once again
despite him and the Corps being defeated in
battle on Earth. Sinestro was abducted from
the Green Lantern Corps by Atrocitus and his
newly created Red Lantern Corps, who learned
of Sinestro's daughter, Soranekhna II, who
was unaware of her parentage and had been the
Green Lantern of Sector 1417 for some time.
Shortly after Sinestro was rescued from the
Green Lantern Corps by his own corps members,
heroes and villains who have died throughout
DC continuity began to arise as reanimated
zombie corpses wielding Black Lantern Rings,
including Aben Sur and his sister Erin, Sinestro's
former wife. It took mass recruitment by the
Green, Yellow, and Red Lantern Corps, as well
as the newly formed Orange, Blue, Indigo, and
Violet teams, to gather enough white light
when combining their energy to attack the Black
Lantern's central power battery, created from
the corpse of the Anti-Monitor by Necron, the
universal embodiment of death. Necron planned
on summoning the embodiment of life, known simply
as the Entity, so he could destroy it, and
subsequently all life in the universe, in one
fell swoop. Once summoned, the Entity possessed
Sinestro, who used the power to fight and help
defeat Necron, saving the universe. Sinestro
became a Green Lantern once again after an evil
Owen known as Krona captured his yellow ring,
along with the seven colored universal entities
of emotion. Helping defeat Krona as a Green
Lantern, Sinestro was allowed to keep his ring,
though he returned to the head of the Sinestro
Corps when he realized the Owens were manipulating
him into destroying the Yellow Lanterns and
eventually all other Cores save for the Green.
In retaliation, Sinestro killed all but two
of the Owens and set off to find and save the
survivors of his destroyed planet of Korugar.
of an ultraviolet light outside of the emotional
spectrum that channels all negative emotion
in general, which he can use to create both
invisible constructs and manipulate life forms.
In this match however, Sinestro will have his
yellow power ring, which is primarily capable
of creating yellow energy and hard light constructs,
such as force fields or like, scary spiders.
It's also capable of empathically determining
an opponent's fears. which it can amplify.
His ring also grants him enhanced strength,
speed, durability, and flight. The ring does,
however, need to be recharged on occasion, and
it is disrupted by the blue energy of hope.
That's Sinestro. Sometimes Magneto's energy
in the comics is depicted as blue. But it's
not very Magnetic energy. Hopeful. It's not
hopeful. Sure it is. Sure it is. All right,
that does it for the backstories and powers
for each of these characters. Now, before we
run the simulations, we like to discuss how
we think one of those 1000 matches would actually
play out and kind of like an improvised scenario.
Yeah. The final results aren't based on the
speculation. This is just for funsies. Now we
don't set any rules for our particular scenario,
save that the characters don't know anything
about each other than they are threats to each
other that need to be put down. They start 50
yards apart on whatever battlefield they're
on and the battlefield is nondescript basically.
We don't take stats for the environment within
these simulations. The characters have to win
on their own merits. So the environment does
not play any sort of factor within the battle
itself because some characters can win in certain
environments and have disadvantages in others.
Right. Exactly. Like if this fight took place
on Mars, Sinestro is dead. Is he though? Yeah.
Cause Mars is full of iron. I guess so is earth.
And if this match took place, like in the middle
of nowhere space, Magneto would- pretty much
be dead. Which is not true because Magneto can
actually draw upon magnetic fields of surrounding
planets and stars. Oh, so like millions of miles
away? Yeah, he can't do that. It would take
a long time for that to get done. It doesn't.
He used the magnetic power of the sun in a
fight against Iron Man in Avengers versus X-Men
to strengthen himself. It made him stronger?
Yes, he can use magnetic fields to make himself
stronger. They fought in space too. And Magneto
like created his own suit of armor using the
metal from nearby satellites. I'm talking about
deep space. Okay, there are no stars or asteroids
or anything around. What are you talking about?
There are no stars in deep space. Deep space.
Okay, Neil deGrasse Tyson. Yeah. You don't
know anything about space. Don't act like you
know about space. Deep space nine. Anyway,
let's go ahead and get this fight started. So
they start 50 yards apart from each other and
they know that they have to beat each other.
Who goes first? I actually think that Sinestro
is a little bit more manic than Magneto. Yeah,
I agree. I think Sinestro would actually go
first. considering that he might also be a little
bit faster. Well, I think he starts off just
by sort of like doing a scan of Magneto, an
empathic scan of what Magneto fears. Well,
Magneto can't be scanned because he has that
helmet that blocks his mind from being read.
He's reading his heart. He's not reading, he
doesn't have a heart helmet. There's no thought
or memory base in the human heart. It's emotion.
No, emotions are not physically held in the
heart, they're held in the brain, fool. Still,
like, the laws of Marvel telepathy being blocked
by helmets doesn't apply to DC. Well, it applies
in this case, so I'm sorry. Why? Because that's
his whole thing. He has telepathic resistance.
It's not telepathy, it's empathy. Same f***ing
thing. Is that the s***? Same frickin' thing.
Is it? Yeah. Can't be scanned. Besides, Magneto
doesn't have fears anyway, it's not gonna help
you. While you're busy scanning, Magneto sees
this guy who he knows to be a threat. And he
shoots an electromagnetic blast at him. Like
lightning? Yeah, it's kind of depicted as lightning-ish
in the comics. Okay, well, since Sinestro's
ring was scanning Magneto, it senses the buildup
of this electromagnetism and puts up a shield
right away, blocking the blast. Okay? So then
that's when Sinestro retaliates by creating
like a million little tiny scary spiders that
just go all around Magneto. Except how did
they get past Magneto's forcefield? They're
created within the force field. You can't project
energy through the force field. Who said his
force field is up? You didn't even say his
force field is up. Magneto traditionally has
his force field up almost at all times. It's
usually just invisible. And that's canon. What?
Yeah. Especially he would have it up during,
at the start of this fight. Okay, so the spiders
crawl all around this force field, and it lets
Sinestro know exactly where this force field
is. Yeah, all around him. Okay. So, once he's
completely encased, in spiders, that's when
Sinestro creates like this vice grip, picks
Magneto up by his forcefield, and just like
curls him into space. Except Magneto breaks
the vice grip by expanding his forcefield to
break the construct that's holding him. Shut
the fu- shut the front door. I almost said it.
And as soon as he breaks the vice grip, Magneto
flies towards Sinestro and he shoots this huge
giant electromagnetic beam at Sinestro. Boom,
forcefield blocked. We gotta get around these
force fields somehow. Alright, so, um, Magneto
taps into whatever, like, electromagnetic currents
are surrounding them. Because everything has
an electromagnetic field, whether it be life
forms or even planets, radiation out in space,
wherever they are, there will be an electromagnetic
field that Magneto can tap into and kind of
use to telekinetically shake Sinestro within
his force field, and kind of like, rattle him
around like a hamster in a hamster ball. And
Sinestro's just like slamming back and forth
against the walls and getting all bloodied from
that. Okay. Which causes Sinestro to drop his
force field. Yeah, yeah, yeah. At that moment,
Magneto sends out this electromagnetic pulse
that affects Sinestro's electric nervous system
and basically gives him a stroke. What? Yeah.
No, it doesn't. Because as the electromagnetic
pulse is coming at him, Huh? He creates a battery
that absorbs that electrical energy. and uses
it to power a big ass cannon, which he fires
right at Magneto. Okay, well Magneto still has
his force field, but I would assume that a
blast that big would actually start taxing his
ability to maintain that force field. Yes,
it's a very big laser. So once the cannon is
done shooting at him, it's out of the energy
that it absorbed or whatever, Magneto drops
his force field and splinters his helmet into
a bunch of tiny metal shards that he just sends
hurling. straight at Sinestro's face. As they're
coming at him, this like dragon wing sweeps
in and like blocks the shards and then like
the wing moves to reveal this giant ass dragon
that then just like fires a huge fireball at
Magneto. And this thing's scary, let me tell
you. But as Magneto's jumping out of the way
of the dragon's flames, he takes all those metal
shards that are within the dragon's wings and
he forms them together into this giant blade
that just slices the dragon's head off and
decapitates him. But the dragon's head like
falls off, rolls to the like grand, but then
like spider legs sprout out of it and it starts
going at Magneto. It's like, I'm going to get
you. That is scary. Magneto's like, what the
hell? Is hella curse word? I don't know. Anyway.
Okay. So Magneto is like freaking the heck out.
All right. So what he does is he summons his
helmet back to him, but he creates a full protective
mask out of it with like mesh eye holes and
everything like that. So he could still see
out of it. He reinforces all the metal around
his body in his metal weave suit so that it's
about as durable as adamantium, okay? Uh-huh.
So this thing's like lunging at him, but he's
armored, so it can't like affect him too much.
And he draws upon the electromagnetic energy
of whatever large planet may be nearby him,
whether it's Earth or it's the Sun or it's another
planet or wherever he is. So he's like coursing
with like this glowing electromagnetic energy,
and it increases his strength so much so that
he just punches this dragon right in the face
and rips his spider legs off. Okay, but as
Magneto is too busy fighting this dragon head,
that's when Sinestro sort of like fills the
area around Magneto with this like ooze that
he's just like drowning in. And then at that
point, Magneto again creates his forcefield
that emanates from his body and pushes the
ooze away, creating basically an air bubble
for himself. And then he probably just like
spins that bubble so that it like sends all
the ooze flying away from him. Okay, well now
that Magneto is dizzy as heck No, no, he was
just spinning the force field, not himself
within those force fields Oh, dumb But he shoots
out this energy blast that connects to Sinestro's
ring And taps into whatever, you know, alien
metals are within the construction of the ring
itself What? Yeah And then- That's like anti-matter
metal You can't do anything with that Wait,
did you say the word metal? Did you say the
word metal? It's anti-matter Like metal- Metal
Dang it! So he pulls the ring off of Sinestro's
hand. No. What? Actually, in the metal event
that they had in the comics recently, like,
yeah, the rings are metal. You are fudged.
So he pulls the ring off of Sinestro's hand,
and then it brings it towards him, realizing
like it's this awesome energy weapon, and Magneto
puts the ring on his own hand. Okay. Little
did you know that Sinestro has built-in safeguards
for anyone else. Who wears his rings? Okay.
So as Magneto puts on his hand, that's when
it like generates a saw blade and chops off
Magneto's hand. Oh, shit! What? This took him
by surprise. Okay, okay, I'll accept that.
So Magneto just lost a hand, but he's not gonna
bleed out because he can hold back his own
blood from flowing out of his arm due to the
iron that's within it. Just like cauterize
it? In effect, yes. Okay, well meanwhile, the
ring flies off of the amputated hand. back
onto Sinestro's finger. But before it gets back
to Sinestro's finger, Magneto stalls it mid-air,
and at which point, Magneto removes his helmet
again, and like turns it into like this metallic
dust that flies over to Sinestro, and Sinestro
inhales it, basically. What is this, X2? Yes.
But I say that before the dust could even get
to Sinestro, he runs over to the rank himself,
puts it on, and then just creates like- But
already has all this metal in his body now.
Well, little did you know that the Green Lanterns
could actually phase through matter on certain
instances. So I'm sure Sinestro can do it as
well. What?! So yeah, he just uses the ring
to phase his molecules away from the metal bits.
Leaving himself vulnerable, standing right
next to all these metal bits that form like
this liquid that just wraps around Sinestro's
ring and hand. And then Magneto makes Sinestro
start punching himself. Okay, well Sinestro
uses his ring to pick up Magneto's amputated
hand and he uses that to start slapping Magneto
across the face. Over and over. In fact, Sinestro
creates like a hundred more zombie hands that
also start slapping Magneto around. Alright,
so Magneto either gets slapped to death or
Sinestro punches himself to death with a metal
fist. Sure, yeah. I did not see that happening.
But I think that does it for this particular
scenario. We'll end it there. and we'll go
to the simulations and run the numbers and figure
out exactly who would win between these two
villains. Let's do it.
Okay, I can't do the mental math off the top
of my head as to who is coming out on top of
this. This is definitely gonna be a surprise
for me. Yeah, it's pretty close here, which
I think makes it a great match. We did figure
that Sinestro is faster than Magneto. Right,
but then Magneto is slightly stronger because
he could essentially affect planets. And while
Sinestro can do the same, it would take a lot
more effort. You think a lot more willpower
to lift a mountain as opposed to Magneto who
can lift a mountain fairly effortlessly. Right,
exactly. Fighting skill, Sinestro came out on
top. Yeah, because he has the training through
the Green Lantern Corps. Right, right. You don't
really see Magneto fight hand to hand too often.
He probably does have some experience in hand
to hand combat, but no formal training. Uh-huh.
Where else do they differ? In terms of durability,
we said that due to Magneto's heavy armor,
it made him less vulnerable to direct attack
as opposed to Sinestro, who has to create a
construct to defend himself. Right, and shield
creation is more represented through the evasiveness
stat, which we more accurately define as the
ability to avoid being hit. As opposed to durability,
which is the ability to resist or recover from
injury to your body directly. Right, exactly.
Intelligence-wise, they're about the same, I
would say. Yeah, yeah, they're both smart villains.
So yeah, taking all those numbers and running
them through the Monte Carlo, we have a winner.
Now, who do you think it's gonna be? I really
hope it's Sinestro, but you put up a much better
fight than I thought you would. Like I thought
I was totally gonna own this, but that freaking
force field, like force fields are hard to get
through. It's always hard when you have two
characters that can have full and penetrable
force fields going at all times. Right, right.
So you need to find a way to kind of like negate
that. And I think that we did that hopefully
in a way that makes sense. Cause you know, the
comic book writers do it all the time. So we'll
see. So, all right. It was an extremely close
match. I'm proud of both of these guys. The
winner of the Magneto Sinestro match is Magneto.
Ah, he won. 57.1% of the matches. Whoa. Compared
to Sinestro's 429 wins. What? I cannot fathom
this. Yeah, Magneto won man. Deal with it.
You have to deal with this. No. Actually I did
not quite see that coming as well. I think
the big factor here was that Magneto always
is wearing his armor. Whether or not his armor
itself has been reinforced. According to the
comics, almost nearly always has his force
field going. He's almost always in a defensive
state. Sinestro could do that, but it would
drain the energy in his ring. Right, right.
Considering we didn't take into consideration
any environmental metal within our scenario,
if there was environmental metal, Sinestro
would have that much harder of a time. I forgot
to take into account that electromagnetism
is essentially everywhere, almost in the universe.
He's essentially in control of one of the four
fundamental forces of the universe. Exactly.
This sucks. Okay, Harry and Tasker, cover your
ears for a few seconds, because this is fucking
bullshit. Damn it. Okay, I'm done. Okay, you
can uncover your ears again. So go ahead and
mark this down as a win in the Marvel column
for Magneto, and go ahead and write into us
and let us know what you guys thought about
this fight. That does it for this episode. Let's
hurry up and wrap this up, this is dumb. Our
next episode, we will be reviewing Jessica Jones,
season three. Right, it's the very last of
the Marvel Netflix shows that's going to air,
and so it's a little bit bittersweet, but the
show has been pretty good consistently, even
with season two being not quite as good as
season one. But I do like the character so much,
so I'm excited. So yeah, we'll be reviewing
that. Go ahead and visit us at dynamicduel.com,
where you can listen to the podcast and get
links to all of our social media accounts so
you can interact with us on Facebook and Instagram
and Twitter and YouTube, although don't do YouTube,
YouTube sucks. Also at Dynamic Duel, you can
find a link to our merchandise store, which
is on T-Public. And the artwork we use for
our products there are from our NoPrizes. This
episode, I will be drawing Sinestro. And who
doesn't want a Sinestro t-shirt? I do. Yeah,
that'd be cool. Don't forget to subscribe to
our show if you haven't already. If you enjoy
the show, go ahead and share it with your friends
and family. Again, we're trying to get to 200
ratings on Apple podcasts. And the quicker
that we do that, the quicker that we can stop
bugging you guys about it. or please rate us
on whatever platform you're listening to us
on. Right. And if you share us on your own
social media account, that goes a long way to
promoting the show. Yep. Make sure to get all
your Jessica Jones season three watching in
before next week and we will talk to you then.
Up, up and away. True believers.