you
Dynamic Dual Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the superiority
between Marvel and DC by comparing their characters
in stat-based battle simulations. I'm Marvelous
Joe. And I'm his twin brother Johnny DC. And
in this episode, it's a Halloween themed episode,
we're going to find out who would win in a fight
between the Batman villain, Man-Bat, and the
Spider-Man villain, Morbius. Yeah, Morbius is
like a vampire and Man-Bat is like this man
that's a bat.
It's spooky. Yeah. Morbius isn't strictly a
vampire. He's like a pseudo vampire. Basically
he did some experiments with vampire bats and
became not a supernatural type of vampire but
like a scientific type of vampire. That was
all done due to the Comics Code Authority because
they couldn't include actual vampires in the
comics at the time. Yeah, so glad that the
publishers got away from using that. Before
we gather statistics on these characters. and
run them through 1,000 simulations to find out
who would win in a fight, we're going to go
over the comic book movie news from the past
week. There wasn't too much news to come out
this past week, basically because DC is gonna
save all their headlines for the upcoming DC
fandom event that's coming out on October 16th.
And basically Marvel is holding on to their
news so that they can release it right after
the event so that they can poach all the headlines.
What? But we will be discussing the upcoming
full celebrity guest list that will be at the
DC fandom event. Marvel totally would pull a
dick move like that. I can't wait for them
to pull that dick move just so I could call
them out on pulling that dick move. And then
what are you gonna do about it? Call them dicks.
As always, we list our segment times in our
episode description, so feel free to check out
our show notes if you wanna skip ahead to a
particular topic. And just a reminder, only
the four most recent episodes of this podcast
are available to the listening public. If you
guys want access to over 200 episodes of archived
content, including Batman versus Moon Knight,
The Lego Batman Movie Review, Asriel vs. Blade,
Our Blade 2 Review, Two-Face vs. Jigsaw, or
our Batman The Long Halloween Review. Be sure
to subscribe to this podcast on Spotify or Patreon,
both of which will provide you with an RSS
feed to use in your own podcast app. On Patreon,
you also get bonus content including bonus
episodes, access to our Discord server, blooper
reels, and more. It's only $2 a month to subscribe
on Spotify or Patreon. And you could do so by
visiting dynamicduel.com slash subscribe, which
is linked in our show notes. And with that out
of the way, quick to the No Prize. A No Prize
is an award that Marvel used to give out up
until the 90s to fans. Our version, the Dynamic
Duel No Prize, is a digital award that we post
on social media that I personally draw for
those who we feel gave the best answer to our
question of the week. For last week, we asked,
who is your favorite Marvel or DC character
created or partially created? by Jack Kirby
and why. Of course, Jack Kirby was one of the
most prolific comic book creators back in the
golden age and silver age of comics. He created
a ton of Marvel and DC's beloved characters
and a lot of you guys responded with your favorites.
Let's go ahead and run down our honorable mentions
as well as the no prize winner. Our first honorable
mention goes to Nate who said, Hey guys, it's
Nate here and for the question of the week,
could you ask a more vague question? I mean,
honestly, you could say any. one of your favorite
characters and chances are, Jack the King Kirby
has made it. But in all honesty, I gotta go
with my favorite character by him is Galactus.
To this day, his design holds up and it is fantastic.
No pun intended, I guess. Well, to answer your
question about whether we could ask something
more vague, the answer is yes. Yes, yeah, totally,
we could have. But to respond to the second
part of your answer. Yeah, when it comes to
Jack Kirby's character designs, I think Lactis
is the epitome of his complex style of line
work and tech-like embellishments, similar to
how he designed the Celestials or the New Gods
over on DC. And it's so strange because it's
like the complete opposite of the Silver Surfer
character who's very stripped down, basically
just like this naked silver dude without any
embellishments. Right, very streamlined. Yeah.
The silhouette of Galactus, I think, is one
of the most iconic and striking designs in comics.
There's like nothing else like it. Oh, definitely
not, yeah, and I really can't wait till we see
him in live action. Like, properly? Right,
yeah, yeah. Because I've seen him show up in
like some video games and stuff and he just
looks so epic. And it's gonna be awesome when
he eventually rears his head in the MCU. Our
next honorable mention goes to Michael Haggerty,
who said... Hey guys, Michael Haggerty here.
So uh... My favorite character by Jack Kirby,
there's only one real way to bring him out,
to announce him like a wrestler. And it's this,
gone the form of man. My favorite Jack Kirby
character is Etrigan. Oh, hit you with a poem.
Anyway, yeah that's it. I'm kind of embarrassed
I did that, but you know, whatever. It's cool,
I stand by it. I stand by my decision. Etrigan.
Etrigan for president. Yeah? We prefer all of
our answers to be in the form of a poem. Yeah,
totally. Take note guys. You know, Etrogen is
definitely one of the coolest characters, I
think personally, that Jack Kirby came up with.
Definitely one of the darkest. Oh yeah, I mean
the spectrum within which Jack Kirby operated
was so broad in terms of genre and different
types of characters. It was awesome. The man
could work within any subject matter. Whether
it was like, you know, the super patriotic Captain
America. to like the dark demonic magic realm
that Etrigan operated in to like the cosmic
sci-fi arena of like the new gods or silver
surfer or something like that. There was like
nothing he couldn't do. I like the medieval
like tunic he gave him. You know, it's not often
that you think of demons and think of them
wearing like lighthearted medieval outfits,
but he made it work and still made them so
bad ass. It was very unique. You wanna talk
about how unique he was in the form of a poem?
words and poems for me to share. This is a challenge
I do not like, but if you don't like it, then
take a hike.
Ah, Jonathan, the next freestyle artist out
there. I am the worst. All right, let's go
ahead and move on to our next honorable mention
given by DC Joe, who said. I got two answers
to this question. First answer is Darkseid,
because he's just one of the most interesting
and most powerful villain that there ever was.
And the other answer is Dr. Doom. In his own
right, he's interesting, but without Dr. Doom,
there is no MF Doom. best rapper ever, R.I.P.
I mean, I think Jonathan might be the best new
rapper out there now. Sweet. But yeah, great
answer with Darkseid and Dr. Doom, respectively,
probably DC and Marvel's greatest villains
ever. It's so crazy that one guy came up with
like the baddest villains for both respective
universes, right? Yeah, they're both very different,
but also, you know, they have some similarities.
They both like to stand around with their arms
behind their back a lot. They both also wear
like tunics. Does Darkseid wear a tunic? Yeah,
kinda, sorta. At least in his original design.
I do have to say Darkseid would totally stomp
on Doctor Doom. I mean, we all saw what Doctor
Doom did to Thanos in 2015's Secret Wars event,
so I don't know about that. I mean, Thanos
is no Darkseid. Let's be real. I mean, that's
true, because Thanos is better. Do we need
to go back to the duel episode between Thanos
and Darkseid? Nope. Exactly. Great answer,
DC Joe. That does it for our honorable mentions.
We want to give big shout outs to Miggy Mathagean,
Patrick and Evan Tomkeaf for taking the time
to visit our website and leave their answers
as well. But the winner of this week's No Prize
is CJ Kraft who said, CJ Kraft here and my
favorite Jack Kirby creation has to be the ever
loving blue eyed thing from Yancy Street. Whenever
it's clobbering time, he gets the job done.
His battles with the Hulk are epic. His back
and forth with Johnny Storm is some of the funniest
stuff in comics. They just apparently can't
get them right in movies. Come on, Marvel, you
gotta fix that. But no other character has
so much of Jack in him, right down to the cigar-chomping
and smart mouth. So gotta be the Thing. Oh
yeah, definitely. The Thing is such a great
answer when it comes to Jack Kirby's creations.
You're right, there was so much that Jack Kirby
had in common with the character of The Thing.
It was almost like he personified himself in
comic form. And what a lovable character. so
influential, you know, the Fantastic Four really
put Marvel comics on the map in the Silver
Age and the character like the thing had never
really been done before, you know, basically
you had this monster who was a hero, usually
monsters were saved for, you know, villains
or monster tales and the like. And really all
of Jack Kirby's work was really influential,
he created so many popular characters that you
know have stood the test of time. It's remarkable
that one man could have that amount of influence.
I think he's had more influence. over the comics
medium and the characters within than any other
person. At least when it comes to Marvel and
DC for sure. Oh absolutely, yeah. The King.
King Kirby. Yeah and it's always nice to revisit
some of these early creators that really formed
the Marvel and DC universe we know and love
as a fan base we owe so much to them. But congrats
again to CJ Craft. Guys, CJ is a long-time
listener of this show. Every year he puts out
a new collection of short horror stories called
Pages of Terror. And a day after this episode
drops, October 13th, his third book, Pages
of Terror 3, hits Amazon. And he's also compiled
these first three books into a collection called
Pages of Terror Trilogy of Fear. I myself read
both of his first books. He's a magnificent
horror writer. So if you're into that at all
and you wanna support a fellow listener, go
onto Amazon and check out Pages of Terror Trilogy
of Fear or any of his Pages of Terror books.
Yeah, I really gotta say, over these past years,
CJ has been like super inspirational and how
he's really pursuing you know his dream of becoming
a writer. I think he's mentioned before like
writers write and that's exactly what he's doing.
As someone who aspires to be you know an artist,
a writer, myself, I'm really proud of the work
that CJ has done and the fact that he's putting
them out there for all of us to read is really
admirable. So congrats once again to CJ for
releasing another book and guys definitely support
your indie artists. That does it for the No
Prize. If you the listener want a shot at winning
your Stay tuned to later on this episode when
we'll be asking another question of the week.
And now that that's done, on to the news!
Okay, so DC's second annual virtual comic convention,
the DC Fandom, is this upcoming Saturday, October
16th. And last week, they announced the full
celebrity guest list that will appear during
the virtual panels. It's a huge list! Yeah,
there's gonna be a lot of people there when
they release the trailer for the DC Fandom event.
While I did recognize some of the celebrities
that are gonna be part of this thing... there
were a lot of faces I didn't recognize. They
were like, join me. And I'm like, I don't even
know who you are. So we have the full celebrity
guest list for the event. What I'm gonna do
is run down this list of names. Jonathan, you're
gonna tell me quickly what they're gonna be
doing there. And so we'll have a good idea
of what this event is going to consist of. Sound
good? Yeah, cool, let's do it. All right, let
me start off the list with Adeel El-Arbi. Oh,
he's one of the co-directors of the HBO Max
film Batgirl. So we're probably gonna be getting
news about that. Okay, who is AJ Hudson? So
he's a voice actor. There's this upcoming preschool
series called Bat Wheels that'll be on Cartoon
Network, and he's the voice of Robin. Okay,
I didn't know that. Yeah, Ethan Hawke is going
to be the voice of Batman. Ethan Hawke? Yeah.
In the children's cartoon? Yeah, preschool
series. Wow, okay, that's quite the cast. All
right, what about Aldous Hodge? Well, Aldous
Hodge is playing Hawkman in the upcoming Black
Adam movie. What about Angel Manuel Soto? He's
the director of HBO Max's upcoming Blue Beetle
film. Oh, so we might get news about that,
that's cool. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Anne LeMay, who's
that? She works for WB Games. She's probably
gonna be tied to some video game. I'm not sure
which one, and I'm not sure why they're calling
her a celebrity. Next on the list is Anson Mount.
I already know who that is. He was the guy
who played Black Bolt in the Inhumans television
show, and he's voicing Batman in the Injustice
animated movie. That's right. Ava DuVernay?
Ava DuVernay, she was going to do a New Gods
film but that got scrapped. She's gonna be here
because she's probably gonna be promoting the
upcoming CW series, Naomi. Who's Bilal Fallah?
He's the other co-director of the Batgirl film
for HBO Max. Bruce Timm, we all know him. Yeah,
yeah, he's a major producer of a lot of DC's
animated content. Cam Newton is gonna be there?
Is that the same Cam Newton as the quarterback
Cam Newton? Yes, it is. And honestly- I can't
figure out why he's gonna be there. I think
he just really likes DC Comics. What a loser.
I'm glad the Broncos beat him in that Super
Bowl about a decade ago. Alright, who's Cameras
Johnson? He's an actor on the Batwoman CW TV
series. He plays Luke Fox, Lucius Fox's son.
And he's supposed to be suiting up as Batwing
in this next season. Oh, that's cool. That's
cool. Candice Patton? She plays Iris West on
CW's Flash TV series. Okay, who's Chris Wood?
He plays Manel on the Supergirl series. Lotta
CW actors here. Oh, is that Manel part of the
Legion of Superheroes? Yes, yes he is. There's
actually a few Legion members that appear on
the Supergirl series. Interesting. Next up
is Christian Convery. Oh, I'm excited for this
actually. He's the young actor who plays Sweet
Tooth on the Netflix show of the same name.
So hopefully we get some kind of news about
season two of that show, because that show was
freaking awesome. And who's Christina Hudson?
She was the screenwriter on Birds of Prey. but
she's also writing the upcoming Flash movie
as well as Batgirl for HBO Max. David Harewood?
He plays Hank Henshaw. Really, he plays Martian
Manator who's pretending to be Hank Henshaw
in the Supergirl series. And who's Dennis Cowan?
He's a comic book artist. He's done quite a
bit of work for the milestone characters like
Icon and Static Shock. And who's Donald Mustard?
I've never heard that name before. He is the
chief creative officer for Epic Games. So...
Maybe there might be some big DC Fortnite announcement
during the fandom. That would be really cool.
That would be cool. Who the hell is this Dwayne
Johnson guy? Actually, that's the one name on
the list that I had no idea what he was doing.
Something about like the hierarchy of power
in the DC universe. He's changing it forever
or something. I don't know. Sounds lame. Who
is Echo Kellum? Oh, he was the actor who played
Mr. Terrific in the CW Arrow series, which is
over. I don't know, maybe he'll make an appearance
on Flash. I haven't really been keeping up with
the CW shows. So. Looks like Ed Boon is gonna
be there. Of course, he's the head of NetherRealm
Games. Yeah, it's expected that he's going
to announce Injustice 3, though I'm really hoping
that he announces the video game that he's
been talking about making on Twitter, which
is DC vs. Marvel. That will break the internet
and my mind. Elizabeth Gillies, who that is?
She's gonna voice the character of Catwoman
in the upcoming animated film Catwoman hunted.
Okay, cool. What about Elizabeth Tullock? She's
the actress who plays Lois Lane in Superman
and Lois Ezra Miller. Hmm. What's he all about?
He of course is the actor who plays the Flash
in the DCEU Who's Freddy Stroma? He's gonna
be playing vigilante in the upcoming Peacemaker
series and Gareth Dunnett Aloe said he's the
writer of the upcoming Blue Beetle film Grant
Gustin He's the Flash on the CW flash series
What about Hindon Walsh? She's a voice actress,
probably most notably in DC for the voice of
Starfire in the Teen Titans Go series. And Jacob
Bertrand? Most people probably know him as
the Hawk in the Cobra Kai series, but he's gonna
do one of the voices in the Batwell series
for Cartoon Network as well. James Gunn is gonna
be there? Oh, probably promoting Peacemaker,
right? Yeah. Who's Jason Momoa? He's gonna kick
your ass. He of course is Aquaman, I really
hope we get like some kind of teaser footage
for Aquaman and the Lost Kingdom. Javisha Leslie?
She's the actress who plays Batwoman in the
Batwoman series. Okay moving on to Jennifer
Holland? That's actually James Gunn's girlfriend.
She's going to be one of Peacemaker's handlers
in the Peacemaker TV series. Oh that's right
and she was also in the Suicide Squad movie.
That's right. Okay who's Jesse Rath? He's the
actor who plays Brainiac 5 in Supergirl. Another
Legionnaire. Who the hell is this Jim Lee guy?
Jim Lee of course is the publisher and CCO
of DC Comics. Also one of the best comic book
artists of our time. Yeah, for sure. He's been
like teasing this massive artwork piece that
he's been working on for like the past few
months on his Instagram. I can't wait to see
that thing fully unveiled. It's gonna be incredible.
Oh, JJ Abrams is gonna be there. That's cool.
So he's probably gonna be talking about like
Justice League Dark. Yeah, probably like the
upcoming Zatanna movie. And I think also Constantine.
And Superman, right? Possibly. Yeah, the upcoming
Superman project that's being written by Ta-Nehisi
Coates. John Cena is gonna be there, of course
promoting peacemaker Justin Hartley, I know
that name. Isn't he the guy voicing Superman
on the upcoming injustice movie? Yeah, that's
right. Casey Walfall She's the actress that's
playing Naomi in the upcoming CW show. Kaylee
Cuoco is gonna be there Of course, she voices
Harley Quinn in that animated series and what
about Leslie Grace? She's playing Batgirl in
that movie Linda Carter. She of course played
Wonder Woman in the old school TV series, but
she most recently played Asterea in the Wonder
Woman 1984 movie. Matt Bomer? Of course he's
playing Negative Man in the Doom Patrol series,
he also voiced the Flash in the recent Justice
Society World War II movie. That's right. Matt
Reeves, he's the director of the upcoming Batman
movie. We're supposed to get a trailer for
the Batman, hopefully we get that, that'll be
cool. I think that's the thing I'm most looking
forward to. Melissa Benoist? Is that how you
pronounce it? Benoist? Yeah, it is. She's Supergirl,
of course, in the CW series. Noah Centineo.
He's gonna be playing Adam Smasher in the upcoming
Black Adam movie. Patrick Redding. He's the
creative director for Warner Bros. Games, so
I think he'll be talking about Gotham Knights.
Patty Jenkins is gonna be there, interesting.
Yeah, yeah, it is interesting. She, of course,
directed Wonder Woman and Wonder Woman 1984.
I'm wondering if she's there to announce Wonder
Woman 3. Maybe, maybe not. Pierce Brosnan.
Holy shit. Man needs no introduction. Of course
he's gonna be playing Dr. Fate in the upcoming
Black Adam movie. That's huge. I'll be tuning
into that panel for sure. Quintessa Swindell.
The name sounds familiar. Who's that? They're
the actor that's gonna be playing Cyclone in
Black Adam. Reggie Hudlin. I already know who
that guy is. He's a writer and producer and
director. He's done work for Marvel Comics as
well, but he also works for DC. Oh yeah, he's
one of the minds behind DC's milestone media
relaunch. What about Robert- Pattinson who's
that guy? He's the goddamn Batman! What about
Ron Funches? He does the voice of King Shark
on the Harley Quinn animated series. And Scott
Minville? He does the voice of Robin in Teen
Titans Go. Scott Snyder. Is that Zack Snyder's
brother? Everyone asks that I'm sure he gets
that question all the time. He's a popular writer
for DC Comics. What about Sefton Hill who's
that guy? He's the creative director and co-founder
of Rocksteady Games. He'll be Suicide Squad
killed the Justice League, most likely. Steve
Aggey? He's gonna be in the upcoming Peacemaker
series. He was also in the Suicide Squad and
did the mocap work for King Shark. Tara Strong?
She is the voice of Raven in Teen Titans Go.
And also has done a lot of Harley Quinn work
as well. Yeah, yep. All right, next is Todd
McFarlane. That's pretty cool. Yeah, he's gonna
be there probably to talk about the DC toy line
that he's making. They're really cool toy sculpts.
Tyler Hocklin is going to be there. Of course,
he's the actor that plays Superman in the Superman
and Lois television show. That's right. Shiloh
Mardi Dwenya. He's the actor who's going to
be playing Blue Beetle in the upcoming movie.
He's also known for his work on Cobra Kai.
Oh, look at that. Yahya Abdul-Mateen II is also
going to be there. Yeah, he's the actor who
played Black Manta in the first Aquaman movie.
I imagine he's going to be there for the sequel,
but he was also Dr. Manhattan in the Watchmen
television series for HBO Max. so you never
know what else he may be there for. Zachary
Levi is gonna be there. Of course, yep, he's
the actor who plays Shazam in those movies.
And last but not least, Zoe Kravitz, who of
course is playing Catwoman in the upcoming The
Batman movie. Right. So a few awesome names
there. I'm probably only gonna turn into the
fandom for a few panels here and there, but
largely, like most Marvel fans, I'll be skipping
the fandom. Good, we don't even want you there,
Normie. Ha ha ha. This is for DC fans. This
list is missing notably I think like Jeff Johns
or anyone else involved in the Green Lantern
Corps series for HBO Max. I'm actually really
surprised not to see anyone's name because that's
like one of the big projects that I'm really
looking forward to hearing more about. Yeah,
where's like Michael Keaton? Yeah, yeah, there's
no Michael Keaton and there's no Sasha Kaia
either, which is kind of disappointing. And
no Andy Muschietti who's directing The Flash.
What's up with that? I was wondering the same
thing. Apparently the only one that's going
to be repping The Flash is gonna be Ezra Miller
during the fandom. Which is kinda disappointing.
Overall, does this list make you more or less
excited for the fandom? I mean, I'm really excited.
This list, I wouldn't say it made me more excited.
It's kind of pretty much what I was expecting.
But yeah, if we would've seen some Henry Cavill
on there or some Michael Keaton, I would've
been much more excited. Well, cool, we'll see
how it all goes down this Saturday, October
16th. How do you visit the DC Fandom event?
All you have to do is go to dcfandom.com. they're
going to be streaming the entire virtual convention
for like the whole day. So there's plenty of
time to check it out. All in all, though, there's
going to be a ton of DC projects that they're
going to be talking about. I'm personally most
looking forward to any project that involves
the DCEU. And that brings us to our question
of the week.
What is your favorite DCEU film so far and why?
There's been 10 of them now. We wanna know
your favorite. Yeah, The Joker is not one of
them. No, no, it's not. Record your answer
at dynamicduel.com by clicking the red microphone
button in the bottom right-hand corner, which
will prompt you to leave us a voicemail. Your
message can be up to 30 seconds long, and don't
forget to leave your name in case we include
you on the podcast. We'll pick our favorite
answer and draw that person a Dynamic Duel No
Prize that we'll post to social media. be sure
to answer before October 16th. Which again is
the day of the fandom. Don't miss it. Bruce
Wayne may appear to be a wealthy playboy, but
beneath his facade his true identity is that
of the Batman, waging an endless war against
crime. Join the caped crusader in Batman the
Audio Adventures, the first scripted audio original
featuring Batman and his villainous rogues
gallery in a world premiere story of life and
death in Gotham City. debuting exclusively
on HBO Max. Starring Jeffrey Wright as Batman
and a who's who of Incredible Saturday Night
Live alums, this rollicking adventure, told
across 10 episodes, is written and directed
by Emmy winner Dennis McNicholas, includes devilishly
delightful original music by Doug Bossie, and
performances by Rosario Dawson, John Leguizamo,
Chris Parnell, Melissa Villasenor, Seth Meyers,
Jason Sudeikis, Brooke Shields, Fred Armisen.
and many, many more. Go to hbomax.com slash
Batman Audio Adventures for more and stream
Batman the Audio Adventures only on HBO Max.
Thanks again to HBO Max for sponsoring this
episode. But now let's get into the main event
where we pit the Batman villain, Man-Bat, against
the Spider-Man villain, Morbius, the living
vampire.
Alright, Manbat vs Morbius. As we said earlier,
Manbat is basically Manbear Pig, but minus
the bear pig and adding a bat. So he's kind
of lame, but Morbius on the other hand is a
legit vampire. Just in time for Halloween, right
off the back of our Venom Let There Be Carnage
review. Morbius is of course a Spider-Man villain
who is also getting his own live action film
this upcoming January starring Jared Lotto as
the character. And that film was supposed to
come out already. We've been planning this episode
for a while, and we always kind of figured
that we would be pitting Man-Bat against Morbius
considering both characters were scientists
who became supervillains by experimenting with
bats. Yeah, I don't know too much about Man-Bat.
Is Man-Bat like vampiric at all, or is he just
like a giant fucking bat? He's like a giant
motherfucking bat. What? Well, that is something
to look out for. If you've never listened to
one of our duel episodes before, the way we'll
determine a winner between Manbat and Morbius
is by running 1000 Monte Carlo simulations using
their statistics. Now, a Monte Carlo simulation
is a probabilistic model used to determine outcomes
through random sampling. In our case, it randomizes
statistics along a normal distribution, which
is a bell curve, as a way to simulate the many
variables that can occur during battle. The
stat parameters we use are based on the official
Marvel power grid. and we use that criteria
to extrapolate the DC's character stats. We've
included some additional stat categories of
our own, such as range, damage, potential,
versatility, and perception, in order to create
a more complete and robust simulation. Running
these 1000 simulations gives us a percentage
of wins for each character, and we declare
the one with the higher percentage to be the
ultimate victor, considering that they're more
likely to win any given battle. No character
ever wins 100% of the time. Comics have shown
that there's always a way for Batman to defeat
Superman. We feel our method falls in line
with the precedents that have been established
in the comic book stories. And we used this
method because it was the least subjective,
most unbiased way to determine who would win.
Of course, we were both heavily biased toward
our respective allegiances, and instead of
debating these matches forever, we just let
the math decide for us. So there's no fan votes
here, and no relying on just feats. Before we
run the simulations though, we like to break
down each character's histories and abilities
before improvising a scenario on how we imagine
one of the 1000 simulations we run would play
out beat for beat. And I think it's my turn
to break down the Marvel character's history
first, so let me go ahead and tell you guys
all about Morbius, the living vampire. Michael
Morbius was born in Greece to a single mother
and grew up with a rare blood disorder similar
to hemophilia. Fearful of her son getting injured,
Michael's mom kept him indoors for most of his
childhood, often bringing him books to read
from the bookstore where she worked. Michael
became an intellectually gifted child, though
he occasionally sneaked out of the house to
play with his best friend, Emil Nicos. During
one such outing, he fell and got injured, causing
both boys to get into trouble and vow to one
day cure Michael's condition. Michael and Emil
grew up... and studied science together at
their university, specializing in human and
animal biology. They won a Nobel Prize for
their research on using vampire bat blood to
cure several other blood disorders, convincing
Michael that was the key to fixing his own condition.
Michael became engaged to a fellow scientist
named Martin Bancroft, though his body was quickly
weakening. Debilitated to the point where he
could barely lift a coffee mug, Michael rushed
an experiment on himself using the vampire
bat blood. and electroshock therapy. The process
transformed his body. His skin turned chalk
white, his canine teeth protruded fangs, his
nose flattened like a bat's, and his eyes turned
blood red. Michael's blood disorder had mutated
into a disease of pseudo vampirism, and he
immediately developed an intense thirst for
human blood. He lashed out and bit his lab
partner and friend, Emil, killing him and drinking
his blood. which revitalized Michael to a normal
appearance and healthy physicality that he had
never known. Restored to his normal mental
state, Michael was shocked to see that he had
murdered his childhood friend. Saddened and
horrified by what he had become, and to protect
his fiancee, Martine, he threw himself into
the Mediterranean Sea, though a fishing vessel
that was traveling toward New York City soon
picked him up. By the time the boat reached
the US, all the crewmen were dead, as Michael
feasted on them during the voyage. He washed
up on the South Hampton shore where Spider-Man
and the Lizard were at the time. Thirsty, Michael
attacked the pair, but was overpowered and
had to flee back into the night. The Lizard
was able to use a sample of Michael's blood
to create a serum that could temporarily transform
himself back into his human form and cure Spider-Man,
who had at that point mutated into having six
arms. You can learn more about Spider-Man in
our Blue Beetle vs Spider-Man dual episode.
Michael began reluctantly feeding off of New
Yorkers, occasionally turning random victims
into pseudo-vampires themselves. He tried abstaining
from drinking blood, but the thirst would take
over when given enough time. Distraught, he
tried to commit suicide, though his new healing
factor would not let him die. With nowhere
to turn, Michael reached out to his former fiancée,
Martine, who collaborated with him from overseas
in developing an antidote. They created a serum
derived from his blood that would cure his
turned victims of their vampirism, though it
unfortunately did not work on himself. He declared
that if he must drink blood in his search for
a cure, then it should be the blood of criminals.
In an attempt to become an anti-hero, Michael
discovered a woman named Barbara Clark, who
was being pursued by a demon named Nilrack.
He went through great lengths to protect the
woman from the monster, though afterward, he
killed Barbara and drank her blood to satisfy
his thirst. feeling immense guilt at his lack
of control. Eventually, Blade the Vampire Hunter,
whom you can learn more about in our Asriel
vs Blade episode, came across Michael and tried
to kill him. Once Blade learned about Morbius'
plight, however, and his anti-hero status,
the two teamed up to defeat an otherworldly
sorcerer named Daimond. Michael also met and
tried to stop another sympathetic monster known
as the Werewolf by Night, real name Jack Russell,
and the two became reluctant rivals. Eventually,
they both teamed up with Ghost Rider and Man-Thing
and formed the first incarnation of the Legion
of Monsters superhero team, though they soon
disbanded after accidentally killing a benevolent
entity called the Starseed. Believing that
perhaps Spider-Man's radioactive blood held
the key to his antidote, Michael attacked him
and managed to get his fangs in the hero's neck.
At that moment, he was hit by a bolt of lightning,
which somehow resulted in Michael being cured
of his pseudo-vampirism. Authorities charged
him for his crimes as a vampire, though She-Hulk
defended him in court claiming he was not responsible
for his actions. After living life as a normal
human again for a few years, Michael was captured
and reverted back to his pseudo-vampire condition
by the Voodoo Queen. He teamed up with Dr.
Strange and Brother Voodoo to stop the Voodoo
Queen's attempt to bring back vampires after
Dr. Strange had eradicated Dracula, but the
group was unsuccessful. You can learn more
about Doctor Strange in our Doctor Fate vs Doctor
Strange episode. Morbius then formed a team
of supernatural heroes with his former allies
called the Midnight Sons and together they
stopped Lilith, the mother of demons, and her
spawn, the Lilin, from plunging the earth into
eternal darkness. During the fight against Lilith,
Michael's ex-fiancee, Martine, was killed and
turned into a vampire herself, bringing him
more torment. Morbius put his mind to work
trying to find a cure for a zombie virus that
had entered Marvel's dimension through the
nexus of all realities in Manthing Swamp. Together
with the Midnight Suns, he helped contain a
zombie outbreak, and he later teamed up with
the Lizard to try and permanently cure their
conditions together at Horizon Labs, though
Michael inadvertently attacked the other scientists
and was sent to the Rapt Prison before he could
finish his work. Recently, Michael was seen
back in Europe, where a group of vampires captured
him and and mixed his blood with their own,
creating a new breed of monsters. With Domino's
help, Michael defeated the new vampires and
continued his journey across the earth in search
for a cure. Powers-wise, Morbius is a pseudo-vampire
in that he has all the abilities of vampires
but none of their traditional weaknesses, except
for the thirst and a minor sensitivity to direct
sunlight. These abilities include superhuman
strength, being able to lift one ton, superhuman
speed, especially in short bursts, night vision
and a sensitivity to the smell of blood, a regenerative
healing factor, sharp fangs and claws, the
ability to glide almost endlessly, he can mesmerize
people through prolonged eye contact with the
duration of his influence depending on his victim's
willpower, he can occasionally create other
pseudo-vampires, and he doesn't age being effectively
immortal. Morbius is also an incredibly gifted
biochemist and Nobel Prize winner. Silver, garlic,
religious relics, stakes through the heart,
all of that have no effect on him. His only
weakness being the fact that he needs human
blood in order to maintain his strength. So
he can't turn into like a bunch of bats or
anything like that? No. He can't like teleport
through shadows? No, I guess he doesn't have
all of their powers. He just has most of their
powers. Okay, he's more like man bat than I
realized. For some reason I thought Morbius
was a lot stronger than you know the one ton
lifting strength. But I'm glad he's not. This
should be a good match, I think. Let me get
into the history of Manbat. When Dr. Robert
Kirkland Langstrom, aka Kirk, was a young boy,
he made national headlines as a missing child
as he became trapped within a deep underground
cavern for six weeks. He was eventually rescued
and began frightening other children, including
a six-year-old Bruce Wayne, with stories of
the half-man... half-bat creatures he believed
he had encountered in the cavern during his
time there. Kirk maintained an obsession with
bats as the years went on, and he attended Gotham
University to become a zoologist specializing
in chiropterology, or the study of bats. It
was during his university years that he met
and dated the chemist Francine Lee, with whom
he shared his ideas of how his bat studies
could pioneer medical breakthroughs. After obtaining
his doctorate, Kirk became a zoologist and
nocturnal mammals expert employed at the Gotham
Natural History Museum and he and Francine
became engaged. After learning that he was slowly
becoming deaf, Kirk developed a serum derived
from bat gland extracts within his museum basement
lab that could benefit blind or deaf people
with enhanced hearing, granting them echolocation
like a bat. Kirk tested his formula on himself.
which had the unintended consequences of mutating
him into a monstrous half-man half-bat hybrid,
a man-bat with large leathery wings and razor-sharp
claws. Terrified by what he had done and overwhelmed
by his enhanced senses, Kirk soon became aware
that criminals had broken into the museum above
him. They were members of the Blackout Gang,
a stealthy group that was currently on the
run from Batman. who you can learn more about
in our Batman vs. Moon Knight episode. Overcome
by his animal instincts, Kirk attacked the gang
alongside Batman, who assumed Kirk was a new
fellow crime fighter. Kirk fled immediately
after, but ran into Batman multiple times over
the coming days as Kirk attempted to steal chemicals
from around the city, desperate to find a cure
before his animal mind took over.
sleeping harmlessly during the day and only
going out at night to wreak havoc throughout
the city. That's hilarious. Yeah, they kind
of like were roommates for a while. Batman,
who by this time had deduced that the creature
was Dr. Kirk Langstrom, attempted to work on
an antidote and enlisted the help of Kirk's
fiance, Francine. Though they were successful,
Manbette rejected the antidote, and in an effort
to prove her love, Francine took the Manbette
serum. transforming into She-Bat. These names,
man. Man-Bat followed the two bat creatures
to Gotham Cathedral, where he forced them both
to take the antidote. Grateful to be human
once again, Kirk and Francine got married soon
after, and Batman was Kirk's best man. Batman
in his Batman costume? Yes. Yep. Interesting.
Okay. The antidote, however, was revealed to
be impermanent, as days after his wedding, Kirk
transformed back into Man-Bat, and with his
animal mind attempting to take control, he created
a more potent formula that would transform
him into Man-Bat permanently. Batman stopped
him from taking it, however, and administered
the antidote once again. Months later, Francine
reverted back to She-Bat, and Kirk helped Batman
track her down and administer the antidote to
her. Eventually, Kirk was able to develop a
new formula that would allow him and his wife
to keep their human minds whenever they transformed.
Kirk became a crime fighter and ally to Batman,
helping him as Man-Bat take down villains such
as the Getaway Genius and Baron Time. The Langströms
later moved to Chicago to get away from Gotham
City's criminal element, only to encounter and
defeat the likes of the Ten-Eyed Man and Dr.
Thanatogenos before moving to New York City.
While there, Kirk teamed up with Robin and
Batgirl in order to stop a villain named the
Outsider who was attempting to kill members
of the Bat family. The Langstrums eventually
became pregnant, and Kirk became a bounty hunter
of sorts, capturing criminals in order to collect
the reward money for his growing family. As
Francine went into labor, Kirk teamed up with
Etrigan the Demon, who you can learn more about
in our Etrigan vs. Ghost Rider episode. to stop
the sorceress Morgan Le Fay from transforming
all of the hospital's babies into demons. Francine
gave birth to a healthy baby girl, whom they
named Rebecca. Now with a child to think of,
Kirk retired as madbat and began working in
construction to support his family. News reports
of a bat creature terrorizing New York City,
however, led him to question whether or not
he really had control over his transformations
while he slept. He later discovered It was his
wife seeking freedoms from the new responsibilities
of motherhood. When the Langstroms realized
Rebecca suffered from acute hearing, Man-Bat
attempted to steal chemicals once again to develop
a cure. Batman stopped him, however, and it
was Superman who later helped Kirk find a cure
for his daughter. A short time after the Langstroms
moved back to Gotham City, Kirk accidentally
made a miscalculation in the formula he and
his wife used to keep their human minds when
they transformed. and his animal mind took
over completely. He secretly returned to the
Batcave, leading Batman and Alfred to wonder
if the Batcave was haunted. Batman eventually
found Man-Bat and attempted to use the antidote,
but Kirk's mind was too far gone and it didn't
work. It wasn't until Man-Bat saw his daughter
Rebecca that Kirk's mind was reawakened and
he was able to take control once again. Although
after that, Kirk was forced to take the antidote
regularly to limit his now more intense transformations.
After getting his job back at the Gotham Natural
History Museum, the long hours caused Kirk
to forget to take his antidote, and he transformed
into an uncontrollable man-bat once again,
kidnapping Jason Todd in an attempt to transform
him into a bat hybrid before being stopped
by the combined effort of Batman, Francine,
and Rebecca. The Langströms later had a son,
Eren. who was born with a deadly illness due
to Kirk's and Francine's altered DNA. Francine
was forced to inject Eren with the Man-Bat serum,
transforming him into a baby-bat hybrid permanently
in order to save his life. Talia Al Ghul, who
you can learn more about in our Daughters of
the Demon vs. Daughters of the Dragon dual episode,
later kidnapped the Langstrom family and threatened
to kill them if they didn't give her the Man-Bat
formula, which they did, in which Talia used
to create an army of bat-hybrid assassins known
as the Manbat Commandos. Later, while Francine
worked as a member of the Outsiders, serving
as their scientific advisor, Kirk realized
he was able to control his Manbat transformations
at will. During the Blackest Night storyline,
Francine discovered a cure for her and her husband's
transformations, while also discovering that
if Kirk transformed one more time, he would
no longer be able to turn back into a human.
Just as Kirk was about to take the cure, a battle
between Black Lantern Solomon Grundy and Bizarro
injured Francine, and Kirk was forced to transform
one final time in order to protect and save
his wife. In post-Flashpoint continuity, the
Manbat Serum originated as a lab-created airborne
virus that plagued Gotham City before its accidental
creator, Dr. Kirk Langstrom, was able to derive
an anti-virus by transforming himself into a
bat hybrid, once again, the Manbat. He took
a villainous turn for a while, allying himself
with Scarecrow during the Arkham Wars and serving
as a member of the Crime Syndicate before joining
an anti-terrorism task force for the supernatural
organization, Shade, which you can learn more
about in our Frankenstein vs. Bloodstone episode.
He was later a member of Woodrow Man's Justice
League Dark Team, during which time he became
an expert on the science of magic. Powers-wise,
Manbat possesses flight thanks to his wings,
as well as enhanced physicality, including superhuman
strength and agility. He has extremely sensitive
hearing that allows for echolocation, and he
can emit sonic blasts with his voice, capable
of stunning his victims. He also has razor-sharp
claws on his hands and feet. He has a brilliant
scientific mind, Though the longer he's in his
Man-Bat form, the harder it is for him to fight
back against Man-Bat's pure, instinctual, and
animalistic mind. He can communicate with bats,
and has a sensitivity to bright lights in his
Man-Bat form. That's Man-Bat. It's interesting,
like, this Batman villain is not really crazy,
like, he's never been to Arkham Asylum or anything,
so he seems quite different from the standard
Batman rogues. He's kinda like Morbius, where
he's basically more of a good guy who gets into
trouble. Yeah, he's a lot like Morbius except
which one do you think came first? Obviously
Morbius. He came out in 1971. Oh Man-bat has
him beat by one year. He came out in 1970. What
a rip-off. But once again But Marvel did it
better because Morbius is a much cooler character
who's actually getting his own film Actually
Man-bat was going to be the villain of the Batman
and Robin sequel But that never happened as
long as Joel Schumacher didn't direct it. I'd
be down to see that I think he was gonna direct
it actually. Eww Nah, that would be no good.
He would have had like nipples, like bright
pink areolas, I think. So these characters are
like so similar then. Although you know what's
interesting is that Morbius, although he was
essentially turned into like a bat vampire
creature, he doesn't have echolocation like
Manbat does. And that's why he's going to die.
Well, let's find out. Now that we've got their
histories and abilities out of the way, let's
speculate on how one of the 1000 simulated matches
will go. The winner is determined by simulations,
not the speculation, but it's fun to imagine
how this fight could play out. We don't set
any rules for this match other than the characters
don't know anything about each other going
in, except that the other character is a threat
that needs to be put down. And we say that
they start off about 50 meters apart in an environment
that has no bearing on the match itself because
we don't take stats for the environment. Plus
certain characters have advantages in some
environments over others, and we want these
characters to win on their own merit. So let's
get into it. Morbius and Manbat meet on the
battlefield. Who goes first? I'm gonna say
that Manbat does just because he's a little
bit more animalistic and wild. So he's gonna
start off by soaring into the air and send out
the shriek that stuns Morbius. So Manbat's
shriek is capable of stunning people? Yes. Yeah,
it can also like shatter windows and stuff.
It's pretty powerful. Well, Morbius would be
particularly susceptible to that because he
does have enhanced hearing. Exactly. Okay, so
Morbius, you know, he's like in pain, he's
stunned, and Manbat, he's gonna use this opening
to just like dive bomb him, right? And he's
gonna slash Morbius' torso, just leaving these
deep bloody gashes before taking off back into
the air. That was a good opening, Salvo. And
Morbius is definitely gonna be feeling the
attack, both audio and physical, but you know,
he's gonna be able to heal those slash wounds.
and he leaps up into the air at Manbat right
at him and digs his own sharp claws into Manbat's
chest and holds on tight and reaches up and
just sinks his teeth into the creature's neck.
Wait, he's gonna bite his neck as they're flying
through the air? Yeah. Except that Manbat reacted
to Morbius's claw attack with a barrel roll
as he's flying through the air, right? So that's
gonna fling Morbius off of him towards the ground
before Manbat could get bit in the neck. Do
a barrel roll! Exactly. Except Morbius isn't
gonna hit the ground, he can glide. So he's
just gonna glide away from Manbat and just kinda
like disappear into the shadows. Shadows? What
shadows? Well wherever there's light, there's
shadows. And wherever there's not light, there's,
you know, also shadows. Okay? I mean, but you
can't hide from Manbat in the shadows though.
He has echolocation. So right when Morbius thinks
he's safe- Manbat's just gonna silently swoop
in and just lift Morbius back into the air by
his hair. That long ass hair that's just easy
to grab. But Morbius is smart, okay? So, when
he realizes that Manbat is able to detect where
he is through echolocation, which Morbius would
know because he'd be able to hear the echolocation
scream, and also he would know where Manbat
is at all times now that Manbat's bleeding
because he could smell his blood. So, when Manbat-
thinks he's getting the drop on Morbius by
swooping in to grab him by the hair. Morbius
counters by dashing to the side and slashing
through one of Manbat's wings and just fricking
turning it into shreds. No, that's right. Manbat's
grounded. All right. So Manbat, he's probably
like screeching in pain. And honestly, that
attack probably like made Dr. Langstrom lose
control over the animal mind within Manbat.
So now it's no more Mr. Nice Manbat. All right.
He's gonna scurry across the ground and just
lunge at Morbius, just like grabbing his jugular
in his jaws and just biting down really hard
going for the kill. Holy shit. Except as Manbat
pounces on Morbius, uh, Morbius is gonna throw
up his arms in- in self-defense, and Manbat
is only just gonna bite into his forearm instead
of Morbius' neck. And with Manbat's bangs, you
know, like, deep into Morbius' forearm, Morbius
is gonna maneuver Manbat's head where he can
expose his neck. and Morbius just sinks his
fangs into Manbat's neck and it's gonna drain
him of all of his blood and energy. So Manbat's
like done, like Morbius just like freaking pushes
him off to the side and Manbat falls lippily
to the ground cause he doesn't have anything
left, Morbius wins. Except Manbat, you know,
he's not frail without his blood. In fact, he's
stronger now than he's ever been because since
Morbius bit him, he's now a pseudo vampire Manbat.
No, no, except, no, that didn't. Nah. He's
man-pseudo-vampire bat with like all white fur
and skin like red eyes and now with his own
healing factor But like still all animal instinct.
He's more dangerous now than ever. Did you
say man pseudo vampire bat? Yes, man pseudo
vampire bat So he's like a giant albino bat
now, but with vampiric tendencies. Yeah. So
Morbis is like, oh shit, I done fucked up Exactly,
but you know Morbius is also gonna be stronger
than he's ever been because he just got done
feasting on the man bats blood So, you know,
he's like full of energy and before man meant
what is it pseudo man's a pseudo vampire bat
Yes Before he could do anything Morbius speed
blitzes him and tackles him to the ground pinning
him down as Morbius looks into his eyes and
Mesmerizes the creature into becoming docile
dude Morbius can't tame the animal mind within
Manitou vampire bat. All right? Animals can't
be hypnotized, so they're not smart enough.
OK, so as Morbius thinks he's hypnotizing Manitou
vampire bat, he's just going to stick his head
out and bite right into Morbius's neck, just
ripping it out entirely and ending this match.
So basically, Manitou vampire bat took advantage
of Morbius just staring at him and it did nothing.
Exactly. Morbius tried and failed. But Morbius
wouldn't die from getting his throat ripped
out. What? Um, but I'm thinking now that Man-Bat
has vampirism and he also has this mutagenic
chemical in his blood that transformed him into
Man-Bat in the first place. I bet you like
in the comics, it probably somehow reacts with
Morbius's own blood disorder. So as Morbius
heals his neck, he also sprouts giant bat wings
and sheds his outfit and he becomes his own.
Man-pseudo-vampire bat-vampire. Man-pseudo-vampire
bat is probably horribly confused by what just
happened. So man-pseudo-vampire bat-vampire
then attacks man-pseudo-vampire bat and rips
his pseudo-man heart out of his vampire bat
chest. Okay, wait, whose heart got ripped out?
The man, pseudo, vampire, bat, vampire? No,
no, the man, pseudo, vampire, man, bat. All
I know is Marvel wins. You don't know shit,
like no one does anymore. Basically, there's
these two giant albino, vampire, pseudo, man,
bats that are attacking each other. There's
just so much cross contamination of like blood
conditions and viruses and shit. Who knows
which one is which one anymore? But let's find
out who wins this scenario by running these
character stats in 1000 simulations and coming
back with a winner. Let's do it!
That was unexpected. What was it again? Pseudo
vampire bat man? No, man pseudo vampire bat
man. Oh, okay. I forgot. But we ran the stats
on these characters. Pretty comparable here,
as I figured it would be. It's definitely gonna
be a close match because these characters are
nearly identical when it comes to things like
speed, evasiveness, strength, damage level,
versatility. But it was determined that Morbius
is much more durable given that he has a regenerative
healing factor, whereas Manbat does not. Right,
but where Manbat did get the edge was in perception,
thanks to his echolocation. That's something
that Morbius didn't have. Manbat also had a
slight advantage when it came to range due to
his sonic shriek that he has. Morbius has some
range with his whole mesmerization thing, but
it's not very much. The victim has to be kind
of in close proximity to see his gaze. So after
crunching these numbers and running the simulations,
who do you think is gonna win this match, Jonathan?
Manbet, hopefully. I'm not sure, I know it's
gonna be close. I really hope it's not the same
results that we got from our Instagram poll,
in which 72% of our Instagram followers chose
Morbius. And I'm like, what? What are you guys
doing? Like, Manbet is way cooler than Morbius.
I don't know how that happened. Manbet is just
too simplistic of a character, I think. He's
not interesting enough to ever be that popular.
Whereas Morbius, you know, he's a fucking vampire.
Vampires are cool. Morbius is like the least
cool vampire in fiction. He's like a living
vampire. How lame is that? Like even other
vampires hate him. It's interesting to me that
Manbat turned out to be not vampiric at all.
I always thought like he'd bite other people
and turn them into Manbats themselves. No,
it all comes down to his serum. Hence the lowered
popularity. hence these poll results. But let
me go ahead and tell you who won. The winner
in the dual matchup between Manbat and Morbius
is Morbius, the living vampire. It was fairly
close. It was 56.4% to 43.6%. So Morbius won
564 matches out of a thousand compared to Manbat's
436 wins. I thought Manbat scored higher in
more stat categories than Morbius. but Morbius
scored much higher when it came to durability.
And intellect, since we reasoned that Man-Bat
isn't always consistent with how smart he is
in that form. I forgot about intelligence. Shit.
At the end of the day, a brilliant human mind
will always beat out a crazy animal mind. That's
just the food chain. Man-Bat turns into a nice
snack for Morbius, and us Marvel fans get another
win. You guys have needed one of those for
a while. DC is totally stomping you guys, so
congrats, I guess. Thanks man. I can't wait
to see Morbius's rotten tomato meter. I'm sure
it'll probably also be at 56.4%. That's probably
true, touche. That was pretty good. But that
does it for this duel guys. Let us know what
you thought about the results by writing to
us at dyna or by visiting us on Facebook, Instagram
or Twitter. You can find links to all of our
accounts by checking out our show notes or
visiting our website dynamic duel.com And on
our site you can also find a link to our patreon
page where we offer bonus content including
bonus episodes and duels, monthly live movie
watch alongs, collectible pincets, and access
to our discord server. Check it out right now
after this episode. Our lowest tier is only
$2 a month. Which is also the cost to subscribe
to this show on Spotify. Subscribe now to access
over 200 archived episodes of this podcast.
Our next episode is going to be a review. We're
going to talk all about the animated series
What If on Disney Plus. Which I have yet to
start watching. Need to get on that. Y'all
be interested in hearing what you think about
it. But that does it for this episode. We want
to give a big thanks to our executive producers,
John Spees, Ken Johnson, Jace Crump, John Storosky,
Zachary Hepburn, John Bechinina, Mitchell Phipps,
Steven Lovato, Dustin Balcom, Salvador Hernandez
Contreras Jr. and Levi Yee-In for helping make
this podcast possible. And we'll talk to you
guys next week. Up up and away, true believers.