This is a DynaMic Network Podcast. Hi, welcome to
the Dynamic Duel Podcast, a weekly show where we
review superhero films and debate the
superiority between Marvel and DC by comparing
their characters in stat-based battle
simulations. I'm Johnny DC. And I'm his twin
brother Marvelous Joe, holy shit. And as you can
tell from the sound of Joseph's voice, he is very
sick, so he will be doing as little talking as
possible this episode, being a dual episode
between Blue Beetle, the Ted Kord incarnation,
and Prowler, the Spider-Man villain. He's mostly
an ally. Well that's news to me. I thought he was a
bad guy. Interesting. Alright, well we're gonna
find out more about him later on in this episode.
Before that, we are not going to break down any
comic book movie news from the past week because
there hasn't been any really some behind-the-set
photos, but I don't know if things are made with AI
nowadays. So until it's confirmed by the studio,
I'm just going to assume everything is fake.
Fucking crickets. This is what happens when
Joseph can't speak. I have no one to laugh at my
jokes. Jokes suck, bro. Your voice sucks, bro. As
always, we list our segment times in our episode
description, so feel free to check out the show
notes if you want to skip ahead to a particular
topic. Our artificially intelligent dual
simulator AJ9K has a quick message for our
listeners, so listen up. Why hello there. Do you
want even more from this podcast? Then become a
part of the dynamic dual community on Patreon
where you can choose from three tiers. The dynamic
2.0 tier gives you access to our Discord chat
server, the fantastic 4.0 tier gives you two bonus
episodes each month, and the X-Force tier makes
you an executive producer of this show. Lastly,
the Dynamite podcast network tier lets you create
your own podcast using this Monte Carlo
simulator. Johnny and Joe will help you develop
your show, provide graphic support and
consultation, and get you simulation results.
Pitch the twins your ideas via email at
dynamicdualpodcast.com. Check it out at
patreon.com. Thanks AJ9K and thanks to everyone
who supports the podcast. Guys be sure to tune into
the other shows in the Dynamite podcast network
this week, including the console combat podcast,
where hosts John and Dean simulate battles
between popular video game characters. In
yesterday's episode, they speculated on who
would win in a dogfight between Fox McLeod from
Star Fox piloting his R-Wing against Wedge and
Tilly's from Star Wars Rogue Squadron piloting
his X-Wing. Over on the Max Destruction podcast,
hosts Scotty and Gilly pay your favor action
heroes from film and television against each
other. This Wednesday, the twins are reviewing
the 1988 film Bloodsport. And finally on the Sanjo
World podcast, hosts Zachary Hepburn speculates
on fights between fan favorite anime and manga
characters. On Thursday, Zach is going to reveal
who would win between Yaroichi Shihou-Yin from
Bleach versus Kizaru from One Piece. Visit
dynamicpodcasts.com or click the link in our show
notes to listen to all of the shows in the Dynamite
podcast network. But with that out of the way?
Quick to the no prize! A no prize is an award that
Marvel used to give out to fans. Our version, the
Dynamic Dual No Prize, is a digital award that we
post on Instagram for the person we feel gave the
best answer to our question of the week. Last week,
we asked, what do you think of Crypto the Superdog
from the Superman sneak peek? And of course, this
question was in regards to the extended trailer
that we received for the Superman film that came
out of CinemaCon. We got four answers, so let's
break down this week's three honorable mentions
before revealing the no prize winner. Our first
honorable mention goes to Christopher Minotti,
who said, Hi guys, Christopher Minotti. So
Crypto, he's a little fluffier than I was
expecting, but I'm still hoping that they do a good
job with him. I get that he's supposed to be the cute
character, the lighthearted, well not
lighthearted, he's a dog, so of course. But I'm
still hoping that they do a good job with him, and
I'm hoping that they have a cool scene with him. The
first time I realized Crypto was cool was in
Blackest Night, when he saved Martha Kent by
ripping up Black Lantern's arm off and then
blasting it with Heat Vision. Yeah, and the comics
Crypto is no joke. He is fiercely loyal and doesn't
have the same morality that someone say like
Superman has. So he's actually fairly dangerous.
This version of the dog is very fluffy, you know,
usually he's depicted as a Labrador of some sorts,
but here he looks very much like almost like a
poodle terrier mutt kind of dog. So they're
definitely trying to play up the cute factor with
him, which is all right. I guess the cuter the dog
is, the more audiences will be happy with it, but
we'll see how it goes. As I said in the last episode,
I have full confidence in James Gunn's writing,
especially when it comes to animal characters,
you take a look at Rocker at Coon or something like
that. So I think things should be fine. Didn't
Crypto almost kill Mongol? Yeah, actually he
straight up bit his throat nearly killing him.
Great answer Christopher, our next honorable
mention goes to Lee Tapscott, who said, What do I
think about Crypto in the Superman trailer? Man, I
love this. I think dogs can really sense if a
person's good or bad. And Crypto just you can just
tell he loves Superman. Superman is so good to him.
This makes me care about him so much in the energy.
And when it comes push to shove, he knows exactly
what his master needs, takes him right to the help
opens up that door. Smart dog. Yeah, like we
mentioned in the last episode, people are kind of
trashing Crypto's intelligence, but I kind of see
it as him being well trained to an extent, right?
He's really happy to see his owner. So he's jumping
on his owner. But once he realizes something is
wrong, he listens to him and takes him straight to
the fortress of solitude. One of the secret
shortcuts of getting a character to be likable in
film is to give them a dog character and have them be
nice to a dog. I've brought this up before. I don't
know if this is what James Gunn is trying to do with
Superman, just to make him more endearing to
audiences who may not necessarily care for the
character. But if he plays his cards right, story
wise, I think he could totally pull that off
between the characters of Crypto and Superman.
Because dogs, like Lee Tapscott said, are
naturally intuitive. And if you like Superman,
general audiences will gather that, oh, this is a
trustworthy character. Great answer, Lee. Our
final honorable mention goes to Peter, who said,
what's up, dynamic dudes? It's Peter. My thoughts
on Crypto was, I thought it was really funny,
honestly. Like when I first saw the trailer, I
laughed audibly, thinking that's a cute dog.
That's something that my dog would do if I had one,
which I don't. But if I did, he would act like that.
And especially since they're training him, I
think it'd be a fun part to the movie. So that's what
I got to say. Thanks, guys. Peter Yeah. So every dog
I've had, I've rescued from an animal shelter. And
they're not the best trained of dogs. When I come
home, my dog, Olive, is still super excited. She's
a little white chihuahua, and you know, she'll hop
on me. It doesn't bother me because she's so small.
I'm sure if she was the size of Crypto, I would be
more irritated by it. But yeah, I totally related
to Crypto jumping on Superman in this extended
trailer. Again, I didn't love it initially. But
once I realized, oh, hey, yeah, this reminds me of
my dog, it became much easier to understand what
James Gunn was trying to do with this dog, because
he said before that Crypto was inspired by his dog
that he rescued, who's not necessarily well
behaved. And so for him to put that into the movie is
a slice of life of sorts. And it's definitely one
that I recognized for my own life. And I think a lot
of people might have an 80 pound German shepherd
mix named Bucky. And I got to say if he did to me, what
Crypto did to Superman, I'd be pissed. I don't
know, but there's also something to be said for a
big lovable dog that loves you unconditionally
and just wants to give you a big hug and kiss when you
come home. That's true. I love my dog. Great
answer, Peter. The winner of this week's no prize,
however, is Travis Herndon. Who said? What's up,
Jeremy? Dude's Travis here. Shout out to my even
twin. So my answer is I like Crypto and honestly, he
doesn't deserve to hate him. Yes, especially from
a certain YouTuber saying that like, well, my dog,
he ain't dog, he's stuff though, whimpered and
whined when I pretend to be hurting stuff. And to
that, Crypto is based off of James Gunn's own dog
who was a rowdy, rambunctious puppy. So I mean, it
wouldn't make sense why he would be acting like
that. It's based off his own dog. Yeah, I'm not sure
which YouTuber Travis is referring to. But like
I've said, the inclusion of Crypto was inspired by
James Gunn's own dog, who he rescued from a
shelter. And you just got to admire that, you know,
taking a dog that could have been put down and
giving it a new home, giving it a loving family,
whether it's behaved or not, you know, it still
deserves to have the love of James Gunn and his
family. For him to include the character of his dog
in the movie, I think is pretty awesome
personally. And I have to say, I'm pretty happy
that everyone who called in seemed to enjoy Crypto
because I was worried that a lot of people weren't,
you know, the internet could be a pretty negative
place sometimes. But shout out to all of our
listeners, especially the ones who have just
called in who like Crypto. I think he's going to be a
fun addition to the Superman film that comes out
this July. Yeah, don't be a cynical asshole on the
internet like dogs, right? Yeah, what are you,
some kind of dog hater? YouTube guy. Yeah, whoever
you are. Great answer, Travis. You win the Speak to
No Prize. If you're the listener want to shout at
winning your own no prize, stay tuned to later on in
this episode when we'll be asking another
question of the week. Another that's done. On to
the question of the week. So as we mentioned,
there's no big comic book movie news from this past
week. So we're going to ask, but we want to know
what's your favorite Marvel or DC comic that
you're reading right now and why it's really hard
for me to stay up to date with current comics. I feel
like all of the comics I read are just to do research
for this show. And I'm very curious to see what
current comics you guys are reading that you just
love right now. Pick your number one favorite and
record your answer at dynamic dual.com by
clicking on the red microphone button in the
bottom right hand corner of the screen, which will
prompt you to leave us a voicemail. Your message
could be up to 30 seconds long. And don't forget to
leave your name in case we include you on the
podcast. We'll pick our favorite answer and award
that person a dynamic dual no prize that we'll post
to Instagram. Be sure to answer before April 16th.
We're recording our next episode a little bit
early because of the Easter weekend. So make sure
to get your answer in early. DC high volume Batman,
the Dark Knight's definitive DC comic stories
adapted directly for audio for the very first
time. Fear. I have to make them afraid. He's got a
motorcycle. Get after him or have you shot? You
mean blow up the building from this moment on. None
of your safe new episodes every Wednesday,
wherever you get your podcasts. But now it's time
to get onto the main events of this episode, where
we find out who would win in a battle between Ted
court, the blue beetle and prowler. All right,
blue beetle versus prowler. Of course, this is the
Ted cord version of blue beetle. And the fact that
we've waited until year. What is this 10 to get to
Ted cord is a travesty of justice. It is wrong, but
we're going to make it right here today. Because
Ted cord is a solid B Lister, if not a Lister of the DC
Comics Pantheon, I would say. Prowler. Not so
much. He's like a C level Spider-Man villain or I
guess a parent ally. I don't know much about him. I
do know that both of these characters are very tech
based. And I think that's why the executive
producers wanted to put them together. I do
remember the parlor from the 90s Spider-Man
television series, the cartoon. But of course, he
was also famously in the into the spider verse
film, as well as beyond the spider verse, although
that version was Miles Morales spoiler alert.
Yeah, there have been two prominent prowler
characters in the comics over the years. You sound
like RFK Junior, man. Okay. And one of them
obviously is Miles Morales is uncle. Correct.
Okay. Now, outside of the cartoons, blue beetle
hasn't had too many appearances in the media. He
was referenced in the live action blue beetle
movie, but we never actually got to see him.
Fingers crossed he appears in an eventual sequel.
We're going to learn more about blue beetle and
Prowler here soon. But to explain the methodology
behind our duels, let's go to our sentient dual
simulator, Alfred Jarvis 9000. AJ and NK tell our
listeners how you go about determining a winner in
our dual matchups. Yes, of course, sir. The way I
determine a winner between the contestants is by
running 1000 Monte Carlo simulations using the
characters statistics. A Monte Carlo simulation
is a probabilistic model used to determine
outcomes through random sampling. In this case, I
randomize the statistics along a normal
distribution as a way to simulate the many
variables that can occur during battle. The stat
parameters are based on the official Marvel power
grid from which the DC characters statistics are
extrapolated. Additional stat categories are
included such as range, damage potential,
versatility and perception in order to create a
more detailed and accurate simulation. The
results of the 1000 simulations provide a
percentage of wins for each character. The
contestant with the higher percentage is
declared the victor as they have a higher
probability to win any given battle. In an
equitable pairing, neither character should win
100% of the matches. The comic book stories have
shown that there's even a way for Batman to defeat
Superman, so the confidence rate of my method
falls in line with the precedents that have been
established in the source material. My
mathematical simulations are without
subjectivity or bias. Feats are not the sole
consideration, nor are fan votes tabulated for
determination of the winner. Thanks, AJ9K.
Before we run the simulations, though, we like to
break down each character's histories and
abilities before improvising a scenario on how we
imagine one of the 1000 simulations would play out
beat for beat. I believe it's your turn to go first,
Joseph, but since you're freaking dying, I will
read all about the prowler. Born in the Bronx as the
youngest of nine children, Hobart Hobie Brown
showed an early talent as an inventor but faced a
difficult upbringing. His father, Tiger Brown,
left the family when Hobie was a baby and later died
during military service in Cambodia. His mother,
overwhelmed by their responsibility, became an
alcoholic, leaving Hobie and his siblings to
raise themselves. After high school, Hobie
became a window washer to support himself despite
his engineering skills. During a job, he was
nearly killed in a battle between Stiltman and
Spider-Man. Inspired to make his window washing
job safer, Hobie designed pneumatic safety
equipment, including air pressure boots to
counter high winds, wrist-mounted sprayers, and
a safety grappling system. You can learn more
about Spider-Man and his duel against Blue
Beetle, Jaime Reyes, and more about Stiltman and
his duel against Kite Man. Hobie's inventive
ideas were rejected by his employer, who had only
hired him to meet a racial quota. After quitting,
Hobie decided to adopt the costumed identity of
the prowler, planning to a robbery and return the
stolen goods to gain publicity for his
inventions. Targeting the Daily Bugle's
payroll, he encountered Peter Parker during the
heist. In order to change into Spider-Man, Peter
faked being thrown out of a window, causing J.
Jonah Jameson to believe the prowler had
committed murder. Spider-Man subdued Hobie, but
realizing his intent was not malicious, let him go
with advice to change his path. Hobie took the
message to heart and abandoned his criminal
plans. Hobie soon impersonated Spider-Man at
Peter's request to help protect his identity,
wearing the costume in front of Peter's friends
while Peter pretended to be ill. Believing
Spider-Man was responsible for the death of
Captain George Stacey, Hobie tried to bring him to
justice but failed. Hobie later married his
longtime girlfriend, Mindy, and worked in
construction. Through the Big Brother program,
he met her young man named Manny Lopez, who was
later killed in a gang incident. Believing Hector
Ayala, the White Tiger, was responsible, Hobie
fought him until realizing his mistake. While
trying to join the superhero team of the
defenders, Hobie was thrown into the harbor by
Valkyrie and chose to retire from heroics.
However, his prowler equipment was stolen and
used by a second prowler to commit a murder.
Spider-Man recovered the gear and persuaded
Hobie to stay uninvolved. Hobie later resumed the
prowler identity to help clear Mindy's name after
she was framed for financial fraud. He retrieved
the evidence from a cellist targeted by the Black
Fox and worked with Spider-Man to clear her name.
When Spider-Man was framed for robbing a
millionaire, Hobie teamed up with several allies
including Puma, Rocket Racer, and Sandman.
Silver Sable, a mercenary from the Eastern
European nation of Simcaria, offered the group
further work. Hobie joined Silver Sable's
mercenary team called the Outlaws and
participated in missions across North America
and England, once battling Excalibur and
uncovering a rogue Arnim Zola construct. At the
time, he trained with his brother Abraham Abe
Brown, who was a martial artist and former wielder
of White Tiger's Jade Amulets as a member of the
Sons of the Tiger. You can learn more about Silver
Sable and White Tiger in their respective duels
against Vigilante and Bronze Tiger. Hobie teamed
up with his brother Abe to fight street crime, but
was temporarily injured battling Killer Shrike.
Though Hobie's wife Mindy left him after
discovering his identity, she returned when he
was paralyzed in a fall caused by the villain Black
Bull. While recovering, his gear was stolen
again, this time by a criminal named Rick Lawson,
who posed as the prowler until being hospitalized
by the vulture. Regaining mobility, Hobie
resumed the prowler role and aided Spider-Man
during a building fire. He provided Spider-Man
with a jet pack used during a period when Peter
adopted the Hornet persona. Hobie was arrested
during the Superhuman Registration Act
conflict, but escaped with the help of Captain
America's secret Avengers. Peter Parker later
hired Hobie to impersonate Spider-Man again to
maintain his cover. Hobie then infiltrated new U
technologies for Parker Industries and
discovered an experiment involving the villain
Electro, who severely injured him. He was placed
in stasis by the genetic mastermind known as the
Jackal and it was cloned. The clone served the
Jackal, while the real Hobie remained
unconscious in cryosleep. After being
recovered, Hobie ended his alliance with
Spider-Man and was hired by Tony Stark to lead a
crowdfunding firm. When the symbiote god Null
invaded Earth, Hobie adopted the identity of
Hornet and used hacked Stark Tech to repel the
symbiotes. Later, during a gang war conflict,
Hobie lent a prowler suit to a man named Aaron Davis
to investigate the villain Hobgoblin. Hobie
warned Davis that he misused the prowler suit, he
would take it back and reclaim the identity. Aaron
Davis was a former career criminal from an
alternate universe called Earth 1610, Marvel's
ultimate universe. There, Aaron was the brother
of Jefferson Davis, the father of Miles Morales.
While Jefferson reformed as a criminal and became
a police officer after marrying Rio Morales,
Aaron continued his criminal life, using stolen
tech to become the prowler. At one point, he broke
into an abandoned Oz Corp facility and knowingly
took a genetically altered spider with him. The
spider later bit his nephew Miles Morales, giving
him spider powers and making him the new
Spider-Man. Though Jefferson disapproved of
Aaron's influence, Miles maintained a close
relationship with his uncle. You can learn more
about Miles Morales Spider-Man and his duel
against Batwing. Aaron traveled to Mexico City to
confront a rival criminal known as the Scorpion,
but was arrested and returned to New York. He
attempted to manipulate Miles and to help him
eliminate the Scorpion, but Miles refused. In a
final confrontation, Aaron's gauntlets
exploded, killing him. Before dying, he
cryptically claimed that Miles was just like him.
After the universal incursions that led to the
collapse and the eventual rebirth of the
multiverse, Aaron was restored to life in
Morales' primary 616 timeline with no memory of
his death. He purchased an iron spider suit off the
black market and helped form a new Sinister 6
alongside bombshell, electro, hobgoblin,
sandman, and the spot stealing a decommissioned
shield helicarrier. Miles, who was also brought
into the main Marvel timeline, confronted his
uncle. And though the Sinister 6 succeeded in
their heist, Aaron appeared to die during the
ensuing battle, though he was merely injured.
Influenced by his nephew, Aaron began distancing
A villain who can learn more about his duel against
Blockbuster. When Miles was kidnapped by the
villain Assessor, Aaron sought help from his
estranged brother Jefferson. After
commissioning a new prowler suit from a criminal
weapons designer, he joined Jefferson in
infiltrating the Assessor's facility, rescuing
Miles. Later while working for the villain
Ultimatum, actually the Earth 616 variant of
Miles, Aaron attempted to assassinate a criminal
but was stopped by Spider-Man Miles. The botched
job resulted in a bounty on Aaron, which forced him
into a deal that placed him under Ultimatum's
control. Aaron joined his nephew Miles at the
hospital for the birth of his sister Billy, and
later helped resist Ultimatum's plan to return
them to their original universe. During a battle
with Ultimatum's forces, including the Green
Goblin and his Goblinoids, Aaron sacrificed
himself by overloading his suit, sending
Ultimatum and the Goblin away. Aaron was presumed
dead. In reality, Aaron awoke in an alternate
dystopian world ruled by Selim, an evil clone of
Miles Morales. Selim used Aaron's unique
dimensional signature to power a shield around
his empire. Aaron was imprisoned and used as a
living power source for decades. When Miles
arrived in the alternate dimension to rescue his
uncle, Aaron was freed and recovered enough to
fight alongside his nephew. After defeating
Selim, Aaron and Miles traveled back to Earth 616.
Upon their return was when Hobie Brown recruited
Aaron to resume the Prowler identity, tasking him
with uncovering the villain Hobgoblin's plans.
Aaron went undercover as a villain for hire and
joined Hobgoblin's crew, supplying weapons to
criminals and clashing with Miles, until his
cover was revealed. Aaron divulged Hobgoblin's
location and joined Miles, Miss Marvel, and
others to raid the villain's hideout, fighting
alongside them to bring down that criminal
empire. And that's Prowler's history.
Nobilities-wise, the Prowler has a specialized
suit made from a modified military flak jacket
that protects him from concussive forces such as
explosions or falls from great heights. It comes
with a variety of pneumatic or air-based gadgets,
including a cape that can expand, allowing him to
glide over great distances. His boots are rubber
insulated with compressed air technology that
allows him to leave multiple stories high and land
safely. His specialized gauntlets have steel
claws used for fighting and scaling buildings,
and they have wrist-mounted compressed air
launchers that can fire projectiles such as
grappling hooks, gas pellets, steel darts,
flares, or compressed air blasts. Prowler's suit
also comes with some stealth and infiltration
gadgets such as night vision goggles and
temperature control to avoid infrared
detection. Both Hobbie and Aaron are
intellectually gifted, one as an inventor and the
other as a thief. They're both experienced
fighters and skilled marksmen. So which version
will you be going with? I figured it could be either
or. If you're more of a fan of Hobbie, you can
imagine him in this fight or if you're more of a fan
of Aaron, who is the modern and current Prowler,
then you can imagine him in this fight. I didn't
realize he had so much compressed air like a tax.
Yeah, that's his whole thing. So does Blue Beetle.
Yeah, they have a lot in common. Interesting, I had
no idea. Well, to find out how much they have in
common, let me get into Blue Beetle Ted Kord's
backstory. Now Theodore Ted Kord was born with a
gifted intellect, excelling in science,
literature and business from a young age. While he
initially considered joining his father's
company, Kord Omni-Versal Research and
Development, his life changed course after
uncovering a nefarious plot by his uncle Jarvis
Kord. Discovering that Jarvis intended to
unleash an army of super androids for world
domination, Ted sought the help of his
archaeology professor, Dan Garrett, who also
happened to be the original Blue Beetle. Together
they confronted Jarvis on Pago Island, where Dan
revealed his heroic identity and used the power of
a mystical scarab he had discovered years
earlier. In the ensuing battle, Dan was mortally
wounded. With his dying breath, Dan entrusted Ted
with the scarab and the Blue Beetle legacy. Though
Ted accepted the mantle, the scarab failed to
activate for him, refusing to give up he trained to
physical perfection, becoming a skilled
hand-to-hand combatant, and constructed a
variety of crime-fighting gadgets, including a
signature air blast pistol and a beetle-shaped
aircraft known as the Bug. Operating
independently of the scarab, Ted forged his own
identity as the second Blue Beetle. Reviving Kord
Omni-Versal, he turned the company into a major R
&D enterprise, Rivalink Star Labs. From his home
base in Chicago, he launched his career as a
costumed vigilante, taking on foes such as the Mad
Men, Carapax the Indestructible Man, and the
villainous cult known as the Men of the Mask. Ted
Kord's early career brought him into the orbit of
the world's greatest heroes when he was recruited
by the Monitor during the Crisis on Infinite
Earths. During the multiversal conflict, Ted
wielded the Blue Beetle Scarab to destroy shadow
demons, but later lost track of it amidst the
chaos. With the crisis resolved, Ted joined the
newly-reformed Justice League. As a founding
member of the Justice League International, Ted
served as the league's primary pilot and
technician. There he met Booster Gold, who
quickly became his closest friend and frequent
partner in crime-fighting and mischief. Known
collectively as Blue and Gold, the duo balanced
comic relief with critical contributions and
missions against League villains. You can learn
more about Booster Gold in our Booster Gold vs.
Cable dual episode. While in the league, Ted's
confidence in Wasteline began to waver due to long
hours spent in the lab. With encouragement from
teammates such as General Glory and Guy Gardner,
he regained his physical conditioning, though
not before suffering severe injuries during
battles, including a coma after Doomstay's
rampage. Despite these setbacks, Ted remained
active in the field, even joining the spin-off
team Extreme Justice alongside Booster and
Captain Adam, who you can learn more about in his
duel against Wonder Man. In time, Ted left the
league and reasserted control of Cord
Omniversal, eventually making it a subsidiary of
Wayne Enterprises. During this period, he grew
close to Barbara Gordon, aka Oracle, initially as
an online acquaintance. The two developed a deep
friendship and Ted provided her team, the Birds of
Prey, with funding and technology. You can learn
more about the Birds of Prey in our Birds of Prey vs.
A Force Team dual episode. Though he eventually
discovered he had a heart condition, Ted
continued his heroics, occasionally operating
as Blue Beetle in spite of the risk. Ted came back
into possession of Dangarit Scarab after it was
unearthed by Hawkman, though it once again
remained inert in his presence. Around the same
time, Ted noticed strange financial movements
within Cord Omniversal. Funds were being
siphoned and rerouted to mysterious shell
companies. He began investigating, only to be
attacked by a group of thugs known as the Mad Men,
severely injuring Booster in the process.
Tracing a signal hidden within his damaged
equipment, Ted uncovered the location of a secret
facility in Switzerland. There he discovered
that Maxwell Lord, one of his former League
teammates, had taken over the organization
Checkmate and intended to use the OMAC project to
neutralize the global metahuman population.
Lord offered Ted a place at his side. When Ted
refused, Max executed him with a gunshot to the
head. Ted's death shocked the hero community. A
statue was erected in his honor, and Barbara
Gordon memorialized his contributions. Though
the Scarab ultimately passed to a new host,
teenager Jaime Reyes, Ted's legacy endured
through his inventions, his friendship with
Booster Gold, and his example as a hero without
powers who stood among gods. In the wake of Ted's
death, Booster Gold and a future blue beetle
attempted to change history by rescuing him
through time travel. When they succeeded in
briefly bringing Ted forward in time, the
resulting timeline plunged Earth into a dystopia
ruled by OMACs, realizing the cost of his
survival, Ted returned to his original time to die
as he was meant to, thereby restoring the
timeline. During the Blackest Night, a Black
Lantern ring reanimated Ted's corpse. As a Black
Lantern, he attempted to murder Booster, Jaime,
and others, but was eventually neutralized using
technology Ted himself had designed. His remains
were taken to a point outside of time known as the
Vanishing Point to prevent further
resurrection. In post-flashpoint continuity,
Ted Corde reemerged, once again depicted as a
scientific, genius, and industrialist who had
retired from being blue beetle due to health
concerns. When Jaime Reyes approached him for
help in understanding the mysterious Scarab, Ted
became his reluctant mentor and benefactor.
Though Jaime initially rejected the superhero
lifestyle, Ted saw promise in him and provided
guidance, resources, and technological
support, constructing a mobile command center
and even donning his old blue beetle suit when
needed. Ted's investigations into the Scarab
brought him into conflict with Dr. Fate, who
declared the Scarab to be magical in origin,
contrary to Ted's belief it was alien technology.
Ted later joined a coalition of heroes including
the question Captain Adam, Nightshade, and more,
who traveled to Mars to confront Dr. Manhattan for
putting Superman into a coma, though Ted and the
other heroes were overpowered and scattered. You
can learn more about Dr. Manhattan in our Dr.
Manhattan vs. Molecule Man dual episode. Ted
later became a target of Black Mask, who
imprisoned him and used illusion-based powers to
impersonate him. Under Black Mask's control,
Corde Industries funneled resources into
illicit operations, including a revamped
Suicide Squad. With help from the Justice League
and an international team known as the
Revolutionaries, the real Ted was freed and
helped dismantle Black Mask's scheme. You can
learn more about Black Mask in his dual against
Madame Mask. Ted reunited with Booster Gold to
form Blue and Gold Restoration, a private hero for
higher business dedicated to helping everyday
people. Though he was ousted from Corde
Industries for mismanagement, Ted chose to keep
working with Booster instead of rejoining the
Justice League. Their venture faced financial
challenges, but they continued their mission,
providing aid to those overlooked by larger
organizations. Ted was briefly imprisoned by the
Batman who laughs on New Apocalypse, where he was
killed by a giant beetle during the Dark
Multiverse Crisis and resurrected via a Black
Lantern Ring. Despite these ordeals, he returned
to life once more and continued his
crime-fighting career alongside his best friend
Booster Gold and protégé Jaime Reyes. Now,
powers-wise, Ted Corde possesses no innate
superpowers as Blue Beetle, but his genius level
intellect places him among the most brilliant
minds in the world. He's a master inventor and
engineer, creating an array of gadgets and
vehicles. His trademark weapon is the BB Gun,
capable of emitting blinding flashes or
compressed air blasts strong enough to knock back
attackers. Though he also carries smoke bombs,
acid capsules, grappling launchers, and small
beetle-shaped flying surveillance drones known
as baby bugs. His greatest engineering feat,
however, is the bug. An airship that can fly at 600
miles per hour, travel into outer space and
underwater, fire electromagnetic beams,
electrify its hull, shoot nets and grapples, and
more, all from the control of his gloves.
Physically, Blue Beetle trained to peak human
condition and was an Olympic-level acrobat and
martial artist, specializing in Akito and
karate, though his weight and physical ability
has fluctuated over the years due to his heart
condition. Thankfully, Blue Beetle's suit
slightly enhances his strength and durability,
while also coming equipped with suction pads that
allow him to adhere to walls and vision-enhancing
goggles. That's Blue Beetle. Is he gonna have his
bug ship during this fight? Hell yes he does! Let me
rephrase that, that wasn't a question. Blue
Beetle will not be having his bug ship during the
course of this fight, it's just gonna be
mono-e-mono. Do you understand? I understand
that it's something that you do not want. Thank
you. Alright. Did you see more about how similar
they are? Because not only do they have like
air-compressed weapons, they can also climb on
walls, one with suction cups, one with claws. They
both have like light strobes. And they both died
like several times. Right, exactly. But now that
we've got their histories and abilities out of the
way, let's speculate on how one of the 1000
simulated matches will go. The winner is
determined by simulations, not the speculation.
But it's fun to imagine how this fight could play
out. AJ9K, what are the rules of our speculation?
Well, I should say there are no rules, other than
the characters have no prior knowledge of the
other going into the fight. All they are aware of
starting out is that the other character is a
threat that needs to be eliminated. For the
speculation, the contestants will begin
approximately 50 meters apart in a nondescript
environment that will have no bearing on the match
itself, as no environmental statistics are
considered in my simulations. The contestants
must earn victory on their own merit. Alright
then, let's get into it. Blue Beetle and a prowler
meet on the battlefield. Who goes first? I'm gonna
say that prowler goes first. He's gonna speed
blitz Blue Beetle with his claws, and before Blue
Beetle can even say, oh shit this guy is scary
fucking fast, he's just gonna get slashed across
his face. No, prowler's fast but not faster than
Blue Beetle can quick draw his BB gun and just flash
a strobe right in the guy's face so he's
disoriented and seeing spots. So with prowler
partially blinded, Blue Beetle's easily gonna
leap over his blitz and tag prowler in the back with
a compressed air blast that just makes him fall
flat on his face. And as he lands, as prowler is
getting up from the ground, Blue Beetle sends out a
few baby bug drones that scan the area. How big are
these drones? I've seen various sizes for these,
sometimes they're like the size of a volleyball,
but I've also seen them like the size of his palm.
Okay, prowler notices these drones as he gets to
his feet, and he's gonna shoot down a gas capsule
that creates a dark cloud of smoke around him and
it's gonna hide him from these drones and from Blue
Beetle's sight. Uh, you know, Blue Beetle's just
gonna switch the drone surveillance to infrared
so he can see prowler's heat signature with his
dope ass goggles. Except prowler is invisible to
infrared. Okay, so I don't know, Blue Beetle
switches to night vision to see through the dark
smoke and uses drones, shoot down some acid cap.
You know, because Blue Beetle's night vision is
activated, prowler, he shoots out a magnesium
flare right then, and it's just gonna light up Blue
Beetle's entire view. And that's gonna
temporarily blind him. So like, as Blue Beetle's
grabbing at his goggles, prowler is gonna shoot
the bug drones out of the air with some darts by our
term as gauntlets. And then he's gonna leap out of
the smoke and just flying kick Blue Beetle right
into his beard gut. Six pack, my man. Six pack. He's
been working out. Six pack of beer. All right, so he
takes the kick, lands on his back, but he's gonna
back somersault onto his hands and knees before
launching himself with his legs back at prowler
and rocking him with a spinning back fist. He's
blind. How did he even see the prowler to hit him? I
don't know. He's, you know, he peered through the
spots in his vision. He's good like that. Well, not
good enough, because prowler blocks this hit. Oh,
it's a spinning double back fist. So when prowler
blocks one hand, Blue Beetle just spins the
opposite direction and clocks him with the other
hand. What? Okay, prowler gets hit, but he's gonna
counter with a spin kick and slashing uppercut
combo, followed by this like compressed air blast
from his gauntlets that just sends Blue Beetle
flying backward and knocking the wind out of him.
No, no, because in the middle of this combo,
suddenly prowler finds himself wrapped in a net
all around him. And as he struggles to move, he's
hoisted into the air by Blue Beetle's bug ship with
a cable that was attached to the net. I said, you're
making me sick here. I said, you can't use the bug
ship. I'm sorry. I thought you'd know I just
naturally use whatever Blue Beetle uses out in the
field. St. Blue Beetle can't have his bug ship is
like saying ghost writer can't have his hell cycle
or silver surfer can't have his surfboard. I doubt
that. Regardless, prowler is gonna slash his way
out of this net with his claws. And then he's gonna
glide down toward Blue Beetle, who's like, Oh,
fuck, my cheating ass is about to die. And prowler
lands feet first onto Blue Beetle, and he
activates his compressed air boots right as he
lands, which like a shotgun blast just explodes
Blue Beetle into a blue smear on the ground. No,
this net is made with metal fibers. And before
prowler could slash his way out of it, the bug ship
just sends an electric current into the net
electrocuting prowler and just sizzling him to a
crisp. Like I said, cheating ass, you can't use the
bug ship in this. I don't know what to tell you, bro.
It happened, except it. Okay, we'll go ahead and
leave the match there. Either Jonathan cheats and
the bug ship captures and electrocutes the
prowler, or he plays this like a man and prowler
just eviscerates Blue Beetle with his air
compressed boots. Hey, it takes a real man to admit
when he's defeated, Joseph. Let's go ahead and
find out who wins by inputting the stats, running
the simulations and finding out who comes out on
top. AJ9K hit it. Inputting data, running
calculations, processing results, simulations
complete. Okay, this was an awesome match. These
characters are way more similar than I would have
thought. And I kind of always love when that
happens. We just kind of serendipitously fall
into an awesome match that I never even knew I
wanted to see. Yeah, they had a lot in common,
including their invasiveness, their fighting
skill, their range, their perception. They had a
lot in common. Yeah, where Blue Beetle had the edge
was versatility. He just has more gadgets and
intelligence, but just barely. Blue Beetle did
have the edge when I came to movement speed,
because yes, I did factor the bug ship into his
stats. You cheating bastard. Well, we just
figured that a majority of the time we see the
character, whether it's in the comics or in other
media, he has his bug ship. It's a big part of who the
character is. It's like seeing Night Owl from
Watchmen without his Owl ship. And because of
that, Blue Beetle also got the edge when it came to
damage level. Yeah, the bug ship is such a big part
of the lore of the character that it was even
incorporated in the Blue Beetle live action
movie, even though Hymeria's doesn't use the bug
ship. Exactly. So who do you think is winning this
one, Jonathan? Is that even a question? Blue
Beetle all the way. And Instagram agrees with me,
because 69% of the people who took the poll voted
for Blue Beetle. Whoever voted for Blue Beetle in
that poll doesn't even know what a 69 is. Let's go
ahead and get the results. Hey, you are, sir. The
winner of the matchup between Blue Beetle and
prowler is, I'm so sick. Can't even say it. Blue
Beetle. Yay. Out of the 1000 matches, Blue Beetle
won 65.6% of the time. Proller only won 34.4%.
Okay, so Blue Beetle wins about two-thirds of the
time. Not quite. About two-thirds, though.
Aren't you glad that you rolled out a bed for this?
This is awesome. No. No, in fact, this whole day
just sucks. Well, sorry to add to your misery, but
also hashtag, sorry, not sorry. Let's get your ass
back in bed so you don't die. That does it for this
duel. AJ9K, help close us out. In our next episode,
we will be reviewing Daredevil born again. I have
not finished watching it, but so far, so good. That
does it for this episode. We want to give a big
thanks to our executive producers, John
Sturrosky, Zachary Hepburn, Dustin Belcom,
Miggy Mathen-Gian, Brandon Estegard, Nathaniel
Wagner, Levi Yatn, Austin Wazelowski, AJ
Dunkerly, Nick Obanto, Scott Camacho, Gil
Camacho, Adam Spees, Dean Molesky, Devin Davis,
Joseph Kirsting, Josh Leiner, Mike Williams, and
Oscar Galvez for helping make this podcast
possible. We'll talk to you guys next week. Up, up,
and away, true believers. Fun fact, Blue Beetle's
alternate dimension variant is called Dung
Beetle, who is a member of the League of Nasty
Bastards. Look it up.